<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Organization of the Ascending Projections F&apos;rom the 
  Ventral Tegmental Area: A Multiple Fluorescent Retrograde Tracer 
  Study in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>ALBERT0 ALBANESE AND DIEGO MINCIACCHI</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The projections from the ventral tegmental area of Tsai 
    (VTA) to the frontal cortex (FC), lateral septum (LS), nucleus 
    accumbens (Acc), caudateputamen (CPu), and lateral habenula (LH) 
    were investigated in the rat by means of the double retrograde 
    fluorescent tracer technique.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">True blue and fast blue were used in combination with 
    nuclear yellow as retrograde tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">After combined injections placed into two different 
    terminal fields, many singly and some doubly labeled neurons were 
    seen in the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">In all cases the labeled cells were observed in the 
    ipsilateral VTA, while after injections placed into the LS and Acc 
    some fluorescent neurons were also seen in the contralateral 
    VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The patterns of distribution of the labeled neurons showed 
    a topographic organization of the VTA efferent pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">However, some degree of overlapping was evident in the 
    distribution of cells retrogradely labeled from different terminal 
    fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The number of the doubly labeled neurons varied according 
    to the sites of combined injections, but in each experiment it 
    never exceeded 10% of the total number of labeled perikarya.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Doubly labeled neurons were particularly numerous after 
    combined injections placed into the FC, LS, or LH; on the contrary, 
    very few doubly labeled cells were observed after combined 
    injections placed into the CPu and LS or LH.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The organization of the ascending VTA projections suggests 
    that they probably integrated into different anatomical sets.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The ascending projections of the ventral tegmental area 
    (VTA) are distributed over several regions of the forebrain, 
    namely, the frontal, suprarhinal, and entorhinal cortices, the 
    amygdala, the lateral septum, the olfactory tubercle, the striatum, 
    the nucleus accumbens, the hippocampus, and the lateral habenular 
    nucleus (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;77; Fallon and Moore, &apos;78; 
    Nauta et al., &apos;78; Beckstead et al., &apos;79; Simon et al., 
    &quot;79; Phillipson and Griffith, &apos;80; Scatton et al., 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Such an array of projections to regions belonging to 
    different anatomical circuitries accounts for uncertainty in 
    attributing a definite functional significance to the VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">However, from many studies it seems that the VTA plays a 
    role in the control of simple motor activity and complex behavior 
    (Le Mod et al., &apos;75; Fink and Smith, &apos;80; Javoy-Agid and 
    Agid, &apos;80); this action is probably exerted via different sets 
    of anatomical connections, such as the the ascending projections to 
    regions belonging to extrapyramidal system or to the limbic 
    system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The VTA contains the dopaminergic cell bodies of the A10 
    cell group (Dahlstrom and Fuxe, &apos;64) and histofluorescence 
    studies have described dopaminergic efferent projections from the 
    VTA (see reviews in Lindvall and Bjorklund, &apos;78; Moore and 
    Bloom, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Immunohistochemical studies have also shown the presence 
    of cholecystokininand enkephalincontaining neurons in the VTA 
    (Hokfelt et al., &apos;80; Johnson et al., &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Furthermore, it is known from morphological studies 
    (Phillipson, &apos;79a) that the VTA can be subdivided into 
    cytoarchitectonically distinct cell groups, which all contain 
    dopaminergic neurons and possibly give rise to different efferent 
    pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Catecholaminecontaining neurons are known to have a rich 
    collateralization pattern (Lindvall and Bjorklund, &apos;74), and 
    it has also been shown that axons arising from neurons located in 
    the VTA give off recurrent collaterals to their parent cell bodies 
    (Phillipson, &apos;79b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Taken together, all these data suggest that the 
    anatomical organization of the VTA cells as well as of their 
    efferent pathways is rather complex and diversified.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Therefore, the question arose as to whether the VTA 
    efferent fibers, which are distributed to limbic and striatal 
    regions of the forebrain, in fact represent collaterals of the same 
    ascending axons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">This problem has been investigated only in part, both 
    electrophysiologically by the antidromic activation technique 
    (Deniau et al., &apos;80) and anatomically by means of fluorescent 
    tracers (Fallon, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In order further to define the hodological organization 
    of some functionally significant circuitries originating in the 
    ventral midbrain tegmentum, the double fluorescent retrograde 
    tracer technique (Kuypers et al., &apos;80) was used in the present 
    study to trace the VTA efferent connections to the frontal cortex 
    (FC), lateral septal nucleus (LS), caudate-putamen (CPu), nucleus 
    accumbens (Acc), and lateral habenular nucleus (LH).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The present report describes the detailed topography of 
    mesencephalic neurons projecting to these regions and shows the 
    presence of cell bodies giving off divergent axon collaterals to 
    different target territories.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s22">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The present study is based on a total of 39 male Wistar 
    rats, weighing 250-300 gm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The animals were deeply anesthetized with sodium 
    pentobarbital (40 mgikg) before undergoing surgery.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Three fluorescent retrograde tracers were used 
    (Bentivoglio et al., &apos;79a, &apos;80b): true blue (TB, 2% 
    aqueous suspension), fast blue (FB, 2% aqueous suspension), and 
    nuclear yellow (NY, 1% aqueous suspension).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Under appropriate light conditions, TB and FB fluoresce 
    blue and label chiefly the neural cytoplasm: They were 
    alternatively injected in combination with NY which, under the same 
    conditions, fluoresces yellow and labels chiefly the neural 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Each animal received one injection of either TB or FB and 
    one of NY in two different regions of the same cerebral hemisphere, 
    by means of two different Hamilton microdrive microsyringes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">With the exception of the cortical injections, all needle 
    insertions were placed stereotaxically, according to the atlas by 
    Pellegrino and Cushman (&apos;67).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The experiments can be subdivided in seven groups (see 
    Table 1): Group A consisted of four animals in which one 
    fluorophore was injected into the FC and the other into the LS; 
    group B consisted of six animals in which the injections were 
    placed into the FC and into the LH; group C consisted of six 
    animals in which the injections were made into the CPu and into the 
    LS; group D consisted of five animals in which the injections were 
    made into the CPu and the LH; group E consisted of six animals in 
    which one tracer was injected into the Acc and the other into the 
    LS; group F consisted of five animals in which the injections were 
    made into the LS and the LH; group G consisted of seven animals in 
    which the injections were placed into the Acc and into the LH.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Following an injection, the syringe was left in place for 
    10 minutes before removal from the brain: This procedure greatly 
    limits the spillage of tracers along the needle tracks.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">In order to prevent the migration of NY out of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons, which can be detected by fluorescent 
    labeling of the adjacent glial nuclei (Bentivoglio et al., 
    &apos;80a), survival after the NY injections varied from 18 to 22 
    hours (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Since survival after TB injections varied from 4 to 8 
    days, while after the FB injections it was 3-5 days (see Table l), 
    two different surgical sessions, one for the TB or FB injections 
    and a second for the NY injection, were performed in each 
    experiment.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">All the animals were perfused transcardially with saline 
    followed by 10% buffered formalin (pH 7.2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The brains were soaked in 30% buffered sucrose (pH 7.2) 
    for a period ranging from 4 to 10 hours, then cut on a freezing 
    microtome into 30-pm-thick sections, which were immediately mounted 
    on slides from distilled water and air dried.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The sections were studied, without coverslipping, under a 
    Leitz Ploemopak fluorescence microscope using a 340380-nm light 
    excitation wavelength and a 430-nm barrier filter (filter-mirror 
    system A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Serial sections through the injection sites were charted 
    for the reconstruction of the size of the injection area; the 
    distribution of labeled neurons was charted on serial drawings of 
    the ventral midbrain tegmentum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">In each case, the singly and doubly labeled perikaria 
    were counted while charting, and the number of doubly labeled 
    neurons was indicated as percentage of the total population of 
    labeled cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">In order to avoid decrease of fluorescence, which may 
    occur during the exposure of tissue specimens to the ultraviolet 
    light, the photographic documentation was taken either after 
    charting or on different sections from those chosen for the 
    charts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The charts were compared with Nissl-stained standard 
    series of the rat brain and were additionally checked by 
    counterstaining some sections with cresyl violet after charting.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s40">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Delimitation of ventral tegmental area</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">In order to draw guidelines for the description of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> labeled 
    neurons, it is convenient to briefly outline the position and 
    boundaries of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Tsai (&apos;25) first described it as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>nucleus ventralis 
    tegmentalis</neuroanatomicalLocation>; but, due to its loose 
    neuronal texture, the term area, rather than nucleus, has entered 
    common terminology.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> is located in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    mesencephalon</neuroanatomicalLocation>, medial to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the cerebral 
    peduncle</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial 
    lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and ventral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the red nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>; 
    ventrally, the area directly abuts <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    interpeduncular nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> has ill-defined boundaries; rostrally 
    and caudally it merges with <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    diencephalic and mesencephalic reticular 
    formations</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, respectively; laterally it is 
    continuous with <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the pars compacta of the 
    substantia nigra (SNC)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and with 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the supralemniscal 
    area</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Cytoarchitectonic studies in the cat and rat have shown 
    that <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral midbrain 
    tegmentum</neuroanatomicalLocation> contains three identifiable 
    cell groupings: <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nucleus paranigralis, 
    the nucleus parabrachialis pigmentosus, and the interfascicular 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">In the rat brain, these nuclei are contained within the 
    boundaries of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Taber, &apos;61; Phillipson, 
    &apos;79a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">As demonstrated with histofluorescence studies, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> is 
    composed largely of dopamine neurons (cell group AlO), and also 
    contains nondopaminergic neurons, which are intermixed with the 
    catecholaminecontaining perikarya (van der Kooy et al., &apos;81; 
    Albanese, &apos;82; Albanese and Bentivoglio, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Therefore, it is convenient to consider the rostrocaudal 
    extent of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the A10 dopamine cell 
    group</neuroanatomicalLocation> as a reliable criterion to define 
    the rostral and caudal boundaries of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">In the light of this consideration, and in accord with 
    two recent topographic histofluorescence studies (Fallon and Moore, 
    &quot;78; Phillipson, &apos;79a), we assume here as the rostralmost 
    level of<neuroanatomicalLocation> VTA</neuroanatomicalLocation> a 
    section just rostral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial 
    accessory optic nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and crossing 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the mammillary body and the tegmental 
    decussatio</neuroanatomicalLandmark>; we assume the caudalmost 
    level is a section just caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    tegmental decussatio</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the red 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s51">Injection sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The <tracerChemical>TB</tracerChemical> injection areas 
    showed two concentric zones around the needle track (Huisman et 
    al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    LS</injectionLocation>, the first zone involved only 
    <injectionLocation>the LS</injectionLocation>, while the second 
    zone extended medially into <injectionSpread>the ipsilatteral 
    medial septum</injectionSpread> and laterally up to 
    <injectionSpread>the ependyma of the lateral 
    ventricle</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">In order to avoid crossing <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    FC</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, in the experiments of group A the 
    septal injections were performed with the syringe sloped at a 
    45&quot; angle from rear to front.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    LH</injectionLocation> the first zone involved <injectionLocation>
    most of the LH and the stria medullaris</injectionLocation>, while 
    the second zone was very narrow and did not extend beyond the 
    borders of <injectionLocation>the LH</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">In cases D138 and D139, in which <injectionLocation>the 
    CPu</injectionLocation> was injected, the overall injection site 
    was quite big; the second zone extended dorsally and laterally up 
    to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the corpus 
    callosum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, medially to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the border of the lateral 
    ventricle</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and ventrally it did not reach 
    the anterior commissure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">In case D153, in which <injectionLocation>the 
    Acc</injectionLocation> was injected, the first zone was just 
    medial to the anterior commissure and the second zone did not 
    exceed the boundaries of the nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">In the charts of <tracerChemical>FB</tracerChemical> 
    injection sites two concentric zones were outlined: The central 
    zone corresponded to the first and second zone depicted by Bharos 
    et al. (&apos;81), while the peripheral zone corresponded to the 
    third zone of the same authors.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    LS</injectionLocation> the two zones were quite similar to those 
    observed with the injection of 
    <tracerChemical>TB</tracerChemical>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    LH</injectionLocation>, the central zone was always restricted to 
    this nucleus; the peripheral zone ventrally did not exceed 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the fasciculus 
    retroflexu</neuroanatomicalLandmark>s, and in some cases it 
    extended medially into <injectionSpread>the medial 
    habenula</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The injection site of case D204 is shown in Figure 1.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The <tracerChemical>NY</tracerChemical> injection sites 
    were also divided into two concentric zones: The central zone 
    corresponded to the first and second zone described by Bharos et 
    al. (&apos;81) and by Huisman et al. (&apos;81); the peripheral 
    zone corresponded to the third zone of the same authors.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">In the cortical injections, the two zones involved large 
    portions of <injectionLocation>the frontal pole and of the 
    supragenual and the anterior cingulate 
    cortices</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    CPu</injectionLocation>, the injection sites involved different 
    parts of this nucleus; in some cases (D190, D198, D200, and D201) 
    the <tracerChemical>NY</tracerChemical> injections involved 
    <injectionLocation>the rostral part of CPu</injectionLocation>, 
    i.e., at the same rostrocaudal level of <injectionLocation>the 
    Acc</injectionLocation>, while in the other cases the injection 
    areas were located more caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">However, the <tracerChemical>NY</tracerChemical> 
    injections <labelingModifier>never</labelingModifier> involved 
    <injectionLocation>the entire volume of the 
    CPu</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">In the case injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    LS</injectionLocation>, the peripheral zone extended medially to 
    <injectionSpread>the ipsilateral medial septum</injectionSpread>, 
    while laterally it did not exceed the border of the lateral 
    ventricle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">In the cases injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    Acc</injectionLocation> the two zones involved 
    <injectionLocation>the anterior commissure and this 
    nucleus</injectionLocation>, with the exception of two cases (D160, 
    D209) in which the peripheral zone extended medially far enough to 
    involve <injectionSpread>the nucleus of the diagonal 
    band</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s68">Topography of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The distribution of flourescent retrogradely labeled 
    neurons in <labelingLocation>the mesencephalon</labelingLocation> 
    varied according to the topography of the injection sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">After <exptLabel>injections placed into <injectionLocation
    >the FC</injectionLocation></exptLabel> <labelingDescription>the 
    retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> were found 
    ipsilaterally in <labelingLocation>the VTA</labelingLocation> and 
    in <labelingLocation>the SNC</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s71">At 
    rostral levels, <labelingDescription>the fluorescent 
    cells</labelingDescription> were predominantly located in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial third of the SNC</labelingLocation> 
    and in <labelingLocation>the adjacent ventral part of the 
    VTA</labelingLocation>, which corresponds to the nucleus 
    paranigralis; at more caudal levels <labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation>
    the medial VTA</labelingLocation>, near the border of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s72">With the exception of 
    <labelingDescription>a few neurons</labelingDescription> situated 
    just beyond the midline, <labelingDescription>no labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    contralateral mesencephalon</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">In <exptLabel>the cases injected into <injectionLocation>
    the LS</injectionLocation></exptLabel> <labelingDescription>many 
    retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> were found in 
    <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral VTA</labelingLocation> they were 
    located medially, close to the border of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
    the interpeduncular nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and also in 
    <labelingLocation>the midline</labelingLocation>, in 
    <labelingLocation>the interfascicular nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    and within <labelingLocation>the fibers of the tegmental 
    decussatio</labelingLocation>; <labelingDescription>some labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were always found more ventrally, 
    proximate to <labelingLocation>the fibers of the mammillary 
    peduncle</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s74">In addition, 
    <labelingDescription>some retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were located in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial part of the contralateral VTA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75"><exptLabel>Injections placed into <injectionLocation>the 
    CPu</injectionLocation></exptLabel> caused 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> of 
    <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral SNC and 
    VTA</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s76">Particularly <labelingLocation>
    the SNC</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>filled with 
    labeled neurons</labelingDescription>; <labelingDescription>the 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    VTA</labelingLocation> were prevalently located in <labelingLocation
    >the lateral part</labelingLocation>, close to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial 
    lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, or medially, near or just 
    beyond <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    midline</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s77">In fact, 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> of 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral VTA</labelingLocation> 
    consisted of <labelingDescription>a small number of fluorescent 
    cells</labelingDescription> lying not far from the midline and 
    probably representing displaced ipsilateral perikarya.</S></TTE>

    <TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s78">In <exptLabel>the cases injected into <injectionLocation
      >the Acc</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were present in 
      <labelingDescription>the medial portion of the 
      SNC</labelingDescription>, but they were 
      <labelingDescription>particularly numerous</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the VTA</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79">In this area, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were predominantly distributed in the 
      midline: At rostral levels they were located between 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the two fasciculi 
      retroflexi</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and in <labelingLocation>the 
      interfascicular nucleus</labelingLocation>, while more caudally 
      they were distributed above <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      interpeduncular nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80">More laterally in <labelingLocation>the 
      VTA</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>many fluorescent 
      cells</labelingDescription> were seen around <labelingLocation>
      the medial lemniscus</labelingLocation> and within 
      <labelingLocation>the rootlets of the oculomotor 
      nerve</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81"><labelingDescription>Neurons</labelingDescription> 
      labeled from <injectionLocation>Acc</injectionLocation> 
      injections were <labelingDescription>rarely 
      found</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      portion of the VTA</labelingLocation>; this was especially true 
      in those cases in which <injectionLocation>the 
      Acc</injectionLocation> injections were rather small (see Fig. 
      8).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82">However, <labelingDescription>some fluorescent 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were always found in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral side</labelingLocation>; they 
      were located somewhat more laterally than those labeled from 
      septal injections.</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">In <exptLabel>the cases injected into <injectionLocation>
    the LH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> <labelingDescription>the 
    retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> were predominantly 
    fond in <labelingLocation>the dorsal part of the ipsilateral 
    VTA</labelingLocation>; they were more numerous at rostral levels, 
    particularly in <labelingLocation>a region situated between the 
    medial lemniscus and the fasciculus 
    retroflexus</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s84"><labelingDescription>No 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> were found <labelingLocation>
    contralaterally</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s85">Collateralization of VTA 
    efferent pathways</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">In all the experiments of combined injections, the 
    retrogradely doubly labeled neurons represented a minority of the 
    total number of retrogradely labeled cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">The doubly labeled neurons were always located only 
    ipsilaterally to the sites of injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">In agreement with previous observations (De Olmos and 
    Heimer, &apos;80), it was noted that the doubly labeled cells were 
    not as brilliantly fluorescent as the singly labeled ones; 
    notwithstanding, the identification of doubly labeled neurons was 
    never doubtful.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">After <exptLabel>combined injections placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the FC and LS</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group A), <labelingDescription>the doubly labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> varied from 5 to 10% of the total 
    number of labeled perikarya and were predominantly distributed in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsolateral part of the ipsilateral 
    VTA</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">After <exptLabel>combined injections placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the FC and LH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group B), <labelingDescription>the doubly labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> varied from 5 to 10% of the total; 
    they were more numerous at rostral levels in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsolateral part of the VTA</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">After <exptLabel>combined injections placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the CPu and LS</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group C), <labelingDescription>very few retrogradely doubly 
    labeled neurons</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation
    >the VTA</labelingLocation>; their number varied from 1 to 2% of 
    the total number of labeled cells (Fig. 5).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">After <exptLabel>combined injections placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the CPu and LH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group D), <labelingDescription>the doubly labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were 2-3% of the total; in rostral 
    sections of the mesencephalon these cells were located in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal part of the 
    VTA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">After <exptLabel>combined injections into 
    <injectionLocation>the Acc and LS</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group E), <labelingDescription>the doubly labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilateral VTA</labelingLocation>, where they represented 2-5% of 
    the total number of labeled cells (Fig. 6).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">In <exptLabel>the cases injected into <injectionLocation>
    the LS and LH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> (group F), 
    <labelingDescription>the retrogradely doubly labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were distributed in <labelingLocation>
    the dorsolateral and rostral portion of the ipsilateral 
    VTA</labelingLocation>; they varied from 7 to 10% of the total 
    population of labeled perikarya (Fig. 7).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">Finally, in <exptLabel>the cases injected into 
    <injectionLocation>the ACC and LH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    (group G), <labelingDescription>the doubly labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    rostral part of the VTA</labelingLocation>, where they represented 
    3-5% of the total population (Fig. 8).</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s96">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">The present data show that mesencephalic neurons 
    projecting to the forebrain display a definite topographic 
    organization; thus, the distribution of neurons retrogradely 
    labeled after injections placed into the FC, LS, CPu, Acc, and LH 
    is consistently reproducible in different experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">However, as this study shows, VTA neurons projecting to 
    different target territories are not clustered into subnuclei but 
    are instead partially intermixed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">The population of neurons giving off divergent axon 
    collaterals does not exceed, in each experiment, 1090 of the total 
    population of retrogradely labeled cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">However, the number of labeled perikarya varied in the 
    different groups of combined injections, thus suggesting an 
    organized pattern of collateralization.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">In fact, very few doubly labeled neurons could be 
    detected in the mesencephalon after combined injections involving 
    limbic and striatal areas (e.g., groups C, D); on the contrary, the 
    number of doubly labeled cells tended to be higher after combined 
    injections placed into two limbic structures (e.g., groups A, B, 
    F).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Therefore, on the basis of the double-labeling 
    experiments it is apparent that the limbic and striatal populations 
    of VTA neurons exchange little communication through direct axonal 
    arborization.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">However, the present study does not deal with two of the 
    known target territories of the VTA ascending system, the amygdala 
    and the entorhinal cortex, which are both believed to play an 
    important role in the limbic system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">This problem is an object for future studies, which will 
    probably make it possible to complete the findings reported 
    here.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">The present study also shows that mesencephaloaccumbens 
    neurons have a somewhat different organization from the rest of VTA 
    rostrally projecting neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">After combined injections involving the Acc and the LS 
    or LH (groups E and G), the number of retrogradely double-labeled 
    neurons was approximately 3-5% of the total population, i.e., 
    higher than the number of cells labeled from CPu and LS or LH 
    combined injections (groups C and D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Second, mesencephaloaccumbens neurons differ from the 
    rest of VTA cells in that they are distributed throughout the 
    ipsilateral ventral tegmentum; this finding is in keeping with the 
    retrograde study by Nauta et al. (&apos;78) and does not support 
    the data by Fallon and Moore (&apos;78) concerning a medioventral 
    clustering of the mesencephaloaccumbens cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Furthermore, in agreement with previous studies in the 
    rat (Chronister et al., &apos;80) and in the cat (Groenenwegen et 
    al., &apos;80), our data demonstrate that the mesencephaloaccumbens 
    pathway is bilateral in origin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">Anterograde tracing studies (Beckstead et al., &apos;79; 
    Simon et al., &apos;79) have shown that this pathway represents the 
    major efferent system of the VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">Morphologically, the Acc belongs to the striatum, but 
    many studies have pointed out that this nucleus is functionally 
    related to the limbic system (see Nauta et al., &apos;78; Johansson 
    and Hokfelt, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">Mogenson et al. (&apos;80) have also suggested that the 
    ACC may constitute a transitional zone or a link between the basal 
    ganglia and the limbic system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">Since a similar role has been attributed to the VTA, it 
    is likely that the mesencephaloaccumbens pathway plays a key role 
    in connecting striatal and limbic circuitries.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">The distribution of mesencephalocortical, 
    mesencephaloseptal, mesencephalostriatal, and mesencephalohabenular 
    neurons, as shown in the present report, is in keeping with 
    previous anterograde and retrograde studies (Beckstead, &apos;76; 
    Carter and Fibiger, &apos;77; Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;77; 
    Bjorklund and Lindvall, &apos;78; Fallon and Moore, &apos;78; Nauta 
    et al., &apos;78; Beckstead et al., &apos;79; Bentivoglio et al., 
    &apos;78, &apos;79b; Simon et al., &apos;79; Phillipson and 
    Griffith, &apos;80; Fallon, &apos;81; Albanese and Bentivoglio, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">However, the present study adds to existing descriptions 
    some new details that may be relevant to our knowledge of the 
    organization of the ascending VTA efferent pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">For the first time the presence of a crossed 
    mesencephaloseptal projection originating from the VTA is 
    reported.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">After HRP injections into the LS, which also extended 
    into the medial septum, Fallon and Moore (&apos;78) did not find 
    retrogradely labeled perikarya in the contralateral VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">Differences in sensitivity between the standard HRP 
    technique and the fluorescent retrograde tracing method may account 
    for this discrepancy.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">The topographic distribution of VTA neurons giving rise 
    to divergent axon collaterals is reported here for the first 
    time.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">The present results show that the doubly labeled VTA 
    neurons are distributed ipsilaterally to the injection sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">This is also true in the case of combined LS and Acc 
    injections (group E), where single TB and NY, but no TBNY doubly 
    labeled cells were found in the contralateral VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">These data are in keeping with the electrophysiological 
    study by Deniau et al. (&apos;80), and with the anatomical report 
    by Fallon (&apos;81), who describes the occurrence of doubly and 
    triply labeled neurons in the VTA after injections placed into the 
    FC, Acc, and LS.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">The use of the multiple fluorescent retrograde tracer 
    technique is one of the few anatomical methods suitable for 
    demonstrating the existence of divergent axon collaterals in neural 
    pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">This technique appears to be more sensitive than other 
    available multiple or single retrograde tracing methods (Huisman et 
    al., &apos;82); however, there is still the possibility that the 
    fluorescent retrogradely double-labeled neurons underestimate the 
    actual population of neurons possessing long axon collateals (De 
    Olmos and Heimer, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">This aspect certainly requires further analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">The multiple fluorescent retrograde tracer technique, 
    however, has hitherto been used in the study of many ascending and 
    descending systems in the brain (Bentivoglio et al., &apos;79b; 
    Bharos et al., &apos;81; Huisman et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">Its application to the ascending pathways of the VTA 
    presents some difficulties especially in the rat, due to the close 
    proximity of some of the injected structures to the fiber bundles 
    ascending from the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">This problem is crucial in the case of injections placed 
    into the Acc, which lies very close to the medial forebrain bundle, 
    a major route containing ascending pathways bound to the FC and 
    CPu, and also in the case of injections placed into the CPu, which 
    necessarily involve the fibers crossing this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">In the light of these considerations, the present study 
    does not deal with combined injections involving the Acc and the FC 
    or the Acc and the CPu, which would have led to dubious retrograde 
    double labeling in the VTA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">Second, it is also possible that neurons singly labeled 
    from Acc or CPu injections may actually represent 
    mesencephalocortical cells, whose axons were severed or damaged at 
    the level of the injection sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">This argument also applies to earlier retrograde tracing 
    studies on the same pathways (Fallon and Moore, &apos;78; Nauta et 
    al., &apos;78; Fallon, &apos;81) and represents a limit of all 
    currently available retrograde tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">However, it must also be remembered that the 
    distribution of mesencephalocortical neurons, as seen in the 
    present study, corresponds only in small part to the topography of 
    mesencephaloaccumbens and mesencephalostriatal cells (e.g., compare 
    Figs. 3,5,6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">This is in keeping with previous anterograde and 
    retrograde tracing findings (Fallon and Moore, &apos;78; Nauta et 
    al., &apos;78; Simon et al., &apos;79) and supports the view that 
    the vast majority of neurons retrogradely labeled from Acc and CPu 
    injections do actually project to these target territories.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Recently, a biochemical report by Scatton et al. 
    (&apos;80) showed that the hippocampal formation receives 
    dopaminergic afferents from the VTA; this pathway is believed to 
    cross the septal region before reaching the hippocampus (Scatton et 
    al., &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">It is possible, therefore, that injections placed into 
    the LS may have damaged axons of passage and caused consequent 
    labeling of mesencephalohippocampal neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">In this respect it must also be considered, however, 
    that the hippocampus certainly represents a minor site of efference 
    of the VTA neurons (Simon et al., &apos;79) and that a precise 
    topographical mapping of the mesencephalohippocampal pathway has 
    not yet been performed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">Very recently, Huisman et al. (&apos;82) have shown 
    that, at least for the FB and NY injections, the central zone of 
    the injection site is the only area from which retrograde transport 
    occurs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">In our material, the terminal fields of the VTA 
    ascending projections were generally largely involved by the 
    central zone of injection areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">As an exception, the injections placed into the FC or 
    into the CPu, two rather large structures, did not involve 
    completely the VTA projection targets.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">This may have caused some reduction of the cell bodies 
    retrogradely labeled from these two territories.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">In this respect, it must be considered, however, that 
    the distribution and the number of fluorescent cells, which were 
    seen after injections placed into the FC (ten cases), were highly 
    reproducible, and that the CPu injections (eleven cases) were 
    placed into different parts of this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Since the mesencephalostriatal axons are known to 
    possess a rich terminal arborization (see Moore and Bloom, 
    &apos;78) it is believed that the fluorescent cells which were seen 
    after CPu injections do represent most of the mesencephalostriatal 
    population.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">Finally, the analysis of the present data brings forth 
    some new important problems concerning the collateralization of the 
    VTA ascending projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">The first question arising is whether the doubly labeled 
    cells, which have been detected in each of the seven groups of 
    combined injections, do belong to separate and distinct 
    subpopulations of VTA neurons or, alternatively, represent a unique 
    subgroup of VTA cells sending long collateral branches to different 
    terminal sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">In the first case, the total number of VTA neurons 
    possessing long axon collaterals would be rather large as compared 
    to the whole VTA neural population, and, in addition, the existence 
    of specific collateralization patterns of the VTA cells may be 
    expected.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">In the latter case, a relatively small subpopulation of 
    VTA cells would send long axon collaterals to more than two target 
    territories, while the remainder of VTA neurons may not possess 
    long axon collaterals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">The present data do not allow to answer to this 
    question, which will require future anatomical and physiological 
    studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">Furthermore, as pointed out earlier, most VTA neurons 
    are catecholamine containing, but the presence of 
    noncatecholamine-containing somata has also been demonstrated in 
    the same region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Therefore, the question arises as to whether the VTA 
    neurons which give off divergent axon collaterals do contain 
    dopamine.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">This problem has not been investigated directly and it 
    is open for future research; however, some indications can be 
    obtained from data in the literature.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">A careful comparison of the present chartings with those 
    obtained by means of anatomohistochemical techniques (Albanese, 
    &apos;82; Albanese and Bentivoglio, &apos;82) reveals that the 
    distribution of nondopaminergic neurons projecting to the FC, LS, 
    and Acc does not overlap with the topography of the VTA cell 
    population which is doubly labeled from the same areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">This consideration supports the view that the doubly 
    labeled cells are dopaminergic.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">However, some recent pharmacological studies (Agnati et 
    al., &apos;80; Chiodo et al., &apos;80; Browder et al., &apos;81) 
    have pointed out the existence of more than one type of 
    mesencephalic dopamine neuron.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">It is therefore apparent that the correlation of 
    anatomical and pharmacological data is a matter of increasing 
    complexity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">However, it is probably from the cooperation of 
    different methodological approaches that it will be possible to 
    formulate a comprehensive functional model of the VTA ascending 
    efferent systems.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="25" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s155">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s156">The authors are greatly 
    indebted to Prof.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s157">G.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s158">Macchi for his guidance and 
    for revising the manuscript, and to Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s159">M.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s160">Bentivoglio for her advice 
    and criticism.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s161">Technical assistance was 
    given by Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s162">A.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s163">Sbriccoli, Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s164">R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s165">Mallucci, Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s166">B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s167">Ghirotti, and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s168">G.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s169">Rosi; the editorial work was 
    performed by Mrs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s170">M.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s171">Bonfante.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s172">Samples of nuclear yellow 
    were kindly supplied by Dr. 0.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s173">Loewe (Hoechst Company, 
    Frankfurt, G.F.R.); fast blue and true blue were purchased from 
    Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s174">K.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s175">Illing (Makromolekulare 
    Chemie, Gross Umstadt, G.F.R.).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s176">This study was supported in 
    part by CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche) grant 
    81.00283.04.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="25" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s177">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Agnati, L.F., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Fuxe, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Andersson, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Benfenati, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Cortelli, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">DAlessandro (1980) The mesolimbic dopamine system: 
    Evidence for a high amine turnover and for heterogeneity of the 
    dopamine neuron population.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Lett. 18:45-51.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Albanese, A. (1982) Dopaminergic and nondopaminergic 
    mesencephaloseptal and mesencephalo-accumbens neurons in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Neuroscience 7rs4.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Albanese, A., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Bentivoglio (1982) The organization of dopaminergic and 
    nondopaminergic mesencephalocortical neurons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Brain R~s. 238:421-425.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Beckstead, R.M. (1976) Convergent thalamic and 
    mesencephalic projections to the anterior medial cortex in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Neurol. 166: 403-416.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Beckstead, R.M., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Nauta (1979) Efferent connections of the substantia 
    nigra and ventral tegmental area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Brain Res. 175:191-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Bentivoglio, M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Kuypers, and C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Catsman-Berrevoets (1980al Retrograde neuronal labeling 
    by means of bisbenzimide and nuclear yellow (Hoechst S769121).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Measures to prevent diffusion of the tracers out of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Lett. 18:19-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Bentivoglio, M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Kuypers, C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Catsman-Berrevoets. and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Dann (1979a) Fluorescent retrograde neuronal labeling in 
    rat by means of substances binding specifically to adenine-thymine 
    rich DNA.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Lett. 12235-240.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Bentivoglio, M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Kuypers, C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Catsman-Berrevoets.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Loewe.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Dann (1980b) Two new flourescent retrograde neuronal 
    tracers which are transported over long distances.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Lett. 185&apos;5-30.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">Bentivoglio, M., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Macchi, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Rossini, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">Tempesta (1978) Brain stem neurons projecting to 
    neocortex: An HRP study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Brain R~s. 31:489-498.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Bentivoglio, M..</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">D. vander Kooy, and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Kuypers (1979b)The organization of the efferent 
    projections of the substantia nigra in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">A retrograde fluorescent double labeling study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Brain Res. 174:l-17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Bharos, T.B..</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Kuypers, R.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Lemon, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Muir (1981) Divergent collaterals frorn deep cerebellar 
    neurons to thalamus and tectum, and to medulla oblongata and spinal 
    cord: Retrograde fluorescent and electrophysiological studies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Brain Res. 42399-410.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Bjorklund, A., and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Lindvall (1978) The meso-telencephalic dopamine neuron 
    system: A review of its anatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">In K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Livingston and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Hornykiewicz (eds): Limbic Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">The Continuing Evolution of the Limbic System 
    Concept.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">New York Plenum Press, pp. 307-331.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Browder.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">S., D.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">German, and P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Shore (1981) Midbrain dopamine neurons: Differential 
    responses to amphetamine isomers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Brain Res. 207: 333-342.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Carter, D.A., and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Fibiger (1977) Ascending projections of presumed 
    dopaminecontaining neurons in the ventral tegmentum of the rat as 
    demonstrated by horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Neuroscience 2569-576.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Chiodo.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">L.A., S.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Antelman, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Caggiula, and C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Lineberry (1980) Sensory stimuli alter the discharge 
    rate of dopamine (DA) neurons: Evidence for two functional types of 
    DA cells in the substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Brain R~s. 189544-549.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Chronister.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">R.B., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Sikes, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Wood, and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">De France (1980) The pattern of termination of ventral 
    tegmental afferents into nucleus accumbens: An anterograde HRP 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Lett. 17.231-235.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Dahlstrom, A., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Fuxe (1964) Evidence for the existence of mono.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">aminecontaining neurons in the central nervous 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Demonstration of monoamines in the cell bodies of brain 
    stem neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Scand.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">[Suppl.] 2321-55.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Deniau, J.M., A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Thierry, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Feger (1980) Electrophysiological identification of 
    mesencephalic ventromedial tegmental (VMT) neurons pro.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">jecting to the frontal cortex, septum and nucleus 
    accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Brain Res. 189~315-326.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Olmos, J.. and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Heimer (1980) Double and triple labeling of neurons with 
    fluorescent substances; the study of collateral pathways in the 
    ascending raphe system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Lett. 197-12.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Fallon, J.H. (1981) Collateralization of monoamine 
    neurons: Mesotelencephalic dopamine projections to caudate, septum, 
    and frontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Neurosci. 1:1361-1368.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Fallon, J.H., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Moore (1978) Catecholamine innervationof the basal 
    forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">IV.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Topography of the dopamine projection to the basal fore 
    brain and neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Neurol. 18@545-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Fink, J.S., and G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Smith (1980) Mesolimbicocortical dopamine terminal 
    fields are necessary for normal locomotor and investigatory 
    exploration in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Brain Res. 199:359-384.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Groenewegen, H.J., N.E.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Becker, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Lohman (19801 Subcortical afferents of the nucleus 
    accumbens septi in the cat, studied with retrograde axonal 
    transport of horseradish peroxidase and bis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">benzimid.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Neuroscience 5: 1903 - 1916.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Herkenham, M., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Nauta (1977) Afferent connections of the habenular 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">A horseradish peroxidase study, with a note on the 
    fiber+f-passage problem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Neural. 173:123-146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Hokfelt, T., J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Rehfeld, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Skirboll, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Ivemark, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Goldstein, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Markey (1980) Evidence for coexistence of dopamine and 
    CCK in mesolimbic neurones.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Nature 285:476-478.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Huisman, A.M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Kuypers, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Verburgh (1981) Quantitative differences in 
    collateralization of the descending spinal pathways from red 
    nucleus and other brain stem cell groups in rat as demonstrated 
    with the multiple fluorescent retrograde tracer technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Brain Res. 209:271-286.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Huisman, A.M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Kuypers, C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Verburgh (1982) Differences in collateralization of the 
    descending spinal pathways from red nucleus and other brain stem 
    cell groups in cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Brain Res. 57; 186-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Javoy-Agid, F., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Agid (1980) Is the mesocortical dopaminergic system 
    involved in Parkinson disease?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Neurology 30:1326-1330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Johansson.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">O., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Hokfelt (1981) Nucleus accumbens: Transmitter 
    histochemistry with special reference to peptidecontaining 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">In R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Chronister and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">De France (eds): The Neurobiology of the Nucleus 
    Accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Brunswick: Haer Institute of Electrophysiological 
    Ressearch, pp. 147-172.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Johnson, R.P., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Sar, and W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Stumpf (1980) A topographic localization of emkephalin 
    on the dopamine neurons of the rat substantia nigra and ventral 
    tegmental area demonstrated by combined 
    histofluorescenceimmunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Brain Res. 194:566-571.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Kuypers, H.G.J.M., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Bentivoglio, C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Catsman-Berrevoets. and T.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Bharos (1980) Double retrograde neuronal labeling 
    through divergent axon collaterals. using two fluorescent tracers 
    with the sameexcitation wavelength which label different features 
    of the cell.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Brain Res. 40:383-392.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Moal.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">M., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Galey, and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Cardo (1975) Behavioral effects of local injection of 
    6-hydroxydopamine in the ventral tegmentum in the rat: Possible 
    role of the mesolimbic dopaminergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Brain Res. @:190-194.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Lindvall.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">O., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Bjorklund (1974) The organization of the ascending 
    catecholamine neuron systems in the rat brain as revealed by the 
    glyoxylic acid fluorescence method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Scad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">[Suppl.] 412: 1-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Lindvall, 0.. and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Bjorklund (1978) Organization of catecholamine neu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">rons in the rat central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">In L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Iversen, S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Iversen, and S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Snyder (eds): Handbook of Psychopharmacology, Vol. 9.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 139-231.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Mogenson, G.J., D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Jones, and C.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Yim (1980) From motivation to action: Functional 
    interface between the limbic system and the motor system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">F rog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Neurobiol. 14:69-97.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Moore, R.Y., and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Bloom (1978) Central catecholamine neuron systems: 
    Anatomy and physiology of the dopamine systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Neurosci. 1:129-169.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Nauta, W.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">,G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Smith.R.L.M.Faull,andV.B.Domesick(1978)Efferent 
    connections and nigral afferents of the nucleus accumbens septi in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Neuroscience 3:385-401.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Pellegrino, L.J., and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Cushman (1967) A Stereotaxic Atlas of the Rat Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">New York: Appleton-CenturyCrofts.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Phillipson, O.T. (1979a) The cytoarchitecture of the 
    interfascicular nucleus and ventral tegmental area of Tsai in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Neurol. 187: 85-98.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Phillipson, O.T. (1979b) A Golgi study of the ventral 
    tegmental area of Tsai and interfascicular nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Neurol. 187;99-116.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Phillipson, O.T.. and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Griffith (1980) The neurones of origin for the 
    mesohabenular dopamine pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Brain Res. 197r213-218.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Scatton, B., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Simon, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Le Moal, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Bischoff (1980) Origin of dopaminergic innervation of 
    the rat hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Lett. 18r125-131.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Simon, H., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Le Mod, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Calas (1979) Efferents and afferents of the ventral 
    tegmental-A10 region studied after local injection of pH] leucine 
    and horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Brain Res. 178r17-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Taber, E. (1961) The cytoarchitecture of the brain stem 
    of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Brain stem nuclei of cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Neurol. 116;27-69.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Tsai, C. (1925) The optic tracts and centers of the 
    opossum, didelphis virginiana.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Neurol. 39:173-216.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">der Kooy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">D., D.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Coscina, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Hattori (1981) Is there a nondopaminergic nigrostriatal 
    pathway?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Neuroscience 6r345-357.</S>
  </References>

</File>

