<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Mamillary Body in the Rat: Topography and Synaptology of 
  Projections From the Subicular Complex, Prefrontal Cortex, and 
  Midbrain Tegmentum</Title>

  <Authors>GARY V. ALLEN AND DAVID A. HOPKINS</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The retrograde and anterograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase conjugated to wheat germ agglutinin (WGA-HRP) has been 
    used to trace afferent connections of the rat mamillary body (MB) 
    at the light and electron microscopic levels.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Injections of WGA-HRP into different parts of the MB 
    resulted in heavy retrograde labeling in the subicular complex, 
    medial prefrontal cortex, and dorsal and ventral tegmental 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Injections of WGA-HRP into each of these brain regions, 
    respectively, resulted in anterograde labeling with specific 
    distributions and characteristic synaptic organizations in the 
    MB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Projections from the rostrodorsal and caudoventral 
    subiculum terminated in a topographically organized laminar fashion 
    in the medial mamillary nucleus bilaterally, whereas afferent 
    projections from the presubiculum and parasubiculum terminated only 
    in the lateral mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Labeled axon terminals which originated from the subicular 
    complex were characterized by round vesicles and formed asymmetric 
    synaptic junctions with small-diameter dendrites and dendritic 
    spines in the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Projections from the prefrontal cortex originated mainly 
    in the infralimbic area and to a lesser degree in the prelimbic and 
    anterior cingulate areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Injections of tracer into these brain regions gave rise to 
    dense labeling of axon terminals in the medial mamillary nucleus, 
    pars medianus, and in the anterior dorsomedial portion of the pars 
    medialis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">The labeled terminals were characterized by round vesicles 
    and formed asymmetric synaptic junctions with small-diameter 
    dendrites and dendritic spines.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Projections from the dorsal tegmental nucleus terminated 
    in the ipsilateral lateral mamillary nucleus, whereas afferent 
    projections from the anterior and posterior subnuclei of the 
    ventral tegmental nucleus terminated topographically in the medial 
    mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The ventral tegmental nucleus, pars anterior projected to 
    the midline region of the medial nucleus and the dorsolateral and 
    ventromedial subdivisions of the pars posterior projected to medial 
    and lateral parts of the medial nucleus, respectively.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">In contrast to the synaptic morphology of subicular 
    complex and medial prefrontal cortex axon terminals in the MB, 
    labeled axon terminals in the MB which originated from the midbrain 
    tegmentum were characterized by pleomorphic vesicles and formed 
    symmetric synaptic junctions with neuronal somata and proximal 
    dendrites as well as distal dendrites and dendritic spines.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The morphological differences among axon terminals of 
    afferent projections from the subicular complex and the medial 
    prefrontal cortex compared to those from the midbrain tegmentum 
    suggest that the inputs differ in terms of excitatory or inhibitory 
    effects on MB neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">It is proposed that cortical, subcortical, and brainstem 
    connections of the MB form three distinct neural circuits which may 
    represent anatomical substrates for different functional 
    activities.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The mamillary body (MB) has been implicated in a wide 
    variety of diverse functions for which the neural basis is poorly 
    understood.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">These functions include learning and memory (Rosenstock 
    et al., &apos;77; Holmes et al., &apos;83a,b; Aggleton and Mishkin, 
    &apos;85), sexual behavior (Lisk, &apos;66), defensive behavior 
    (Krieckhaus, &apos;67), the regulation of autonomic activity (Cragg 
    and Hamlyn, &apos;59; Faiers et al., &apos;76), and the initiation 
    and propagation of seizure activity (Green and Morin, &apos;53; 
    Jinnai et al., &apos;69; Mirski and Ferrendelli, &apos;83, 
    &apos;84, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">In keeping with the diversity of functions attributed to 
    the MB, this structure receives afferent fibers from widespread 
    regions such as the hippocampal formation (Guillery, &apos;56; 
    Nauta, &apos;56; Valenstein and Nauta, &apos;59; Raisman et al., 
    &apos;66; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;75, &apos;77; Swanson and 
    Cowan, &apos;75, W), prefrontal cort.ex (Saper, personal 
    communication; Wouterlood et al., &apos;87), and midbrain tegmentum 
    (Guillery, &apos;56; Cowan et al., &apos;64; Petrovick9, &apos;73, 
    &apos;85; Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;84; Liu et al., &apos;84; 
    Shibata, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">The MB also has efferent projections to the anterior 
    thalamus (Guillery, &apos;57; Cruce, &apos;75; Watanabe and Kawana, 
    &apos;80; Seki and Zyo, &apos;84) and midbrain (Guillery, &apos;57; 
    Nauta, &apos;58; Cruce, &apos;77; Liu et al., &apos;84), most of 
    which arise from neurons with collateral projections to both 
    thalamus and midbrain (Takeuchi et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Relatively little is known regarding the synaptic 
    organization of the MB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">In a recent study, we have described the cytoarchitecture 
    and normal ultrastructure of the MB in the rat (Allen and Hopkins, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">The purpose of the present study was to identify the 
    synaptic organization of major afferent systems to the MB in order 
    to provide an anatomical framework for a better understanding of 
    its functional roles.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">As a necessary prelude to electron microscopic analysis, 
    the locations of the cells of origin and the distributions of 
    afferents in the MB were confirmed at the light microscopic level 
    by using the retrograde and anterograde transport of wheat germ 
    agglutinin-horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRP).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s22">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The subjects were 89 adult male, Wistar rats weighing 
    250-500 g.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Stereotaxic injections of WGA-HRP were made into the MB, 
    subicular complex, medial prefrontal cortex, and midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The atlas of the rat brain by Paxinos and Watson 
    (&apos;86) was used to determine coordinates for stereotaxic 
    injections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">The animals were anesthetized with sodium pentobarbital 
    (40-60 mg/kg IP) for all surgical procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Injections of 0.01-0.12 ~1 of 1-59; aqueous solutions of 
    WGA-HRP were made by using a 1 p1 Hamilton syringe fitted with a 
    mineral-oil-filled glass micropipette (tip diameter 40-100 Fm).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">To obtain small injections of WGA-HRP, the exact volume 
    of tracer to be injected followed by a small volume of light 
    mineral oil were taken up into the glass micropipette.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">With this procedure, mineral oil separated the WGA-HRP 
    from the tip of the micropipette and, thus, diffusion of the 
    WGA-HRP from the micropipette was reduced as the micropipette was 
    lowered into the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The micropipette was positioned in the brain for at least 
    20 minutes while the WGA-HRP was slowly pressure injected.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Injections of WGA-HRP into brain regions adjacent to the 
    MB, subicular complex, medial prefrontal cortex, and midbrain, or 
    into the ventricular system, served as controls for uptake of 
    tracer by axons of passage or nonspecific uptake of tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">For the electron microscopic analysis, controls included 
    sections from the contralateral side of the MB following unilateral 
    WGA-HRP injections into the midbrain, sections through the MB which 
    were not incubated in tetramethyl benzidine (TMB) and 
    3&apos;,3&apos;-diaminobenzidine (DAB), and sections from the 
    brains of normal unoperated rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">This control material ensured that WGA-HRP reaction 
    products were distinguishable from other electrondense structures 
    or endogenous peroxidase activity.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s34">Light microscopy</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Injections of WGA-HRP were made into the MB (N = 16), 
    subicular complex (N = 18), medial prefrontal cortex (N = 4), and 
    midbrain (N = 16).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">After 1-3 days, the animals were perfused with 500 ml of 
    normal saline and 0.5% magnesium chloride followed by 1000 ml of 
    1.0% paraformaldehyde and 1.25% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate 
    buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The brains were removed and placed in 30% 
    sucrose-phosphate buffer overnight before being cut into series of 
    40 pm-thick sections with a freezing microtome.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The sections were incubated in TMB according to the 
    method of Mesulam (&apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">One series of sections was counterstained with 1% neutral 
    red and a second series was left unstained.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s40">Electron microscopy</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Injections of WGA-HRP were made into the subicular 
    complex (N = 12), medial prefrontal cortex (N = 5), and midbrain (N 
    = 18).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">After 1-3 days, the animals were perfused with 300 ml of 
    0.15 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) followed by 1000 ml of 0.5% 
    paraformaldehyde and 2.5% glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">The brains were removed and placed in 0.15 M phosphate 
    buffer prior to cutting 100 pm sections through the region of the 
    MB with a vibratome (Lancer).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">Two different histochemical procedures were used to study 
    anterograde and retrograde labeling in the MB at the electron 
    microscopic level.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">One series of sections was treated with DAB (Itoh et al., 
    &apos;79) as the chromogen and a second series of sections was 
    treated with TMB (Mesulam, &apos;78) followed by a second 
    incubation in DAB (Rye et al., &apos;84; Lemann et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Rye et al. (&apos;84) originally showed that 
    stabilization of the highly sensitive TMB reaction product with a 
    sequential incubation in DAB was useful for combined use in 
    anterograde and retrograde tracing and subsequent 
    immunohistochemical staining procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Lemann et al. (&apos;85) showed that stabilization of TMB 
    reaction product with a sequential incubation in DAB was also 
    useful for visualization of anterograde and retrograde labeling at 
    the electron microscopic level.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">In the present study, the pH of the acetate buffer used 
    in the TMB incubation medium was adjusted from pH 3.5 up to pH 7.0 
    in order to ascertain the optimal development of reaction product 
    along with the best tissue preservation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Regions containing the MB were cut into blocks and 
    processed for electron microscopy according to standard methods 
    (see Materials and Methods, Allen and Hopkins, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Ultrathin sections were cut with a diamond knife and 
    stained with uranyl acetate-lead citrate or left unstained before 
    examination with a Zeiss EM 10A electron microscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s51">Nomenclature</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The nomenclature of the subicular complex used in the 
    present study corresponds with Meibach and Siegel&apos;s (&apos;77) 
    modifications of the initial descriptions of the hippocampal 
    formation by Lorente de N6 (&apos;34).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">The nomenclature used for the prefrontal cortex follows 
    that proposed by Krettek and Price (&apos;77).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s54">Quantitative analyses</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">The diameters of labeled axon terminals were calculated 
    by taking the mean of the long and short axes of the terminals as 
    measured directly from electron micrographs (final magnification 
    ~16,000).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Since the MB is known to have reciprocal projections to 
    the midbrain (Guillery, &apos;57; Cruce, &apos;77; Takeuchi et al., 
    &apos;85), estimates of the numbers of labeled and unlabeled 
    neurons in the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei were made from 1 
    pm-thick plastic sections (toluidine blue stained) following 
    injections of WGA-HRP into the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Only perikarya which were sectioned through the nucleolus 
    were counted.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Approximately 1,900 cells were counted from sections cut 
    from selected rostral to caudal levels of the MB in eight 
    animals.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s59">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">in the present study , injections of <tracerChemical
     id="w">wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation
     region="MBO">the region of the mb</injectionLocation> resulted in 
    <labelingDescription density="6" id="1" type="n">dense retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation
     region="SUB,PL,DTN,VTN">the subicular complex , medial prefrontal 
    cortex , and dorsal and ventral tegmental nuclei</labelingLocation> 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61"><labelingModifier mod="&lt;" objectId="1"
     subjectId="2">fewer</labelingModifier> <labelingDescription id="2"
     type="n">retrogradely labeled perikarya</labelingDescription> were 
    observed in <labelingLocation region="NDB">the nucleus of the 
    diagonal band of broca</labelingLocation> , and 
    <labelingDescription density="2" type="n">small numbers of widely 
    scattered labeled perikarya</labelingDescription> were found in 
    <labelingLocation region="LHA">the lateral 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s62">
    <labelingDescription density="6" type="f">dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation
     region="ATN, DTN, VTN, TRN, ???">the anterior thalamus , dorsal 
    and ventral tegmental nuclei , nucleus reticularis tegmenti pontis 
    , and medial pontine nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s63">Merents from the 
    subicular complex</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Light microscopy.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s65">figure 1 shows the 
    differential distribution of <labelingDescription type="n">
    retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in the subicular 
    complex following injections of <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation region="MM,LM">the 
    medial and lateral mamillary nuclei</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">in one of the cases illustrated in figure 1 , the 
    injection site ( inset ) was centered in <injectionLocation
     region="MM">the midline of the medial mamillary 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> and included <injectionSpread
     region="MM">most of the subnuclei of the medial nucleus 
    bilaterally</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s67"><injectionSpread region="LM"
     yesNo="0">the lateral mamillary nucleus</injectionSpread> was 
    spared but there was some spread from the principal injection site 
    dorsally into <injectionSpread region="SUMm">the medial portion of 
    the supramamillary nucleus</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s68">
    <labelingDescription density="6" type="n">large numbers of 
    retrogradely labeled perikarya</labelingDescription> were found 
    bilaterally in <labelingLocation region="SUBv,SUBd">all layers of 
    the dorsal and ventral portions of the subiculum</labelingLocation> 
    but <labelingDescription density="0" type="n">no labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation
     region="PRE,PAR">the presubiculum or 
    parasubiculum</labelingLocation> ( figs . 1 , 2 ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s69">
    <labelingDescription density="2" type="n">a few retrogradely 
    labeled neurons</labelingDescription> were also found in 
    <labelingLocation region="RSP">the deep layers of the retrosplenial 
    granular cortex</labelingLocation> ( figs . lb , 2 ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">in the second case illustrated in figure 1 , the 
    injection site ( inset ) was located mainly in <injectionLocation
     region="LM">the lateral mamillary nucleus</injectionLocation> with 
    a slight involvement of <injectionSpread region="MMl">the lateral 
    part of the medial nucleus</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s71">in 
    addition , there was some spread from the injection site dorsally 
    into <injectionSpread region="SUMl, LHA">the lateral portion of the 
    supramamillary nucleus and lateral hypothalamus</injectionSpread> 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72"><labelingDescription density="5" type="n">numerous 
    retrogradely labeled perikarya</labelingDescription> were found 
    mainly ipsilaterally in <labelingLocation region="PRE,PAR">the 
    presubiculum and parasubiculum</labelingLocation> ( figs . 1 , 3 ) 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73"><labelingDescription density="3" type="n">a few labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation
     ipsiContra="i" region="SUBd">ipsilateral dorsal 
    subiculum</labelingLocation> as well as in <labelingLocation
     ipsiContra="c" region="PRE">the contralateral 
    presubiculum</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">following injections of <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation region="SUB">the 
    subicular complex</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription
     type="r">anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> was 
    distributed in distinct horizontal bands or layers across 
    <labelingLocation region="MBO">the mb</labelingLocation> 
    bilaterally ( fig . 4 ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s75">the horizontal layers of 
    <labelingDescription type="f">anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> were present primarily in either 
    <labelingLocation region="MMd, MMi, MMv">dorsal or intermediate or 
    ventral parts of the medial mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    depending on the locations of the injection sites in 
    <injectionLocation region="SUB">the rostral to caudal parts of the 
    subicular complex</injectionLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">figure 4a - d shows the results from a representative 
    case in which <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - hrp</tracerChemical> 
    was injected into <injectionLocation region="SUB" topography="rd">
    the rostrodorsal portion of the subiculum</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77"><labelingDescription>the resultant anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation
     ipsiContra="b" region="MM">the medial mamillary nucleus 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> and formed a horizontal layer across 
    <labelingLocation region="MMm" topography="d">the dorsal portion of 
    the medial mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4b - d ) 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78"><labelingDescription type="f">the anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was <labelingDescription density="3">
    moderate to light</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation
     region="MM" topography="r">the anterio( fig . 4b ) and middle ( 
    fig . 4c ) thirds of the medial nucleus</labelingLocation> and 
    <labelingDescription density="6" type="f">
    heavy</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation region="MBO"
     topography="c">the posterior third of the mb</labelingLocation> ( 
    fig . 4d ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s79"><labelingLocation region="MMam"
    >the anteromedial part of the medial nucleus ( pars medianus 
    )</labelingLocation> contained <labelingDescription density="2"
     type="f">only sparse anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> ( 
    fig . 4b ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">figure 4e - h shows the results from a representative 
    case in which <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - hrp</tracerChemical> 
    was injected into <injectionLocation region="SUB" topography="cv">
    the caudoventral part of the subicular complex</injectionLocation> 
    which included <injectionSpread region="PRE,PAR">the presubiculum 
    and parasubiculum</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s81">in this 
    case , <labelingDescription density="6" type="f">heavy anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation
     ipsiContra="b" region="MMm" topography="cv">the ventral portion of 
    the posterior half of the medial mamillary nucleus 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4g , h ) , 
    <labelingDescription density="4" type="f">whereas moderate to light 
    anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> was present in 
    <labelingLocation ipsiContra="b" region="MM">the intermediate and 
    dorsal parts of the anterior half of the medial nucleus 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4f , g ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82"><labelingLocation region="MMme">the pars 
    medianus</labelingLocation> showed <labelingDescription density="1"
     type="f">very sparse or no anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> following injections in 
    <injectionLocation region="SUB" topography="cv">the caudoventral 
    part of the subicular complex</injectionLocation> ( fig . 4f ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83"><labelingDescription>moderate to light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also found in <labelingLocation
     ipsiContra="i" region="LM">the lateral mamillary nucleus mainly 
    ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4g ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">cases in which the <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation region="SUB"
    >the subicular complex</injectionLocation> did not involve 
    <injectionSpread ipsiContra="PRE,PAR" yesNo="0">the presubiculum 
    and parasubiculum</injectionSpread> showed 
    <labelingDescription density="0">no anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation region="LM">the 
    lateral mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4a - d ) 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85">Electron microscopy.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86">following injections of <tracerChemical>
      wgahrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the subicular 
      complex</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>labeled axons 
      and axon terminals</labelingDescription> were observed in both 
      <labelingLocation>the medial ( figs . 5 - 8 ) and lateral ( fig . 
      6c ) mamillary nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87">when dab was used as the chromogen , 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axon terminals</labelingDescription> 
      were characterized by the presence of small amounts of electron - 
      dense reaction product which were located in membrane - bound , 
      lysosomal - like structures ( fig . 5 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">Identification of <labelingDescription>labeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> following DAB histochemistry 
      required careful study of low-contrast, unstained sections with 
      the electron microscope because in stained sections the DAB 
      reaction product, although darker, resembled the staining seen in 
      normal lysosomes.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">in contrast , when the tmb - dab procedure was used , 
      <labelingDescription>amorphous patches of electron - dense 
      reaction product were found in axons and axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      mb</labelingLocation> ( figs . 6 - 8 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90"><labelingDescription>the tmb - dab - labeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> could be easily identified in 
      stained sections at low magnifications because the tmb - dab 
      reaction product formed relatively large complexes and did not 
      resemble normal tissue organelles ( fig . 7 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">There were, however, some disadvantages with the 
      TMB-DAB procedure in comparison to the DAB procedure.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">for example , tissue elements were less well preserved 
      and the reaction product was usually so large that it tended to 
      obscure the contents of <labelingDescription>the axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> and the morphology of synaptic 
      junctions following incubations in <labelingLocation>the standard 
      tmb incubation medium ( acetate buffer ph 3 . 5 - 4 . 0 
      )</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6a ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">These problems were reduced when the pH of the acetate 
      buffer used in the TMB incubations was made less acidic (pH 
      4.6-6.0).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94"><labelingLocation>this simple modification of the tmb 
      procedure</labelingLocation> resulted in a noticeable reduction 
      in the amount of reaction product within the axon terminals , 
      allowing visualization of synaptic vesicles and the morphology of 
      synaptic junctions along with a much improved preservation of 
      neural elements ( fig . 6b - d ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">The number of <labelingDescription>labeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> observed at the electron 
      microscopic level was markedly decreased when the pH of the 
      acetate buffer was greater than 6.0.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96"><labelingDescription>labeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> from the subicular complex ranged 
      in diameter from 0 . 8 to 2 . 0 pm , contained mainly round 
      vesicles ( diameter = 40 nm ) , and formed asymmetric synaptic 
      junctions mainly with small - diameter ( less than 2 pm ) 
      dendrites and dendritic spines .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97"><labelingDescription>individual labeled axon terminals 
      occasionally</labelingDescription> formed synaptic contacts with 
      two adjacent dendrites ( fig . 8 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>labeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> from the subicular complex only 
      <labelingDescription>rarely</labelingDescription> contained 
      pleomorphic vesicles and formed synaptic junctions with neuronal 
      somata or proximal dendrites .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99"><labelingDescription>unlabeled axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> with pleomorphic vesicles and 
      symmetric synaptic junctions with neuronal elements were , 
      nonetheless , readily identified in this material .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s100"><labelingDescription>
      many labeled axon terminals</labelingDescription> appeared to 
      form two separate synaptic specializations on individual 
      dendritic profiles ( figs . 5 , 6b , d , 8a ) , but serial 
      sectioning of several labeled merents from the medial prefrontal 
      cortex</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Light microscopy.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">the distributions of <labelingDescription type="n">
    retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation region="PL">the medial prefrontal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> were mapped following injections of 
    <tracerChemical abb="w">wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation region="MBO">the mb</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">figure 9 shows the results from a representative case in 
    which <labelingDescription type="n">retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation region="PL">the 
    medial prefrontal cortex</labelingLocation> ( figs . 9a , b , 10 ) 
    was obtained following an injection of <tracerChemical abb="w">wga 
    - hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation region="MM">the 
    medial mamillary nucleus</injectionLocation> ( fig . 9c ) 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">terminals revealed that two apparently distinct synaptic 
    specializations on the same dendrite were parts of a single 
    continuous synaptic specialization (Fig. 8).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">the injection was centered in <injectionLocation
     region="MMm" topography="m">the medial part of the medial 
    mamillary nucleus</injectionLocation> with some spread of reaction 
    product laterally into <injectionSpread region="MMm" topography="l">
    the lateral parts of the medial mamillary nucleus</injectionSpread> 
    and dorsally into <injectionSpread region="SUMm">the medial portion 
    of the supramamillary nucleus</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s106">
    <labelingDescription type="n">the retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation region="PL">the 
    prefrontal cortex</labelingLocation> were pyramidal - shaped ( fig 
    . 9b ) and were distributed from the rostral limit of the 
    prefrontal cortex to a level just rostral to the genu of the corpus 
    callosum ( fig . 10 ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s107"><labelingDescription id="4"
     type="m">most of the retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were located in <labelingLocation
     region="ILA" topography="deep">the deep layers of the infralimbic 
    area</labelingLocation> while <labelingModifier mod="&lt;"
     objectId="4" subjectId="3">fewer</labelingModifier> 
    <labelingDescription id="3" type="n">labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were found rostrally and dorsally in 
    or near <labelingLocation region="PL-5,ACA-5">layer v of the 
    prelimbic and anterior cingulate areas</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108"><labelingDescription density="2" type="n">a few labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were also found <labelingLocation
     region="TT" spRln="n" topography="l,v">lateral and ventral to the 
    tenia tecta</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s109">some of 
    <labelingDescription type="n">the latter 
    cells</labelingDescription> were located in <labelingLocation
     region="ILC" topography="c">the caudal end of the infralimbic 
    cortex</labelingLocation> where they approached <labelingLocation
     region="NDB" spRln="n" topography="r">the rostralmost extent of 
    the vertical limb of the diagonal band of broca</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">after unilateral injections of <tracerChemical abb="w">
    wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation region="PL/ILA">
    the medial prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> ( fig .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">iia ) , <labelingDescription density="6" type="nt">dense 
    anterograde and retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was 
    observed in <labelingLocation region="HY" spRln="c,l">the caudal 
    and lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( fig . llb , c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">the injection site shown in figure 11a was centered in 
    <injectionLocation region="ILA/PL" topography="m">the medial wall 
    of the prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> with some spread 
    dorsally into <injectionSpread region="???">the medial precentral 
    area</injectionSpread> , laterally into <injectionSpread
     region="CLA,CP">the claustrum and caudate / 
    putamen</injectionSpread> , and ventrally into <injectionSpread
     region="TT">the region of the tenia tecta</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113"><labelingDescription density="6" type="f">dense 
    anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> was present along 
    <labelingLocation region="MM" topography="d">the dorsal margin of 
    the medial mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation ipsiContra="b" region="MMme">the pars medianus 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 11b , c ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s114">
    <labelingDescription density="6" type="f">dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also found in <labelingLocation
     region="mfb,cp" topography="-,m">the medial forebrain bundle and 
    the medial part of the cerebral peduncle</labelingLocation> ( fig 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">IlC).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s116">in addition , 
    <labelingDescription type="fn">anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> were found mainly in 
    <labelingLocation region="SUMl">the lateral portions of the 
    supramamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> and along 
    <labelingLocation ipsiContra="i" region="TM" topography="l,v">the 
    lateral and ventral margins of the mb in the tuberomamillary 
    nucleus</labelingLocation>, mainly ipsilaterally ( fig . 11b , c ) 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <em-tte><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">Electron microscopy.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s118">following <tracerChemical>wga 
    - hrp</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation>the 
    medial prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>
    electron - dense reaction product was found in axon 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    mamillary nucleus , pars medianus , and along the dorsal border of 
    the pars medialis</labelingLocation> ( fig . 12 ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s119">The 
    distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    MB</labelingLocation> at the electron microscopic level 
    corresponded well with that observed at the light microscopic 
    level.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s120">The labeled synaptic profiles 
    were usually small (diameter of less than 2 pm), contained mainly 
    round vesicles, and formed asymmetric synaptic junctions with 
    smalldiameter dendrites (Fig. 12) and dendritic spines.</S></em-tte>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s121">Reciprocal connections 
    between the MB and the midbrain</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">Light microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">figure 13 shows the results from a representative case 
    following an injection of <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the medial mamillary 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">the injection site ( fig . 13a ) was centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the midline of the mb including the pars 
    medianus and pars medialis rostrally and the pars posterior 
    caudally</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">there was some spread from the principal injection site 
    laterally into <injectionSpread>the pars 
    lateralis</injectionSpread> and dorsally into <injectionSpread>the 
    medial parts of the supramamillary nucleus</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>
    the anterior ( fig . 13b ) and posterior ( fig . 13c ) parts of the 
    ventral tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127"><labelingDescription>the labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the posterior part 
    of the ventral tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> formed 
    <labelingDescription>a compact cluster dorsolaterally with fewer 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> being present ventromedially 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was located in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial pontine nuclei</labelingLocation> ( fig . 13b ) and 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the nucleus reticularis 
    tegmenti pontis</labelingLocation> ( fig . 13c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><labelingDescription>a few retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were also located in <labelingLocation>
    the dorsal and median raphe nuclei , laterodorsal tegmental nucleus 
    , and the locus coeruleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">there was <labelingDescription>no anterograde or 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">after injections of <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <labelingLocation>the lateral mamillary 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( see fig . 3b ) , <labelingDescription>
    dense retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was found in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral portion of the dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 14a ) , and 
    <labelingDescription>moderate anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was located in <labelingLocation>
    both the dorsal and ventral parts of the dorsal tegmental nucleus 
    ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">in addition , there was <labelingDescription>heavy 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventromedial part of the posterior ventral tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , whereas <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsolateral part of the ventral tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> contained <labelingDescription>only a 
    few retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> ipsilaterally 
    ( fig . 14b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">because the ventral tegmental nucleus projects to the 
    medial nucleus and not the lateral mamillary nucleus ( cowan et al 
    . , &apos; 64 hayakawa and zyo , &apos; 84 takeuchi et al . , 
    &apos; 85 shibata , &apos; 87 ) , <labelingDescription>the 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> seen in <labelingLocation>
    the ventral tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> in this case was 
    due to that part of the <tracerChemical>wga - hrp</tracerChemical> 
    injection site which involved <injectionLocation>the lateral part 
    of the medial mamillary nucleus</injectionLocation> ( see fig . 3b 
    ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><labelingDescription>a few retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were also present in <labelingLocation>
    the anterior ventral tegmental nucleus , dorsal and median raphe 
    nuclei , laterodorsal tegmental nucleus , and locus 
    coeruleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">in addition , <labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the dorsomedial part of the nucleus reticularis tegmenti pontis 
    ipsilaterally and the medial pontine nuclei 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">the distribution of <labelingDescription>anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    mb</labelingLocation> was studied following injections of 
    <tracerChemical>wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into selected parts of 
    the midbrain tegmentum .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">in figure 15a - d , the injection was centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the ipsilateral ventral tegmental 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> and included parts of adjacent 
    tegmental structures such as <labelingLocation>the dorsal and 
    median raphe nuclei , the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus , and the 
    pontine reticular formation</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">there was some spread of tracer caudally into 
    <labelingLocation>the region of the dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>
    the caudal mb</labelingLocation> ( fig . 15b ) as well as in 
    <labelingLocation>more rostra1 parts of the medial mamillary 
    nucleus ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 15c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also present in <labelingLocation
    >the midline nucleus pars medianus bilaterally</labelingLocation> ( 
    fig . 15d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141"><labelingDescription>light anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilateral lateral mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 
    15c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">in addition , <labelingDescription>moderate to light 
    anterograde and retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was 
    present in <labelingLocation>the supramamillary and tuberomamillary 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s143">
    A</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s144">B 
    C D</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">following unilateral injections of <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the region of the 
    anterior ventral tegmental nucleus</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the pars medianus and midline portions of the pars medialis 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> ( fig . 15e ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146"><labelingDescription>moderate to light retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also found in <labelingLocation>
    the medial and lateral parts of the medial mamillary nucleus and 
    along the ventral and lateral borders of the lateral 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">following injections of <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the region of the 
    dorsal tegmental nucleus</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>
    anterograde and retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was found 
    in <labelingLocation>the lateral mamillary nucleus 
    ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Electron microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">following injections of <tracerChemical>
    wgahrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    midbrain</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was found in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral ( figs . 16a , 18b , 19c ) and medial 
    ( figs . 16b , c , 17 , 18a , 19a , b ) mamillary 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">when dab was used as the chromogen , <labelingDescription
    >neuronal somata ( figs . 16a , 18b , c ) , dendrites ( fig . 16c ) 
    , axons , and axon terminals</labelingDescription> ( fig . 16 ) 
    contained <labelingDescription>electron - dense reaction product 
    which</labelingDescription> was located in membrane - bound , 
    lysosomal like structures .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">In contrast to the labeling observed in <labelingLocation
    >the MB</labelingLocation> following DAB histochemistry, after 
    sequential TMB-DAB histochemistry the reaction product observed in 
    neuronal somata (Figs. 17, HA), dendrites, axons, and axon 
    terminals (Figs. 17B, 19) was characterized by amorphous patches of 
    electron-dense material that were often associated with intact or 
    disrupted electron-dense lysosomes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152"><labelingDescription>labeled axon 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    mb</labelingLocation> which originated from the midbrain were 
    usually less than 2 km in diameter , contained mainly pleomorphic 
    vesicles , and formed symmetric synaptic junctions with labeled and 
    unlabeled neuronal somata ( figs . 16 , 17 ) , proximal and distal 
    dendrites ( figs . 16 , 19 ) , and dendritic spines ( fig . 19a ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153"><labelingDescription>individual labeled terminals 
    occasionally</labelingDescription> synapsed with two adjacent 
    dendrites ( fig . 19b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154"><labelingDescription>only one of 137 labeled axon 
    terminals</labelingDescription> from the midbrain contained round 
    vesicles and formed an asymmetric synaptic junction with a dendrite 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">All other axon terminals with round vesicles and 
    asymmetric synapses were unlabeled and usually synapsed with 
    dendrites and dendritic spines (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Allen and Hopkins, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">following injections of <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    midbrain</injectionLocation> , numerous <labelingDescription>
    retrogradely labeled perikarya</labelingDescription> were found in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral mamillary nucleus and each subnucleus 
    of the medial mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">estimates of <labelingDescription>the numbers of labeled 
    and unlabeled perikarya</labelingDescription> in 1 pm - thick 
    sections revealed that 8090% of the cells in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral nucleus and 80 - 9070 of the cells in each subnucleus of 
    the medial mamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> were 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled</labelingDescription> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159"><labelingDescription>electron - dense reaction 
    product</labelingDescription> was found in both medium - sized ( 
    diameter 16 . 0 - 30 . 0 pm ) ( fig . 17a ) and small ( diameter 9 
    . 0 - 15 . 9 pm ) ( fig . 18 ) neurons .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160"><labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in both <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    and the medial mamillary nuclei</labelingLocation> were 
    characterized by an eccentrically located nucleus which exhibited 
    one or more invaginations of the nuclear envelope .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">the nucleus usually contained fine chromatin , a 
    spherical nucleolus , and <labelingDescription>the occasional dense 
    clump of fine chromatin - like material</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162"><labelingDescription>the cytoplasm of labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> contained varying amounts of rough 
    and smooth endoplasmic reticulum , golgi complexes , mitochon dria 
    , ribosomes , lysosomes , lipofuscin granules , clear vesicles , 
    occasional dense - cored vesicles , multivesicular bodies , 
    vacuoles , microtubules , and neurofilaments .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">the cytoplasm of medium - sized cells usually contained 
    aggregates of rough endoplasmic reticulum which were arranged into 
    <labelingLocation>parallel arrays of cisternae , while the rough 
    endoplasmic reticulum of small neurons was sparse and loosely 
    scattered in the cytoplasm</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164"><labelingDescription>the plasma membranes of labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were often closely apposed to those 
    of other <labelingDescription>unlabeled</labelingDescription> ( fig 
    . 17a ) and <labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> ( fig . 18a ) .</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s165">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">The present study shows 1) that the subicular complex, 
    medial prefrontal cortex, and dorsal and ventral tegmental nuclei 
    have dense afferent projections to the MB, 2) that the terminal 
    fields of these afferent projections are highly topographically 
    organized in the MB, 3) that axon terminals which originate from 
    the subicular complex and the medial prefrontal cortex are 
    characterized mainly by round vesicles and form asymmetric synaptic 
    junctions with small-diameter dendrites and dendritic spines, and 
    4) that axon terminals which originate from the midbrain tegmentum 
    are characterized by pleomorphic vesicles and form symmetric 
    synaptic junctions with neuronal somata and proximal dendrites as 
    well as distal dendrites and dendritic spines.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">An analysis of the patterns of anterograde labeling 
    observed in the MB in the present study following injections of 
    tracer into the subicular complex, medial prefrontal cortex, and 
    midbrain tegmentum indicates that the various subnuclei of the MB 
    constitute foci for distinct topographically organized neural 
    circuits with these diverse brain regions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s168">Merents from the 
    subicular complex</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">With regard to the cells of origin in the subicular 
    complex, the present study shows that cells in most layers of the 
    dorsal and ventral subiculum project to the medial mamillary 
    nucleus, whereas cells in the deep layers of the presubiculum and 
    parasubiculum project to the lateral mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">These results confirm and extend findings of Meibach and 
    Siegel (&apos;77) and Swanson and Cowan (&apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">However, Meibach and Siegel (&apos;77) indicated that 
    cells in the presubiculum and parasubiculum project to the caudal 
    part of the medial mamillary nucleus bilaterally, whereas Swanson 
    and Cowan (&apos;77) reported that anterograde labeling in the 
    lateral mamillary nucleus was consistently present only when 
    injections of tracer involved the presubiculum and parasubiculum as 
    in the present study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">A few cells were retrogradely labeled in the 
    retrosplenial granular cortex following injections of tracer into 
    the region of the medial mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">A projection to the MB from the retrosplenial cortex has 
    not previously been reported in the rat (Meibach and Siegel, 
    &apos;77; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77) or cat (Edinger et al., 
    &apos;79) although a projection from the retrosplenial cortex to 
    the MB has been identified in the rhesus monkey (Ekstein and 
    Rosene, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">However, it is likely that many, if not all, of the 
    retrogradely labeled cells observed in the retrosplenial cortex in 
    the present study project to nuclei adjacent to the MB such as the 
    supramamillary nucleus and/or tuberomamillary nucleus since 
    retrogradely labeled cells were also usually present in the 
    retrosplenial granular cortex when injections spread into these 
    regions and in control injections in these areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">We have identified the locations of neurons in different 
    parts of the subicular complex with projections to the medial and 
    lateral mamillary nuclei and have confirmed that afferents from the 
    subicular complex are topographically organized in a laminar 
    fashion in the medial mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">It is also important to note that the pars medianus 
    contained only very sparse or no anterograde labeling following 
    WGA-HRP injections into different parts of the subicular complex, 
    which confirms the anterograde tracing studies of Guillery 
    (&apos;56) and Meibach and Siegel (&apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">The latter finding is significant in the context of the 
    distribution of afferent fibers from the medial prefrontal cortex 
    and the midbrain tegmentum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s178">Merents from the medial 
    prefrontal cortex</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">The present results show that projection neurons in the 
    medial prefrontal cortex have a dense terminal field in the pars 
    medianus and the dorsal border of the anterior third of the medial 
    mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">This finding corresponds with a recent HRP transport 
    study of Saper (personal communication) and the study of Wouterlood 
    et al. (&apos;87) in which the anterograde transport of the lectin 
    Phaseolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin was used.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">A comparison of the distributions of afferent fibers in 
    the medial mamillary nucleus which originate from the medial 
    prefrontal cortex and the subicular complex indicates that the 
    terminal fields have very little or no overlap in the MB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The pars medianus of the medial mamillary nucleus 
    receives a dense projection from the medial prefrontal cortex and 
    only a very sparse projection from the subicular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Thus, neural circuits which include the medial 
    prefrontal cortex and the subicular complex may be segregated in 
    part on the basis of their connections with different subnuclei of 
    the medial mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The idea of separate neural circuits which include 
    different subnuclei in the MB will be elaborated later in the 
    discussion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s185">Reciprocal connections 
    between the MB and the midbrain</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The present study is in agreement with previous studies 
    (Guillery, &apos;57; Cruce, &apos;77; Liu et al., &apos;84; Hopkins 
    et al., &apos;85; Takeuchi et al., &apos;85) regarding projections 
    from the lateral and medial mamillary nuclei to the dorsal and 
    ventral tegmental nuclei, respectively, and projections from both 
    the lateral and medial mamillary nuclei to the dorsomedial part of 
    the nucleus reticularis tegmenti pontis and the medial pontine 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Furthermore, the present results have confirmed that the 
    reciprocal connections between the MB and the midbrain tegmentum 
    are highly topographically organized (Guillery, &apos;57; Cruce, 
    &apos;77; Takeuchi et al., &apos;85; Shibata, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Following injections of WGA-HRP into the MB, 
    retrogradely labeled cells were also present outside the dorsal and 
    ventral tegmental nuclei in the dorsal and median raphe nuclei, 
    laterodorsal tegmental nucleus, and locus coeruleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Retrograde labeling in these regions was most dense when 
    the MB injections were relatively large and the injection sites 
    involved structures adjacent to the MB such as the premamillary, 
    supramamillary, and tuberomamillary nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Since dense anterograde labeling was found in the dorsal 
    premamillary nucleus (Shibata, &apos;87) and moderate to light 
    anterograde labeling was found in the supramamillary and 
    tuberomamillary nuclei following injections in the midbrain, it is 
    likely that many of the retrogradely labeled cells located in the 
    midbrain, other than those found in the dorsal and ventral 
    tegmental nuclei, have projections to structures adjacent to the 
    MB.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Based on the present findings and the results of 
    previous studies (Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;84; Liu et al., &apos;84; 
    Petrovickjl, &apos;85; Takeuchi et al., &apos;85; Shibata, 
    &apos;87), it is apparent that the distributions of afferent fibers 
    in the MB which originate from different parts of the midbrain tend 
    to terminate within the boundaries of specific subnuclei in the 
    MB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">For example, the anterior ventral tegmental nucleus 
    projects mainly to the pars medianus of the medial mamillary 
    nucleus bilaterally, the dorsolateral part of the posterior ventral 
    tegmental nucleus projects to the pars medialis and pars posterior 
    ipsilaterally, the ventromedial part of the posterior ventral 
    tegmental nucleus projects to the pars lateralis and pars basalis 
    ipsilaterally, and the dorsal tegmental nucleus projects to the 
    lateral mamillary nucleus ipsilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">In contrast, afferents from the subicular complex form 
    horizontal layers which spread across the medial nucleus 
    bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Thus, the horizontal distribution of afferent fibers 
    from the subicular complex appears to be orthogonally oriented to 
    the somewhat subnuclear-specific organization of afferent 
    projections which originate from the midbrain tegmentum and the 
    topographical MB projection to the anterior thalamus (Cruce, 
    &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Furthermore, the distribution of afferent fibers in the 
    pars medianus which originates from the anterior ventral tegmental 
    nucleus overlaps almost exclusively and precisely with that which 
    originates from the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s196">Descending projection 
    neurons in the MB</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The present results show that at least 80-90% of the 
    cells in the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei were retrogradely 
    labeled following injections of WGA-HRP into the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">A similar percentage of perikarya in the MB were 
    retrogradely labeled following injections of WGA-HRP into the 
    anterior thalamus (Takeuchi et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Furthermore, the ultrastructural features of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons in the present study were identical to 
    those of neurons in the MB which were retrogradely labeled after 
    anterior thalamic injections (Takeuchi et al., &apos;85) and MB 
    neurons of the normal rat (Allen and Hopkins, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Thus, it is appears likely that most neurons in the 
    medial and lateral mamillary nuclei project to the midbrain 
    tegmentum as well as to the anterior thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Strong evidence in support of this finding was provided 
    in the fluorescent retrograde double-labeling experiments of 
    Takeuchi et al. (&apos;85) which demonstrated that most cells in 
    the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei were double labeled 
    following injections of different fluorescent dyes into the 
    anterior thalamus and midbrain.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s202">Fine structure of MB 
    merents</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">The present results provide the first electron 
    microscopic analysis of the synaptic relationships of axon 
    terminals in the MB which arise from identified sources.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Based on the present findings, it is apparent that cells 
    in the MB receive afferent fibers from cortical and brainstem 
    regions which have different synaptic morphologies and terminate 
    for the most part on different regions of the neuron (see summary 
    diagram, Fig. 20).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Afferent fibers which originate in the subicular complex 
    and the medial prefrontal cortex are characterized by round 
    vesicles and form asymmetric synaptic junctions (RA) with distal 
    dendrites and dendritic spines.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">In contrast, afferent fibers which originate from the 
    dorsal and ventral tegmental nuclei are characterized by 
    pleomorphic vesicles and form symmetric synaptic junctions (PS) 
    with neuronal somata and proximal dendrites as well as distal 
    dendrites and dendritic spines.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">The distributions of RA and PS synapses observed in the 
    present study in which histochemical procedures were applied to the 
    tissues correspond with the distributions of RA and PS synapses 
    observed in the MB of the normal rat (Allen and Hopkins, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">There is evidence indicating that afferents from the 
    subicular complex may have an excitatory influence on MB 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Parmeggiani et al. (&apos;71) and Poletti et al. 
    (&apos;73) have recorded excitatory responses from mamillary 
    neurons following stimulation of the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">In addition, significant decreases in the high-affinity 
    uptake of the excitatory amino acid glutamate in the MB have been 
    measured following fornix transection (Storm-Mathisen and Opsahl, 
    &apos;78; Walaas and Fonnum, &apos;80) and hippocampal extirpation 
    (Nitsch et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Thus, the present findings are consistent with the 
    possibility that RA synapses which originate from the subicular 
    complex have an excitatory influence over MB neurons and use 
    glutamate as a neurotransmitter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">With respect to the effect afferents from the midbrain 
    tegmentum may have on ME3 neurons, Mugnaini and Oertel (&apos;85) 
    have indicated that numerous cells in the dorsal and ventral 
    tegmental nuclei are immunoreactive for an antibody directed 
    against glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD), the synthesizing enzyme 
    for the inhibitory amino acid GABA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">In addition, Mugnaini and Oertel (&apos;85) have also 
    indicated that moderate to low levels of GAD-positive fibers are 
    present in the neuropil of the MB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Immunocytochemical studies in other regions of the 
    central nervous system (McLaughlin et al., &apos;74; Ribak, 
    &apos;78; Ribak et al., &apos;79; Somogyi et al., &apos;83) have 
    indicated that GAD-positive axon terminals are of the PS type.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Furthermore, Andersen et al. (&apos;64), Ito et al. 
    (&apos;641, and Uchizono (&apos;65, &apos;67) have shown that PS 
    synapses in the cerebellum are inhibitory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Thus, it is possible that afferents from the dorsal and 
    ventral tegmental nuclei may form inhibitory PS-type synapses on 
    mamillary neurons and may use GABA as a neurotransmitter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s217">Neural circuitry of the 
    MB</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s218">
    The medial and lateral mamillary nuclei have complex synaptic 
    connections with cortical, subcortical, and brainstem 
    structures.</S>
    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s219">
    From a comparison of the afferent and efferent connections of the 
    MB, the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei can be seen as 
    participating in at least PREFRONTAL CORTEX AFFERENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s220">
    MIDBRAIN AFFERENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">three distinct neural circuits with the medial 
    prefrontal cortex, subicular complex, and the midbrain tegmentum 
    (Fig. 21).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">For example, the medial mamillary nucleus, but not the 
    lateral nucleus, receives afferent projections from the dorsal and 
    ventral subiculum, medial prefrontal cortex, and ventral tegmental 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">In contrast, the lateral mamillary nucleus receives 
    major afferent fibers from the presubiculum, parasubiculum, and 
    dorsal tegmental nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">In addition, the medial nucleus has ascending 
    projections to the anteromedial and anteroventral thalamic nuclei 
    and descending projections to the ventral tegmental nucleus 
    ipsilaterally, whereas the lateral nucleus has ascending 
    projections to the anterodorsal thalamic nucleus bilaterally and 
    descending projections to the dorsal tegmental nucleus 
    ipsilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Although both the medial and lateral mamillary nuclei 
    have descending projections to the nucleus reticularis tegmenti 
    pontis and medial pontine nuclei, these projections appear to be 
    topographically organized and essentially nonoverlapping in these 
    regions (Hopkins et al., &apos;85; Aas and Brodal, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Therefore, it may be advantageous to consider the MB as 
    consisting of a medial and a lateral nucleus which are 
    distinguished not only by the size and morphology of their cells 
    (Allen and Hopkins, &apos;88) but also by the anatomical 
    organization of their afferent and efferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Furthermore, the connections of the medial mamillary 
    nucleus are organized such that it contains cell groups which are 
    part of at least two quite separate neural circuits.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">One of these circuits is the so-called &quot;Papez 
    circuit&quot; (MacLean, &apos;52).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Papez (&apos;37) reasoned that the circuitous flow of 
    impulses from the cingulate cortex which passes through the 
    hippocampus, MB, and anterior thalamus before returning to the 
    cingulate cortex may form an anatomical substrate for emotion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">However, the present results indicate that the pars 
    medianus is not part of this pathway but instead receives a 
    substantial input from the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Anatomical (Van der Kooy et al., &apos;82; Terreyberry 
    and Neafsey, &apos;87) and physiological (Burns et al., &apos;83; 
    Terreyberry and Neafsey, &apos;84; Hurley-Gius and Neafsey, 
    &apos;86) studies have indicated that the medial prefrontal cortex 
    may mediate respiratory, cardiovascular, and gastric activity 
    through its connections with the nucleus of the solitary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">In keeping with the separation of neural circuits, the 
    pars medianus projects to the anteromedial thalamic nucleus (Cruce, 
    &apos;75; Watanabe and Kawana, &apos;80; Seki and Zyo, &apos;84), 
    which in turn projects to the medial prefrontal cortex (Beckstead, 
    &apos;76; Krettek and Price, &apos;77; Divac et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Thus, impulses may follow a circuitous route from the 
    medial prefrontal cortex to the medial mamillary nucleus, to the 
    anterior thalamus, and back to the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Both the &quot;Papez circuit&quot; and the medial 
    prefrontal cortex-MB circuit are influenced by afferent fibers 
    which reach the MB from different parts of the ventral tegmental 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Cells in the anterior ventral tegmental nucleus project 
    mainly to the pars medianus and cells in the posterior ventral 
    tegmental nucleus project to the other subnuclei of the medial 
    mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Thus, these two neural pathways are also distinguished 
    by the fact that they each receive afferent information from 
    different sources in the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">In addition, other circuits which include the 
    premamillary, supramamillary, and tuberomamillary nuclei (Allen and 
    Hopkins, &apos;87) may also play a role or be related to the neural 
    processing which occurs in MB circuits.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">These three different anatomical circuits which include 
    different subnuclei of the MB maybe reflected in differences among 
    the functional activities of the medial and lateral mamillary 
    nuclei as well.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Clinical (Victor et al., &apos;71; Mair et al., 
    &apos;79) and experimental studies (Rosenstock et al., &apos;77; 
    Aggleton and Mishkin, &apos;85) have described impairments in 
    learning and memory in patients or subjects following damage to the 
    medial mamillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">In another aspect, cells in the medial mamillary nucleus 
    of the normal rat have significantly higher levels of 
    2-deoxyglucose uptake than cells located in the lateral nucleus 
    (Sokoloff et al., &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Therefore, it appears that cell groups in the medial and 
    lateral nuclei have differences in functional and metabolic 
    activities as well as differences in their afferent and efferent 
    connections such as those elucidated in the present study.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s242">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s243">The authors thank K.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s244">McCleave, S.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s245">Morrison, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s246">Sasinek for technical 
    assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s247">This work was supported by 
    grant MT-7369 from the Medical Research Council of Canada.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s248">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Aas, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">-E., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Brodal(1988) Demonstration of topographically organized 
    projections from the hypothalamus to the pontine nuclei: An 
    experimental anatomical study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Neurol. 268t313-328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Adams, J.C. (1977) Technical considerations on the use 
    of horseradish peroxidase as a neuronal marker.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Neuroscience 2141.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Aggleton, J.P., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Mishkin (1985) Mammillary-body lesions and visual 
    recognition in monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Brain Res. 58t190-197.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Allen, G.V., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Hopkins (1987) Mamillary, supramamillary and 
    tuberomamillary nuclei: Connections with infralimbic cortex in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Abstr. 13.1166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Allen, G.V., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Hopkins (1988) Mamillary body in the rat: A 
    cytoarchitectonic, Golgi, and ultrastructural study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Neurol. 27539-64.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Andersen, P., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Eccles, and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Voorhoeve (1964) Postsynaptic inhibition of cerebellar 
    Purkinje cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Neurophysiol. 27;1138-1153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Beckstead, R.M. (1976) Convergent thalamic and 
    mesencephalic projections to the anterior medial cortex in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Neurol. 166r403-416.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Burns, S.M., E.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Geisert, S.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Winternitz, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Wyss (1983) The role of the cingulate cortex gyrus in 
    cardiovascular functioning.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Acta Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">(Basel) 20528A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Cowan, W.M., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Guillery, and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Powell (1964) The origin of the mamillary peduncle and 
    other hypothalamic connections from the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Anat. 98:345-363.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Cragg, B.G., and L.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Hamlyn (1959) Histologic connections and electrical and 
    autonomic responses evoked by stimulation of the dorsal fornix in 
    the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">I:187-213.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Cruce, J.A.F. (1975) An autoradiographic study of the 
    projections mammillothalamic tract in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Brain Res. 85211-219.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Cruce, J.A.F. (1977) An autoradiographic study of the 
    descending connections of the mammillary nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Neurol. 176:631-644.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Divac, I., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Kosmal, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Bjorklund, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Lindvall(l978) Subcortical projections to the prefrontal 
    cortex in the rat as revealed by the horseradish peroxidase 
    technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Neuroscience 3t785-796.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Ekstein, J.M., and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Rosene (1984) Topography of the fornix trajectory and 
    mamillary body termination of efferenta from the subiculum and 
    supracallosal subiculum in the Rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Abstr. 10:331.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Faiers, A.A., F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Calaresu, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Mogenson (1976) Factors affecting cardiovascular 
    responses to stimulation of hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Neurol. 5Zt188-206.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Green, J.D., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Morin (1953) Hypothalamic electrical activity and 
    hypothalamo-cortical relationships.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Physiol. 172175-186.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Guillery, R.W. (1956) Degeneration in the 
    post-commissural fornix and the mamillary peduncle of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Anat. 90:350-370.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Guillery, R.W. (1957) Degeneration in the hypothalamic 
    albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Anat. 91:91-115.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Hayakawa, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Zyo (1984) Comparative anatomical study of the 
    tegmentomamillary projection in some mammals: A horseradish 
    peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Brain Res. 300:335-349.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Holmes, E.J., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Butters, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Jacobson, and B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Stein (1983a) An examination of mammillary-body lesions 
    on reversal learning sets in monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Psychol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">II:159-165.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Holmes, E.J., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Jacobson, B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Stein, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Butters (1983b) Ablations of the mammillary nuclei in 
    monkeys: Effects on postoperative memory.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Neurol. 81:97-113.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Hopkins, D.A., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Morrison, and G.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Allen (1985) Mamillary body projections to precerebellar 
    relay nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Rec. 211:85A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Hurley-Gius, K.M., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Neafsey (1986) The medial frontal cortex and gastric 
    motility: Microstimulation results and their possible significance 
    for the overall pattern of organization of the rat frontal and 
    parietal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Brain Res. 365,241-248.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">M., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Yoshida, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Obata (1964) The cerebellar-evoked monosynaptic 
    inhibition of Dieters neurones.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Experentia 20:515-516.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Itoh, K., Konishi, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Nomura, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Mizuno, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Nakumura, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Sugimoto (1979) Applications of coupled oxidation 
    reaction to electron microscopic demonstration of horseradish 
    peroxidase: cobalt-glucose oxidase method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Brain Res. 175:341-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Jinnai, D., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Mogami, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Mukawa, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Iwata, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Kobayashi (1969) Effects of brainstem lesions on 
    Metrazol-induced seizures in cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Electroencephalogr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Clin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Neurophysiol. 27t404-411.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Price (1977) The cortical projections of the mediodorsal 
    nucleus and adjacent thalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Neurol. 171:157-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Krieckhaus, E.E. (1967) The mammillary bodies: Their 
    function and anatomical connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Acta Biol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Exp. 27:319-337.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Lemann, W., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Saper, D.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Rye, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Wainer (1985) Stabilization of the TMB reaction product 
    for electron microscopic retrograde and anterograde fiber 
    tracing.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Bull. 142777281.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Lisk, R.D. (1966) Increased sexual behavior in the male 
    rat following lesions in the mammillary region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Exp. 2001.161:129-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Liu, R., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Chang, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Wickern (1984) The dorsal tegmental axoplasmic transport 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Brain Res. 310:123-132.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Lorente de Nb, R. (1934) Studies on the structure of the 
    cerebral cortex. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Continuation of the study of the Ammonic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Psychol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Neurol. 46:133-177.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">MacLean, P. (1952) Some psychiatric implications of 
    physiological studies on frontotemporal portion of limbic system 
    (visceral brain).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Electroencephalogr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Clin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Neurophysiol. 4:407-418.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Mair, W.G.P., E.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Warrington, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Weiskrantz (1979) Memory disorder in Korsakoff s 
    psychosis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">A neuropathological and neuropsychological investigation 
    of two cases.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Brain 102749-783.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">McLaughiin, B.J., J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Wood, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Saito, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Barber, J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Vaughn, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Roberts, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">-Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Wu (1974) The fine structural localization of glutamate 
    decarboxylase in synaptic terminals of rodent cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Brain Res. 76:377391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">McLean, J.H., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Hopkins (1982) Ultrastructural identification of labeled 
    neurons in the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus nerve following 
    injections of horseradish peroxidase into the vagus nerve and 
    brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Neurol. 206243-252.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Siegel (1975) The origin of fornix fibers which project 
    to the mammillary bodies in the rat: A horseradish peroxidase 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Brain Res. 88:518-522.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Siegel (1977) Efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Brain Res. 124:197-224.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">-M. (1978) Tetramethyl henzidine for horseradish 
    peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue 
    reaction-product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural 
    afferents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Mirski, M.A., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Ferrendelli (1983) Individual and combined effects of 
    convulsant and anti-convulsant drugs on regional brain 
    metabolism.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Abstr. 9:627.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Mirski, M.A., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Ferrendelli (1984) Interruption of the mammillothalamic 
    tracts prevents seizures in guinea pigs.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Science 226:72-74.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Mirski, M.A., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Ferrendelli (1987) Interruption of the connections of 
    the mamillary bodies protects against generalized pentylenetetrazol 
    seizures in guinea pigs.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Neurosci. 7:662-670.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Mugnaini, E., and W.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Oertel(1985) An atlas of the distribution of GABAergic 
    neurons and terminals in the rat CNS as revealed by GAD 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Bjorklund and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Vol. 4 GABA and Neuropeptides in the CNS, Part I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 406-608.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Nauta, W.J.H. (1956) An experimental study of the fornix 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Neurol. 104247-272.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Nauta, W.J.H. (1958) Hippocampal projections and related 
    neural pathways to the midbrain in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Brain 81:319-340.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Nitsch, C., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">-K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Kim, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Shimada, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Okada (1979) Effect of hippocampus extirpation in the 
    rat on glutamate levels in target structures of hippocampal 
    efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Lett. 11295-299.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Papez, J.W. (1937) A proposed mechanism of emotion.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Psychol. 38:725-744.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Parmeggiani, P.L., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Azzaroni, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Lenzi (1971) On the functional significance of the 
    circuit of Papez.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Brain Res. 30:357-374.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates 
    (2nd edition).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Australia: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Publishers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Petrovickjr, P. (1973) Note on the connections of Gudden 
    s tegmental nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Efferent ascending connections in the mammillary 
    peduncle.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Acta Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">(Basel) 86.165-190.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Petrovickp, P. (1985) Gudden s tegmental nuclei and 
    their connections to the hypothalamus and the reticular 
    formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">An experimental study using retrograde labeling with HRP 
    or iron-dextran in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Hirnforsch. 26:531-537.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Poletti, C.E., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Kinnard, and P.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">MacLean (1973) Hippocampal influence on unit activity of 
    hypothalamus, preoptic region, and basal forebrain in awake, 
    sitting squirrel monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Neurophysiol. 36~308324.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Raisman, G., W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Cowan, and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Powell (1966) An experimental analysis of the efferent 
    projection of the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Brain 89:83 -88.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Ribak, C.E. (1978) Aspinous and sparsely-spinous 
    stellate neurons in visual cortex of rats contain glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Neurocytol. 7t461479.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Ribak, C.E., A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Harris, J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Vaughn, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Roberts (1979) Inhibitory, GABAergic nerve terminals 
    decrease at sites of focal epilepsy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Science 205:211-214.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Rosenstock, J., T.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Field, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Greene (1977) The role of the mammillary bodies in 
    spatial memory.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Neurol. 55t340-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Rye, D.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Saper, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Wainer (1984) Stabilization of the tetramethylhenzidine 
    (TMB) reaction product: Application for retrograde and anterograde 
    tracing and combination with immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Cytochem. 321145-1153, Seki, M., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Zyo (1984) Anterior thalamic afferenta from the 
    mamillary body and the limbic cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Neurol. 229 242-256.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Shibata, H. (1987) Ascending projections to the 
    mammillary nuclei in the rat: A study using retrograde and 
    anterograde transport of wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Neurol. 264,205215.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Sokoloff, L., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Reivich, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Kennedy, M.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Des Rosien, C.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Patlak, K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Pettigrew, 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Sakurada, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Shinohara (1977) The [ C] deoxyglncose method for the 
    measurement of local cerebral glucose utilization: Theory, 
    procedure, and normal values in the conscious and anesthetized 
    albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Neurochem. 28:897-916.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Somogyi, P., T.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Freund, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">-Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Wu, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Smith (1983) The section-Golgi impregnation procedure. 
    2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Immunocytochemical demonstration of glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase in Golgi impregnated neurons and in their afferent 
    boutons in the visual cortex of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Neuroscience 9~475490.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Storm-Mathisen, J., and M.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Opsahl(1978) Asparate and/or glutamate may be 
    transmitters in hippocampal efferents to septum and 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Lett. 9t65-79.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Swanson, L., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Cowan (1975) Hippocampal-hypothalamic connections: 
    Origin in subicular cortex, not Ammon s horn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Science 189:303304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Swanson, L., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Cowan (1977) An autoradiographic study of the 
    organization of the efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Neurol. 17249-84.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Takeuchi, Y., G.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Allen, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Hopkins (1985) Transnuclear transport and axon 
    collateral projections of the mamillary nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Bull. 14t453-468.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Terreyberry, R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Neafsey (1984) The effects of medial prefrontal cortex 
    stimulation on heart rate in the awake rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">IOt614.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Terreyberry, R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Neafsey (1987) The rat medial frontal cortex projects 
    directly to autonomic regions of the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Bull. 19t639-649.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Uchizono, K. (1965) Characteristics of excitatory and 
    inhibitory synapses in the central nervous system of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Nature 207~642-643.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Uchizono, K. (1967) Synaptic organization of the 
    Purkinje bellum of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Brain Res. 4%-113.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Valenstein, E.S., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Nauta (1959) A comparison of the distribution of the 
    fornix system in the rat, guinea pig, cat, and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Neurol. 113~337-363.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Van der Kooy, D., J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">McGinty, L.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Koda, C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Gerfen, and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Bloom (1982) Visceral cortex: A direct connection from 
    prefrontal cortex to the solitary nucleus in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Lett. 33:123-127.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Victor, M., R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Adams, and G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Collins (1971) The Wernicke-Korsakoff Syndrome.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Contemporary Neurology Series, Vol. 7.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Philadelphia, P A F.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Davies Co.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Walaas, I., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Fonnum (1980) Biochemical evidence for glutamate as a 
    transmitter in hippocampal efferents to the basal forebrain and 
    hypothalamus in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Neuroscience 5t1691-1698.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Watanabe, K., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Kawana (1980) A horseradish peroxidase study on the 
    mammillothalamic tract in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Acta Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">(Basel) 108t394-401.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Wouterlood, F.G., H.W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Steinbusch, P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Luiten, and J.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Bol (1987) Projection from the prefrontal cortex to 
    histaminergic cell groups in the posterior hypothalamic region of 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Anterograde tracing with Phaseolus uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin combined with immunocytochemistry of histidine 
    decarboxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Brain Res. 406~330-336.</S>
  </References>

</File>

