<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Functional and Anatomical Organization of Cardiovascular 
  Pressor and Depressor Sites in the Lateral Hypothalamic Area. 11. 
  Ascending Projections</Title>

  <Authors>GARY V. ALLEN AND DAVID F. CECHETTO</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Microinjections of L-glutamate or D,L-homocysteic acid 
    were used to stimulate cell bodies in the region of the lateral 
    hypothalamic area (LHA) selectively.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Subsequent iontophoretic injections of Phaseolus 
    vulgaris-leucoagglutinin or pressure injections of wheat germ 
    agglutininhorseradish peroxidase were made into regions containing 
    identified pressor and depressor sites and their connections with 
    the forebrain and cerebral cortex were traced.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The results indicate that decreases in blood pressure 
    (10-45 mm Hg) and heart rate (20-70 bpm) could be elicited from 
    tuberal (LHAt) and posterior (LHApj sites in the LHA and that these 
    regions have ascending projections to the insular cortex, the 
    ventral forebrain including the septal-diagonal band of Broca 
    complex, the ventral palladium, substantia innominata, amygdala, 
    and the lateral preoptic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">In contrast, increases in blood pressure (10-40 mm Hg) and 
    heart rate (20-70 bpm) were elicited primarily from neurons located 
    adjacent to the fornix in the perifornical area (PFA).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Injections of tract tracers into this region produced 
    terminal labeling that differed markedly from the pattern seen 
    following injections of tracer into depressor sites in the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">In addition, the pattern of anterograde labeling seen 
    following injections of tracer into the anterior PFA differed from 
    that seen following injections of tracer into the posterior PFA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Injections of tracer into the anterior PFA resulted in 
    dense terminal labeling in the medial preoptic area and the 
    parvicellular paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus whereas 
    injections into the posterior PFA resulted in dense terminal 
    labeling in the lateral septa1 nucleus, nucleus accumbens, bed 
    nucleus of the stria terminalis, as well as the medial preoptic 
    area and the parvocellular paraventricular nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">The results demonstrate that the posterolateral 
    hypothalamus of the rat contains two regions with specific 
    cardiovascular function and highly organized connections with 
    diencephalic, forebrain, and cortical structures. c1 1993 
    WiIey-Liss, Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">This study is part of a continuing investigation of the 
    functional anatomical organization of the lateral hypothalamic area 
    (LHA).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Recently we have described the anatomical organization of 
    descending projections from regions in the LHA with specific 
    cardiovascular responses (Allen and Cechetto, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">In this study, we extend these findings by describing the 
    anatomical organization of ascending projections from portions of 
    the LHA with specific cardiovascular responses.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The LHA is an important site for the processing of 
    ascending information from the periphery.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Anatomical and physiological investigations have 
    demonstrated projections to the LHA from viscero-autonomic 
    structures in the brain stem including the parabrachial nucleus, 
    nucleus of the solitary tract, and the ventral lateral medulla 
    (Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Kita and Oomura, &apos;82; ter 
    Horst et al., &apos;89; Allen and Cechetto, &apos;91) and the 
    spinal cord (Yamada and Otani, &apos;78; Burstein et al., &apos;87; 
    Katter et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Extracellular recording studies have mapped the locations 
    of neurons in the lateral hypothalamic area responding to baroand 
    cherno-receptors in the cat (Thomas and Calaresu, &apos;72) and rat 
    (Allen and Cechetto, &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">In addition, gustatory stimulation elicits changes in 
    firing frequency of LHA neurons (Norgren, &apos;70).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The LHA is reciprocally connected to many forebrain and 
    cortical areas including the paraventricular nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus, anterior hypothalamic nucleus, rostra1 portion of the 
    LH.4, medial and lateral preoptic areas, bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis, central and basomedial nuclei of the amygdala, lateral 
    septal nucleus, septddiagonal band of Broca complex, nucleus 
    accumbens, ventral striatum, and insular and medial prefrontal 
    cortices (Saper et al., &apos;79; Berk and Finkelstein, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">These investigations considered the LHA as a whole 
    without regard for specific functional regions within the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Thus, the possible function of most, if not all, of these 
    connections is not known.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">It is possible that forebrain or cortical projections to 
    the LHA represent the first stage for autonomic outflow to the 
    periphery.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Projections from cardiovascular pressor and depressor 
    sites in the insular cortex are topographically organized in the 
    tuberal and posterior portions of the LHA (Yasui et al., 
    &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Furthermore, microinjection of the presynaptic blocker, 
    cobaltous chloride, into the LHA completely blocks cardiovascular 
    and sympathetic nerve responses elicited by stimulation of the 
    posterior insular cortex (Cechetto and Chen, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">This suggests that one function of the LHA is to mediate 
    cardiovascular and sympathetic responses elicited from the insular 
    cortex and possibly from other forebrain and cortical sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Thus, the LHA receives visceral afferent information, 
    projects to forebrain and cortical sites involved in autonomic 
    control, and mediates descending autonomic signals from the 
    forebrain and cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">It is suggested that these connections of the LHA may be 
    part of long-loop reflexes involved in integration of autonomic and 
    behavioral mechanisms.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s25">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Sixty-five adult male, Wistar rats (250-400 g) were 
    anesthetized with intraperitoneal injections of chloralose (100 
    mg/kg) or chloral hydrate (350 mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The femoral artery was cannulated and arterial blood 
    pressure was monitored using a Statham P23D pressure transducer and 
    continuously recorded on a Grass model 7 polygraph.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Mean arterial pressure was monitored by filtering the 
    pulsatile arterial pressure with a 0.5 Hz high frequency filter.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Heart rate was determined from the pulse pressure using a 
    Grass 7P44 tachograph and was continuously recorded on the 
    polygraph.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The femoral vein was cannulated for the administration of 
    drugs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Rectal temperature was maintained at 37 ?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">0.5&quot;C with a heatingpad.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s33">Chemical stimulation of 
    the LHA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">In 44 animals, the LHA was systematically mapped for 
    arterial blood pressure responses following microinjections of 
    small volumes (5-50 nl) of the excitatory amino acid 
    D,L-homocysteate (0.01-1.0 M) or L-glutamate (0.1-1.0 M) in 
    phosphate-buffered saline solution (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">It was found In the present study, we identified 
    cardiovascular responsive sites in the LHA and described their 
    afferent and efferent connections with structures in the forebrain 
    and cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Cell bodies in the LHA were selectively stimulated by 
    small injections of the excitatory amino acids, L-glutamate, or 
    D,L-homocysteate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The anatomical connections of cardiovascular responsive 
    regions were traced following iontophoretic injections of Phaseolus 
    uulgarisleucoagglutinin (PHA-L) or pressure injections of wheat 
    germ agglutinin conjugated to horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRP), 
    Preliminary results of this investigation have been presented 
    (Allen and Cechetto, &apos;90b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">that reproducible changes in blood pressure and heart 
    rate could be elicited following smaller, 5-10 nl, injections of 
    D,L-homocysteate (0.1 M) or L-glutamate (0.5 M) and these volumes 
    were routinely used in most of the cases to systematically map 
    cardiovascular responsive sites in the posterolateral 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Single injections of excitatory amino acid were made at 
    200 to 250 pm steps along each track.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Each track in the LHA (Bregma coordinates: 
    anteriorposterior -3.3 to -3.8; medial-lateral 0.0 to 2.0; 
    dorsalventral 7.5 to 9.5; from Paxinos and Watson, &apos;86) was 
    placed 250-500 pm apart.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Control injections of phosphate buffered saline (pH 7.4) 
    were made into the same sites.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">The bottom of the micropipette track was marked either by 
    an electrolytic lesion (1 second onioff cycle, 100 PA, 10 minutes) 
    or by a small injection (10-30 nl) of rhodamine latex microspheres 
    (Lumofluor).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">At the end of the experiment.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">the animals that were not used in the tract tracing 
    studies were perfused with physiological saline (250 ml) followed 
    by a solution of 10% formal saline (500 ml).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Frozen sections (50 km) were cut, stained with 0.1% 
    thionin, and camera lucida drawings were made of sections through 
    the LHA and the injections sites were identified and plotted.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s46">Tract tracing studies of 
    the LHA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">In preliminary experiments a marked reduction was found 
    in the degree of anterograde transport of both WGA-IIRP and PHA-L 
    from sites in the LHA that had previously received injections of 
    excitatory amino acids, especially D,L-homocysteate This is likely 
    due to the excitotoxic efects of excitatory amino acids on the 
    uptake or transport of tracer substances by neurons in the LHA 
    (Olney, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Therefore, the ascending projections of regions that 
    contain identified cardiovascular sites in the LHA were examined by 
    placing tracer substances into the contralatera1 LHA, without 
    removing the micropipette from the stereotaxic manipulator, at the 
    exact coordinates which produced maximal pressor or depressor 
    responses.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">This procedure provided the best approximation for the 
    placement of tracer substances into brain sites that were 
    contralateral to the cardiovascular responsive sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Injection of retrograde and anterograde tracers were made 
    in 21 rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Iontophoretic injections (7 seconds onioff cycle, 5 FA, 
    positive current, 30 minutes) of 2.5% PHA-L (n = 11) or pressure 
    injections of 5% WGA-HRP (n = 10) were made into the LHA 
    contralateral to identified cardiovascular responsive sites.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Animals that received injections of PHA-L were 
    reanesthetized after 7 days and perfused with phosphate buffered 
    saline (pH 7.4, 250 ml), followed by 250 ml of 4% paraformaldehyde 
    in sodium acetate (pH 6.5) and 250 ml of 4% paraformaldehyde in 
    sodium borate (pH 11.0; Berod et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">The brains were removed and postfixed in the last 
    perfusate for 4-10 hours and then stored in 30% sucrose in 
    phosphate buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Transverse sections (40-50 km) were cut into three series 
    with a freezing microtome.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">One series of sections was processed for the 
    immunohistochemical demonstration of PHA-L according to the 
    technique of Gerfen and Sawchenko (&apos;84) with diaminobenzidine, 
    a second series was incubated in a diaminobenzidine-nickel ammonium 
    complex (Hancock, &apos;841, and a third series of sections was 
    counterstained with 0.1% thionin.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Animals that received injections of WGA-HRP were 
    sacrificed after 1-3 days and perfused with 250 ml physiological 
    saline, followed by a mixture of 1% paraformaldehyde and 0.5% 
    glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer (500 ml, pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The brains were removed and placed in 30% sucrose in 
    phosphate buffer overnight.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Transverse sections (50 pm) were cut into series with a 
    freezing microtome and processed by the tetramethylbenzidine method 
    of Mesulam (&apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">One series of sections was lightly stained with 0.1% 
    thionin and a second series was left unstained.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The WGAHRP tracer experiments were necessary to confirm 
    the results of the PHA-L experiments and the retrograde labeling 
    observed in the WGA-HRP studies provided information regarding the 
    sources of afferent input to cardiovascular pressor and depressor 
    cell groups in the LHA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Camera lucida drawings were made of PHA-L and WGAHRP 
    injection sites and of the distribution of anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling in the forebrain and cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The PHA-L injection sites were small compared to the 
    WGA-HRP sites and were characterized by Golgi-like filling of cell 
    bodies and their processes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Labeled processes that exhibited a uniform diameter were 
    assumed to be axonlike fibers whereas varicosities along the path 
    of axons and at the ends of axons and thin stalked-like appendages 
    were assumed to be axon terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">The WGA-HRP injection sites were characterized by a dark 
    staining central core surrounded by a lighter staining halo 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Based on the results of the present study and previous 
    WGA-HRP tract tracing studies (Allen and Hopkins, &apos;89, 
    &apos;901, the central core region was assumed to be the effective 
    site of transport of tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The fine punctate labeling observed in the WGAHRP 
    material was assumed to be terminal labeling and could be readily 
    differentiated from retrogradely filled cell bodies.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s67">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s68">Excitatory amino acid 
    stimulation of the LHA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">the cardiovascular responses elicited following selective 
    stimulation of cell bodies in the lha with small injections of 
    excitatory amino acids were described in detail in a precedingpaper 
    ( see allen and cechetto , &apos; 91 ) and are briefly described 
    here .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Although we used a few 50 nl injections to locate 
    responsive regions, we routinely used only 5-10 nl injections to 
    identify two distinct groups of cells that elicit specific 
    cardiovascular responses when stimulated with the excitatory amino 
    acids L-glutamate or D,L-homocysteate.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">stimulation of cells located in the tuberal ( lhat ) and 
    posterior ( lhap ) regions of the lha elicited primarily decreases 
    in blood pressure and heart rate , whereas stimulation of cells 
    located in the perifornical area ( pfa ) elicited primarily 
    increases in blood pressure and heart rate ( fig . 1 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">in many instances , injection of excitatory amino acids 
    200 to 250 km distal to the initial site resulted in no response or 
    the opposite response to the original .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">most microinjections of excitatory amino acids medial to 
    the pfa , in the region of the dorsal medial hypothalamus , did not 
    elicit changes in blood pressure and heart rate .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">a few of these sites in the lateral edge of the dorsal 
    hypothalamic area evoked small decreases in blood pressure and 
    heart rate .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">thus , it can be seen that the pressor responses observed 
    in the pfa are specific to this region and are not a result of 
    spread of chemical stimulant into the adjacent structures such as 
    the dorsal medial hypothalamic region ( fig . 1 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">the magnitude and duration of the responses appeared be 
    directly related to the volume , concentration , and site injection 
    of excitatory amino acid .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">The responses to D,L-homocysteate were, in most cases, 
    more brisk than those of similar volume and concentration of 
    L-glutamate.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">the decreases in blood pressure ( 1045 mm hg ) occurred 
    within 5 to 60 seconds of the injection of excitatory amino acid 
    and returned to baseline within 20 to 180 seconds .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The decreases in blood pressure were usually accompanied 
    by a decrease in heart rate (20-70 bpm).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">increases in blood pressure ( 10 - 40 mm hg ) and heart 
    rate ( 20 - 70 bpm ) occurred within 5 to 60 seconds of the 
    injection of excitatory amino acid and returned to baseline within 
    20 to 130 seconds .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">In 3 of 39 pressor responses, an increase in blood 
    pressure was accompanied by a decrease in heart rate (20-40 
    bpm).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s82">Ascending projections 
    from a region containing depressor sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">the ascending projections of <labelingLocation>cell 
    groups in cardiovascular responsive regions of the 
    lha</labelingLocation> were traced following iontophoresis of 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> or microinjection of 
    <tracerChemical>wga - hrp</tracerChemical> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">preliminary studies indicated that microinjection of 
    <tracerChemical>excitatory amino acids</tracerChemical> may inhibit 
    the uptake or transport of the neuroanatomical tract tracers 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> and <tracerChemical>wga - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> ( see allen and cechetto , &apos; 91 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Thus the tracer injections were made contralateral to the 
    sites where maximal depressor and pressor cardiovascular responses 
    were elicited.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">figure 2 ( case a351 shows a representative case 
    illustrating the organization of anterograde labeling following an 
    iontophoretic injection of <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> 
    into a region containing a depressor site ( see response fig . 2f ) 
    in <injectionLocation>the lha</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">the injection site ( fig . 2e ) contains 
    <labelingDescription>a dense cluster of pha - lfilled 
    cells</labelingDescription> located medial to the zona incerta and 
    immediately dorsal to the medial border of the internal capsule at 
    the level of the lhat .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">the <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> injection 
    site is characterized by golgi - like staining of cell bodies and a 
    dense brown staining of the adjacent neuropil .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">The degree of neuropil staining can be varied by the 
    length of time the sections incubate in the DAB-hydrogen peroxide 
    solution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">we have found that the actual effective injection site 
    involves only the pha - l - stained cells and there is 
    <labelingDescription>no detectable 
    anterograde</labelingDescription> transport from the diffuse brown 
    staining of the tissue around the dab stained cells .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91"><labelingDescription>the anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> observed in this case was 
    predominately ipsilateral .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92"><labelingDescription>many labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> swept medially and ventrally from the 
    injection site into <injectionLocation>the 
    ipsilateral</injectionLocation> pfa and <labelingDescription>a few 
    labeled fibers</labelingDescription> extended into <labelingLocation
    >the dorsal and ventral medial hypothalamic 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2e ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93"><labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
    coursed laterally and caudally into <labelingLocation>the zona 
    incerta , lhap , posterior hypothalamic nucleus , medial and 
    lateral mamillary nuclei , supramamillary nucleus , and 
    tuberomamillary nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingDescription>a few labeled 
    axons</labelingDescription> passed through the dorsal hypothalamic 
    region to enter <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
    pfa</labelingLocation> and lhat .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95"><labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
    also extended dorsally into thalamic structures .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96"><labelingDescription>moderate to light terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>
    reuniens , mediodorsal , paraventricular , lateral dorsal , and 
    posterior nuclei of the thalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97"><labelingDescription>a few labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> also entered <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral habenula</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2e ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">rostrally , <labelingDescription>dense terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed extending mcdially from 
    the lha into <labelingLocation>the pfa</labelingLocation> and a 
    region dorsal to <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus of 
    the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> and extending laterally into 
    <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata</labelingLocation> ( 
    fig . 2d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99"><labelingDescription>moderate to light 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    parvocellular portions of the paraventricular nucleus , anterior 
    hypothalamic nucleus , anterior portion of the lateral hypothalamic 
    area</labelingLocation> ( figs .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">zd , 3b ) , and in <labelingLocation>the central nucleus 
    of the amygdala</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101"><labelingDescription>light terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>
    midline thalamic structures and basolateral and ventral portions of 
    the amygdala</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">at the level of the crossing of the anterior commissure 
    ( fig . 2c ) , <labelingDescription>dense terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral preoptic area</labelingLocation> ( see figs . 2c , 8b ) , 
    <labelingLocation>ventral palladium , and horizontal limb of the 
    diagonal band of broca</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103"><labelingDescription>light terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis , septohypothalamic nucleus , 
    and medial</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4b ) and <labelingLocation>
    lateral septal nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">more rostrally , <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was predominant in <labelingLocation>
    the medial septal nucleus and dorsomedial part of the lateral 
    septal nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105"><labelingDescription>terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the cerebral cortex</labelingLocation> , especially 
    <labelingLocation>layer v of the agranular and dysgranular portions 
    of the insular cortex</labelingLocation> and more lightly in 
    <labelingLocation>layer v of the somatosensory cortex ( areas i and 
    11 )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106"><labelingDescription>very light terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the somatomotor and frontal cortex</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2a , 
    b ) , including <labelingLocation>prelimbic and infralimbic ( fig . 
    4a ) areas</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">the patterns of labeling seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    forebrain and cerebral cortex</labelingLocation> following 
    injections of tracer into depressor sites in the lhat and lhap 
    showed no obvious differences .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">figure 5 ( rat a10 ) shows the distribution of 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the forebrain 
    and cerebral cortex</labelingLocation> following a representative 
    injection of <tracerChemical>wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation>the lha</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">The injection site (Fig. 5E) consists of a central core 
    (black zone) surrounded by a diffuse spread of the tracer (diagonal 
    lines).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">The central core is considered to be the effective site 
    for transport of the tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">the core of the injection was centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the lhap</injectionLocation> and extended 
    rostrally into <injectionSpread>the lhat and caudally into the 
    ventral tegmental area and medial portion of the substantia 
    nigra</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">the pattern of <labelingDescription>anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    forebrain and cerebral cortex</labelingLocation> was similar to 
    that seen following iontophuretic injections of <tracerChemical>pha 
    - l</tracerChemical> into similar sites in <injectionLocation>the 
    lha</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113"><labelingDescription>the anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was predominately ipsilateral 
    although there was <labelingDescription>moderate to light labeling 
    contralaterally</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">at the level of the injection site , 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found extending dorsally into 
    <labelingLocation>the midline and intralaminar thalamic nuclei 
    including the parafascicular nucleus and the lateral 
    habenula</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">at <labelingLocation>the level of the paraventricular 
    nucleus of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 5d ) , 
    <labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral hypothalamic area , substantia innominata , the amygdala , 
    caudate - putamen , and the insular cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116"><labelingDescription>moderate to light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was located in <labelingLocation>the 
    paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( 
    figs . 5d , 6c ) and in <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal and 
    anterior paraventricular nuclei of the thalamus</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117"><labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were widely scattered in 
    <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus including the paraventricular , 
    anterior , and lateral hypothalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">in <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>dense anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    central , medial , and anterior cortical nuclei</labelingLocation> 
    and <labelingDescription>moderate to light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the ventral and basolateral nuclei</labelingLocation> ( figs . 5d , 
    6d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">in <labelingLocation>the insular 
    cortex</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present primarily in 
    <labelingLocation>layers v and vi uf the dysgranular and agranular 
    regions</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120"><labelingDescription>heavy retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present primarily in 
    <labelingLocation>layer v of dysgranular and agranular 
    cortices</labelingLocation> with <labelingDescription>lighter 
    anterograde and retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> extending 
    dorsally into <labelingLocation>the granular insular cortex and 
    somatosensory areas i and i1 and ventromedially into the claustrum 
    , endopiriform nucleus , and piriform cortex</labelingLocation> ( 
    figs . 5a - d , 6a ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">at the level of the anterior commissure ( fig . 5c ) , 
    <labelingDescription>dense anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis , particularly the lateral and 
    ventral regions</labelingLocation> , and in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral palladium and insular cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122"><labelingDescription>moderate to light anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was present in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial and lateral preoptic area and medial 
    and lateral septal complex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    caudate</labelingLocation> putamen most likely originated from 
    spread of the injection site caudally into <injectionSpread>the 
    medial portion of the substantia nigra</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">rostrally , <labelingDescription>dense anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> was located in 
    <labelingLocation>the nucleus accumbens and medial prefrontal 
    cortex especially the prelimbic , infralimbic and dorsal peduncular 
    areas</labelingLocation> ( figs . 5a - b , 6b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125"><labelingDescription>moderate anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also found in <labelingLocation>
    the anterior olfactory nucleus and ventral lateral orbital frontal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126"><labelingDescription>moderate to light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral frontal cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">Ascending projections from a region containing pressor 
    sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">figure 7 ( case a371 shows a representative case of an 
    injection of <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> into a region 
    containing a pressor site ( see response fig . 7f ) in 
    <injectionLocation>the pfa at the level of the 
    lhat</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">the injection site consists of <labelingDescription>a 
    dense group of pha - l - filled cells</labelingDescription> located 
    dorsal , medial , and ventral to the fornix ( fig . 7e ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130"><labelingDescription>pha - l - labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> extended from the injection site 
    medially and dorsally into <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial 
    hypothalamic nucleus and dorsal hypothalamic 
    region</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> passed laterally into the lhat and 
    ventrally and caudally along the third ventricle to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the posterior hypothalamic , supramamillary , and 
    tuberomamillary nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">These projections are predominately ipsilateral.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132"><labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> extended rostrally in <labelingLocation
    >the medial forebrain</labelingLocation> bundle to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the anterior portion of the 
    lha</labelingLocation> , while <labelingDescription>other labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> swept medially and dorsally to 
    terminate in <labelingLocation>the parvocellular portion of the 
    paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( 
    figs . 7d , 3a ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133"><labelingDescription>light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also seen projecting laterally 
    to terminate in <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata and the 
    central nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation> and coursing 
    dorsally to terminate in <labelingLocation>the anterior and 
    posterior paraventricular nuclei of the thalamus</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">at the level of the crossing of the anterior commissure 
    ( fig . 7c ) , <labelingDescription>dense terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral portion of the medial preoptic nucleus and ventral and 
    lateral portions of the bed nucleus of the stria t , 
    wminalis</labelingLocation> ( fig . 8a ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135"><labelingDescription>moderate 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial portion of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> ( fig . 
    7b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136"><labelingDescription>very light 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral and medial septa1 complex , septohypothalamic nucleus , and 
    infralimbic cortex</labelingLocation> ( fig . 7a , b ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">figure 9 ( case a40 ) shows the typical pattern of 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
    seen following injections of <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> into  <injectionLocation>a region containing a 
    pressor site ( see response fig . 9f ) located more posteriorly in 
    the pfa at the level of the lhap</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><labelingDescription>pha - l - filled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in the injection site were located 
    mainly <labelingLocation> ventral to the fornix and extended medial 
    and dorsal to the fornix</labelingLocation> ( fig . 9e ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><labelingDescription>anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> coursed from the injection site 
    medially and caudally to 
    <labelingModifier>terminate</labelingModifier> in <labelingLocation>
    the posterior hypothalamic , arcuate , supramamillay , and 
    tuberomamillary nuclei</labelingLocation> and coursed laterally 
    into <labelingLocation>the lhap</labelingLocation> and dorsally 
    into <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal and paraventricular nuclei 
    of the thalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">at the level of the paraventricular nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus ( fig . 9d ) , <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> ascended in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial forebrain</labelingLocation> bundle to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the parvocellular portion of the paraventricular 
    nucleus of the hypothalamus and the adjacent periventricular region 
    and the anterior hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141"><labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> extended laterally in <labelingLocation
    >the substantia innominata</labelingLocation> to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the central nucleus of the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> and swept dorsally to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the midline thalamic region</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">at the level of the anterior commissure ( fig . 9 0 , 
    <labelingDescription>dense terminal labeling</labelingDescription> 
    was found in <labelingLocation>the medial and lateral portions of 
    the medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> ( figs . 8c , 9c ) 
    and in <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis</labelingLocation> ( fig . 9c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">more rostrally , <labelingDescription>dense terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial portion of the nucleus accumbens and the lateral septal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 9b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">in <labelingLocation>the lateral septal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> the labeling was concentrated mainly in 
    <labelingLocation>the intermediate and ventral 
    subnuclei</labelingLocation> ( fig . 8d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145"><labelingDescription>light terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial septal - diagonal band of broca complex and the infralimbic 
    cortex</labelingLocation> ( fig . 9a , b ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">there are several exceptions in the distribution of 
    labeling observed following injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    posterior pfa</injectionLocation> compared with the labeling 
    resulting from injections more anteriorly in <injectionLocation>the 
    pfa</injectionLocation> , as described above .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">compared to the ascending projections from anterior 
    portions of the pfa , projections from the posterior pfa were 
    <labelingDescription>more dense</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral septum , septohypothalamic nucleus , 
    nucleus accumbens , bed nucleus of the stria terminalis , medial 
    part of the medial preoptic area , anterior hypothalamus , central 
    nucleus of the amygdala , and the thalamic paraventricular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">figure 10 ( case a361 shows a representative case of the 
    distribution of <labelingDescription>anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    forebrain</labelingLocation> following an injection of 
    <tracerChemical>wga - hrp</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation>a region containing a pressor site ( see 
    response fig . 10f ) in the pfa</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">the injection site was characterized by a darkly stained 
    dense core and <labelingDescription>a lighter stained halo 
    region</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">the central core of the injection site involved 
    <injectionLocation>most of the dorsal - medial and anterior - 
    posterior</injectionLocation> portions of the pfa and spread 
    rostromedially into <injectionSpread>the lateral portion of the 
    dorsomedial hypothalamic nucleus</injectionSpread> , laterally into 
    <injectionSpread>the medial portion of the lhat and 
    lhap</injectionSpread> , caudoventrally into <injectionSpread>the 
    dorsal and ventral premamillary nuclei</injectionSpread> , and 
    caudomedially into <injectionSpread>the posterior hypothalamic and 
    medial supramamillary nuclei</injectionSpread> ( fig . 10e ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">as both anterior and posterior portions of the pfa were 
    involved in the injection , the distribution , but not 
    concentration , of <labelingDescription>anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    forebrain</labelingLocation> was similar to that seen with both 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> injections previously 
    described ( see cases a37 , fig . 7 , and a40 , fig . 9 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152"><labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> extended rostrally from the 
    injection site in the medial forebrain bundle to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the parvocellular portion of the paraventricular 
    nucleus of the hypothalamus and the anterior hypothalamic 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 10d ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153"><labelingDescription>very light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial and central nuclei of the amygdala</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154"><labelingDescription>light anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    paraventricular nucleus of the thalamus</labelingLocation> and 
    <labelingDescription>moderate retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    anterior hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">more rostrally , <labelingDescription>moderate to light 
    anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> was found in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial and lateral preoptic area , bed 
    nucleus of the stria terminalis , and medial and lateral septal 
    complex</labelingLocation> ( fig . 10b , c ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">labeling was concentrated mainly in <labelingLocation>
    the intermediate and ventral subnuclei of the lateral septal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157"><labelingDescription>moderate to light retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral preoptic area , septohypothalamic , and lateral septal 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> ( fig . 10b , c ) .</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s158">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s159">Excitatory amino acid 
    injections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">Determination of the effective stimulation zone 
    following microinjection of excitatory amino acids into brain 
    regions is a potential problem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Other investigators have injected similar volumes of 
    radiolabeled substances and relied upon autoradiographic labeling 
    techniques to determine the limits of diffusion of the 
    microinjected substances (Spencer et al., &apos;88, &apos;89, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">However, this technique does not indicate the region 
    where sufficient concentration of excitatory amino acids are 
    present to induce excitation of neuronal elements.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">Another approach to this problem is to microinject small 
    volumes of chemical stimulant at different locations in brain sites 
    and to map the distribution of the various responses.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">A measure of the distances between sites that give 
    opposing responses or where the response is lost will give an 
    indication of the effective stimulation zone of an injection 
    site.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">We routinely used only 5-10 nl injections of low 
    concentrations of D,L-homocysteic acid (0.1 M) or L-glutamate (0.5 
    M).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">These were the smallest volumes of excitatory amino 
    acids, in our experimental conditions, that could be injected and 
    still elicit a cardiovascular response.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">These volumes and concentrations are less than those 
    used by Sun and Guyenet (40 nl; &apos;861, Gelsema et al. (50-100 
    nl; &apos;871, and Hinrichsen (50-100 nl; &apos;88) and compare 
    favorably with recent chemical stimulation studies by Spencer et 
    al. (4-15 nl; &apos;88, &apos;89, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">The close proximity of different cardiovascular 
    responsive sites allowed us to estimate to some degree of accuracy 
    the effective spread zone of the excitatoiy amino acid injection 
    sites.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">An opposite response or loss of response was often 
    produced by a similar injection only 200-250 p,m distal to the 
    initial site.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Movement of the pipette back to the original site and 
    injection of excitatory amino acid would then reproduce the 
    original response.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">Thus, it appears that diffusion of the chemical 
    stimulant is limited to a range of 200-250 p,m or less and we were 
    able to systematically stimulate and map the distribution and 
    functional characteristics of small groups of cells throughout the 
    posterolateral hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s172">Cardiovascular responses 
    from the posterolateral hypothalamus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">The results indicate that distinct groups of cells exist 
    in the LHA and PFA with specific cardiovascular functions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">Injections of small volumes of excitatory amino acids in 
    the posterolateral hypothalamus elicits decreases in blood pressure 
    and heart rate mainly in the LHAt and LHAp, whereas increases in 
    blood pressure and heart rate were primarily elicited more medially 
    in the perifornical region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">In our previous discussion of these cardiovascular 
    responses (Allen and Cechetto, &apos;91), we indicated that the 
    cardiovascular responses can be reconciled with previous reports 
    and for the first time demonstrate the range of responses that can 
    be obtained from a systematic stimulation of all of the LHA 
    including the PFA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Briefly, our findings are in agreement with those of Sun 
    and Guyenet (&apos;86), who used small injections of L-glutamate to 
    stimulate cells in the PFA of halothane-anesthetized rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">They are also in agreement with Spencer et al. 
    (&apos;89) who showed significant decreases in arterial blood 
    pressure and heart rate following discrete injections of 
    L-glutamate into the LHAt.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">We also observed a few small depressor responses in the 
    lateral portion of the dorsal hypothalamic region that are likely 
    on the lateral edge of a depressor region that has been identified 
    in the dorsal hypothalamic area (Spencer et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">We did not investigate efferent projections from cells 
    in this site.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">We recently demonstrated dense projections from a region 
    containing depressor cells in the LHA to the rostral, middle, and 
    commissural portions of the nucleus of the solitary tract, the 
    lateral tegmental field, and the ventral lateral medulla, as well 
    as the ventrolateral central gray, pedunculopontine tegmental 
    nucleus, and medial and lateral parabrachial nuclei (Allen and 
    Cechetto, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">In contrast, projections from a region containing 
    pressor cells in the PFA terminate primarily in the ventrolateral 
    central gray and laterodorsal tegmental region, especially 
    Barrington&apos;s nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">These findings indicate that a region with depressor 
    responses in the LHA may influence cardiovascular activity by 
    direct projections to viscerosensory and visceromotor nuclei of the 
    brain stem whereas the descending projections of the YFA to the 
    central gray suggest a possible role in neural processing for pain 
    (Bausbaum and Fields, &apos;84) and defence behavior (Bandler, 
    &apos;82; Depaulis et a]., &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s183">Ascending 
    functional-anatomical connections of the LHA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The ascending projections to the forebrain and cerebral 
    cortex from regions containing pressor and depressor sites in the 
    PFA and LHA were determined following iontophoretic injections of 
    PHA-L or pressure injections of WGAHRP into these regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The results confirm and extend the findings of previous 
    studies that have demonstrated ascending projections from the LHA 
    to the forebrain and cerebral cortex (Saper et al., &apos;79; 
    Ottersen, &apos;80; Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;82; ter Horst and 
    Luiten, &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Figure 11 summarizes the anatomical organization of 
    projections from a region with pressor sites in the PFA and the 
    region containing depressor sites in the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Major differences were noted in the organization of 
    these projections to the cerebral cortex, ventral basal forebrain, 
    and diencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">The LHA showed widespread ascending cortical projections 
    especially to the insular cortex and the somatosensory, 
    somatomotor. medial prefrontal, and ventral orbital frontal 
    cortices (Allen et al., &apos;9lJ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">In contrast, the PFA showed only a light projection to 
    the infralimbic region of the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">In the ventral basal forebrain, ascending projections 
    from the region containing depressor sites in the LHA were more 
    dense than those from the region with pressor sites in the PFA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">More specifically, dense terminal labeling from the 
    tuberal and posterior portions of the LHA was observed in the 
    septal-diagonal band of Broca complex, ventral palladium, 
    substantia innominata, and the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Injections of PHA-L into the LHA revealed an extensive 
    projection to the amygdala, including dense terminations in the 
    central nucleus and moderate to light labeling in the medial, 
    ventral, and basolateral subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">In contrast, Berk and Finkelstein (&apos;82) described a 
    limited projection from the LHA to the capsule of the central 
    nucleus of the amygdala in their autoradiographic studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">The dense labeling observed in the amygdala in the 
    present study suggests that the PHA-L technique may be more 
    sensitive than autoradiographic tract tracing.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Ascending projections from anterior and posterior 
    portions of the PFA differed from each other and differed from that 
    of the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Ascending projections to the ventral forebrain from the 
    anterior PFA were light to moderate whereas projections from the 
    posterior PFA were dense in the lateral septal nucleus, nucleus 
    accumbens, and the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The LHA, on the other hand, had dense projections to 
    more lateral and ventral structures such as the substantia 
    innominata and ventral palladium.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">In the septal complex, the posterior but not the 
    anterior PFA had dense terminations in the ventral and intermediate 
    portions of the lateral septal nucleus, whereas the LHA had dense 
    terminations in the medial septaldiagonal band of Broca complex and 
    the dorsomedial portion of the lateral septal nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">In the diencephalon, ascending projections from the PFA 
    region containing pressor sites were very dense in the medial 
    preoptic area and were light in the lateral preoptic area, whereas 
    those from the LHA were more pronounced in the lateral preoptic 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">In the anterior hypothalamic nucleus, moderate afferent 
    inputs originated from the posterior PFA and only light inputs 
    originated from the anterior PFA and the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Both anterior and posterior portions of the PFA showed 
    dense projections to the parvocellular paraventricular nucleus of 
    the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">In contrast, the LHA showed dense terminations more 
    laterally in the perifornical area and in the anterior portion of 
    the LHA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">It is interesting to note that, no apparent differences 
    were observed in the organization of projections to the brain stem 
    from the region containing pressor cell groups in the anterior and 
    posterior parts of the PFA whereas descending projections from 
    tuberal and posterior portions of the LHA did show significant 
    differences (Allen and Cechetto, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Although the PHA-L injection sites in the region of the 
    fornix were small, it is possible that there may have been some 
    anterograde transport from cells located in the dorsal medial 
    hypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Previous PHA-L transport studies have shown that the 
    dorsal medial hypothalamic nucleus has a moderate to dense 
    projection to the ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus and the 
    paraventricular nucleus of the thalamus (ter Horst and Luiten, 
    &apos;86, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">However, our PHA-L injections in the PFA region produced 
    little or no anterograde labeling in these regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">In addition, the premamillary nuclei have also been 
    shown to have a dense projection to the ventromedial hypothalamic 
    nucleus (ter Horst and Luiten, &apos;87; Luiten and Room, 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">In the present study, there was little anterograde 
    labeling in the ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus following 
    injections of PHA-L into the posterior portions of the PFA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">This suggests that the anterograde transport from the 
    PFA described in this study originates primarily from a group of 
    cells in the region of the PFA with little or no involvement of 
    adjacent cells in the dorsal medial hypothalamus or premamillary 
    region.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">The WGA-HRP injections in the LHA or PFA appear to be 
    large and overlap with cell groups in adjacent regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">However, our drawings indicate both the effective uptake 
    region as well as the diffusion zone of the injection and in most 
    cases the effective injection site is located within a particular 
    functionally defined region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">The distribution of anterograde labeling compares with 
    that seen in cases with PHA-L injections into similar regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Furthermore, the WGA-HRP injections are important 
    because they are necessary for determining the possible sources of 
    afferent input to the specific cardiovascular responsive regions of 
    the posterolateral hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The region containing pressor sites in the PFA and the 
    region with depressor sites in the LHAdiffer significantly in the 
    organization of afferent inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The retrograde labeling seen in the WGA-HRP tract 
    tracing studies indicates that the LHA receives input from the 
    medial prefrontal cortex, insular cortex, nucleus accumbens, septal 
    complex, bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, medial and lateral 
    preoptic area, amygdala, anterior and paraventricular hypothalamic 
    nuclei, and the lateral habenular nucleus, whereas the PFA receives 
    a more restricted input mainly from the anterior hypothalamic 
    nucleus, the lateral preoptic nucleus, and the ventral and 
    intermediate portions of the lateral septal nucleus (Swanson and 
    Cowan, &apos;79; Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Kita and Oomura, 
    &apos;82; Luiten et al., &apos;87; Allen et d., &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">The differential projections from the regions containing 
    pressor and depressor sites in the posterolatcral hypothalamus to 
    cortical and forebrain regions may indicate their functional 
    significance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">The results indicate that the region with depressor 
    sites in the LHA have extensive projections to cortical regions 
    such as the insular, lateral, and medial prefrontal, somatomotor, 
    and somatosensory cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">The somatomotor and medial prefrontal cortical regions 
    have been considered likely autonomic control sites in the cortex 
    and have been implicated in integrating behavioral and autonomic 
    responses (Hoff et al., &apos;63; Cechetto and Saper, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">The insular cortex, in particular, has been shown to be 
    a locus of integration of behavioral and autonomic responses (Allen 
    et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">The insula receives visceral information from the 
    periphery (Cechetto and Saper, &apos;871, diffuse association 
    sensory cortical information (Robinson and Burton, &apos;80a,b; 
    Horster and Ettlinger, &apos;87) and, in turn, sends very specific 
    command signals to the autonomic nervous system (Yasui et al., 
    &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">We have recently demonstrated that the region containing 
    depressor sites in the LHA has direct descending pathways to brain 
    stem autonomic control sites such as the parabrachial nucleus, 
    nucleus of the solitary tract, ventral lateral medulla, and 
    sympathetic output regions of the spinal cord (Allen and Cechetto, 
    &apos;91) and it has been demonstrated to mediate sympathetic 
    responses originating in the insular cortex (Cechetto and Chen, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">However, recent functionalanatomical studies (Yasui et 
    al., &apos;91) have indicated that descending projections from 
    pressor and depressor sites in the insula have topographical 
    terminations in the LHA with little or no input to the PFA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">It is possible that pressor responses from the insula 
    may involve activation of a select group of cells in the LHA that 
    have local projections to the PFA whereas depressor responses from 
    the insula may involve activation of depressor cells in the LHA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s224">The present results indicate that the region containing 
    depressor sites in the LHA is also extensively connected with 
    limbic forebrain regions such as the arnygdala, substanLs MS DBB s% 
    A BNST VP SI AMYG</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s225">MPC LF SCIAI IC -Ls - MS -t DBB - s% + A --., BNST -VP 
    +sI AMYG --t + - MPO LPO -AH + PVH - M A L</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s226">MPO LPO AH PVH</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">tia innominata, and the medial septal-diagonal band of 
    Broca complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">The amygdala, in particular, has been considered to be a 
    critical site for the integration of cortical exteroceptive 
    information with interoceptive afferents to generate descending 
    signals for coordination of autonomic control (Cechetto and 
    Calaresu, &apos;83, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Thus, it may be concluded that the region containing 
    depressor sites in the LHA is more generally involved in the 
    coordination of signals from cortical and forebrain stem sites that 
    have been demonstrated to be involved in the integration of 
    emotional, behavioral, and autonomic responses.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">The LHA, most likely, relays the autonomic signals to 
    the periphery via direct connections with medullary and spinal cord 
    autonomic control sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">In contrast, the region containing pressor sites in the 
    PFA do not have widespread connections with cortical and forebrain 
    limbic structures but have more extensive connections with 
    hypothalamic regulatory areas such as the medial preoptic-anterior 
    hypothalamic region and the parvocellular paraventricular nucleus 
    of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Many investigations have indicated the role of the 
    medial preoptic-anterior hypothalamic region in regulation of fluid 
    balance using knife cuts and lesions (Buggy and Johnson, &apos;77; 
    Johnson and Buggy, &apos;78; Brody and Johnson, &apos;81; Gardiner 
    et al., &apos;85) and anatomical studies have shown that 
    angiotensin-stained fibers from the subfornical organ terminate in 
    the region of the medial preoptic area (Miselis, &apos;81; Lind et 
    al.. &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus is known 
    to be involved in integrating the endocrine-autonomic responses of 
    fluid balance as well as other endocrine-autonomic responses 
    associated with homeostasis (Swanson and Sawchenko, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">In addition, the region containing pressor sites in the 
    PFA have limited descending projections that terminate for the most 
    part in the central gray and the dorsolateral tegmental region, 
    especially the pontine micturition center, Barrington&apos;s 
    nucleus (Allen and Cechetto, 91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">This suggests that the PFA may be involved in the 
    integration of cardiovascular and fluid regulation in hypothalamic 
    and forebrain sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">This information may be relayed from the PFA to sites in 
    the midbrain and pons, which mediate defence and pain responses.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">The present findings indicate that specific regions in 
    the posterolateral hypothalamus are functionally distinct and have 
    differential connections with forebrain and cortical sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">The evidence suggests that a region containing depressor 
    sites in the LHA may influence cardiovascular function by direct 
    connections with brain stem autonomic nuclei and that the 
    widespread limbic cortical and forebrain reciprocal connections may 
    be involved in the integration of the autonomic aspects of 
    emotions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">On the other hand, the region containing pressor sites 
    in the PFA may reflect the cardiovascular component of pain and 
    defence responses through connections with the central gray and 
    dorsolateral tegmental region as well as limbic-autonomic 
    structures in the hypothalamus and forebrain.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s240">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s241">This research was supported 
    by Heart and Stroke Foundation of Ontario grant B.1417 (DFC).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s242">GVA is a recipient of a Heart 
    and Stroke Foundation of Canada Fellowship and DFC is a Career 
    Investigator with the Heart and Stroke Foundation of Ontario.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s243">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Allen, G.V., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Hopkins (1989) Mamillary body in the rat: Topography and 
    synaptology of projections from the subicular complex, prefrontal 
    cortex, and midbrain tegmentum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Neurol. 286:311-336.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Allen, G.V., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Hopkins (19901 Topography and synaptology uf mamillary 
    body projections to the mesencephalon and pons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Neurol. 301:214-231.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Allen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">G.V., and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Cechetto (1990ai Baroand chemorereptor activation of 
    single unik in the posterior hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Can. 21:212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Allen, G.V., and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Ccchettn (1990h) Functional and anatomical organization 
    or posterior hypothalamic cardiovascular pressor and depressor 
    sites.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Ahstr. 16:556.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Allen; G.V., and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Cechetto (1991) Functional and anatomical organization 
    of cardiovascular pressor and depressor sites in the lateral 
    hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Descending projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Neurol. 314:1-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Allen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">G.V., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Saper, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Hurley, and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Cechetto (1991) Organization of visceral and limbic 
    connections in the insular cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Neurol. 31O:l-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Bandler, R. (1982) Induction mate into midbrain but 
    30:183-188.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Bausbaum, A.I., and H.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Fields (1984) Endogenous pain control systems: Brainstem 
    spinal pathways and endorphin circuitry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Neurosci. 7:309-338.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Finkelstein (1981) Merent projections to che preoptic 
    area and hypothalamic regions in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Neuroscience 6:16011624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Finkelstein (1982) Efferent connections of the lateral 
    hypothalamic area of the rat: An autoradiographic investigation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Bull. 8:511-526.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Berod, A., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Hartman, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Pujol (1981) Importance of fixation in 
    immunohistochemistry: Use of formaldehyde solutions at variable pH 
    for the localization of tyrosine hydroxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Cytochem. 29:844-850.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Brody, M.J., and A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Johnson (1981) Role of forebrain structures in models of 
    experimental hypertension.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">In F.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Abboud, H.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Fozzard, J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Gilmore and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Reis (eds): Disturbances in Ncurogenic Control of the 
    Circulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Baltimore: Williams and Wilkins, pp. 105-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Buggy, J., and A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Johnson (1977) Preoptic-hypothalamic periventricular 
    lesions: Thirst deficits and hypernatrernia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Physiol. 253 (Regulatory Integrative Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Physiol. 21:R44-R52.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Burstein, R., K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Cliffer, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Giesler, Jr. (1987) Direct somatusensory projections 
    from the spinal cord to the hypothalamus and telencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Neurosci. 7:4159-4164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Cechetto, D.F., and F.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Calaresu (1983) Response of single units in the amygdala 
    to stirnulation of buffer nerves in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Physiol. 244 (Regulatory Integrative Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Physiol. 13):Rti46-R651.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Cechetto, D.F., and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Calaresu (1984) Units in the amygdala responding to 
    selective activation of carotid baroand chemoreceptors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Physiol. 248 (Regulatory Integrative Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Physiol. 14j:R832-R836.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Cechetto, D.F., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Saper (19871 Evidence for a viscerotopic sensory 
    representation in the cortex and thalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Neurol. 262:2745.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Cechetto, D.F., and S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Chen (1990) Subcartical sites mediating sympathetic 
    responses from insular cortex in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Physiol. 258:R245R255.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Cechetto, D.F., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Saper (1990) Role of the cerebral cortex in autonomic 
    function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">In A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Loewy, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Spyer (eds).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">The Autonomic Nervous System: Central Regulation of 
    Autonomic Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. 208-223.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Depaulis, A,, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Bandler, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Vergnes (1989) Characterization of pretentorial 
    periaqueductal matter neurons mediating intraspecific defensive 
    behaviors in the rat by microinjections of kainic acid.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Brain Res. 486: 12 1-132.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Gardiner, T.W., J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Verbalis, and E.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Stricker (1985) Impaired secretion of vasopressin and 
    oxytocin in rats after lesions of nucleus medianus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Physiol. 249 (Regulatory Integrative Comp. physiol. 
    18i):R681R688.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Gelsema, A.J., D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">McKitiick, and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Calaresu (1987) Cardiovascular responses to chemical and 
    electrical stimulation of amygdala in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Physiol. 263 (Regulatory Integrative Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Physiol. 22):R712-R718.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Gerfen, C.R., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons, 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseo1u.s uulgari.s leucoagglutinin 
    (PHAL).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Hancock, M.B. (1984) Visualization of 
    peptide-immunorcactive processes on serotonin-imrriunoreactive 
    cells using two-color imrnunoperoxidase staining.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Cytochem. 32:311-314.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Hinrichsen, C.F.L. (19881 Projections of the midlateral 
    posterior hJpothalamic area influencing cardiorespiratory function 
    in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Evol. 32:10&amp;amp;118.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Hoff, E.C., J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Kell, Jr., and M.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Carroll, Jr. (1963) Effects of cortical stimulation and 
    lesions on cardiovascular function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Rev. 43:68114.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Horster, W., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Ettlinger (1987) Unilateral removal of the posterior 
    insula or of area SII: Inconsistent effects on tactile, visual and 
    auditory performance in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Brain Res. 26.1-17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Johnson, A.K., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Buggy (1978) Periventricular preoptic-hypothalamus is 
    vital for thirst and normal water economy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Physiol. 234 (Regulatory Integrative Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Physiol. 3):K122-R129.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Katter, J.T., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Burstein, and C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Giesler, Jr. (1991) The cells of origin of the 
    spinohypothalamic tract in cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Neurol. 303:lOl-112.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Kita, H., andY.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Oomura (1982) An HRP study of the afferent connections 
    to rat lateral h,ypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Bull.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Rfi.7-71.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Lind, R.W., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Swanson, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Ganten (1984) Angiotcnsin I1 immurioreactivity in the 
    neural afferents and efferents of the subfornical organ of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Brain Res. 321:209-215.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Iditen, P.G.M.; andP.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Room (1980) Interrelations between lateral; dorsomedial 
    and ventromedial hypothalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Brain Res. 190:321-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Luiten, P.G.M., G.J. ter Horst, and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Steffens (1987) The hypothalamus, intrinsic Connections 
    and outflow pathways to the endocrine system in relation to the 
    control of feeding and metabolism.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Neurobiol. 28:1-54.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">-M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for horseradish 
    peroxidase neurochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue reaction-product 
    with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural afferents and 
    effcrents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Histochern.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Miselis, R.R. (1981) The efferent prqjections of the 
    suhfnrnical organ of the rat: A circumventricular organ within a 
    neural network subserving water halance.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Brain Res. 230:1-23.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Norgren, R. (1970) Gustatory refiponses in the 
    21:63-77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Olney.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">J.W. (1978) Keurotoxicity Olney, and McGeer (eds).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Kainic Acid as a Tool in Neurobiology York: Raven 
    Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Ottersen, O.P. (1980) Afferent connections to the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat and cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Afferents from the hypothalamus and the basal 
    telencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Neurol. 194267-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Australia: Academic Press Inc., Harcourt Brace 
    Jovanovich, Publishers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Robinson, C.J.!</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Burton (1980a) Organization of somatosensory receptive 
    fields in cortical areas 7b, retroinsula, postauditory and granular 
    insula ofM. fasciculans.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Neurol. 192;069-092.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Robinson, C.J., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Burton (1980hl Somatic submodality distribution within 
    the second somatosensory (SII), 7b, retroinsular, postauditory, and 
    granular insular cortical areas of M. fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Neurol. 192093-108.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Swansun, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Cowan (1979) An autoradiographic study of the eKerent 
    connections of the lateral hypothalamic area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Neurol. 183:689-706.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Spencer, S.E., W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Sawyer, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Loewy (1988) L-Glutamate stimulation of the zona incerla 
    in Ihe rat decreases herat rate and blood pressure.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Brain Res. 458:72-81.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Spencer, S.E., W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Sawyer, and AD.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Locwy (1989) Cardiovascular effects produced by 
    L-glutamate stimulation of the lateral hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Physiol. 257 (Heart Circ.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Physiol. 26):H540-H522.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Spencer, S.E., W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Sawyer, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Loewy (1990) L-Glutamate mapping of cardioreactive areas 
    in the rat posterior hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Brain Res. 511:149-157.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Sun, M.K.. and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Guyenet (1986) Hypothalamic glutamergic input to 
    medullary sympathoexcilatory neu runs in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Physiol. 251:R79% R810.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Swanson, L.W., al1dW.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Cowan (1979) The Connections of the septal region in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Neurol. 186:621-656.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Swanson, L.W.. and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Sawchenko (1983) Hypothalamic integration: Organization 
    of the paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Neurosci. 6:269-324.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Horst, G.J., and P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Luiten (1986) The projections of the dorsomedial 
    hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Bull. 16:231-248.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Horst, G.J., P. de Boer, P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Luiten, and J.D. van Willigen (1989) Ascending 
    projections from the solitary tract nucleus to the hypothalamus: A 
    Phmseolus uulgurzs lectin tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Neuroscience Yl:785-797.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Horst, G.J., and P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Luiten (1987!</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin tracing of 
    intrahypothalamic connections of the lateral, ventromedial, 
    dorsomedial and paraventricular hypothalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Bull. 18:191-203.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Thomas, H.R., and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Calaresu (19721 Responses of single units in the medial 
    hypothalamus to electrical stimulation of the carotid sinus nerve 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Brain Res. 44:4942.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Yamada, J., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Otani i1978) The spinoperiventricular rabbit, rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Neurol. 61r395-406.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Yasui, Y., C.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Breder, C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Saper, and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Cechetto 11991) Autonomic responses and efferent 
    pathways from the insular cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Neurol. 303355-374.</S>
  </References>

</File>

