<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>A Study of the Reciprocal Connections Between the Septum and 
  the Entorhinal Area Using Anterograde and Retrograde Axonal Transport 
  Methods in the Rat Brain</Title>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The reciprocal connections between the septum and the 
    entorhinal area (EA) was studied in the rat brain using anteroand 
    retrograde axonal transport methods.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">After injections of large volumes (2 x 100 nl) of 
    horseradish peroxidase (HRP) conjugated to wheat-germ agglutinin 
    (WGA) into the medial septum (MS) and the diagonal band of Broca 
    (dbB), anterogradely transported HRP-WGA was found primarily in 
    layers I1 and IV of the medial and lateral EA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Injections of HRP-WGA (50-100 nl) or fluorescent dyes 
    (50100 nl) into different parts of the retrohippocampal region 
    resulted in labeling, by retrograde axonal transport, of cells in 
    the MS and dbB, both ipsiand contralateral to the injected 
    hemisphere.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The labeled cells were either small (long axis of soma: 
    10-15 pm), round, and oval, or medium (15-25 pm) to large (25-35 
    pm) of fusiform or multipolar shape.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">By using the method of retrograde fluorescent double 
    labeling, the septal afferents to the EA were found to give off 
    collaterals to other parts of the hippocampal region.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">A much smaller number of septal cells appeared to send 
    bilateral projections to the EA of both hemispheres.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Studies employing retrograde transport of HRP in 
    combination with acetylcholinesterase (AChE) histochemistry on the 
    same tissue section showed that, while a large number of cells 
    projecting to the EA contain AChE, many projecting cells are devoid 
    of AChE reaction products.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">These findings suggest that the septo-entorhinal 
    projection consists of a cholinergic as well as a noncholinergic 
    component.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The entorhinal efferents to the septum were studied after 
    injections of HRP-WGA into different parts of the retrohippocampal 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Labeled fibers could be traced through the fimbria to 
    their terminal fields in the intermediate parts of the lateral 
    septal nucleus and to the most lateral aspect of the vertical limb 
    of the dbB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The cells giving rise to this projection were situated in 
    layer IV of the medial and layers I1 through V of the lateral 
    EA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Taken together, the present findings demonstrate a close 
    anatomical relationship between the septum and the entorhinal area, 
    in addition to the better known connections between the septum and 
    the Ammon s horn.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The hippocampal region is used as a collective name for 
    the Amman&apos;s horn, area dentata, subiculum, Preand 
    Parasubiculum, and the entorhinal area (area 28 a, b; see 
    Blackstad, 56).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The retrohippocampal region consists of the subicular 
    complex and the entorhinal area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">For more detailed descriptions of the different 
    hippocampal subfields see Blackstad, 56; Swanson and Cowan, 79.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Accepted December 2, 1983.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Angel Alonso s permanent address is Research Department, 
    Center Ramon y Cajal, Madrid, Spain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Address reprint requests to Christer KGhler, Department 
    of Pharmacology, Astra Research Laboratories, SGde,-tglje, Sweden, 
    The hippocampal region&apos; of the rat is innervated by neurons 
    located in the medial parts of the septal area (Meibach and Siegel, 
    &apos;77; Raisman, &apos;66; Siegel and Tassoni, &apos;71; Swanson 
    and Cowan, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Several neuroanatomical studies have shown that the 
    septal projections to the hippocampal formation originate in the 
    medial septal nucleus (MS) and the nucleus of the diagonal band of 
    Broca (dbB) (Segal and Landis, &apos;74; Wyss et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">The major terminal fields of these hippocampal afferents 
    are found in the hilus and the molecular layer of the area dentata 
    as well as in the stratum oriens and stratum pyramidalae of the 
    regio inferior and regio superior (Mellgren and Srebro, &apos;73; 
    Rose et al., &apos;76, Mosko et al., &apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">While most earlier studies have focused on the 
    organization of the septal projections to the hippocampal 
    formation, far less is known about the septal innervation of the 
    retrohippocampal structures, and, in particular the entorhinal 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Nevertheless, studies using degeneration (Mellgren and 
    Srebro, &apos;73) and axonal transport (Segal, &apos;77; Beckstead, 
    &apos;78; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77) methods have pointed out the 
    possible existence of a projection from the septum to the 
    entorhinal area in the rat brain, although the exact origin, 
    termination, and neurochemical identity of this projection have 
    remained unknown.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">In the rat, the EA is the major route by which cortical 
    input reaches the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The perforant path, which originates in layers I1 and I11 
    of the EA (Steward, &apos;76; Steward and Scoville, &apos;761, 
    provides a potent excitatory input to the granule cells of the area 
    dentata (Andersen et al., &apos;66).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Thus, the neurons of the EA occupy a key position within 
    the intrinsic neuronal circuit of the hippocampal region, and the 
    identification of their afferent and efferent connections remains 
    an important step in understanding hippocampal function.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Recent studies have shown that the EA is innervated by 
    neurons situated in a large number of different cortical and 
    subcortical brain regions, including the septum (Srebro et al., 
    &apos;79; Wyss et al., 79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Furthermore, it has been suggested that the 
    septo-entorhinal projection is part of a larger cholinergic system 
    connecting the septum with the hippocampal region (Mellgren and 
    Srebro, &apos;73; Shute and Lewis, &apos;67).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">In the present study, we have examined the 
    septo-entorhinal connections in more detail, using anterograde and 
    retrograde axonal transport methods and acetylcholinesterase (AChE) 
    histochemistry in the rat brain.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s29">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s30">Subjects</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The present study was based on an analysis of brains from 
    50 male albino rats of the Sprague-Dawley strain (Anticimex, 
    Sweden; weight at surgery: 150-250 g).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">During the experiments the rats were housed under regular 
    laboratory conditions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s33">HRP histochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The rats were anesthetized with pentobarbital (Mebumal; 
    60 mgkg) and positioned in a Kopf stereotaxic instrument with the 
    head of the animal kept in a horizontal position.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Injections of horseradish peroxidase (HRP, Sigma Chemical 
    Co., St.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Louis, USA; 30-40% (w/v) dissolved in saline containing 
    1% dimethylsulfoxide) or HRP coupled to wheatgerm agglutinin 
    (HRP-WGA, Sigma; 2% (w/v) dissolved in saline) were made into the 
    medial (MEA) and lateral (LEA) entorhinal area, respectively, or 
    into the septal region, of individual rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The injections were made either by pressure (50-100 nl) 
    through a glass pipette (outer diameter 70100 pm) glued to a 
    Hamilton microsyringe (1 pl), or by iontophoresis through a fine 
    glass capillary.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The injections into the entorhinal area were made with 
    the pipette angled 10&quot; (MEA) or 12&quot; (LEA) to the vertical 
    plane.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Two to seven days after surgery the rats were deeply 
    anesthetized, tracheotomized, provided with artificial respiration, 
    and perfused through the ascending aorta with warm (20째C) saline 
    (50 ml) followed by 500 ml of either 3% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) or a mixture of paraformaldehyde and 
    glutaraldehyde (2% and 1%, respectively) in 0.1 M sucrose-phosphate 
    buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">The fixation was followed by a rinse with 500 ml of 5% 
    (w/v) sucrose-phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Some of the brains injected with HRP were processed for 
    the histochemical visualization of AChE (Geneser-Jensen and 
    Blackstad, &apos;71).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">These rats were perfused with saline (50 ml) followed by 
    500 ml of 4% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">The brains were removed and stored in 20% (w/v) 
    sucrose-phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) at 4째C until they were cut in a 
    cryostat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The HRP-injected brains were reacted according to the 
    method of Mesulam (&apos;76a) and Mesulam and Mufson (&apos;80) 
    using tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) as a chromagen.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Briefly, the cut sections (30-40 pm thick) were collected 
    onto gelatine-albumin-coated glass slides and dried before they 
    were washed and preincubated with TMB for 20 min at room 
    temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The reaction was initiated by adding 2-3 ml of 0.01% H202 
    to the TMB preincubation medium, and stopped by transfer of the 
    sections to acetic buffer (pH 3.3) in distilled water.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">The reacted sections were either stained with neutral red 
    or immediately coverslipped with Pertex (Histolab, Gothenburg, 
    Sweden).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s48">AChE histochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Horizontal or frontal sections were stained for the 
    visualization of AChE using the Koelle copper-thiocholine method 
    described by Geneser-Jensen and Blackstad (&apos;71) and by 
    Mellgren and Srebro (&apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Briefly, glass-mounted sections were incubated for 60-90 
    min at 37째C in a solution (pH 5.01, containing 
    acetylthiocholineiodide (4 mM), copper sulphate (2 mM), and glycine 
    (10 mM) in acetate buffer (50 mM).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The incubation was terminated by several quick washes in 
    distilled water and the sections subsequently immersed in 1.25% 
    sodium sulphite (pH 7.5) for 45-60 sec.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">After several washes in distilled water the sections were 
    developed for 60 sec in 1% silver nitrate.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Nonspecific esterases were deactivated by the addition of 
    etopropazine (Ndiethylaminoethylphenothiazine, 0.2 mM) to the 
    incubation medium.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s54">AChE histochemistry in 
    combination with HRP on the same tissue section</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">The sections were reacted with the copper-thiocholine 
    method as described above or a method based on the above protocol, 
    but with exposure of the sections to 10% potassium ferricyanide for 
    2 min after the HRP reaction in order to produce a reddish-brown 
    precipitate in the AChE-positive cells (Mesulam and Van Hoesen, 
    &apos;76).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s56">Retrograde fluorescent 
    tracing</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">In a separate series of experiments, the fluorescent dye 
    Granular blue (GB; 5%1, dissolved in distilled water) was injected 
    into different parts of the entorhinal area or into the septum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">In studies of the branching projections of septal neurons 
    GB and Propidium iodide (PI; Sigma Chemical Co., St.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Louis, USA; 3%, dissolved in distilled water) were 
    injected into different parts of the hippocampal region in the same 
    rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The fluorochrome-injected brains were fixed by 
    transcardial perfusion with a rinsing solution (50 ml) containing 
    (w/ v) sucrose (0.8&apos;70), glucose (0.4%), and NaCl (0.8%) in 
    distilled water, followed by 500 ml of a fixative containing (w/ v) 
    paraformaldehyde (4%), tannic acid (l%), and magnesium sulphate 
    (4%).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">For a detailed description of this method see DeOlmos and 
    Heimer (&apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The brains were kept in a 20% (w/v) sucrose-phosphate 
    buffer (pH 7.4) solution until they were cut in a cryostat at - 
    15째C.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The sections (30 pm thick) were collected onto 
    gelatine-albumin-coated glass slides and allowed to dry before they 
    were coverslipped with Entellan (Histolab, Gothenburg) and examined 
    under a Leitz Ortoplan fluorescent microscope equipped with 
    epi-illumination.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="25" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s64">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Several excellent reviews exist on the subdivisions of 
    the septal area in the rat (Harkmark et al., &apos;75; Srebro et 
    al., &apos;75; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;79), cat (Andy and Stephan, 
    &apos;64), and man (Harkmark et al., &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">In the present study we have followed the nomenclature 
    proposed by Swanson and Cowan (&apos;79) and by Harkmark et al. 
    (&apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">the major components of the septal area as revealed by 
    ache histochemistry are shown in figure 1 .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">The nomenclature used in the present study for the EA is 
    based primarily on the work of Blackstad (&apos;56) and Haug 
    (&apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">the subdivisions of major areas and layers of the 
    retrohippocampal region , including the ea , are shown in figure 2 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s70">General comments about 
    the injection sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71"><tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> injections the use 
    of the tmb histochemical technique ( mesulam , &apos; 76 ) 
    precludes any definitive statements about the actual spread of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> around the site of infusion 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">The injection site is generally found to be larger when 
    the tissue is reacted with the TMB as compared to diaminobenzidine, 
    at least when the HRP is delivered by pressure (Morrell et al., 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">the issue of the effective injection site is further 
    complicated by our lack of detailed knowledge about the active 
    uptake and axonal transport of <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> 
    from different sectors of the areak ) containing the diffuse , 
    blueish reaction product around the track of the injection pipette 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">in the studies of anterograde transport of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical>  from <connxOrigin>the 
    septum</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the entorhinal 
    area</connxTermination> , large ( 2 x 100 nl ) intraseptal 
    injections of <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical> were used 
    ( fig . 3a ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">these injections were aimed at <injectionLocation>the 
    medial septum and diagonal band of broca</injectionLocation> , but 
    the area containing <labelingDescription>the hrp reaction 
    product</labelingDescription>  was never completely restricted to 
    these subdivisions but included also <injectionSpread>the lateral 
    septum , the medial part of the nucleus accumbens , and the 
    cingulate cortex overlying the septal nuclei</injectionSpread>  
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">in fact , injections of smaller volumes ( 50 nl ) into 
    either <injectionLocation>the medial or the lateral 
    septum</injectionLocation> , respectively , also resulted in some 
    spread of the hrp into <injectionSpread>the adjacent septal 
    nuclei</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">in spite of the spread of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> within <injectionSpread>the 
    septum</injectionSpread> , after each of these smaller injections a 
    separate population of neurons were labeled in <labelingLocation>
    the hippocampal formation</labelingLocation> ( alonso and kohler , 
    &apos; 82 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">thus , it is possible that the area of uptake and 
    transport of <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> is actually more 
    restricted than would be predicted from the area containing the 
    blue color around the injection site .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">the present material includes relatively large injections 
    ( 100 - 200 nl ) of <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation>the ea</injectionLocation> with the spread of 
    reaction product throughout <injectionSpread>the entire 
    retrohippocampal region</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Thus, it is likely that active uptake and retrograde 
    transport of the conjugate occurred from 
    <injectionSpread>structures other than the EA</injectionSpread> 
    (such as <injectionSpread>the preand 
    parasubiculum</injectionSpread>).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">in several cases , however , the 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> injections were restricted to 
    either <injectionLocation>the medial or the lateral subdivisions of 
    the ea</injectionLocation> , and , the presence of anterogradely 
    transported <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> was noted only in 
    <labelingLocation>that portion of the molecular layer of the area 
    dentata</labelingLocation> which is known ( blackstad , &apos; 58 
    hjort - simonsen and jeune , &apos; 72 steward , &apos; 76 ) to be 
    occupied by the terminals of the medial and lateral perforant path 
    , respectively ( fig . 3 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">this distribution of <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> 
    in <labelingLocation>the molecular layer of the area 
    dentata</labelingLocation> was used as a guide when determining if 
    the injections were restricted to <injectionLocation>either part of 
    the ea</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">two representative <tracerChemical>hrp - 
    wga</tracerChemical> injections in <injectionLocation>the medial 
    and lateral ea</injectionLocation> , respectively , are shown in 
    figure 3b .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Comparisons between the retrograde transport found in 
    brains with large or small injections showed a good correspondance 
    with regard to the general distribution of labeled cells in 
    different brain areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Fluomchrome injections <tracerChemical>Granular 
    blue</tracerChemical> and <tracerChemical>Propidium 
    iodide</tracerChemical> produced completely different patterns of 
    labeling around the site of infusion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">Injections of small quantities - ( 50 nl) of GB resulted 
    in a well-restricted area of diffusion extended spherically 
    approximately 0.25-0.50 mm from the track of the injection 
    pipette.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">in contrast to <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> and 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> , the size of the 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> injection site was well 
    restricted and increased over time , which suggests that the 
    injection site seen at 5 - 7 days after surgery represents the 
    largest area contaminated by <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">It should be pointed out, however, that in most cases 
    severe damage of the nervous tissue was found along the track of 
    the injection pipette.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">This is a common problem associated with GB injections in 
    many brain regions, and may result in unwanted filling of damaged 
    axons passing through the area of GB infusion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">Injections of <tracerChemical>PI</tracerChemical> did not 
    result in the same nonspecific damage as 
    <tracerChemical>GB</tracerChemical>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">However, the exact area of the 
    <tracerChemical>PI</tracerChemical> injection site was found to be 
    extremely difficult to determine, since no clear border appears to 
    exist between PI-labeled and nonlabeled tissue.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">It seems, however, that PI can spread for longer 
    distances in the brain than GB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">In the case of injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PI</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    EA</injectionLocation>, we have assumed that little, if any, of the 
    dye spread into <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the 
    hippocampus</injectionSpread>, since no labeling of intrinsic 
    hippocampal or commissural pathways could be found.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s94">Septa1 projections to the 
    entorhinal area Antemgrade transport studies </S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">The case described in detail here is a large ( 2 x 100 nl 
    ) injection of <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation>the medial septum and the diagonal band of 
    broca</injectionLocation> ( see fig . 3a ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">blue reaction product is present throughout 
    <injectionSpread>the entire septal area including the ms , the 
    vertical limb of dbb , the lateral septal nuclei , the anterior 
    hippocampal rudiment , and the medial parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">little or no deposit of <tracerChemical>hrp - 
    wga</tracerChemical> is present in <labelingLocation>the horizontal 
    component of the dbb or the olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">our material also includes several smaller ( &amp;&lt; 
    100 nl ) injections of <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical> 
    into <injectionLocation>the septum</injectionLocation> showing 
    anterograde transport to <labelingLocation>the 
    ea</labelingLocation> but the labeling found in these cases 
    <labelingDescription>is less prominent</labelingDescription> , 
    although the general distribution of fibers and preterminal 
    processes in the ea closely resembles the large 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> injection where 
    <labelingDescription>anterogradely transported hrp - 
    wga</labelingDescription> is present throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the entire hippocampal region</labelingLocation> 
    , including <labelingLocation>the entorhinal 
    area</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99"><labelingDescription>hrp - wga - filled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> are found to leave the injection site 
    and to reach <labelingLocation>the hippocampal 
    region</labelingLocation> by route of three main pathways : 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal fornix , the fimbria , and the ansa 
    lenticularis and the piriform cortex</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4 ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">the <labelingDescription>hrp - wga filled 
    axons</labelingDescription> leave <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> and course caudally in <labelingLocation>
    the dorsal fornix</labelingLocation> and <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral part of the fimbria</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">while <labelingDescription>the 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    fornix</labelingLocation> appear to be destined primarily for 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal parts of the subicular complex and the 
    retrosplenial area</labelingLocation> , those in <labelingLocation>
    the fimbria</labelingLocation> show a more general distribution to 
    <labelingLocation>all dorsal - ventral levels of the ammon s horn 
    and the entorhinal area</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">The distribution of septal efferents to the Ammon s horn 
    has been described in detail by Crutcher et al. ( 81) and will not 
    be dealt with further here, except for the drawings shown in Figure 
    4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">as <labelingDescription>the hrp - wga - filled 
    axons</labelingDescription> leave <labelingLocation>the fornix - 
    fimbria</labelingLocation> they assemble in <labelingLocation>the 
    alveus and the stratum oriens</labelingLocation> , where they 
    course in a caudal direction toward <labelingLocation>the angular 
    bundle</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">at this level many of the fibers radiate toward 
    <labelingLocation>the preand parasubiculum</labelingLocation> as 
    well as <labelingLocation>the ea</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105"><labelingDescription>numerous 
    fibers</labelingDescription> run along <labelingLocation>the 
    angular bundle</labelingLocation> , and <labelingDescription>hrpwga 
    - filled profiles , indicating labeled axons</labelingDescription> 
    , can be followed as they run from the deep and toward 
    <labelingLocation>the more superficial layers of the 
    ea</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">within <labelingLocation>the ea</labelingLocation> , the 
    dustlike precipitate of hrp - wga reaction product is 
    <labelingDescription>heterogeneously distributed between the 
    different layers</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">thus , what appears to be <labelingDescription>a dense 
    terminal field</labelingDescription> is present in <labelingLocation
    >layer iv of both the medial and the lateral ea</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108"><labelingDescription>a distinct , though sparser 
    terminal field</labelingDescription> is present in <labelingLocation
    >layer i1 of the entire ea</labelingLocation> ( fig . 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109"><labelingLocation>at the most ventral levels of the 
    ea</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>anterogradely 
    transported hrpwga</labelingDescription> is present in 
    <labelingLocation>all layers</labelingLocation> , although most of 
    the reaction product is present in <labelingLocation>layers i1 and 
    iv</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">analysis of horizontal sections cut through the 
    hippocampal region clearly show <labelingDescription>hrp - wga - 
    filled fibers</labelingDescription> that enter 
    <labelingLocation>the ea</labelingLocation> via a ventral route by 
    way of <labelingLocation>the ansa lenticularis</labelingLocation> 
    and through <labelingLocation>the amygdala and the piriform 
    cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111"><labelingDescription>these fibers</labelingDescription> 
    distribute to <labelingLocation>all layers of the ventral parts of 
    the lateral ea</labelingLocation> and to <labelingDescription>a 
    minor extent</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
    mea</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112"><labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> 
    containing <labelingDescription>the hrp - wga reaction 
    product</labelingDescription> are present in <labelingLocation>the 
    angular bundle of these ventral levels</labelingLocation> , 
    indicating that some of the septal efferents ascend in the angular 
    bundle to more dorsal parts of the hippocampus ( fig . 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">in addition to the projection from <connxOrigin>the 
    septum</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the ea</connxTermination> 
    , <labelingDescription>anterogradely transported hrp - 
    wga</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>both the 
    parasubiculum and the deep layers of the 
    presubiculum</labelingLocation> at dorsal levels , indicating the 
    existence of an efferent projection from <connxOrigin>the 
    septum</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the subicular 
    complex</connxTermination> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114"><labelingLocation>the dense innervation of layers i1 and 
    iv of the ea</labelingLocation> occurs in register with the laminar 
    distribution of ache staining in this area .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">similar overlapping distribution of 
    <labelingDescription>anterogradely transported 
    hrp</labelingDescription> and ache is found in <labelingLocation>
    the parasubiculum and the deep layers of the 
    presubiculum</labelingLocation> , and support earlier lesion 
    studies ( mellgren and srebro , 73 ) , which suggests that the ea 
    like <connxTermination>the hippocampus</connxTermination> is 
    innervated by cholinergic fibers from <connxOrigin>the medial 
    septum</connxOrigin> ( mellgren and srebro , 73 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">retrogrude transport studies injections of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>hrpwga</tracerChemical> into either 
    <injectionLocation>the medial or the lateral entorhinal 
    area</injectionLocation> resulted in 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde</labelingDescription> axonal 
    transport of the protein to the parent cell bodies in 
    <labelingLocation>the dbb and the ms</labelingLocation> , in 
    addition to a large number of other brain areas .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117"><labelingDescription>a majority of the retrogradely 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> are situated within 
    <labelingLocation>the vertical and the horizontal limbs of the dbb 
    and the horizontal nucleus of the dbb</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">similarly , injections of either 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    ea</injectionLocation> resulted in <labelingDescription>retrograde 
    labeling of cell bodies</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
    the dbb and ms</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">The general position and morphology of 
    <labelingDescription>the fluorochrome-labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> correspond well to those labeled by 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical>, although the fluorescent dyes 
    labeled more cells per section.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">the superior sensitivity of <tracerChemical>the 
    fluorochromes</tracerChemical> over 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> as retrograde tracers is 
    particularly evident with regard to the labeling of septal cells 
    located contralateral to the injected hemisphere .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">analysis of serial frontal sections cut through 
    <labelingLocation>the septum</labelingLocation> showed that a 
    majority of <labelingDescription>the cells</labelingDescription> 
    projecting to <connxTermination>the ea</connxTermination> are 
    located in <labelingLocation>the middle to caudal parts of the 
    structure</labelingLocation> ( fig . 5 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">in all cases examined , <labelingDescription>a small 
    number of hrp - positive cells</labelingDescription> are present in 
    <labelingLocation>the dbb and ms contralateral to the injected 
    hemisphere</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">few , if any , <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are situated in <labelingLocation>the 
    most rostra1 parts of the dbb</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">the use of relatively long survival times ( up to 5 days 
    ) in combination with a strong fixation of the tissue resulted in 
    the visualization of hrp reaction product in 
    <labelingDescription>the somata and proximal parts of the dendrites 
    of the labeled cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">in some brains , <labelingDescription>extensive staining 
    of the cell bodies and dendrites</labelingDescription>  allowed a 
    preliminary analysis of their morphology .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">A closer inspection of these cells suggests that they 
    constitute a morphologically heterogeneous population (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">thus , <labelingDescription>the 
    cells</labelingDescription> projecting to <connxTermination>the 
    ea</connxTermination> are either of small ( long axis of the soma : 
    10 - 15 pm ) size and oval shape or medium ( 15 - 25 pm ) to large 
    ( 25 - 35pm ) size and fusiform or multipolar in shape .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128"><labelingLocation>the caudal part of the 
    ms</labelingLocation> is rich in medium to large multipolar and 
    fusiform cells with long dendrites that cross the midline and 
    invade <labelingLocation>the ms of the opposite 
    side</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">neurons projecting to <connxTermination>the medial and 
    lateral part of the ea</connxTermination> , respectively , occur 
    intermingled in <labelingLocation>the horizontal limb of the 
    dbb</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">in <labelingLocation>the ms and vertical limb of the 
    dbb</labelingLocation> , however , the position of these cells 
    shows a certain degree of geographical segregation : cells 
    projecting to the lateral ea tend to be located more lateral than 
    those projecting to the medial ea ( fig . 5 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">this medial to lateral arrangement is also seen after 
    small injections of <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> into 
    <injectionLocation>the lateral</injectionLocation> and 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    medial ea</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">analysis of the retrograde axonal transport of the dyes 
    to <labelingLocation>the septum</labelingLocation> showed a 
    separation between the neurons that give rise to these two 
    projections : a majority of the cells 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled</labelingDescription> 
    from <injectionLocation>the medial part of the 
    ea</injectionLocation> occupy a more medial position in 
    <labelingLocation>the septum</labelingLocation> as compared to 
    those labeled by <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> after 
    <injectionLocation>lateral ea</injectionLocation> injections .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">retrograde transport of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> in combination with ache in a 
    separate series of experiments , retrograde axonal tracing of hrp 
    from <connxOrigin>the ea</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the 
    septum</connxTermination> was combined with ache histochemistry on 
    the same tissue section ( for discussion of this method see hardy 
    et al . , &apos; 76 mesulam , &apos; 76 mesulam and van hoesen , 
    &apos; 76 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">taken together , these experiments show that 
    <labelingDescription>a large number of cells</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the dbb and the ms</labelingLocation> contain 
    both the blue hrp reaction product and the brown ( or reddish ) 
    color which indicates the presence of cytoplasmatic ache .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135"><labelingDescription>the ache - positive 
    cells</labelingDescription> projecting to <connxTermination>the 
    entorhinal area</connxTermination> do not belong to any 
    morphologically distinct group of neurons , since small ovoid as 
    well as large multipolar <labelingDescription>ache - positive 
    cells</labelingDescription> contain the retrogradely transported 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> ( figs . 7 , 8 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">however , <labelingDescription>a relatively large number 
    of cells</labelingDescription> that lack histochemically detectable 
    ache are retrogradely labeled by hrp after large injections of the 
    protein into <injectionLocation>the hippocampal region, including 
    the ea</injectionLocation>  ( figs . 9 , 10 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">this finding suggests that there may exist a prominent , 
    noncholinergic projection from <connxOrigin>the 
    septum</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the entorhinal area ( and 
    the hippocampal formation )</connxTermination> , in addition to the 
    one presumed to be cholinergic .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">the number and the relative positions of 
    <labelingDescription>achepositive and ache - negative cells 
    containing hrp</labelingDescription> are shown schematically in 
    figure 7 .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">although many of <labelingDescription>the hrp - 
    iabeledache - negative and hrp - labeledache - positive 
    cells</labelingDescription> in large part occur intermingled within 
    <labelingLocation>the septum</labelingLocation> , a closer 
    inspection reveals that <labelingDescription>hrp - labeled neurons 
    lacking ache reactivity tend</labelingDescription> to be situated 
    primarily in <labelingLocation>parts of the 
    septum</labelingLocation> that contain 
    <labelingDescription>relatively few ache - positive 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in normal material ( fig . 8 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">branching of septa1 projections injections of either 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    ea</injectionLocation> resulted in similar distribution of 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">analysis of brains where 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> ( or 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> ) had been injected into 
    <injectionLocation>the ea</injectionLocation> , and 
    <tracerChemical>pi</tracerChemical> ( or 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> ) into <injectionLocation>the 
    dorsal or ventral hippocampal formation of the same 
    side</injectionLocation> , showed a picture of retrograde labeling 
    qualitatively similar to that seen with 
    <tracerChemical>hrp</tracerChemical> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">in one representative experiment , 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> was injected into 
    <injectionLocation>the dorsal hippocampus and pi into the medial 
    entorhinal area</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">the <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> injection was 
    situated at <injectionLocation>the border between the subiculum and 
    ca1</injectionLocation> , with the tip of the pipette in 
    <injectionLocation>the molecular layer of the area 
    dentata</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Spread of the dye extended approximately 0.5 mm around 
    the track of the pipette as well as along the pipette into 
    <injectionSpread>the overlying neocortex</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">With exception of the neocortex, diffusion of 
    <tracerChemical>GB</tracerChemical> did not occur to any 
    extrahippocampal region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">The spread of <tracerChemical>PI</tracerChemical> after 
    <injectionLocation>entorhinal</injectionLocation> injections is 
    more difficult to determine, but a zone of bright red fluorescence 
    extended spherically at least 0.5 Gm from the center of the 
    injection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147"><labelingDescription>the neurons</labelingDescription> 
    projecting to <connxTermination>the hippocampal formation and the 
    ea</connxTermination> , respectively , occur intermingled along 
    <labelingLocation>the rostrocaudal axis of the 
    septum</labelingLocation> , although the cells labeled from 
    <injectionLocation>the dorsal hippocampus</injectionLocation> are 
    present far <labelingLocation>more rostra1 in the diagonal 
    band</labelingLocation> than are the ea projecting ones .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">in addition to these single labeled cells , 
    <labelingDescription>a relatively large number of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>both the dbb and 
    the ms</labelingLocation> contained both fluorochromes within their 
    somata ( fig . 9 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149"><labelingDescription>cell counts 
    performed</labelingDescription> in several rats showed that 
    approximately 20% of all <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> are double - labeled after these 
    injections .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">in several instances , <labelingDescription>double - 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> are present also contralateral 
    to the injected hemipshere .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">the proportion of double - labeled cells did not differ 
    significantly when comparisons were made between the 
    <injectionLocation>dorsal and ventral 
    hippocampal</injectionLocation> injections vis - a - vis those made 
    in <injectionLocation>the ea</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">in a separate series of experiments , 
    <tracerChemical>the fluorescent dyes</tracerChemical> were injected 
    into <injectionLocation>various parts of the right and left 
    hippocampal region</injectionLocation> , respectively .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">These experiments showed that, in contrast to the 
    relatively large proportion (20%) of 
    <connxOrigin>septal</connxOrigin> neurons projecting to both 
    <connxTermination>the HPC and EA</connxTermination> ipsilateral to 
    the injection, few cells (&amp;lt; 5%) showed branching projections 
    to <connxTermination>the EA or HPC</connxTermination> of both 
    hemispheres.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s154">Entorhinal projections 
    to the septum</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">anterogmde tmnsport studies injections of 
    <tracerChemical>hrp - wga</tracerChemical> into different parts of 
    <injectionLocation>the ea</injectionLocation> resulted in 
    a<labelingDescription>nterograde axonal 
    transport</labelingDescription> of the protein to  <labelingLocation
    >the septum</labelingLocation> , in addition to a large number of 
    other subcortical structures .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">after <tracerChemical>hrpwga</tracerChemical> iniections 
    into <injectionLocation>the mea</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> can be 
    followed from the injection site toward the angular bundle which 
    thev either denetrate on their way to the alveus or ascend within 
    to more dorsal levels .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157"><labelingDescription>alarge number of hrp - wga - 
    labeled fibers</labelingDescription> run rostrally in 
    <labelingLocation>the alveus</labelingLocation> to enter 
    <labelingLocation>the fimbria</labelingLocation> , where they 
    occupy its most lateral portion .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">on their route to the terminal field in <labelingLocation
    >the ls</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> 
    <labelingModifier>traverse</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsolateral part of the septum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">further rostrally they turn ventral as they enter 
    <labelingLocation>the intermediate parts of the lateral septal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">throughout the rostrocaudal axis of the septum , 
    <labelingLocation>the medial septal nucleus and the intermediate 
    part of the lateral septum</labelingLocation> are 
    <labelingDescription>the dominant terminal fields of the ea 
    projections</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">at the most rostra1 levels <connxOrigin>the 
    ea</connxOrigin> efferents occupy the entire <labelingLocation>
    lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162"><labelingDescription>the terminal 
    fields</labelingDescription> of the efferents from <connxOrigin>the 
    mea and lea</connxOrigin> show <labelingDescription>a high degree 
    of overlap</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">the only apparent difference is <labelingDescription>a 
    slightly less prominent input</labelingDescription> to 
    <connxTermination>the ms and dbb</connxTermination> from 
    <connxTermination>the lateral than from the medial 
    ea</connxTermination> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">retrograde transport studies injections of either 
    <tracerChemical>hrpwga</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>gb</tracerChemical> into <labelingLocation>the 
    intermediate part of the lateral septum</labelingLocation> resulted 
    in labeling , by retrograde axonal transport , of cells in both 
    <labelingLocation>the mea and the lea</labelingLocation> ( figs . 
    11 , 12 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">analysis of the laminar distribution of the retrogradely 
    labeled neurons revealed that a majority of these cells are located 
    in <labelingLocation>layer iv of both the mea and the 
    lea</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">after long survival times ( up to 3 days ) , 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are found also in <labelingLocation>
    layers i and i11</labelingLocation> ( fig . 11 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">a majority of these cells , however , are found in 
    <labelingLocation>the most lateral part of the 
    lea</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">close to the rhinal fissure , 
    <labelingDescription>scattered cells</labelingDescription> 
    containing hrpwga reaction products or gb fluorescence are present 
    in <labelingLocation>all cortical layers , including layers v and 
    vi</labelingLocation> ( fig . 11 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">analysis of serial horizontal sections cut through the 
    ea showed <labelingDescription>an increasing number of retrogradely 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> at successively more ventral 
    levels ( see fig . 11 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170"><labelingDescription>a large number of the retrogradely 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> appears to be pyramidal or 
    stellate in shape .</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s171">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Using the methods of anterograde and retrograde axonal 
    tracing, we have analyzed the connections between the septum and 
    the entorhinal area in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">The findings of reciprocal connections between the 
    septum and the EA extend previous investigations showing prominent 
    connections between the septum and the hippocampal formation 
    (Powell and Cowan, &apos;55; Raisman, &apos;66; Raisman et al., 
    &apos;66; Segal and Landis, &apos;74; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;79; 
    Cragg and Hamlyn, &apos;56; Siegel and Tassoni, &apos;77; Meibach 
    and Siegel, &apos;77) in several animal species, including the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The findings of the present study indicate that the 
    reciprocal connections between the septum and the retrohippocampal 
    structures are more extensive than previously recognized.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">The observation that the EA is innervated by neurons in 
    the septum suggests that septal modulation of hippocampal activity 
    can occur at different levels within the hippocampal region, 
    including the entorhinal area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">The septo-entorhinal projection The existence of a 
    pathway from the septum to the EA was suggested in early 
    degeneration studies by Mellgren and Srebro (&apos;73) and in 
    autoradiographic experiments by Swanson and Cowan (&apos;79) and 
    Hunt and Schmidt (&apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">In the two latter studies, however, the septo-entorhinal 
    projection was mentioned only incidentally and no detailed analysis 
    of the terminal distribution of this pathway was reported.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">It is clear from the present study, however, that the 
    septal innervation of the EA is far more extensive than has been 
    recognized in previous studies.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">The extensive labeling of this pathway in our experiment 
    may have been due to the injections of relatively large volumes of 
    tracer, in combination with reltively long survival periods (up to 
    5 days).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">The need for large injections of tracer to demonstrate 
    this pathway is probably due to the elongated and slightly curved 
    shape of the dbB, which harbors a majority of the EA projecting 
    cells, since restricted injections of HRP-WGA (Alonso and Kohler, 
    unpublished observations) or 3H-amino-acids (Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;79) into small parts of the dbB resulted in modest labeling 
    of the septal efferents to the entorhinal area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">A majority of the septal projections to the EA appear to 
    terminate in layers I1 and IV.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">This pattern of distribution is in register with the 
    laminar distribution of AChE.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">The overlap of HRP and AChE reaction products suggests 
    that the AChE activity in the EA may derive from septal efferents 
    to layers I1 and IV.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">That this may be the case was indicated previously by 
    lesion experiments, showing a loss of AChE activity and the 
    presence of terminal degeneration in these layers after 
    electrolytic destruction of the medial septum (Harkmark et al., 
    &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The question remaining to be settled, however, is to 
    what extent AChE in the EA indicates the existence of a cholinergic 
    septo-entorhinal projection in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The usefulness of AChE as a histochemical marker for 
    cholinergic neurons has been challenged in several recent studies 
    (see Fibiger, &apos;82, for review) and many studies have shown 
    that in some brain regions AChE-positive cells do not contain 
    choline acetyltransferase immunoreactivity (CAT) (see Levey et al., 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">There exists good experimental evidence that AChE 
    activity in the hippocampal formation resides partly in cholinergic 
    afferents from the medial septum and the diagonal band of Broca, 
    although far less is known about the identity of entorhinal 
    AChE.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Numerous CAT-immunoreactive fibers have been 
    demonstrated in the hippocampal region (Kimura et al., &apos;80), 
    which suggests that this region does receive a cholinergic 
    innervation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">However, the possibility that entorhinal AChE derives 
    also from noncholinergic afferents cannot be ruled out at 
    present.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Interesting in this regard is the observation that in 
    the spinal cord and substantia nigra AChE hydrolyzes substance P 
    (SP) (see Chubb et al., &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Since SP-immunoreactive nerve terminals are present in 
    the EA (Vincent et al., ,811, such a role for AChE cannot be 
    excluded.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Although further studies are needed to settle this 
    issue, there is indirect evidence indicating that part of the 
    septo-entorhinal projection indeed belongs to a general cholinergic 
    pathway connecting the medial septum and the diagonal band with the 
    hippocampal region (see Shute and Lewis, &apos;67; Mellgren et al., 
    &apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">For example, the distribution of AChEand CAT-positive 
    cells appears to overlap in the medial septum (Kimura et al., 
    &apos;80), although this correlation is not perfect (see Levey et 
    al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">The septal neurons retrogradely labeled from the EA 
    contain AChE (present study), and lesions of the septum result in a 
    depletion of AChE staining in both the hippocampus and EA with a 
    similar time course (Mellgren and Srebro, &apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Furthermore, biochemical studies have shown loss of CAT 
    and acetylcholine activity after destruction of the medial septum 
    (Oderfeld-Nowak et al., &apos;74; Pepeu et al., &apos;71; Sethy et 
    al., &apos;73).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">In the present study many of the cells in the septum, 
    retrogradely labeled from the EA, were found to contain AChE as 
    judged from experiments combining HRP and AChE histochemistry on 
    the same tissue section (Mesulam, &apos;76; Mesulam and Van Hoesen, 
    &apos;76; Hardy et al., &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">In addition, HRP-labeled cells lacking detectable 
    amounts of AChE in their cytoplasm were found after entorhinal or 
    hippocampal injections of HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">This observation suggests that there may exist a 
    noncholinergic component of the pathway from the septum to the 
    hippocampal region, including the EA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Recent studies using antibody to CAT (Kimura et al., 
    &apos;81) support the impression created from AChE-stained 
    sections, namely that not all cells in the diagonal band of Broca 
    are cholinergic.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Furthermore, massive injections of HRP (or 
    fluorochromes) into the hippocampal region, including the EA, 
    resulted in retrograde labeling of more cells per section than 
    could be accounted for by the number of AChE-stained cells found in 
    adjacent sections or in sections cut from fresh tissue (present 
    study).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The presence of HRP-labeled neurons lacking AChE 
    activity was established using two histochemical methods for the 
    visualization of AChE that offer different optical resultion of 
    AChE vis-a-vis HRP reaction products (see Materials and 
    Methods).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Both methods gave the same results.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">It seems unlikely that fixation procedures or optical 
    factors reduced or abolished the visability of AChE in HRP-labeled 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">First, the number of AChE-positive cells or the quality 
    of staining did not differ significantly in sections of the septum 
    from normal unfixed or formaldehyde-fixed brains.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Second, in several brains the sections were 
    &quot;overincubated&quot; for AChE.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">This procedure did not alter the number of 
    HRPAChE-positive to HRP-AChE-negative cells.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Third, the sections were analyzed using Nomarski optics, 
    which enhances the contrast in the section and greatly facilitates 
    the identification of HRP-stained neurons lacking AChE (see Levey 
    et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Under these conditions only cells with blue reaction 
    product in their somata and dendrites, but with a white nucleus and 
    a soma lacking brown precipitate, were accepted as 
    AChE-negative.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">This stringent criterion might in fact have resulted in 
    a slight underestimation of the actual number of 
    HRP-positiveAChE-negative cells, since many septal cells are 
    cholinoceptive (Kimura et al., &apos;81; Fibiger, &apos;82), with 
    precipitate of AChE activity covering the outer surface of their 
    soma membranes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">The neurochemical identity of the 
    &quot;noncholinergic&quot; component of the septo-entorhinal 
    projection remains unknown at present.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">However, the MS and dbB have recently been shown to 
    contain a large number of cells immunoreactive for glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase (GAD) (Kohler and ChanPalay, &apos;83), the enzyme 
    responsible for the synthesis of yaminobutyric acid.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">It remains to be established if any of these 
    GAD-positive neurons project to the hippocampal region, including 
    the entorhinal area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Many of the septal cells with projections to the EA have 
    axon collaterals to the hippocampal formation of the same 
    hemisphere.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">However, in spite of the fact that many of the cells in 
    septum have collaterals to the HPC and the EA, a very small number 
    of cells showed bilateral projections to both hemispheres in the 
    double-labeling experiments, although a single neuron may have an 
    axon that crosses to the contralateral EA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The same type of organization has been observed in 
    another midline structure, the dorsal raphe nucleus, where few 
    cells project bilaterally to the EA (Kohler and Steinbusch, 
    &apos;82) or the striatum (Van der Kooy and Hattori, &apos;80) as 
    shown by the method of fluorescent retrograde tracing.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">The enforhinul-septul projection Until recently, the 
    perforant path was regarded as the only efferent pathway of the 
    entorhinal area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">It is now well established that the EA has extensive 
    extrahippocampal projections to a number of cortical and 
    subcortical structures in the rat (Srebro et al., &apos;79; Wyss, 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">One important target of these EA efferents is the septum 
    as shown earlier using retro grade fluorescent tracing (Kohler and 
    Eriksson, &apos;81), and ii the present study using both 
    anterograde and retrogradt tracing methods.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Within the septum, the terminal distribution of the EA 
    projection is restricted to the intermediate parts of the lateral 
    septum, parts of the medial septal nucleus, and the vertical limb 
    of the dbB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">This distribution is different from the terminal field 
    occupied by projections from the dorsal hippocampus, but overlaps 
    to a certain degree with the projections originating from cells 
    situated at ventral levels of the hippocampal formation (Swanson 
    and Cowan, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Although the lateral septal area has been shown to 
    project to several hypothalamic areas (see Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;79), little is yet known about the efferent projection(s) of 
    its intermediate parts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Until this information becomes available it is difficult 
    to relate the EA innervation of the intermediate part of the 
    lateral septum to a more general neuronal network connecting this 
    particular septal nucleus with other parts of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">It is interesting, however, that a small component of 
    the projections from the EA enters the MS-dbB complex, since this 
    part of the septum contains neurons that project back upon the 
    hippocampal region, including the entorhinal area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">A majority of the cells in the EA which contribute to 
    the septal projection are situated in layer IV and to a minor 
    extent in layer I1 of both the medial and lateral EA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">These are the same layers that receive afferents from 
    the medial septum and diagonal band of Broca.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">It remains to be shown if the same neurons of layer IV 
    that project to the septum are innervated by the septal efferents 
    to this layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">The projections from layer IV of the EA to the septum 
    have axon collaterals to the nucleus accumbens septi as well as to 
    the frontal cortex, as demonstrated in retrograde fluorescence 
    tracing experiments (Kohler and Eriksson, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Layer I1 of the EA contains neurons that give rise to 
    the perforant path (Steward and Scoville, &apos;76) as well as some 
    of the septal projecting cells, but it is not known if these cells 
    have axon collaterals to both the septum and the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">The chemical identity of the projection to the septum is 
    not known at present.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">It is possible that at least some of these fibers may 
    use glutamate or aspartate since it has been shown (Zaczek et al., 
    &apos;79; Walaas, &apos;81) that their transection results in 
    reductions of the high-affinity uptake of 3H-glutamate in the 
    septal area.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements><S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
   format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
   id="s231">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S></Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s232">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Alonso, A., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Kohler (1982) Evidence for separate projections of 
    hippocampal pyramidal and non-pyramidal neurons to different parts 
    of the septum in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Lett. 31:209-214.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Andersen, P., B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Holmquist, and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Voorhoeve 11966) Entorhinal tion of dentate granule 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Scand. 66:448-460.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Andy, O.J., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Stephan (1964) The Septum of the Cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Springfield, Thomas.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Biscoe, T.J., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Straughan (1966) Microelectrode studies in the cat 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">(Lond.) 183:341-359.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Bjorklund, A., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Skagerberg (1979) Simultaneous use of retrograde 
    fluorescent tracers and fluorescent histochemistry for convenient 
    and precise mapping of monoaminergic projection and collateral 
    arrangements in the CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Meth. 1:261:277.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Blackstad, T.W. (1956) Commissural connections of the 
    hippocampal region in the rat with special reference to their mode 
    of termination.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Neurol. 105:417-537.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Blackstad, T.W. (1958) On the termination of some 
    afferents to the hippocampus and fascia dentata.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">An experimental study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Acta Anat. 35:202-214.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Reckstead.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">R.M. 11978) Afferent connections of the entorhinal area 
    rat as demonstrated by retrograde cell labeling with horseradish 
    idase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Brain Res. 152:249-264.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Chubb.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">I.W., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Hodgson, and G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">White (1980) Acetylcholinesterase hydrolyses substance 
    P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Neuroscience. 52065-2072.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Cragg, B.G., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Hamlyn (1956) A histological study of some commissural 
    and septal connections of the hippocampus in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">bond.) 90591-596.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Crutcher, K.A., R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Madison, and J.N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Davis 11981) A study of the rat septohippocampal pathway 
    using anterograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Neuroscience 6:1961-1973.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">DeOlmos, J., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Heimer (1980) Double and triple labeling of neurons with 
    fluorescent substances: The study of collateral pathways in the 
    ascending raphe system.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Neursci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">I9:7-12.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Fibiger, H.C. (1982) The organization and some 
    projections of cholinergic neurons of the mammalian forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Rev. 4:327-388.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Geneser-Jensen, F.A., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Blackstad (1971) Distribution of acetylcholinesterase in 
    the hippocampal region of the guinea pig. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Entorhinal area, parasubiculum and presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Z.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Zellforsch. 114:460-481.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Hardy, H., L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Heimer, R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Switzer, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Watkins (1976) Simultaneous demonstration of horseradish 
    peroxidase and acetylcholinesterase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Lett. 3:l-5.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Harkmark, W., S.I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Mellgren, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Srebro 11975) Acetylcholinesterase histochemistry of the 
    septal region in rat and human: Distribution of enzyme activity.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Brain Res. 95.281-289.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Haug.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">F.M.S. 11976) Sulphide silver pattern and 
    cytoarchitectonics of parahippocampal areas in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Special reference to the subdivision of area 
    entorhinalis (area 28) and its demarcation from the piriform 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Cell.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Biol. 525-73.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Hjort-Simonsen, A. 11971) Hippocampal efferents to the 
    ipsilateral entorhinal area: An experimental study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">I42:417438.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Hjort-Simonsen, A., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Jeune (1972) Origin and termination of the hippocampal 
    perforant path in the rat studied by silver impregnation.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">I44:215-232.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Hunt, S., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Schmidt (1979) The relationship of 
    a-bungarotoxin-binding activity and cholinergic termination within 
    the rat hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Neurosci. 4.385-592.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Kimura, M., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">McGeer, F.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Peng, and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">McGeer (1980) Choline acetyltransferase-containing 
    neurons in rodent brain demonstrated by immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Science 208:1057-1059.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Kimura, M., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">McGeer, J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Peng, and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">McGeer (1981) The central cholinergic system studied by 
    choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Neurol. 200:151-201.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Kohler.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">C., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Eriksson (1981) Efferent projections from the entorhinal 
    area to the basal forebrain and frontal cortex originate in layer 
    IV.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Neurosci. 7:420 (abstract), Kohler, C.. and V.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Chan-Palay (1983) Distribution of gamma-aminobutyric 
    acid containing neurons and terminals in the septal area.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">An immunohistocheniical study using antibodies to 
    glutamic acid decarboxylase in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Embryol. 167153-65.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Kohler, C.. and H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Steinbusch (1982) Identification of serotonin and 
    nonserotonin-containing neurons of the midbrain raphe projecting to 
    the entorhinal area and the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">A combined immunohistochemical and fluorescent 
    retrograde tracing study in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Neuroscience 7:951-975.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Levey, A.I., B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Wainer, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Mufson, and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Mesulam (1983) Co-localization of acetylcholinesterase 
    and choline acetyltransferase in the rat cerebrum.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Neurosci. 9:9-22.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Lorente de No, R. (1934) Studies on the structure of the 
    cerebral cortex. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Continuation of the study of the ammonic system.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">J.Psychol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Neurol. 46:113-177.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Mellgren, S.I., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Srebro (1973) Changes in acetylcholinesterase 
    distribution of degenerating fibers in the hippocampal region after 
    tal lesions in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Brain Res. 52:19-36.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Siege1 (1977) Efferent connections of the septal area in 
    the rat: An analysis utilizing retrograde and anterograde transport 
    methods.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Brain Res. 119:1-20.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Mesulam, M.M. (1976aJ The blue reaction product in 
    horseradish peroxidase histochemistry: Incubation parameters and 
    visibility.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Cytochem. 24:1273-1280.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">SEPTO-EhTORHINAL INTERCONNECTIONS Mesulam, M.M. (1976b) 
    A horseradish peroxidase cation of the efferents of 
    acetylcholinesterase Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Cytochem. 24:1281-1286.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Mesulam M.M., and G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Van Hoesen (1976) Acetylcholinesterase-rich pro.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">jections from the basal fore-brain of the rhesus monkey 
    to the neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Brain Res. 109:152-157.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Mesulam, M.M., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Mufson (1980) The rapid anterograde horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Neuroscience 5: 1277-1286.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Morell.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">J.I., L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Greenberger, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Pfaff (1981) Comparison of horse.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">radish peroxidase visualization methods: Quantitative 
    results and fur.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">ther technical specifics.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Cytochem. 29:903-916.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Mosko, S., G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Lynch, and C.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Cotman (1973) The distribution of septal projections to 
    the hippocampal formation of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Neural. 152163-174.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Oderfeld-Nowak, B., 0.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Narkiewicz, J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Bialowas, J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Dabrowska, A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Wieraszko, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Gradkowska (1974) The influence of septal nuclei 
    lesion?</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">on activity of acetylcholinesterase and 
    choline-acetyltransferase in the hippocampus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Acta Neurobiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Exp. 34:787-789.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Pepeu, G., A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Mulas, A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Rufi, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Satgui (1971) Brain acetylcholine levels in rats with 
    septal lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Life Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">IO:l81-184.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Powell, T.B.S., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Cowan (1955) An experimental study ent connections of 
    the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Brain 78:115-135.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Raisman, G. (1966) The connections of the septum.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Brain 89r317-348.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Raisman, G., M.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Cowan, and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Powell (1966) An experimental analysis of the efferent 
    projection of the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Brain 89:83-108.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Ropert, N., Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Ben-Ari, K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Krnjevic, and P Pole (1980) Septohippocampal pathway and 
    cholinergic disinhibition of pyramidal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Can.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Physiol. 11:118.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Rose, A.M., T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Hattori, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Fibiger (1976) Analysis of the septo-hippocampal pathway 
    by light and electron-microscopic autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Brain Res. 108r150-174.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Segal.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">M. 11977) Afferents to the entorhinal cortex of the rat 
    studied by the method of retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Neurol. 57.750-765, Segal, M., and S.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Landis (1974) Afferents to the hippocampus of the rat as 
    studied with the method of retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Brain Res. 78:l-15.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Sethy, V.H., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Kuhar, R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Roth, M.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Van Woert. and G.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Aghajanian (1973) Cholinergic neurons: Effect of acute 
    septal lesions on acetylcholine and choline content of rat 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Brain Res. 55:481-484.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Shute, C.C.D., and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Lewis (1967) The ascending cholinergic reticular 
    systems: Newortical, olfactory and subcortical projections.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Brain 90:497521.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Siege], A,, and J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Tassoni (1971) Differential efferent lateral and medial 
    septal nuclei to the hippocampus Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Evol. 4:201-219.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Srebro.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">B..</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Harkmark, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Kohler (19791 Afferent and efferent projections of the 
    entorhinal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Suppl. 3:143 (abstract).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Srebro, B., S.I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Mellgren, and W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Harkmark (1975) Distribution of acetylcholinesterase in 
    the septal region of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">In.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">De France (ed): First International Symposium on Septal 
    Nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Detroit: Wayne State University Press.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Steward, 0. (1976) Topographic organization of the 
    projections entorhinal area to the hippocampal formation of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Neural. 167:285-314.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Steward, O., and S.A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Scoville (19761 Cells of origin of entorhinal cortical 
    afferents to the hippocampus and fascia dentata of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Neurol. 169r347-370.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">S..anson, L.W.. and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Cowan (1977) An autoradiogaphic study of the 
    organization of the efferent connections at&apos; the hippiicainpal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Neural. 17249-84.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Van der Kooy.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">D., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Hattori (1980) Dorsal raphe cells with collateral 
    projections to the caudate-putamen and substantia nigra: A 
    fluorescent retrograde double-labeling study in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Brain Res. 186:l-7.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Vincent.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">S.R., H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Kimura. and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">McGeer (19811 Organization of substance P fibers within 
    the hippocampal fbrmation demonstrated with a biotin-avidin 
    immunoperoxidase techniquv.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Neurol. 199:133143.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Vincent, S.R.. and E.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">McGeer (1982, A hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Brain Res. 215,349-351.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Walaas, I. (1981) Biochemical evidence for overlapping 
    neocortical and allocortical glutamate projections to the nucleus 
    accumbens and rostra1 caudatoputamen in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Neuroscience 6:399-407.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Wyss.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">J.M., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Swanson, and M.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Cowan (1979) A study of subcortical afferents to the 
    hippocampal formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Neuroscience 4r463477.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Wyss, J.M. 119811 An autoradiographic study of the 
    efferent connections the entorhinal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Neural. 199:495-512.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Zaczek, R., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Hedreen, and J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Coyle (1979) Evidence for a hippocampalseptal 
    glutamatergic pathway in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Neural. 65r145-156.</S>
  </References>

</File>

