<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Representation of the Cecum in the Lateral Dorsal Motor 
  Nucleus of the Vagus Nerve and Commissural Subnucleus of the Nucleus 
  Tractus Solitarii in Rat</Title>

  <Authors>STEVEN M. ALTSCHULER, DAVID A. FERENCI, RICHARD B. 
  LYNN,</Authors>

  <Authors>AND RICHARD R. MISELIS</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Motor fibers of the accessory celiac and celiac vagal 
    branches are derived from the lateral columns of the dorsal motor 
    nucleus of the vagus nerve.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">These branches also contain sensory fibers that terminate 
    within the nucleus of the tractus solitarii.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">This study traces the innervation of the intestines by 
    using the tracer cholera toxin-horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">In 53 rats, the tracer was injected into either the 
    stomach, duodenum, jejunum, terminal ileum, cecum, or ascending 
    colon.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">With all cecal injections, prominent retrograde labeling 
    of cell bodies occurred bilaterally in the lateral columns of the 
    dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus nerve above, at, and below the 
    level of the area postrema.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Dendrites of laterally positioned neurons projected 
    medially and rostrocaudally within the dorsal motor nucleus of the 
    vagus nerve and dorsomedially into both the medial subnucleus and 
    parts of the commissural subnucleus of the nucleus of the tractus 
    solitarii.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Sensory terminal labeling occurred in the dorsolateral 
    commissural subnucleus at the level of the rostral area postrema 
    and the medial commissural subnucleus caudal to the area 
    postrema.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Additionally, there was sensory terminal labeling within a 
    small confined area of the dorsomedial zone of the nucleus of the 
    tractus solitarii immediately adjacent to the fourth ventricle at a 
    level just anterior to the area postrema.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Stomach injections labeled motoneurons of the medial 
    column of the entire rostrocaudal extent of the dorsal motor 
    nucleus of the vagus nerve and a sensory terminal field primarily 
    in the subnucleus gelatinosus, with less intense labeling extending 
    caudally into the medial and ventral commissural subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Dendrites of gastric motoneurons project rostrocaudally 
    and mediolaterally within the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus 
    nerve and dorsolaterally within the nucleus of the tractus 
    solitarii.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">They are most pronounced at the level of the rostral area 
    postrema where many dendrites course dorsolaterally terminating 
    primarily within the subnucleus gelatinosus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Injections of the duodenum labeled a small number of the 
    cells within the medial aspects of the dorsal motor nucleus of the 
    vagus nerve.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Jejunal, ileal, and ascending colon injections labeled 
    cells sparsely within the lateral aspects of the dorsal motor 
    nucleus of the vagus nerve bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">No afferent terminal labeling was evident after injection 
    of these areas of the bowel.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The dorsal vagal complex has a prominent 
    viscerotopography: the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus nerve has 
    a mediolateral organization corresponding to end-organ innervation; 
    the nucleus of the tractus solitarii has a rostrocaudal axis of 
    visceral representation with some overlap corresponding to 
    rostrocaudal positioning along the alimentary canal and 
    mediolateral separation of terminals within the nucleus.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Progress in topographical studies of visceral innervation 
    has accelerated with the introduction of new tracers and injection 
    strategies to control them.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Where there have been ambiguities concerning viscerotopic 
    representation in the vagal complex (Kalia and Mesulam, 
    &apos;80a,b; Hinrichsen and Ryan, &apos;81; Kalia, &apos;81; 
    Yoshida et a]., &apos;81; Rogers and Hermann, &apos;83; Holstege et 
    al., &apos;83; Fryscaket al., &apos;841, there is now more 
    certainty of its existence (Gwyn et al., &apos;79; Katz and Karten, 
    &apos;83; Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; Bieger and Hopkins, 
    &apos;87; Rinaman and Miselis, &apos;87; Pagani et al., &apos;88; 
    Altschuler et al., &apos;89; Okumura and Namiki, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">With direct intramuscular injection of the tracers 
    (particularly ones with receptor binding properties) or their 
    application to cut nerves, a strong viscerotopic organization for 
    the upper alimentary tract has been established within the NA and 
    NTS of the rat (Bieger and Hopkins, &apos;87; Altschuler et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">In contrast to the viscerotopic organization proposed or 
    the NA (Lawn, &apos;66a,b; Bieger and Hopkins, &apos;87), the DMN 
    is organized mediolaterally with respect to specific branches of 
    the subdiaphragmatic vagus (Fox and Powley, &apos;85; Norgren and 
    Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">This scheme, which parcels the DMN into a series of 
    longitudinal columns running the entire rostrocaudal extent of the 
    nucleus, has been primarily derived from the application of tracer 
    to the major branches of the subdiaphragmatic vagus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Each DMN is comprised of a large medial column of cells 
    lying immediately adjacent to the midline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">These columns of cells provide efferent axons to the two 
    gastric branches.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">In the lateral aspects of each DMN, a column of cells of 
    much smaller mediolateral extent exists and contributes fibers to 
    the celiac and accessory celiac branches of the subdiaphragmatic 
    vagus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Within the left medial DMN, an additional column exists 
    composed of a few scattered cells providing axons to the hepatic 
    branch.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The formation of the rat DMN into longitudinal cell 
    columns raises the issue of how the innervation of specific 
    abdominal viscera is organized within these columns.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">This question is best answered by direct intramuscular 
    injection of tracer into the viscera under study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">To date, the majority of studies utilizing this technique 
    have focused on the stomach and pancreas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Although a number of investigations have suggested that 
    these structures are represented throughout the entire DMN (Weaver, 
    &apos;80; Takayama et al., Key words: intestines, celiac branch of 
    vagus, cholera toxin-horseradish peroxidase, viscerotopy &apos;82; 
    Leslie et al., &apos;82; Sharkey and Williams, &apos;83; Luiten et 
    al., &apos;84), two recent studies employing HRP conjugates, in 
    which adequate measures to prevent spread and leakage of tracer 
    were performed, have demonstrated a far more localized retrograde 
    labeling of cell bodies primarily within the medial columns of the 
    DMN (Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; Rinaman and Miselis, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">These findings suggest that specific abdominal viscera 
    are localized to either the medial or lateral bilaterally 
    symmetrical columns.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">We performed a series of intramuscular injections with 
    CT-HRP in different regions of the small and large bowel in order 
    to determine the viscera represented in the lateral columns of the 
    DMN.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Preliminary studies revealed that extremely small numbers 
    of cells were retrogradely labeled within the DMN following 
    injection of CT-HRP into most regions of the bowel.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The major exception to this observation was the cecum, 
    where injections of CT-HRP resulted in consistent retrograde 
    labeling of cell bodies within the lateral columns of the DMN 
    (Ferenci et al., &apos;89a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">On the basis of our preliminary results, the majority of 
    injections in this study involved the cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Additionally, since CTHRP is very effective in labeling 
    distal dendritic processes, a comparison of the dendritic fields of 
    medial and lateral column motoneurons was undertaken.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The distributions of labeled perikarya within the vagal 
    ganglia and afferent terminal fields within the NTS were also 
    investigated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">We were most interested in relating their distributions 
    to previously obtained viscerotopic mappings of the vagal ganglia 
    and NTS following injection of tracer into the upper alimentary 
    tract (Altschuler et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">In our experience, CT-HRP is more effective than free HRP 
    and equally effective as the wheat germ agglutinin-HRP conjugate in 
    labeling afferent terminal fields (Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; 
    Altschuler et al., &apos;89).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s38">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Fifty-three adult male Sprague-Dawley rats weighing 
    210-510 g were employed in these experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">The animals were anesthetized with ketamine (85 mgikg) 
    and xylazine (12 mg/kg) prior to aseptic surgical procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">CT-HRP, conjugated in our laboratory by a modification of 
    a previously described method (Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85a), was 
    utilized as the neural tracer in these studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Briefly, CT (supplied by Sigma or List Biological) was 
    covalently attached to HRP (Sigma type VI) to make CT-HRP by using 
    glutaraldehyde as a homobifunctional bridge molecule in a two-step 
    process (Avrameas and Ternynck, &apos;71; Gonatas et al., 
    &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">HRP (153 mg) was incubated with glutaraldehyde [EM grade; 
    200 pl of a 25% solution in 1,800 p1 of potassium phosphate buffer 
    (pH 6.8)] for 4 hours at 1:lOO molar concentration ratio to 
    activate the molecule (Molin et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">By utilizing gel filtration chromatography (LKB Ultrogel 
    AcA44, 1.6 cm x 90 cm; eluent 0.15 M NACl), monomeric HRP that 
    contains both unreacted and activated HRP was separated from the 
    polymeric byproducts of the activation reaction.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Fractions containing 40 kd product were pooled and 
    concentrated to approximately 1 ml (Amicon CF25 concentrating cone) 
    and reacted with CT (4 mg) in 0.1 M carbonate buffer (pH 9.5) for 
    40 hours at 4°C (molar ratio of HRP to CT was 80:l).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Lysine (1 M) was added to the reaction for 6 to 8 hours 
    at 4°C to terminate the reaction and the CT-HRP conjugate was then 
    purified by a second gel filtration.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Large molecular weight fractions (84-150 kd) containing 
    the conjugate were pooled and concentrated to a volume of 1.5-2.5 
    ml using Amicon CF50 concentrating cones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The final protein concentration of the conjugate was 
    adjusted to 0.22-0.44% using phosphate buffered saline as 
    determined by Lowry or Bradford assays (Lowry et al., &apos;51; 
    Bradford, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">This concentration range is very dilute compared to the 
    concentration of tracer used by others.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">After abdominal laparotomy and packing the abdomen with 
    dry gauze (precautions to capture leaking tracer), the organ to be 
    injected was exteriorized and placed on a dry gauze and parafilm 
    bed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Most injections involved the cecum (n = 30), as this 
    portion of both the small and large bowel yielded the most 
    consistent retrograde and anterograde labeling in the dorsal vagal 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Additional injections were made in other regions of the 
    intestine including the duodenum (n = 6), jejunum (n = 31, terminal 
    ileum (n = 4), and ascending colon (n = 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Six animals received injection of CT-HRP into the stomach 
    and served as controls.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The tracer was applied through the serosal surface of the 
    bowel wall in 0.5-3 ~1 aliquots at multiple sites via a glass 
    micropipette affxed with sealing wax to a Hamilton syringe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">It should be noted that these injection volumes did not 
    remain within the viscus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">They leaked back out the injection tract when the pipette 
    was withdrawn.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The great majority of the volume leakage occurred within 
    the first 1 to 2 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">In light of this problem, it is difficult to know the 
    amount of tracer that remained and actually contributed to the 
    injection site.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Therefore, the volumes we report below (the actual 
    volumes leaving the syringe) are an overestimation of the amount in 
    the injection site.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The large volumes of dilute tracer utilized, however, 
    were necessary to inject the appropriate viscus at multiple sites 
    in a reasonable amount of time.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">It is also obvious that precautions must be taken to 
    collect the leakage (Fox and Powley, &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Spread was controlled by exteriorizing and isolating the 
    viscus from adjacent structures with gauze and by blotting and 
    mopping up each injection site with cotton swabs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The injected viscus was exteriorized for periods up to 45 
    minutes postinjection and rinsed frequently in order to dilute any 
    tracer that leaked from the injection site and prevent drying.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">After replacing the viscus, the peritoneal cavity was 
    flooded with sterile isotonic saline to dilute the tracer 
    concentration further to levels inadequate for binding.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">The initial low protein concentration of the CT-HRP made 
    this possible.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The saline was then aspirated and this was repeated two 
    more times.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The adequacy of our measures to control spread of the 
    tracer was documented in five animals in which the cecum was 
    injected.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Sections and en bloc segments of small intestines 
    (terminal ileum and jejunum) and ascending colon removed from these 
    animals during histological processing did not show evidence of HRP 
    reaction product following their incubation with TMB.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Ventral cecal injections were defined as on the surface 
    of the cecum most frequently seen immediately upon opening the 
    abdomen of a rat in dorsal recumbency with the head in a superior 
    position.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">In general, under these conditions, the ascending colon 
    is to the viewer&apos;s left, the ileum is to the viewer&apos;s 
    right, and the convex surface of the cecum is toward the viewer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Dorsal cecal injections were made on the opposite 
    surface.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Total cecal injections included both ventral and dorsal 
    surfaces with the volumes of tracer from 70 to 105 pl (note 
    qualification above).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Lateral injections of the cecum were performed over both 
    ventral and dorsal surfaces of the half of the cecum that included 
    the appendix using volumes of tracer up to 80 p1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Medial injections were made over the opposite half of the 
    cecum toward the colon and utilized similar tracer volumes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Proximal duodenal injections were made beginning 0.5 cm 
    distal to the pylorus over a 2 cm segment using volumes up to 45 
    p1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Distal duodenal injections began between 4 and 7 cm 
    distal to the pylorus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">Jejunal injections were made in the area 34-62 cm 
    proximal to the ileocecal junctions over a segment of 2 cm using 
    volumes up to 80 p1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Terminal ileal injections were just proximal to the 
    ileocecal junctions with volumes up to 30 pl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Ascending colonic injections were made over a 0.5 cm 
    segment just distal to the cecocolonic junction using volumes up to 
    40 p1.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">In the stomach cases, the entire dorsal and ventral 
    surfaces of all regions (forestomach, corpus, and antruml pylorus) 
    were injected with volumes of tracer ranging up to 80 p1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Methods to control spread were similar to those employed 
    with the bowel injections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">After survival periods of 3-6 (usually 3) days, the rats 
    were perfused according to the protocol of Mesulam (&apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Frozen serial 40 p,m sections of the brainstem and spinal 
    cord were made in either the transverse, sagittal, or horizontal 
    planes and the tissue was then processed for HRP according to the 
    TMB protocol of Mesulam (&apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">All histological material was studied with both brightand 
    polarized darkfield microscopy and selected sections were 
    counterstained with neutral red.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Sections were photographed with an Olympus BH-2 
    photomicroscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The analysis of data includes estimates of the number of 
    retrogradely labeled cells in different parts of the DMN made from 
    counts of transverse sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">It should be emphasized that the counts reported 
    represent estimates because of the inherent problems of counting 
    HRP labeled cells in thick sections through the DMN (Norgren and 
    Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">The intensity of labeling of individual cells was of 
    sufficient magnitude to obscure the presence of the nucleus and 
    nucleolus, thus negating their use in estimating the number of 
    labeled cells (Abercrombie, &apos;46; Gundersen, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">The most reliable particle (Gundersen, &apos;86) for 
    counting was the discrete profile (Fox and Powley, &apos;85) of a 
    CT-HRP labeled cell apparent under brightfield illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">Utilizing this technique, we were able to distinguish 
    basal dendrites and fragments of cells, which were excluded from 
    the counts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">The size of DMN neuron limited its appearance to at most 
    two serial sections when tissue was serially cut into 40 +m 
    sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">Therefore, in order to minimize the double counting of 
    cells (fractionator procedure; Gundersen, &apos;86), every other 
    section was examined and the labeled cells counted.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">The obex was defined as the opening of the central canal 
    into the fourth ventricle (generally located approximately 250 pm 
    behind the rostral edge of the AP), and this landmark was used to 
    calculate the rostral and caudal extent of neuronal labeling 
    following injection of tracer into the cecum and stomach.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Data from a group of animals are always expressed as the 
    mean +SEM.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">Statistical analyses were performed by using the 
    independent t test (Croxton and Cowen, &apos;39).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">In selected animals, en bloc incubations for HRP 
    histochemistry of the sensory ganglia of the IXth and Xth nerves 
    (Altschuler et al., &apos;89) were also performed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">Labeled cells were counted from whole mounts of the 
    ganglia and plotted through a camera lucida tube attached to the 
    Olympus BH-2 microscope to aid in the construction of viscerotopic 
    mapping of the sensory ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">The distribution of labeled perikarya was evaluated in 
    ten ganglia from six cases in which the entire cecum was injected 
    and four ganglia from two stomach cases.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s99">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s100">DMN labeling</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">injections of <tracerChemical>ct - hrp</tracerChemical> 
    into <injectionLocation>different regions of the small and large 
    bowel</injectionLocation> resulted in central neuronal labeling 
    restricted to <labelingLocation>the dmn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">The labeling of <labelingLocation>DMN</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> following 
    injections of <injectionLocation>all regions of the 
    bowel</injectionLocation> except <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the 
    cecum</injectionSpread> was <labelingDescription>quite 
    sparse</labelingDescription> with a maximum of 32 labeled neurons 
    seen in any one of these cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">in contrast with all injections of 
    <injectionLocation>the cecum</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>a consistent pattern of neuronal labeling of 
    far greater number</labelingDescription> was observed .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">central neuronal labeling was virtually confined to 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral aspects of the dmn 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> following all total 
    <injectionLocation>cecal</injectionLocation> injections ( figs . 1 
    - 3 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">although many labeled dendrites were visible within 
    <labelingLocation>the medial aspects of the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> bilaterally this area conspicuously 
    <labelingModifier>lacked labeled neurons</labelingModifier> except 
    in <labelingLocation>the most anterior aspects of the dmn 
    where</labelingLocation> there was <labelingDescription>a sparse 
    distribution of labeled cells</labelingDescription> ( figs . 2 , 3 
    ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106"><labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were observed extending from 
    approximately 2 , 000 pm caudal to the obex ( defined as opening of 
    the cc ) to approximately 900 pm rostral to the obex .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">However, they were most numerous at the level of the 
    obex (560 pm below to 640 pm above).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108"><injectionLocation>medial and lateral injections of the 
    cecum</injectionLocation> <labelingDescription>showed less dense 
    neuronal labeling</labelingDescription> in the same distribution as 
    <injectionLocation>total cecal injections</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109"><injectionLocation>ventral and dorsal surface injections 
    of the cecum</injectionLocation> showed no difference in the 
    density of neuronal labeling between <labelingLocation>the right 
    and left sides of the dmn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">following injections of <injectionLocation>the 
    stomach</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were <labelingDescription>densely 
    packed</labelingDescription> medially , occupied 
    <labelingLocation>a much greater rostrocaudal and mediolateral 
    extent of the dmn bilaterally</labelingLocation> than observed 
    after cecal injections , and rarely extended into 
    <labelingModifier>the most lateral portions of the 
    nucleus</labelingModifier> ( figs . 3 , 4 , and table 1 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">although the cecum had by far the greatest 
    representation in <labelingLocation>the dmn</labelingLocation> of 
    any area of the bowel , it was of much less magnitude in comparison 
    to the stomach ( see table 1 for cell counts ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">injections of <injectionLocation>the proximal and distal 
    portions of duodenum</injectionLocation> labeled 
    <labelingDescription>a small number of cells</labelingDescription> 
    within <labelingLocation>the medial aspects of the 
    dmn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113"><injectionLocation>jejunal , ileal , and ascending 
    colon</injectionLocation> injections labeled 
    <labelingDescription>cells sparsely</labelingDescription> within 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral column of the dmn 
    bilaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s114">Dendritic 
    architecture</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115"><labelingDescription>prominent dendritic 
    labeling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    confines of the dmn</labelingLocation> was present following total 
    injection of <injectionLocation>the cecum</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116"><labelingDescription>a portion of the dendritic 
    arborization projected medially</labelingDescription> at all 
    rostrocaudal levels into <labelingLocation>the medial aspects of 
    the dmn</labelingLocation> where labeled motoneurons were observed 
    following injection of tracer into <injectionLocation>the stomach 
    and duodenum</injectionLocation> ( figs . 2 - 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117"><labelingDescription>a few 
    dendrites</labelingDescription> appear to cross the midline to 
    <labelingLocation>the opposite dmn</labelingLocation> ( see fig . 3 
    for example ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">within <injectionLocation>the confines of the lateral 
    dmn</injectionLocation> , there is an extensive arborization of 
    dendritic processes projecting rostrocaudally ( fig . 3a ) in a 
    pattern with striking similarities to that seen in <labelingLocation
    >the medial aspects of dmn</labelingLocation> following 
    <injectionLocation>stomach</injectionLocation> injections ( fig . 
    3b ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">For the lateral column, the rostrocaudal dendrites far 
    outnumber those projecting medially and dorsally.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">The extranuclear <labelingDescription>dendritic 
    processes</labelingDescription> of cecal motoneuions were more 
    limited than those of stomach motoneurons (Figs. 2, 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">they projected dorsomedially into <labelingLocation>the 
    nts</labelingLocation> , terminating within <labelingLocation>the 
    medial ( med nts ) and commissural subnuclei ( com nts 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">Their orientation was almost perpendicular to the 
    extranuclear dendrites of stomach motoneurons, which exited the DMN 
    in a dorsolateral direction.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">Rostral to the AP, cecal motoneurons lacked significant 
    extranuclear dendrites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">the dendrites of gastric motoneurons terminated within 
    different areas of the nts , occupying areas where there was 
    <labelingDescription>a lack of dendrites of cecal motoneurons and 
    cecal afferent terminal labeling</labelingDescription> ( fig . 4 ) 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s125">nts terminal labeling</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126"><labelingDescription>afferent terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed within <labelingLocation
    >the nts</labelingLocation> in ten animals in which 
    <tracerChemical>ct - hrp</tracerChemical> was injected throughout 
    <injectionLocation>the entire cecum</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127"><labelingDescription>no afferent terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was visualized following injection 
    of the tracer into <injectionLocation>the other areas of the 
    bowel</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">although <labelingDescription>the density of afferent 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> varied between cases , the 
    extent and distribution of labeling was quite consistent ( compare 
    figs . 2 and 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">anterior to ap , <labelingDescription>light afferent 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> was bilaterally localized 
    to <labelingLocation>the periventricular portion of the nts in an 
    area just medial and dorsal to the gel nts</labelingLocation> ( 
    figs . 2a , 4a ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130"><labelingDescription>heavier 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was evident caudally within 
    <labelingLocation>the com nts</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">This labeling extended caudally to a level approximately 
    500 +m caudal to the obex where it rapidly disappeared.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">at the level of the anterior ap , afferent labeling was 
    concentrated dorsolaterally within <labelingLocation>the com 
    nts</labelingLocation> occupying an area immediately subjacent to 
    the ap .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">(Figs. 2, 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><labelingDescription>very light afferent 
    labeling</labelingDescription> extended into <labelingLocation>
    adjacent areas of the med nts</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">in case in66 where the density of 
    <labelingDescription>terminal labeling was the 
    heaviest</labelingDescription> of the cases surveyed , 
    <labelingDescription>light terminal labeling</labelingDescription> 
    extended into <labelingLocation>the marginal aspects of the 
    ap</labelingLocation> however , there was no spread to stomach 
    afferent terminal fields ( fig . 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">toward the caudal aspects of the ap and extending 
    caudally beyond it , <labelingDescription>afferent 
    terminals</labelingDescription> tended to occupy a more localized 
    area within <labelingLocation>the com nts</labelingLocation> close 
    to the midline but dorsal to sites penetrated by gastric motoneuron 
    dendrites ( figs . 2 , 4 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">injection of <injectionLocation>the 
    stomach</injectionLocation> with <tracerChemical>ct - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> resulted in <labelingDescription>heavy 
    afferent terminal labeling</labelingDescription> within 
    <labelingLocation>the gel nts</labelingLocation> and 
    <labelingDescription>lighter labeling</labelingDescription> within 
    <labelingLocation>the medial subnucleus and midline com 
    nts</labelingLocation> at the level of the ap ( fig . 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><connxTermination>gastric</connxTermination> afferents , 
    however , did not extend as far caudally in the midline 
    <connxOrigin>com nts</connxOrigin> as those from <connxOrigin>the 
    cecum</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s139">Vagal ganglia 
    labeling</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">after injection of <tracerChemical>ct - 
    hrp</tracerChemical> into either <injectionLocation>the cecum or 
    stomach</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>perikaryal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was limited to 
    <labelingLocation>nodose ganglia</labelingLocation> ( fig . 5 ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Within this inferior portion of the fused ganglionic 
    mass, the location of labeled perikarya was quite similar following 
    injection of <injectionLocation>the stomach and 
    cecum</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">However,<labelingDescription> the density of labeling 
    was far greater</labelingDescription> following injections of 
    <injectionLocation>the stomach</injectionLocation> (118 2 10 cells 
    vs. 50 2 6 cells, P &amp;lt; 0.05).</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s143">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">The present results indicate that the rat small and 
    large intestines receive limited parasympathetic innervation from 
    the DMN with the cecum representing a major exception.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Together the stomach and the cecum appear to receive the 
    vast majority of efferent projections from the DMN to the 
    alimentary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">Although previous studies have shown a strong 
    representation for the stomach within the DMN (Yamamoto et al., 
    &apos;77; Leslie et al., &apos;82; Scharoun et al., &apos;84; 
    Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; Pagani et al., &apos;88; Okumura 
    and Namiki, &apos;go), this study provides the first evidence for a 
    significant topographically distinct representation for the cecum 
    within the DMN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s147">DMN-motor neuronal 
    columns</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Motoneurons projecting to the cecum were found to occupy 
    an area within the lateral aspects of the DMN bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">Labeled cells were most numerous and densely packed 
    within the caudal DMN forming a coherent column between the level 
    just caudal to the obex and rostral to the AP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">These columns were situated laterally, with little 
    overlap, to the more medial column of labeled DMN cells found 
    following injection of the stomach (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">The separation of gastric and cecal representation by 
    columns in the DMN is not surprising considering previous 
    observations in the spinal cord, NA, and hypoglossal nucleus that 
    motoneurons innervating a specific muscle tend to group in a single 
    longitudinal column (Sterling and Kuypers, &apos;67; Odutola, 
    &apos;76; Burke et al., &apos;77; Krammer et al., &apos;79; 
    Kuzahara and Chou, &apos;80; Miyazaki et al., &apos;81; Goshgarian 
    and Rafols, &apos;81; Bieger and Hopkins, &apos;87; Furicchia and 
    Goshgarian, &apos;87; Anderson et al., &apos;88; Bao et al., 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">The cecum appears to be specifically innervated by the 
    celiac and accessory celiac branches of the subdiaphragmatic vagus 
    since these branches carry axons from motoneurons of the lateral 
    columns on the DMN (Fox and Powley, &apos;85; Norgren and Smith, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">The rostrocaudal distribution of retrograde labeling 
    within the DMN found following injection of the cecum in the 
    present study closely matches that obtained previously after 
    incubation of the celiac and accessory celiac branches of the 
    subdiaphragmatic vagus with true blue or free HRP (Fox and Powley, 
    &apos;85; Norgren and Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">Additionally, cecal afferents terminate within the NTS 
    in a pattern with striking similarities to that found following 
    incubation of the celiac and accessory celiac branches with HRP 
    (Norgren and Smith, &apos;88) (see below for details).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">The virtual lack of labeled cells within the medial 
    columns of the DMN and terminal labeling within the gel NTS 
    (gastric afferent terminal area) following injection of the cecum 
    indicates that vagal innervation of the cecum is limited to these 
    two branches of the subdiaphragmatic vagus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">In contrast, the distribution of labeled DMN cells and 
    pattern of terminal labeling seen following injection of the 
    stomach conforms to the pattern of labeling observed previously 
    with incubation of the two gastric branches of the subdiaphragmatic 
    vagus with tracer (Fox and Powley, &apos;85; Norgren and Smith, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s157">The present results support a mediolateral organization 
    within the DMN corresponding to the rostrocaudal positioning along 
    the alimentary canal (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s158">DMN cells projecting to the stomach and duodenum were 
    limited to the medial columns, while those projecting to the 
    jejunum, ileum, and ascending colon were located within the lateral 
    columns.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s159">A similar mediolateral distribution of labeled cells 
    within the DMN following injection of free HRP into different 
    regions of the bowel has been previously reported in the cat 
    (Satomi et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s160">This distribution of DMN labeling suggests the duodenum 
    receives innervation from either the gastric or hepatic branches 
    while the more distal area of the small intestine and proximal 
    large bowel are Soft palate</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s161">......</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s162">:A: Esophagus ::&amp;lt; Stomach</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="36" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s163">[il Cecum</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">innervated by the celiac and accessory celiac branches 
    of the subdiaphragmatic vagus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Additional studies are needed to determine precisely the 
    most distal extent of vagal innervation of the large bowel, 
    although the study of Satomi et al. (&apos;78) in the cat suggests 
    that there is limited vagal efferent innervation originating in the 
    lateral DMN that extends to the rectum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Our findings are corroborated by recent 
    electrophysiological studies in the rat (Carlson et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">In addition to the stomach and duodenum, the pancreas 
    and liver appear to be preferentially innervated by motoneurons 
    located in the medial columns of the DMN (Magni and Carobi, 
    &apos;83; Fox and Powley, &apos;85; Rinaman and Miselis, &apos;87; 
    Norgren and Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Within the medial column, there is no data to suggest 
    that multiple hollow and nonhollow viscera occupy discrete 
    nonoverlapping areas (Magni and Carobi, &apos;83; Fox and Powley, 
    &apos;85; Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; Rinaman and Miselis, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">However, for the stomach, preliminary evidence is 
    accumulating in the rat and cat that a more precise viscerotopic 
    organization exists within the medial column such that the 
    antrum/pylorus is represented most medially, the fundus most 
    laterally, and the body diffusely through mediolateral extent of 
    the column (Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; McConnie et al., 
    &apos;88; Pagani et al., &apos;88; Okumura and Namiki, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s170">DMN-dendritic 
    organization</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">The use of CT-HRP as a retrograde neuroanatomical tracer 
    provided the first evidence that DMN neurons projecting to the 
    stomach and pancreas have extensive dendritic arborizations within 
    the DMN and NTS (Shapiro and Miselis, &apos;85b; Rinaman and 
    Miselis, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">For cecal projecting DMN neurons, we have similarly 
    demonstrated dendritic projections coursing through the DMN and 
    projecting into the overlying NTS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">Our results also indicate that unique fields of 
    dendritic projections within the NTS exist for neurons located 
    within medial and lateral columns of the DMN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">Within the DMN, we found that most dendrites of cecal 
    motoneurons appear to run rostrocaudally within the confines of the 
    lateral columns (Fig. 3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">A similar pattern of dendritic arborizations was found 
    for gastric motoneurons within the medial columns of the DMN, 
    confirming earlier studies of Shapiro and Miselis (&apos;85b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">This arrangement of motoneuron dendrites appears to 
    allow for coordination of efferent activity throughout the extent 
    of the cell column as it is a common feature of many motoneuronal 
    columns involved in the generation of patterned behaviors located 
    in the spinal cord and medulla (Goshgarian and Rafols, &apos;81; 
    Bieger and Hopkins, &apos;87; Furicchia and Goshgarian, &apos;87; 
    Anderson et al., &apos;88; Bao et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Within the confines of the DMN, where vagal 
    afferent-dendritic contacts are limited (Kalia, &apos;81; Neuhuber 
    and Sandoz, &apos;86; Rinaman et al., &apos;89), this anatomical 
    arrangement of dendrites would facilitate the effects of restricted 
    vagal afferent inputs over the entire rostral caudal extent of the 
    column through potential dendro-dendritic interactions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">The potential for interactions between motoneurons of 
    the lateral and medial columns also exists.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">At all rostrocaudal levels, dendrites of cecal 
    motoneurons project into the medial column of DMN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s180">NTS-codistribution of 
    DMN dendrites and vagal sensory afferents</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">From their origin within the lateral columns of the DMN, 
    a portion of the dendrites of cecal motoneurons always penetrated 
    the NTS selectively in a dorsomedial direction primarily 
    terminating in areas that also receive innervation by cecal 
    afferents (med NTS and dorsolateral and midline portion of the com 
    NTS).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The AP and an area of the NTS just medial to the gel 
    NTS, designated as the periventricular NTS (Kalia et al., 
    &apos;84), were the only sites where cecal afferents terminated 
    that lacked innervation by the dendritic processes of cecal 
    motoneurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Codistribution of afferent terminals and dendritic 
    processes of DMN neurons within the NTS was also apparent following 
    injection of tracer into the stomach, confirming earlier studies by 
    Shapiro and Miselis (&apos;85b) and Rinaman et al. (&apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Our results suggest that NTS and DMN are organized to 
    allow for an organ-specific monosynaptic interaction of vagal 
    afferents and dendrites of DMN neurons in the NTS for the stomach 
    and perhaps the cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">At the ultrastructural level, synaptic contacts between 
    labeled dendritic processes and sensory aferents have been 
    demonstrated in the gel NTS following application of CT-HRP to 
    cervical vagus or its injection into the stomach (Rinaman et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Further support for the concept of organ-specific 
    interaction is provided by our findings that dendrites of gastric 
    and cecal projecting motoneurons tend not to permeate, but actually 
    encircle or avoid, the afferent terminal fields of the other 
    respective organs.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s187">NTS-organ injection vs. 
    vagal nerve branch injections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">The establishment of cecal innervation by the celiac and 
    accessory celiac branches and stomach innervation by the gastric 
    branches of the subdiaphragmatic vagus, based on the patterns of 
    DMN labeling, provides a basis to compare the distributions of 
    afferent terminal labeling following direct organ injection with 
    application of tracer to the nerve innervating that organ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">A major observation in this regard is that the 
    distribution of afferent terminal labeling within the NTS, 
    following injection of tracer into the cecum, closely resembles the 
    sum of the distributions of labeling generated following the 
    incubation of the celiac and accessory celiac branches of the 
    subdiaphragmatic vagus with HRP (Norgren and Smith, &apos;88) 
    [compare Fig. 4 of this study with Figs. 6 and 7 of Norgren and 
    Smith (&apos;88)l.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Cecal afferents were found to terminate principally 
    within areas of the NTS that show no terminal labeling after 
    application of HRP to the gastric branches of the subdiaphragmatic 
    vagus or the injection of tracer into the stomach (Shapiro and 
    Miselis, &apos;85b; Norgren and Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">The distributions of afferent terminals following 
    injection of the stomach and cecum appear to summate to match the 
    distribution of terminal labeling found after incubation of the 
    subdiaphragmatic vagus in much the same way as the gastric and 
    celiac and accessory branches do (Norgren and Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s192">NTS and nodose ganglion 
    viscerotopy</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">With regard to the viscerotopic organization of the NTS, 
    the results of the present study confirm our previous observations 
    that alimentary tract aferents are primarily topographically 
    organized in distinct subnuclei, with only minimal overlap 
    (Altschuler et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">At the level of the AP where afferent terminals of the 
    pharynx, esophagus, stomach, and cecum are found (Altschuler et 
    al., &apos;89; present data), a mediolateral organ-specific 
    segregation within the is NTS, cen NTS, gel NTS, and com NTS is 
    quite prominent (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">An additional organizational feature of the NTS apparent 
    from studies utilizing organ-specific injections (Altschuler et 
    al., &apos;89; present data) is that a rostrocaudal axis of 
    visceral representation corresponding to rostrocaudal positioning 
    along the alimentary canal extends from the palate to the cecum 
    (Fig. 6).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Sensory neurons, located within the ganglia of the IXth 
    and Xth nerve and projecting to the upper alimentary tract, have 
    been previously shown to segregate according to their rostrocaudal 
    positioning within the alimentary tract; those projecting to the 
    palate and pharynx were primarily found in the superior portion of 
    the fused ganglionic mass, while those projecting to the esophagus 
    and stomach were limited to the inferior portion or nodose ganglion 
    (Altschuler et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Our results would lend further support to the concept of 
    a crude viscerotopic organization within the ganglionic mass.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">The distributions of labeled cells following injection 
    of cecum and the stomach were indistinguishable and limited to the 
    nodose ganglion.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Incubation of the major branches of the subdiaphragmatic 
    vagus with HRP has similarly resulted in labeling of cell bodies 
    limited to the nodose ganglion (Norgren and Smith, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Within the nodose ganglion there appear to be discrete 
    populations of substance P, calcitonin gene-related peptide, and 
    peptide histidine methionine containing neurons that project to the 
    cecum (Chery-Croze et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The presence of substance P immunoreactive nerve 
    terminal and preterminal processes within com NTS (cecal afferent 
    terminal field) has also been documented (Kalia et al., &apos;841, 
    suggesting that this neuropeptide is transported centrally within 
    the axons of cecal sensory neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s202">Central vs. peripheral 
    control in the GI system</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">If one utilizes the number of retrogradely labeled cells 
    and density of afferent terminal labeling as a basis of comparison, 
    our results indicate that the small bowel and ascending colon 
    receive a far more limited vagal innervation than the cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">This result may reflect the relative densities of the 
    central and enteric neural elements present in different areas of 
    the bowel.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">For vagal sensory afferents it may also reflect the 
    density of terminal processes within the different layers of the 
    bowel.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Presumably our techniques of injections would favor the 
    labeling of sensory afferents that terminate within the muscular 
    layers of the bowel.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Studies by Christensen et al. (&apos;83) with a silver 
    impregnation method in the American opossum have demonstrated that 
    the density of nerve cell bodies within the myenteric plexus is 
    quite variable along the length of the bowel.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Indeed, a major finding of their study was that the 
    number of perikarya in the myenteric plexus of the cecum is 
    approximately half that in the rest of the small bowel and proximal 
    colon (Christensen et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">This study confirms earlier, less comprehensive 
    investigations utilizing methylene and toluidine blue preparations 
    in the guinea pig (Matsuo, &apos;34; Tafuri, &apos;571, rabbit 
    (Maslennikova, &apos;62), and monkey (Ohkubo, &apos;36) 
    demonstrating that the least densely enteric innervated region of 
    the intestines is the cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">In a similar vein, Berthoud et al. (&apos;90) have 
    recently demonstrated that the density of &quot;vagal 
    profiles&quot; is much greater in the cecum than in the small bowel 
    of rats following the injection of the tracer DiI in the DMN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">The physiological significance of differences in the 
    densities of central and enteric neural elements in different areas 
    of the bowel remains unknown.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">For the small bowel, the findings of Christensen et al. 
    (&apos;83) in conjunction with our results suggest a more limited 
    role for the vagus nerve as compared to nerves intrinsic to the 
    bowel in control of activity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Most studies to date have focused on determining the 
    role of intrinsic and extrinsic nerves in the control of intestinal 
    myoelectric activity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The small bowel of most nonruminant mammals is 
    characterized by a complex of well-defined cyclic motor activity, 
    the MMC, which generally originates in the duodenum and progresses 
    caudally down the intestines (Sarna, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The initiation and migration of the MMC have been shown 
    conclusively to depend entirely on neural elements intrinsic to the 
    bowel (Weisbrodt et al., &apos;75; Aeberhard and Bedi, &apos;77; 
    Bueono et al., &apos;79; Aeberhard et al., &apos;80; Itoh et al., 
    &apos;81; Ormsbee et al., &apos;81; Sarr and Kelly, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Nerves extrinsic to the bowel only appear to modify the 
    timing of MMC cycles and the duration of its phases (Sarna, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">The ability of a limited number of extrinsic neurons to 
    modify intrinsically generated myoelectric activity of the small 
    bowel may result from single vagal fibers having contact with many 
    enteric ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Such an anatomical demonstration has been provided 
    following injection of either DiI or PHA-L into the DMN of rats 
    (Kirshgessner and Gershon, &apos;89; Berthoud et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Although the cecum has a reduced number of enteric 
    elements compared to other areas of the bowel, the generation of 
    its myoelectric activity, as in the small bowel, does not appear to 
    be dependent on the vagus since baseline activity remains unaltered 
    following vagotomy (Lee and Nakayama, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">A topographically distinct area of representation for 
    cecum within the dorsal vagal complex, however, may provide an area 
    for the integration of cecal activity with activity of other areas 
    of the gastrointestinal tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">A role for the cecum in the regulation of upper 
    gastrointestinal motility has been suggested based on the 
    observations that cecectomized rats have faster rates of luminal 
    transport than intact rats (Ambuhl et al., &apos;79) and that 
    germ-free rats, whose cecums are enlarged secondary to an absence 
    of bacterial flora, have slower rates of gastrointestinal transit 
    (Abrams and Bishop, &apos;67; Iwai et al., &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">In support of this contention, Itano and Neya (&apos;85) 
    have demonstrated in the rat that increases in cecal volume produce 
    a sustained decrease in the frequency of phasic contraction and 
    basal tone of the stomach that was dependent on the integrity of 
    both the vagus and splanchnic nerves.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s223">SUMMARY</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">In conclusion, results of the present study, in 
    conjunction with past studies utilizing direct intramuscular 
    injection of tracer (Altschuler et al., &apos;891, support a strong 
    viscerotopic organization within the NTS with regard to the 
    alimentary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">For the DMN there is a mediolateral columnar 
    organization that is strongly viscerotopic with regard to the 
    stomach and cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">However, within a specific column, there exists a far 
    less discrete viscerotopic organization for the small bowel and 
    ascending colon, portions of the intestinal tract that have more 
    extensive enteric innervation than the cecum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">The viscerotopy of sensory terminals within the NTS and 
    mediolateral organization of the DMN with its organ-specific 
    dendritic penetration of the NTS provides an organizational 
    framework for medullary control of gastrointestinal function in 
    which viscus-specific effects on DMN motor output are possible.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Within each DMN column, where presumably a large portion 
    of the dendritic arbors interact, the potential for coordinated 
    generalized motor output exists.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s229">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s230">The authors would like to 
    thank J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s231">Escardo and D.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s232">Ottenheimer for their 
    technical assistance and C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s233">Latessa and S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s234">Forman for typing.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s235">This research was supported 
    by NIH grants DK-01747 (S.M.A), DK-07066 (D.A.F), and GM-27739 
    (R.R.M).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s236">Preliminary accounts of this 
    data were presented at the American Gastroenterological 
    Association, Washington D.C., May, 1989 (Ferenci et al., &apos;89a) 
    and the Society for Neuroscience, Phoenix, Arizona, October, 1989 
    (Ferenci et al., &apos;89b).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

</File>

