<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Inferior Olivary Nuclear Complex of the Rat: Morphology and 
  Comments on the Principles of Organization Within the Olivocerebellar 
  System</Title>

  <Authors>S. AUSIM AZIZI AM) D.J. WOODWARD</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">This study was undertaken (1) to provide a description of 
    the normal morphology and anatomical interrelationships within the 
    inferior olivary cell groups and (2) to determine the topographical 
    organization of projections from this nuclear complex to the 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Conventional histological methods and the technique of 
    retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase (HRP) and WGA-HRP in 
    conjunction with the sensitive chromogen tetramethyl benzidine were 
    used in this series of experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">In common with that of other animals, the inferior olivary 
    nucleus of the rat consists of three subdivisions: the medial 
    accessory olive (MAO), dorsal accessory olive (DAO), and principal 
    olive (PO).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The MA0 is made of several subnuclei including a, b, c, 
    and nucleus beta.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">On the basis of their common connections, the smaller 
    subnuclei, dorsal cap, ventrolateral outgrowth, and dorsomedial 
    cell column can be considered as parts of the MAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The DAO is made of two subdivisions or lamellae-the dorsal 
    and ventral folds-joined together laterally to form a twisted 
    V-shaped structure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The principal olive consists of dorsal and ventral 
    lamellae.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">A point-to-point projection was determined for four areas 
    of the cerebellum: the anterior lobe, the posterior vermis, the 
    intermediate and the lateral cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Analysis of the details of the projection system revealed 
    that distinct groups of cells, here referred to as lamellae, 
    project to sagittal zones of the cerebellum. (1) The medial 
    accessory olive appears to be composed of three lamellae: 
    horizontal, vertical, and rostral.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The horizontal lamella (elsewhere denoted as groups a and 
    b) projects to a sagittal zone in the vermal anterior lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The vertical lamella (groups c, beta, dorsal cap, 
    ventrolateral outgrowth, and dorsomedial cell column) projects to a 
    sagittal zone in the posterior vermis and the flocculus, and the 
    rostral lamella projects to the lateral cerebellum. (2) The dorsal 
    accessory olive is composed of two distinct lamellae which we have 
    previously denoted as the dorsal and ventral folds.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The dorsal fold projects to the vermal anterior lobe and 
    receives afferents from the spinal cord, whereas the ventral fold 
    projects to a sagittal zone in the intermediate cerebellum and 
    receives afferents primarily from dorsal column nuclei. (3) The 
    principal olive contains the two familiar lamellae: dorsal and 
    ventral lamellae, each of which projects to a specific sagittal 
    strip in the lateral cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Each of these lamellae appears to process information 
    from distinct ascending and descending systems.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The determination of the nature of topographical 
    organization of the large system of the olivocerebellar connections 
    is of major importance in mammalian neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Detailed studies of this system have been carried out in 
    the cat (see Courville et al., &apos;80; Brodal and Kawamura, 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Recent data on the topography and connections of the 
    olivocerebellar system in the rat (Gwyn et al., &apos;77; Furber 
    and Watson, &apos;83; Eisenman, &apos;84; Payne et al., &apos;85) 
    have either studied small components of the system or have mainly 
    confirmed the earlier studies on other mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">In this report we present new concepts on the 
    organization within this system.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">A more detailed analysis of point-to-point projections 
    will be presented in later communications along with additional 
    visual representations of the inferior olivary complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Structures in the brain have been traditionally grouped 
    and classified on the basis of their histological disposition.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">One way of grouping the olivary nuclei is to identify 
    groups of olivary cells on the basis of their common afferents and 
    efferents and to emphasize anatomical landmarks that perhaps are 
    not detailed elsewhere.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">In the present report, we have reviewed such an 
    organization and have presented additional nomenclature on this 
    basis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">As part of an analysis of this system, an initial task in 
    our studies in the rat was to obtain a detailed understanding of 
    the organization of the various components of the olivary nuclear 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">A second phase of this work was to establish the nature 
    of point-to-point connections from specific regions of the olive 
    onto each major cerebellar lobule.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">A third step was to relate our findings to the known 
    topographically organized olivary afferents and to make some 
    initial functional correlations.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">To accomplish these ends, we examined a complete series 
    of brainstem sections in considerable detail to establish the major 
    regional boundaries of olivary zones as described in many 
    vertebrate species including primates and humans (Kooy, &apos;17) 
    and more recently in the rat (Gwyn et al., &apos;77), cat (Brodal, 
    &apos;40; Walberg, &apos;56; Taber, &apos;61), and monkey (Bowman 
    and Sladek, &apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Our study revealed a gross feature of the olivocerebellar 
    projection in which the fiber system rotates 90&quot; as it ascends 
    to the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Caudal olivary regions project to midline cerebellar 
    areas, and rostral regions of the olive project to the 
    hemispheres.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Analysis of the details of the projection system 
    indicated that distinct groups of cells, here referred to as 
    lamellae, project to sagittal zones of the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Our study further revealed a complex organization of 
    projections in the form of a banding pattern (perpendicular to 
    lamellae) observed in multiple olivary areas of cells of origin.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">A principle of organization appears to be that the 
    lamellae form the basis of sagittal projection zones and bands form 
    lobule projection modules.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Preliminary reports of portions of these data have 
    appeared previously (McGrane et al., &apos;77; Azizi et al., 
    &apos;78, &apos;82).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s32">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">A complete series of transverse sections, cut at 40 pm on 
    a freezing microtome and stained with cresyl violet or neutral red, 
    were examined throughout the extent of the olive of two albino and 
    ten Long-Evans female hooded rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Seventy sections in each series were examined 
    individually and the outlines of the olivary cell regions and 
    ventral surface of the brainstem were drawn with the use of a 
    drawing tube mounted on a Leitz Orthoplan microscope or an overhead 
    projector.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">A section-by-section analysis was essential to clarify 
    transitions in olivary regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Portions of several rat brains (20 of 148) used in the 
    entire series of experiments (as described below) were studied in 
    equivalent detail to resolve transition areas.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">A final summary series of outlines was prepared with 
    slight adaptations to account for the most constant features among 
    the many brainstems.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">These were used to establish major boundaries between 
    olivary subdivisions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The method of retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase (HRP) was employed systematically to explore the pattern 
    of the olivary projections to the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">One hundred forty-eight female hooded and albino rats 
    weighing 180-280 g were used in this phase of the study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Injections of 0.04-0.2 pl, 1040% solutions of HRP or 
    WGA-HRP (2%) in water were made with glass micropipettes (35-75pm 
    tips) attached to a 1-pl Hamilton syringe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Placements of large injections were made into anterior, 
    posterior, and lateral cerebellar lobules of 15 rats under 
    pentobarbital anesthesia.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">The remainder of the animals received small injections of 
    HRP in lobules and sublobules of the anterior However, it could not 
    be determined with certainty where the edge of the effective zone 
    of axon terminal uptake was located.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">Our opinion is that the effective injection zone is 
    within the central region of the stained area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Cells stained by retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase were located on the transverse brainstem sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The low-power (10 X) objective was used to determine the 
    location of the cells in a standard olivary series cut 
    rostrocaudally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">The relative numbers of cells were manually translated 
    into dot density diagrams to indicate the cell distribution within 
    the olive.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s48">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s49">Gross organization</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">As in other mammalian species (Kooy, 17), most olivary 
    neurons are located within <neuroanatomicalLocation>the three major 
    nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation>-<neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    medial accessory olive (MAO), the dorsal accessory olive (DAO), and 
    the principal olive (PO)</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Gwyn et al., 
    77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The minor nuclei from caudal to rostral are 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal cap (DC), the nucleus beta, the 
    ventrolateral outgrowth (VLO), and the dorsomedial cell column 
    (DMCC)</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">On the basis of their connections, these small subnuclei 
    can be associated with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    MAO</neuroanatomicalLocation>; therefore, we will categorize them 
    operationally as parts of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    MAO</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">An additional minor subnuclew is <neuroanatomicalLocation>
    the dorsal fold (DF) of the DAO</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which 
    was first delineated by McGrane et al. ( 77).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">An alternative way of organizing the cell groups within 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the inferior olivary 
    complex</neuroanatomicalLocation> entails the parcellation of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the olivary 
    nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation> into groups with common afferents 
    and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Additional terms are necessary to appropriately explain 
    some of the concepts and divisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The term, lamella, is applied here generically to denote 
    groups of neurons with common afYerents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">These groups of cells mostly form plates or slabs and 
    appear to be anatomically distinct subdivisions within 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the olive</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">In the following description and in Table 1 and Figure 9, 
    we have correlated this lamellar organization with the classically 
    described olivary subnuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Examination of serial coronal sections beginning at 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the caudal end of the 
    I0</neuroanatomicalLocation> in <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    medulla</neuroanatomicalLandmark> showed that, moving rostrally, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the caudal tip of the 
    MA0</neuroanatomicalLocation> appears first as an oval-shaped group 
    of cells lying about 0.3 mm caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    obex</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">This small group is known as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>subgroup b</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 
    1, sec. 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Slightly rostrally, this cell group enlarges 
    dorsomedially and a smaller cell group, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a</neuroanatomicalLocation>, appears 
    immediately lateral to it (Fig. 1, sec. 3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Rostral to this, the first and second groups join, 
    forming a continuous horizontal sheet of neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">This sheet of cells has unique afferents and efferents 
    (see Discussion) and composes <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral 
    portion of the caudal half of the MAO</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">We refer to this group of cells as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the horizontal 
    lamella</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Another cell group, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>c</neuroanatomicalLocation>, appears 
    adjacent to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    midline</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and dorsomedial to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the first cell 
    group</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 1, sec. 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The nucleus 
    beta</neuroanatomicalLocation> is located just ventral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the dorsal cap</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
    and is fused ventrally with <neuroanatomicalLocation>subnucleus 
    c</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 1, secs. 7-11).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The nucleus 
    beta</neuroanatomicalLocation> in the rat is a group of cells 
    distinct from c with a somewhat different pattern of projections to 
    <connxTermination>the cerebellum</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Caudally, <neuroanatomicalLocation>subgroups c and 
    beta</neuroanatomicalLocation> are distinct (Fig. 1, secs 7,8); 
    however, rostrally they form a continuous vertical slab of cells 
    with common afTerents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">This vertical slab together with the smaller cell 
    subgroups, dorsal cap, ventrolateral outgrowth, and dorsomedial 
    cell column, form another lamella, <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    vertical lamella of the MAO</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">This lamella, although not forming a continuous sheet, 
    can be considered operationally as one unit (see Discussion).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Thus, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the caudal and medial 
    MA0</neuroanatomicalLocation> are made of two lamellae, oriented 
    perpendicularly in an L shape.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">At the level where <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the three 
    parts of the MA0 (a, b, and c)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> join, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal cap 
    (DC)</neuroanatomicalLocation> first appears (Fig. 1, sec. 5) and 
    continues rostrally as <neuroanatomicalLocation>the most dorsal and 
    medial part of the MAO</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The ventrolateral outgrowth appears as a discrete cell 
    group ventrolateral to<neuroanatomicalLandmark> the dorsal 
    cap</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 1, secs. 11, 121, joined with 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nucleus 
    beta</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    DMCC</neuroanatomicalLocation> is located at a more rostral 
    level.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The rostral portion of the main 
    body of MA0</neuroanatomicalLocation> forms another slab of cells 
    with distinct connections, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the rostral 
    lamella</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">In the rat, this lamella of cells appears to form the 
    rostral continuation of groups b and c; however, it has separate 
    afferents and efferents from b and c (see Discussion).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The dorsal accessory 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> first appears as a flat group of 
    cells, dorsal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    MAO</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Slightly rostral, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    DAO</neuroanatomicalLocation> enlarges, extending ventrolaterally 
    about 1.2 mm from <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    midline</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    ventral surface of the brainstem</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 1, 
    secs. 9-11).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">More rostral it separates into two layers or lamellae, 
    joined laterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">The most dorsal and caudal lamella is defined here as the 
    dorsal fold and the ventral layer or lamella is referred to here as 
    the ventral fold (Fig. 1, secs.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">11-14).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">The dorsal and ventral folds together form the twisted, 
    V-shaped structure of the DAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The term fold has been used here to describe the folding 
    of the two lamellae of the DAO that form the V-shape.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">It will be noted later that significant functional 
    differences exist between the dorsal and ventral folds.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The principal 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> originates as a small group of 
    cells lateral to<neuroanatomicalLandmark> the 
    MA0</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and ventral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the dorsal 
    fold</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">This group of cells quickly forms 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal lamella of the principal 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The ventral lamella of the 
    principal olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> extends dorsomedially 
    from <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the dorsal 
    lamella</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 1, secs. 14, 15).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLocation> refers to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the area of the inferior olivary 
    complex</neuroanatomicalLandmark> where relatively rapid changes in 
    crosssectional appearance of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the inferior 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> take place (Fig. 1, secs. 
    10-15).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Rostra1 to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> consists primarily of a 
    three-layered sigmoid structure with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    ventral fold of DAO</neuroanatomicalLocation> joined medially to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal lamella of the 
    PO</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which in turn is joined laterally to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral lamella of the 
    PO</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The rostral lamella of the 
    MA0</neuroanatomicalLocation> lies ventral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the sigmoid 
    structure</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the DMCC</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    occupies a midline site.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> exhibits this basic confguration 
    from the end of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to its rostral end.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The minor subnuclei, the dorsal 
    cap, and the nucleus beta</neuroanatomicalLocation> are located 
    caudally to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The ventrolatera1 outgrowth and 
    the dorsal fold of DAO</neuroanatomicalLocation> occur just at the 
    level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    dorsomedial cell column</neuroanatomicalLocation> is located 
    rostrally to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>this 
    area</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s94">Topography of projections 
    from the olivary complex</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">The series of injections in these experiments was 
    designed to obtain information from major regions of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the entire 
    cerebellum</neuroanatomicalLocation>: <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    anterior lobe, the posterior vermis, the intermediate zone, and the 
    lateral hemisphere</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">Multiple injection sites were required to cover each 
    major lobule, and the resulting label appeared in neurons within 
    distinctly different olivary nuclei, permitting a lobule-by-lobule 
    comparison.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">The olivary labeling shown on the following series of 
    coronal olivary maps represents a compilation of data obtained from 
    many individual HRP injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">Figure 2 demonstrates two injection sites and labeling in 
    the olive (Fig.2C,D) following HRP injections in lobule VIb-c (Fig. 
    2 4 .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s100">projectiom to the 
    anterior lobe of the cerebellum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Twenty-five animals were used in this phase of the 
    study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">The results revealed that the anterior lobe receives 
    projections from the horizontal lamella (groups a and b) in the 
    caudal MA0 and almost the entire DAO.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">The series 
    included<exptLabel><tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
    into <injectionLocation>vermal lobules 111, IV, and 
    V</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s104">Midline 
    <injectionLocation>vermal</injectionLocation> injections in 
    <injectionLocation>these lobules</injectionLocation> labeled 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in the 
    <labelingLocation>caudolateral MA0</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3C, 
    secs. 1-11).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s105">The clusters of cells labeled 
    with these injections were located in <labelingLocation>subnuclei a 
    and b</labelingLocation>, an area more lateral than those labeled 
    with injections in posterior vermis (see below).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s106">On the 
    other hand, placements of HRP laterally in <injectionLocation>
    lobules IV and V</injectionLocation> tended to label 
    <labelingLocation>the DAO</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>heavily</labelingDescription> (Fig. 3C, secs. 
    9-18, solid squares).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s107"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>both 
    the dorsal fold and lateral aspects of the ventral fold of the 
    DAO</labelingLocation>, as well as in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    aspect of rostral MA0</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3C, secs. 1117).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Results from three cases,<exptLabel>A-96, A-42, and 
    CH-19</exptLabel>, with injections in <injectionLocation>lobules N 
    and V</injectionLocation> are represented in Figure 4C secs. 9-18 
    (solid squares).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s109">Projections to the 
    posterior vermis and the tlocculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">The results (Fig. 4f showed that the posterior vermis 
    receives projections primarily from the vertical lamella (groups c 
    and beta) in the caudal MAO.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112"><exptLabel>Fifty-two posterior vermal injections in 
    <injectionLocation>lobules VIa-c, VII, VIII, and 
    IXa-c</injectionLocation></exptLabel> were analyzed.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">Placement of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in 
    <injectionLocation>lobule VIa</injectionLocation> of seven rats 
    resulted in <labelingDescription>scattered 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>groups b and 
    c</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4C, secs. 1-10, open triangles), whereas 
    injections in <injectionLocation>lobule VIb-c</injectionLocation> 
    labeled <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>subnuclei c and beta</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">Results from three cases, <exptLabel>A-43, A-53, and 
    CH-14</exptLabel>, are presented in Figure 4C secs. 6-11 (solid 
    triangles).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115"><exptLabel>Eight successful injections</exptLabel> 
    covering <injectionLocation>the entire lobule 
    VII</injectionLocation> were analyzed.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s116">Results 
    from three cases are presented in Figure 4C (open circles).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117"><labelingDescription>Labeled cells</labelingDescription> 
    were observed in <labelingLocation>subnucleus c</labelingLocation> 
    and <labelingLocation>nucleus beta</labelingLocation> at the level 
    of the transition zone.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118"><exptLabel>Injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>lobule 
    VIII</injectionLocation></exptLabel> were attempted in ten 
    animals.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s119">Nine of these cases were 
    successful in the sense that the injection site was within 
    <injectionLocation>the vermal lobule VIII</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">These injections labeled <labelingDescription>olivary 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the caudal MA0 
    (subnucleus b), the medial MA0 (subnucleus c), and nucleus 
    beta</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4, solid circles).</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121"><exptLabel>Cases A-97, A-75, and A-128</exptLabel> are 
    depicted in Figure 4C, secs. 1-9 (solid circles).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122"><exptLabel>Eighteen cases</exptLabel> with successful 
    injections in <injectionLocation>sublobules 
    IXa-c</injectionLocation> were examined.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s123">Each of 
    these injections covered <injectionLocation>part or all of one or 
    more of the sublobules IXa-c</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124"><labelingDescription>HRP-labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>
    olivary areas at the transition zone level in the beta nucleus, 
    subnucleus c, and the dorsal cap</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4, secs. 
    5-13, open squares).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s125">It appears that 
    <connxTermination>the midline vermal lobule 
    IXa-c</connxTermination> receives afferents mainly from <connxOrigin
    >the nucleus beta</connxOrigin>, while <connxTermination>the 
    lateral area of the uvula</connxTermination> is the site of 
    termination of climbing fibers from <connxOrigin>the subnucleus 
    c</connxOrigin> (Fig. 4).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s126"><labelingDescription>A few 
    cells</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal cap of Kooy</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127"><exptLabel>Injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
    flocculus</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, without involvement of 
    <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the paraflocculus</injectionSpread>, 
    labeled <labelingLocation>olivary</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> only in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap of Kooy</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    4C, secs. 5-12, solid squares).</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    flocculus</neuroanatomicalLocation> has been considered together 
    with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the midvermal 
    region</neuroanatomicalLocation> because <connxTermination>
    flocculus</connxTermination> and <connxTermination>parts of 
    posterior midvermis (uvula)</connxTermination> receive inputs from 
    <connxOrigin>common olivary regions, i.e., the vertical lamella or 
    specifically the dorsal cap</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The vertical 
    lamella</neuroanatomicalLocation> appears to be 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a functionally distinct zone of the 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation>, receiving mainly visual and 
    vestibular afferents and relaying this information to 
    <connxTermination>the flocculus and 
    midvermis</connxTermination>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">Our results demonstrate that, for the most part, the 
    neurons that project to <connxTermination>the posterior 
    vermis</connxTermination> are located within <connxOrigin>the 
    vertical lamella of the MA0</connxOrigin> (Fig. 4, secs. 1-12).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">It should be noted that the extensive series of small 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections <injectionLocation>
    in lobules VIbc-IX</injectionLocation> of different animals allows 
    an overview of the <connxOrigin>olivary</connxOrigin> projections 
    to <connxTermination>a complete sagittal cerebellar 
    zone</connxTermination> as previously defined and discussed 
    (Armstrong et al., &apos;74; Courville, &apos;75; Groenewegen and 
    Voogd, 77; Chan-Palay et al., &apos;77; Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">Thus, these results reveal that the sagittal zonation in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the cerebellum</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    corresponds to a topographical organization within 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the inferior 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> such that each sagittal strip of 
    climbing fibers may originate from a distinct lamella of neurons in 
    <connxOrigin>the inferior olive</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s133">Projections to the 
    posterior lobe intermediate zone.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><exptLabel>Twenty-six cases with injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the intermediate region of the posterior 
    lobe</injectionLocation></exptLabel> were analyzed.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s135">In the 
    rat we presumed the area slightly medial as well as lateral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the longitudinal vessels demarcating the 
    vermis and lateral hemisphere</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to be 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the intermediate 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s136">Most of the labeling found 
    following injections in this area was concentrated in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal half of rostral lamella of MA0 and the 
    medial portion of the ventral fold of the 
    DAO</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137"><exptLabel>Six HRP injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    intermediate lobule VI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labeled 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral caudal half of the rostral lamella of 
    MA0</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5C, secs. 14-21, solid triangles).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><labelingDescription>Some labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>
    dorsomedial regions of the DAO at the junction of this subnucleus 
    and the PO</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><exptLabel>Injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    intermediate lobule VII</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labeled 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>medial MA0 and the medial area of the ventral 
    fold of DAO</labelingLocation> at the level of 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the transition 
    zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 5, secs. 14-20, solid 
    circles).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">In <exptLabel>six different cases with injections in 
    <injectionLocation>intermediate areas of crura I and 
    11</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, the number of labeled cells 
    observed in <labelingLocation>the inferior olive</labelingLocation> 
    was <labelingDescription>comparatively small</labelingDescription>, 
    although <labelingDescription>a large number of 
    cells</labelingDescription> were filled with HRP in 
    <labelingLocation>the pons</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral reticular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141"><exptLabel>Placements of HRP in <injectionLocation>the 
    medial area of the paramedian 
    lobule</injectionLocation></exptLabel> resulted in labeling of 
    distinct areas within <labelingLocation>the rostral lamella of 
    MA0</labelingLocation> and <labelingLocation>the medial region of 
    the ventral fold of DAO</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5, secs. 14-18, 
    open triangles).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142">The nucleotopic projection is 
    similar to that observed for <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    intermediate zones of lobulus simplex</neuroanatomicalLocation> and 
    for <neuroanatomicalLocation>crura I and 
    11</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143"><exptLabel>HRP placements in <injectionLocation>
    intermediate areas of lobule VIII</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, 
    in five different animals, resulted in labeling in <labelingLocation
    >the lateral part of the ventral fold of the DAO</labelingLocation> 
    (Fig. 5C, secs. 14-19, open squares).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">There is a nucleotopic organization within <connxOrigin>
    the caudal portion of the rostral lamella of MA0</connxOrigin> with 
    regard to projections to <connxTermination>the intermediate zones 
    of simplex, crura I and 11, and the paramedian 
    lobule</connxTermination> (Fig. 5, secs. 16-19).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Neurons that project to <connxTermination>
    simplex</connxTermination> (solid triangles) are located 
    ventrally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">Those projecting to <connxTermination>crura I and 
    I1</connxTermination> (solid circles) are located dorsally, while 
    the group of cells that contributes climbing fibers to 
    <connxTermination>the paramedian lobule</connxTermination> (open 
    triangles) is located between these two tiers (Fig. 5, secs. 
    16-19).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">Overall,<connxTermination>the intermediate zones of the 
    cerebellum</connxTermination> receive climbing fiber projections 
    from <connxOrigin>the caudal aspect of the rostral lamella of the 
    MA0 and the medial aspect of the ventral fold of the 
    DAO</connxOrigin> at the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    transition zone</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s148">Projections to the 
    cerebellar hemispheres.</S>
    <S avgH="23" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s149"><connxTermination>
    The lateral cerebellum</connxTermination> was found to receive 
    projections mainly from <connxOrigin>rostral 
    olive</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Virtually all of <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were located in <labelingLocation>the 
    rostral aspect of the rostral lamella of MA0 and both lamellae of 
    PO</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">In 33 animals, <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> was 
    injected laterally in <injectionLocation>lobulus simplex, crus I 
    and crus 11, the paramedian lobule, the lateral pyramis, and the 
    paraflocculus</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">These injection sites tended to be larger than those in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>vermal areas</neuroanatomicalLocation> and 
    resulted in correspondingly <labelingDescription>heavier 
    labeling</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">In five animals with <exptLabel>injections in 
    <injectionLocation>lobulus simplex</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, 
    <labelingDescription>a zone of heavy labeling</labelingDescription> 
    was present in <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial zone of the 
    rostral lamella of MA0 that extended from near its rostral tip to 
    the transition zone</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were also noted in <labelingLocation>
    the DMCC</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s156">Also, <labelingDescription>a 
    group of cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial DAO</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>heavily 
    labeled</labelingDescription> (Fig. 6C, secs. 13-20, solid 
    circles).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157"><exptLabel>Three injections in <injectionLocation>crus 
    I</injectionLocation></exptLabel> <labelingDescription>labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the midsection of 
    the ventral lamella of the PO</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6C, secs. 
    15-19, solid squares).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s158">Eight HRP injections in 
    <injectionLocation>crus I1</injectionLocation> labeled olivary 
    neurons that were diffusely scattered at <labelingLocation>the 
    extreme rostral end of the MA0 and the ventral lamella of the 
    PO</labelingLocation>(Fig. 6C, secs. 14-22, solid 
    triangles).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">The distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> found after<exptLabel>injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the paramedian 
    lobule</injectionLocation></exptLabel> was slightly different than 
    that present after injections of crura I and 11.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160"><labelingDescription>Labeled olivary 
    cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    midsection of both ventral and dorsal lamellae of the 
    PO</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6C, secs. 15-21, open circles).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Three cases (A-54, CH-19, and CH-13) demonstrated this 
    pattern of labeling.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162"><exptLabel>Two cases with injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the lateral region of lobule 
    VIII</injectionLocation></exptLabel> demonstrated 
    <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the far caudal aspects of the 
    PO</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6C, secs. 11, 12, open 
    squares).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163"><exptLabel>Twelve cases with successful injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the pardocculus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    were analyzed.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s164"><labelingLocation>Two major 
    groups of olivary neurons</labelingLocation> were labeled.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165"><labelingDescription>A column of labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription>, about 800 pm long, was located in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral zone of the rostral 
    MAO</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s166"><labelingDescription>A second 
    group of cells</labelingDescription>, located in <labelingLocation>
    the junction between dorsal and ventral lamellae of the 
    PO</labelingLocation>, was labeled throughout <labelingLocation>the 
    rostrocaudal extent of the principal olive</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    6, secs. 1322, open triangles).</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s167">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">In the course of this study, we addressed the issue of 
    the conformation and topographical organization of the inferior 
    olive in the rat as well as the patterns of organization within its 
    olivocerebellar system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">A comprehensive analy sis of the totality of efferents 
    from the inferior olivary complex to the cerebellum proved critical 
    for identifying the lamellar organization within this system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Conversely, the functional significance of the lamellae 
    became clear through a process of examination of afferents to each 
    lamella.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">In addition, as is noted in the following discussion, 
    the inferior olive can be divided on the basis of common 
    connections into three functional regions that include one or more 
    lamellae within the traditional olivary subcomponents of the MAO, 
    DAO, and PO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">The functional zones include a somatosensory zone in the 
    caudal olive, a visualvestibular zone, and an integrative zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">The following discussion of the connections of 
    traditional olivary subnuclei reviews the basis for emerging 
    concepts of lamellar and functional organization of the olivary 
    complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s174">The medial accessory 
    olive (MAO)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Morphology.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">This subnucleus in the rat is similar to the homologous 
    regions in the cat and monkey (Brodal, &apos;40; Taber, &apos;61; 
    Bowman and Sladek, &apos;73) and constitutes the largest subgroup 
    of the inferior olivary complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">In marsupials the MA0 is laterally displaced (Martin et 
    al., &apos;75; Watson and Herron, &apos;77) due to a slightly 
    different course of ontogeny in these mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">On the basis of their common connections we have divided 
    the MA0 into three lamellae (see Results and belowbthe rostral 
    lamella, the vertical lamella, and the caudally located horizontal 
    lamella.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Merents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">We propose that the MA0 can be divided into three 
    functional subdivisions which parallel the lamellar 
    organization.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">This conclusion is based both on the results of this 
    study and on a review of the literature in the rat and other 
    species (see below).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">These three regions or lamellae are partially 
    coextensive and are the following: The horizontal lamella.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">This region includes the caudallateral portion of the 
    MA0 (subgroups a and b) and is primarily a somatosensory zone (see 
    Figs. 3, 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Results of this study show that this area of MA0 
    contributes climbing fibers primarily to the midline vermal area of 
    the anterior lobe of the cerebellum in the rat (Fig. 3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">These results are similar to those in the cat (Brodal 
    and Walberg, &apos;77) and opossum (Martin et al., &apos;80, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The caudal-latera1 portion of the MA0 has similar 
    afferents to the DAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">It has been shown in the rat (Swenson and Castro, 
    &apos;83a,b), cat (Mizuno, &apos;66; Boesten and Voogd, &apos;75; 
    Berkley and Worden, &apos;78; Berkley and Hand, &apos;78; Walberg, 
    &apos;82; Molinari, &apos;84), and monkey (Kalil, &apos;79) that 
    the dorsal column nuclei, spinal cord, and the spinal trigeminal 
    nucleus project to the caudal MA0 (subgroups a and b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">It appears that the caudal-lateral MAO, or horizontal 
    lamella, in conjunction with the DAO, receives peripheral 
    somatosensory inputs mainly from the spinal cord and the dorsal 
    column nuclei and projects to the midvermal area of the anterior 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">The vertical lamella.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Based on afferents and efferents this aggregate appears 
    to be involved with visual and vestibular functions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">The results of the present study demonstrate that the 
    cell groups that compose the vertical lamella, i.e., subgroups c, 
    beta, the dorsal cap (of Kooy), the ventrolateral outgrowth, and 
    the dorsomedial cell column all project to a midline strip of 
    vermal lobules VIVIII and to a slightly lateral zone of vermal 
    lobule IX (Figs. 4, 7).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">This projection pattern is in agreement with those in 
    the cat (Hoddevik et al., &apos;76; Brodal, &apos;761, monkey 
    (Brodal and Brodal, &apos;81, &apos;82), and opossum (Linauts and 
    Martin, &apos;78b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">The results of our previous studies in the rat (Azizi et 
    al., &apos;82) have demonstrated that parts of the vertical lamella 
    (subnucleus c) receives afferents from the superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Other authors (Graham, &apos;77; Weber et al., &apos;78; 
    SaintCyr and Courville, &apos;82, in the cat; Frankfurter et al., 
    &apos;76, in primates) have shown a similar tecto-olivary 
    projection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The nucleus beta receives additional afferents from the 
    pretectal (Walberg et al., &apos;81; Martin et al., &apos;82), 
    fastigial (Sugimoto et al., &apos;80), and vestibular nuclei 
    (Saint-Cyr and Courville, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Such a tecto-olivomidvermal projection has been shown 
    electrophysiologically in the cat (Jeneskog, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The dorsomedial cell column receives afferents from the 
    vestibular nuclei and the interstitial nucleus of Cajal (Saint-Cyr 
    and Courville, &apos;79) and projects to the uvula (Brodal, 
    &apos;76; this study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">The ventrolateral outgrowth receives fibers from the 
    pretectal areas (Walberg et al., &apos;81) and projects to the 
    uvula as well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">These cerebellar targets can be seen as portions of an 
    overall sagittal projection zone of the medial MA0 (Fig. 7).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">A well-studied subnucleus, the dorsal cap of Kooy, is 
    known to have a relatively complex input and output pattern (Mizuno 
    et al., &apos;73; Maekawa and Simpson, &apos;73; Frankfurter et 
    al., &apos;76; Weber and Harting, &apos;80; Walberg et al., 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The results of the present investigation reveal that the 
    dorsal cap projects to the flocculus and uvula, corroborating the 
    results of a previous study in the rat (Blanks et al., &apos;83) 
    (Fig. 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">The caudal aspect of this subnucleus receives fibers 
    from the nucleus of the optic tract and the dorsal terminal nucleus 
    of the accessory optic tract that mediate visual information to the 
    flocculus from the ipsilateral eye (Maekawa and Takeda, &apos;79; 
    Takeda and Maekawa, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">The rostral aspect of this subnucleus is the site of 
    termination of axons from the ventromedial tegmental area and 
    mediates visual information to the dorsomedial flocculus from the 
    contralateral eye (Alley et al., &apos;75; Maekawa and Takeda, 
    &apos;79; Takeda and Maekawa, &apos;80), indicatthe dorsal cap 
    integrates information from both</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">ing that eyes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Thus, it appears that the medial MA0 is mostly, if not 
    completely, involved with visual and vestibular functions (Fig. 
    9).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">The rostral lamella This area encompasses the region of 
    the main body of the MA0 rostral to the transition zone, referred 
    to here as the rostral lamella.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Previous studies in the squirrel monkey (Rutherford and 
    Gwyn, &apos;80) have indicated that the rostral aspect of MA0 is 
    composed of the anterior end of cell group a.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">However, from our analysis it appears that in the rat 
    this group of cells is the rostral end of groups b and c.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">In future publications on the threedimensional structure 
    of the inferior olive, the disposition as well as relations of this 
    lamella with other cell groups will become more clear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">As will become apparent from the following discussion, 
    the afferents and efferents of this group of cells are distinctly 
    different from horizontal and vertical lamellae; therefore, this 
    group is classified separately as a new lamella.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">In the current study in the rat, the rostral aspect of 
    this lamella was found to project to the contralateral 
    paraflocculus and hemisphere including lobulus simplex, crura I and 
    11, and the paramedian lobule (Figs. 5, 6, 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">The caudal area of this lamella projects to intermediate 
    lobules VI, VII, and VIII.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">The rostral lamella of MA0 appears to receive a variety 
    of projections from motor areas in the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">By utilizing retrograde and anterograde methods, a 
    descending projection system from the mesencephalon to the rostral 
    MA0 was demonstrated in the cat (Takeda and Maekawa,&apos;76; 
    Saint-Cyr and Courville, &apos;81, &apos;821, opossum (Henkel et 
    al., &apos;73, and rat (Brown et al., &apos;77; Swenson and Castro, 
    &apos;83a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Further studies have suggested that the nucleus of 
    Darkschewitsch (cat, Mabuchi and Kusama, &apos;70; Onodera, 
    &apos;84; opossum, Linauts and Martin, &apos;78a) and the 
    periaqueductal gray (cat, Walberg, &apos;74; rat, Swenson and 
    Castro, &apos;83b) send fibers to the rostral subdivision of the 
    MAO.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">It appears that this rostral subdivision of the MA0 
    receives projections from mesencephalic motor regions and projects 
    to the lateral and vestibular cerebellum (Fig. 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Since the afferents and efferents of this nucleus are 
    similar to those of the principal olive, this subdivision of the 
    MA0 may function as a unit with the principal olive.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s218">Dorsal accessory 
    olive</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Morphology.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">This subnucleus is a V-shaped structure consisting of 
    two lamellae: a small dorsocaudal lamella, named here the dorsal 
    fold, and a more rostral and ventral lamella, the ventral fold.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">The ventral fold is the larger of the two components 
    (about two-thirds of the total volume of DAO) and most likely makes 
    up a major fraction of the DAO in other species.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Our observations indicate that the DAO is an 
    anatomically continuous structure and that the dorsal and ventral 
    folds are fused in the lateral aspect of the subnucleus to 
    construct the V-shape (Fig. 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">This Vshape feature was first noted by Kooy (&apos;17), 
    who described its presence in the mammals other than the rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Efferents and afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Analysis of the connections of this subnucleus indicates 
    that the DAO is primarily related to the somatosensory system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Results of the present study indicate that the DAO 
    mainly projects to the anterior lobe and to the intermediate areas 
    of the posterior lobe of the cerebellum (Figs. 3, 5).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Further analysis of our results disclosed that the 
    dorsal fold (lamella) and the lateral regions of the ventral fold 
    (lamella) project to the vermal anterior lobe (vermal zones b and c 
    in the cat), whereas the more rostral and medial DAO (the entire 
    ventral fold) projects to the intermediate zones of the anterior 
    and posterior lobes (Figs. 3,5).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">The clearly delineated sagittal cerebellar projection 
    zones reinforce the gross anatomical designation of the two DAO 
    regions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">These results are similar to those in the cat (Brodal 
    and Walberg, &apos;77; Kotchabhakdi et al., &apos;78) for zones 
    that can be equated to the dorsal and ventral folds of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Anatomical studies in monkey (Brodal and Brodal, 
    &apos;81, &apos;82) and opossum (Linauts and Martin, &apos;78b), 
    although not as detailed as those in the cat, demonstrate the same 
    general pattern of projections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Electrophysiological studies (Gellman et al., &apos;83, 
    &apos;85) of somatosensory areas of the inferior olive have shown 
    that the dorsal fold in the cat contains a nearly complete, 
    although diffuse, somatosensory map of the body, whereas the 
    ventral fold has a more precise somatosensory map.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Our view is that the areas mapped by Gellman et al. 
    (&apos;83, &apos;85) correspond to our dorsal and ventral folds in 
    the rat and to the regions noted by Kooy (&apos;17).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The map of Gellman et al. (&apos;83) also corresponds 
    well with the anatomical data describing afTerents to the DAO in 
    the rat (Swenson and Castro, &apos;83a), cat (Boeston and Voogd, 
    &apos;75; Berkley and Hand, &apos;78; Berkley and Worden, 
    &apos;78), and opossum (Martin et al., &apos;80, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">The anatomical studies have shown that the gracile 
    nucleus projects to the lateral DAO and the cuneate nucleus to the 
    medial DAO, while axons of the spinal trigeminal nucleus end in the 
    most medial zone of the DAO (Walberg, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Fibers from the spinal cord terminate in the lateralmost 
    area of the DAO and cover the entire region corresponding to the 
    dorsal fold (rat, Swenson and Castro, &apos;83a; cat, Mizuno, 
    &apos;66; Boesten and Voogd, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Electrophysiological studies have further described an 
    extensive spino-olivocerebellar system that terminates in precise 
    sagittal zones of the anterior lobe (Larson et al., &apos;69a,b; 
    Oscarsson and Sjolund, &apos;77a-c; Sjolund, &apos;78; Anderson and 
    Nyquist, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Thus it appears that the DAO receives a topographically 
    organized somatosensory projection mainly from the periphery and 
    that the dorsal fold, in effect, is dominated by afferents from the 
    spinal cord.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s238">The principal olivary 
    nucleus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Morphology.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">In rat the principal olive (PO) is small compared to the 
    MA0 or DAO (Fig. 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Thus, the name designation is a misnomer in this animal 
    because it is in fact a smaller subnucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">The PO in the rat is similar to those in the cat 
    (Brodal, &apos;40; Walberg, &apos;56; Taber, &apos;61) and monkey 
    (Bowman and Sladek. &apos;73). consisting of two lamellae, dorsal 
    and ventral, which form a U-shaped configuration with the hilus 
    opening medially.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">However, the dorsal lamella can be observed in places to 
    fuse with the ventral fold of the DAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">In the opossum the PO has a slightly different shape, 
    which may be due to a different course of ontogeny in the 
    marsupials (Martin et al., &apos;75; Watson and Herron, 
    &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">In primates, man, and elephants, this subnucleus is the 
    largest component of the inferior olive, which exhibits many folds 
    and lamellae (Kooy, &apos;17; Jenkins, &apos;05).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">From the pattern of connectivity and its parallel 
    increase in size with the lateral cerebellum, it appears that the 
    evolution of this nucleus in mammals is commensurate with that of 
    the lateral cerebellum (Kooy, &apos;17; Larsell, &apos;52).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Overall, it appears that the PO in the rat has an 
    appropriate size relative to the development of the lateral 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Efferents and afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">The results of this communication reveal that the PO 
    mainly projects to the lateral cerebellum (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">These results are congruent with familar results in the 
    cat (Brodal, &apos;40; Brodal and Walberg, &apos;77; Kotchabhakdi 
    et al, &apos;78) and monkey (Brodal and Brodal, &apos;81, &apos;82) 
    and in somewhat general agreement with those in the opossum 
    (Linauts and Martin, &apos;78b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">The available data on the projections to the PO indicate 
    that the perirubral area, the cortex, and the lateral cerebellar 
    nuclei project to this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">The dorsal lamella of the PO receives projections from 
    the parvicellular area of the red nucleus in the cat (Edwards, 
    &apos;72; Saint-Cyr and Courville, &apos;82), monkey (Miller and 
    Strominger, &apos;73; Strominger et al., &apos;791, and opossum 
    (Linauts and Martin, &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">In the monkey, the rostral red nucleus may project to 
    both lamellae (Strominger et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">In the rat, a projection from the red nucleus to the PO 
    has also been shown (Swenson and Castro, &apos;83a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Another group of mesencephalic projections to the PO 
    originates within the pretectal area and the central gray.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">The pretectal area in the cat, specifically, the nucleus 
    of the optic tract, projects to the dorsal lamella (Walberg et al., 
    &apos;81) while the periaquaductal gray (nucleus of Darkschewitsch) 
    projects to ventral lamella of the PO (Walberg, &apos;74; Saint-Cyr 
    and Courville, &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">The PO is the target of a topographically organized 
    projection from the dentate nucleus in the rat (Haroian, &apos;82; 
    Swenson and Castro, &apos;83a), cat (Tolbert et al., &apos;76; 
    Berkley and Worden, &apos;781, monkey (Kalil, &apos;79), and 
    opossum (Martin et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Unlike the basilar pons that receives major projections 
    from widespread areas of the cortex, the inferior olive is known 
    only to receive projections from the motor cortex in the rat 
    (Bishop et al., &apos;76; Brown et al., &apos;77; Swenson and 
    Castro, &apos;83a,b) and cat (Sousa-Pinto, &apos;69; Sousa-Pinto 
    and Brodal, &apos;69; Berkley and Worden, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">However, other areas of the cerebral cortex may 
    indirectly influence the PO via rubro-olivary fibers or other 
    nuclei of the mesencephalon (Oka et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">A substantial unresolved issue is the identification of 
    diverse areas of mesencephalon that project to the PO and, in turn, 
    the resolution of the multiple afYerents that project to these 
    mesencephalic areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s261">Principles of 
    organization within the olivocerebellar system</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">First, a global organization details the totality of 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">A gross generalization is that the olivocerebellar 
    fibers rotate 90&quot; before reaching the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">The hemispheres of the cerebellum receive projections 
    from rostral cells in the olive, while the anterior midvermis and 
    Dosterior midvermis receive fibers from lateral and medial caudal 
    olivary zones, respectively Fig. 8).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Second, the results have led us to propose that the 
    olivary complex (the MAO, DAO, and PO) can be subdivided further 
    into slablike lamellae, as have been described above.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">At this point we can delineate a total of seven 
    different lamellae based largely on the detailed information on the 
    projections from olive to the cerebellar cortex (Fig. 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Two are the familiar dorsal and ventral lamellae of the 
    PO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">The dorsal and ventral folds of the DAO constitute two 
    additional lamellae.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Finally, the MA0 is divided into three lamellae-the 
    rostral, the horizontal, and the vertical-with the latter including 
    the dorsal cell outcroppings.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Most of the lamellae appear to be folds of slablike 
    groupings of olivary projection neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">The dorsal and ventral lamellae of the PO and the two 
    parts of the DAO clearly can be considered folds but the three 
    parts of the MA0 are more accurately regarded as fused subunits 
    pig. 9).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">The principal distinguishing property of each lamella is 
    that each unit projects to one of seven corresponding sagittal 
    zones in the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">As shown in Figure 9, the two lamellae of the PO project 
    to two zones in the cerebellar hemisphere.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">The lamellae (folds) of the DAO correspond to two 
    sagittal zones in the anterior lobe and intermediate zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">The three lamellae of the MA0 correspond to three 
    sagittal zones in the anterior and posterior vermal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Thus, the seven lamellae correspond to seven sagittal 
    zones in the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">A nomenclature has not appeared with regard to these 
    zones in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">We suggested that these are homologous to the following 
    zones in the cat (Groenwegen et al., &apos;79): (1) Zone 1 in the 
    rat (Fig. 9) corresponds to zone B in the cat (Groenwegen et al., 
    &apos;79). (2) Zone 2 in the rat (Fig. 9) is homologous to zones C1 
    and C3 in the cat. (3) Zone 3 in the rat (Fig. 9) is homologous to 
    the anterior part of zone A in the cat. (4) Zone 4 is homologous to 
    the posterior part of zone A. (5) Zone 5 is homologous to C2. (6) 
    Zones 6 and 7 are homologous to D.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">The physical edges of each lamella project to an edge of 
    each sagittal zone, at which point there occurs a transition in the 
    zone of the olive that projects to the adjacent strip of cerebellar 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Within a lamella, there is a continuous field of cells 
    projecting onto a continuous surface of cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">The borders of portions of the lamellae appear to be 
    fused in a continuous cell mass both with the MA0 and the lateral 
    bend of the PO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">However, a careful examination of the organization of 
    the projections of neurons shows a discontinuity in cerebellar 
    cortical targets at the points of fusion between the lamellae.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">A third principle of organization is that the olivary 
    complex can be divided into three functional zones on the basis of 
    common connections (Fig. 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">These functional zones may be composed of more than one 
    lamellae.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">They consist of the following: (1) The caudal somatic 
    sensory zone primarily receives from the ascending somatic sensory 
    pathways and includes both lamellae of the DAO (dorsal and ventral 
    folds) and the horizontal lamella of the MA0 (Fig. 9, dotted 
    area).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s286">
    (2) The medial visual and vestibular zone includes the vertical 
    lamella that consists of c and beta in the main body of MA0 along 
    with the minor subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s287">
    This region re-</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">ceives from the mesencephalic visual-vestibular projects 
    to posterior vermis and the flocculus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">(3) The rostral zone receives inputs mainly from 
    telencephalic and diencephalic centers and includes both lamellae 
    of PO and the rostral lamella of MA0 (Fig. 9).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">A fourth principle of organization is revealed by the 
    discovery of a system of bands of cells within the inferior olive 
    rostral to the transition zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Each band includes the totality of projections to a 
    single cerebellar hemispheric lobule.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">If a small injection of HRP were to be made entirely 
    confined within the cerebellar cortical region of a single sagittal 
    zone, then a small cluster of olivary neurons would be retrogradely 
    stained, located entirely within the lamella projecting to that 
    sagittal zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">If, on the other hand, the injection was to straddle two 
    sagittal zones, the two resulting labeled clusters would be located 
    in two olivary lamellae.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Invariably, such clusters are found in adjacent lamellae 
    in the mediolateral direction (Fig. 10).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Finally, a series of overlapping injections covering the 
    lateral portion of an entire single lobule (including the 
    intermediate and lateral, but not the vermal portions) labels a 
    series of olivary cell clusters within several lamellae, which 
    correspond to the sagittal zones within that lobule.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Such olivary cell clusters define a band that traverses 
    the olivary complex and that is oriented perpendicular to the 
    lamellae.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Figure 11 illustrates the organization of a band 
    corresponding to cells projecting to the paramedian lobule.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Bands extending mediolaterally have been identified for 
    several of the cerebellar lobules (Fig. 10).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">These bands are topographically organized within the 
    olive as follows: (1) For lobulus simplex, a band of cells 
    encompasses dorsomedial cell clusters in the MA0 and both lamellae 
    of the PO and medial aspects of the DAO (Fig. 10, vertical 
    lines).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">(2) Lateral and ventral to the band projecting to the 
    lobulus simplex is another band of cells that projects to the 
    paramedian lobule.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">This band traverses to MAO, DAO, and both lamellae of 
    the PO (Fig. 10, gray areas).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">(3) A band of cells occupying more ventral regions in 
    the PO projects to crura I and I1 (Fig. 10, horizontal lines).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">(4) A lateral band that occupies the ventral MA0 and 
    lateral bend of the PO projects to the paraflocculus (Fig. 10, 
    slanted lines).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Overall, the bands are stacked so that the projections 
    to lobulus simplex are dorsal, to paraflocculus are ventral, and to 
    crus I and I1 and paramedian are in between.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Such a banding pattern does not apply to the relatively 
    narrow vermal region that receives afYerents from olivary regions 
    caudal to the transition zone.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s306">Relationship between the 
    lamellar organization and cell bands</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">The current studv reveals Datterns of connectivity not 
    emphasized previously.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Analys&apos;is of results of multiple small HRP 
    injections in single lobules of the cerebellum indicated that small 
    clusters or patches of labeled cells within the olive form the 
    basic units of the bands as well as the lamellae (Fig. 11).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">For example, a patch projecting to the of the paramedian 
    lobule is located in the most medial DAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">This same cluster is also part of the ventral fold 
    (lamella) Of the DAO.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">The Patch Projecting to a slightly lateral area in the 
    paramedian is located in the rostral MAO and a unit of another 
    lamella, the rostra1 lamella Of the MA&apos;&apos; the Of to the 
    lateral paramedian is located in the and forms portions of the 
    dorsal and ventral lamella (Fig. 11).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">The main point is that each cluster or patch within a 
    cell band gives rise to a portion of the fibers in an individual 
    sagittal zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">A complete sagittal Strip is made Up Of C h S - ters or 
    patches of cells from several cell bands.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">These clusters are located physically adjacent to one 
    another in a single olivary subnucleus pig. 11).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">F~~ a group of subclusters all located in the rostral 
    MA0 (the rostral lamella) combine to give rise to a sagittal strip 
    on the media1 aspect of the hemisphere.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">It should be noted that extremely nWOW Sagittal Strips 
    may be visualized by any study of connectivity in which subportions 
    of the lamellar structures are filled with anterogradely 
    transported staining material.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">A more detailed clarification of this postulated 
    Organization Will be presented in later publications.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s318">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s319">This work was supported in 
    part by NIDA grant DA2338 and NIAA grant AA3901 to D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s320">Woodward and by an award from 
    the Biological Humanics Foundation.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s321">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Alley, K., R.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Baker, and J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Simpson (1975) Afferents to the vestibulocerebellum and 
    the origin of the visual climbing fibers in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Brain Res. 98582-589.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Anderson, G., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Nyquist (1983) Origin and sagittal termination areas of 
    cerebro-cerebellar climbing fibre paths in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Pbysiol.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">(Lond.) 337:257-285.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Armstrong, D.M., R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Harvey, and R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Schild (1974) Topographical localization in the 
    olivo-cerebellar projection: An electrophysiological study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Neurol. 154:287-302.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Azizi, S.A., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Burne, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Woodward (1978) Topography of afferent projections to 
    posterior vermal cerebellum of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Abstr. 4:63.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Azizi, S.A., G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Mihailoff, R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Burne, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Woodward (1981) The pontocerebellar system in the rat: 
    An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">I.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Posterior Vermis.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Neurol. 197:543-558.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Azizi, S.A., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Burne, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Woodward (1982) The inferior olivary ~ ~ C ~ , ofthe U S 
    rat: A tecto-olivomidvermal pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="12" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">CC44b.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Berkley, K.J., and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Hand (1978) Projections to the inferior olive of the 
    cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Comparisons of input from the gracile, cuneate and the 
    spinal trigeminal nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Neurol. 18Ot253-264.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Berkley, K.J., and 1.13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Worden (1978) Projections to the inferior olive ofthe 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Comparisons of input from the dorsal column nuclei, the 
    lateral cervical nucleus, the spino-ohvary pathways, the cerebral 
    cortex and the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Neurol. 180:237-252.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Bishop, G.A., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">McCrea, and S.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Kitai (1976) A horseradish peroxidase study of the 
    cortico-olivary projection in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Brain Res. 116;306-311.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Blanks, R.H.I., W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Precht, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Torigoe (1983) Afferent projections to the cerebellar 
    Flocculus in the pigmented rat demonstrated by retrograde transport 
    of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Brain Res. 52;293-306.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Boesten, A.J.P., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Voogd (1975) Projections of the dorsal column nuclei and 
    the spinal cord on the inferior olive in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Neural. 161t215-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Bowman, J.P., and J.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Sladek, Jr. (1973) Morphology of the inferior olivary 
    complex of the rhesus monkey, (Macaca mulatta).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Neurol. 152,.299-316.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Brodal, A. (1940) Experimentelle untersuchungen uber die 
    olivo-cerebellare lokalisation. 2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Ges.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Psychiatr. 169:l-153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Brodal, A. (1976) The olivocerebellar projection in the 
    cat as studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">The projection to the uvula.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Neurol. 166t417-426.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Brodal, A., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Walberg (1977) The olivocerebellar projection in the cat 
    studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">IV.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">The projection to the anterior lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">I72:85-108.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Brodal, A., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Kawamura (1980) Olivocerebellar projection: A review.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Cell Biol. 64:l-140.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Brodal, P., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Brodal (1981) The olivocerebellar projection in the 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Experimental studies with the method of retrograde 
    tracing of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Neurol. 201t375-393.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Brodal, P., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Brodal(1982) Further observations on the olivocerebellar 
    projections in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Brain Res. 45:71-83.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Brown, J.T., V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Chan-Palay, and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Palay (1977) A study of afferent input to the inferior 
    olivary complex in the rat by retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Neurol. 176:l-22.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Burne, R.A., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Eriksson, J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Saint-Cyr, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Woodward (1978) The organization of the pontine 
    projections to lateral cerebellar areas in the rat; Dual zones in 
    the pons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Brain Res. 139:340-347.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Chan-Palay, V., S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Palay, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Brown, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Van Itallie (1977) Sagittal organization of 
    olivocerebellar and reticulocerebellar projections: 
    Autoradiographic studies with 35s-methionine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Erain Res. 30561-576.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Courville, J. (1975) Distribution of olivocerebellar 
    fibers demonstrated by a radioautographic tracing method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Brain Res. 95253-263.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Courville, J., C. de Montigny, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Lamarre (Eds) (1980) The Inferior Olivary Nucleus: 
    Anatomy and Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">New York: Raven Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Edwards, S.B. (1972) The ascending and descending 
    projections of the red nucleus in the cat: An experimental study 
    using an autoradiographic tracing method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Brain Res. 48:45-63.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Eisenman, L.M. (1984) Organization of olivocerebellar 
    uvula in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Evol. 24:l-12.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Frankfurther, A,, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Weber, G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Royce, N.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Strominger, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Harting (1976) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    tecto-olivary projection in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Brain Res. 118:245-257.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Furber, S.E., and C.R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Watson (1983) Organization of the olivocerebellar 
    projection in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Evol. 22132-152.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Gellman, R., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Houk, and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Gibson (1983) Somatosensory properties of the inferior 
    olive of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Neurol. 215t228-243.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Gellman, R., A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Gibson, and 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Houk (1985) Inferior olivary neurons in the awake cat: 
    Detection of contact and passive body displacement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Neurophysiol. 54:40-60.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Graham, J. (1977) An autoradiographic study of the 
    efferent connections of the superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Neurol. 173:629-654.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Groenewegen, H.J., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Voogd (1977) The parasagittal zonation within the 
    olivocerebellar projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Climbing fiber distribution in the vermis of cat 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Neurol. 174:417-488.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Groenewegen, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">J., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Voogd, and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Freedman (1979) The Parasagittal zonation within the 
    olivocerebellar projection. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Climbing fiber distribution in the intermediate and 
    hemispheric parts of cat cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Neurol. 183:551-602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Gwyn, D.G., G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Nicholson, and B.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Flumerfelt (1977) The inferior olivary nucleus of the 
    rat: A light and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Neurol. 174:489-520.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Haroian, A.J. (1982) Cerebello-olivary projections in 
    the rat: An autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Brain Res. 235:125-130.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Henkel, C.K., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Linauts, and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Martin (1975) The origin of the annuloolivary tract with 
    notes on other mesencephalo-olivary pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">A study by the horseradish peroxidase method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Brain Res. 100:145-150.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Hoddevik, G.H., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Brodal, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Walberg (1976) The olivocerebellar projection in the cat 
    studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase. 111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">The projection to the vermal area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Neurol. 169:155-170.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Jeneskog, T. (1983) Zonal termination of the 
    tecto-olivocerebellar pathway in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Brain Res. 49:353-362.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Jenkins, G.B. (1905) A study of the morphology of the 
    inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Rec. 10t317-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Kalil, K. (1979) Projection of the cerebellar and dorsal 
    column nuclei upon the inferior olive in the rhesus monkey: An 
    autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Neurol. 188r43-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Kooy, F.H. (1917) The inferior 10:205-369.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Kotchabhakdi, N., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Walberg, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Brodal (1978) The olivocerebellar projection in the cat 
    studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">VII.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">The projection to lobulus simplex, crus I and 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Neurol. 182:293-314.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Larsell, 0. (1952) The morphogenesis and adult pattern 
    of the lobules and fissures of the cerebellum of the white rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Neurol. 97:281-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Larson, B., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Miller, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Oscarsson (1969a) A spinocerebellar climbing fiber path 
    activated by the flexor reflex afferents from all four limbs.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">(Lond.) 201:641-649.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Larson, B., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Miller, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Oscarsson 11969b) Termination and functional 
    organization of the dorsolateral spino-olivocerebellar path.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">(Lond.) 203r611-640.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Linauts, M., and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Martin (1978a) An autoradiographic study of 
    midbrain-diencephalic projections to the inferior olivary nucleus 
    in the opossum (Didelphis virginiana).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Neurol. 179:325-354.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Linauts, M., and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Martin (1978b) The organization of olivo-cerebellar 
    projection in the opossum, Didelphis virginiana, as revealed by the 
    retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Neurol. 179~355-382.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Mabuchi, M., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Kusama (1970) Mesodiencephalic projections to the 
    inferior olive and the vestibular and perihypoglossal nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Brain Res. 17:133-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Maekawa, K., and J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Simpson (1973) Climbing fiber responses evoked in 
    vestibulocerebellum of rabbit from visual system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Neurophysiol. 36:649-666.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Maekawa, K., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Takeda (1979) Origin of descending afferents to the 
    rostra1 part of dorsal cap of inferior olive which transfers 
    contralateral optic activities to the flocculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Brain Res. 172:393-405.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Martin, G.F., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Dom, J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">King, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Robards, and C.R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Watson (1975) The inferior olivary nucleus of the 
    opossum (Didelphis marsupialis virginiana), its organization and 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Neurol. 160.507-534.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Martin, G.F., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Culberson, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Laxon, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Linauts, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Panneton, and 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Tschismadia (1980) Afferent connections of the inferior 
    olivary nucleus with preliminary notes on their development.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Studies using the NorthAmerican opossum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Courville et al.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">(eds): The Inferior Olivary Nucleus: Anatomy and 
    Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">New York: Raven Press, pp 35-73.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Martin, G.F., G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Bishop, J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Culberson, J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">King, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Laxson, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Linauts, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Panneton (1982) Spino-olivocerebellar circuits in the 
    NorthAmerican opossum with notes on their development.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">In S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Palay and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Chan-Palay (eds): The Cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">New Vistas.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Springer-Verlag pp. 162-189.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">McGrane, M.K., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Eriksson, R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Burne, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Woodward (1977) The inferior olivary complex in the rat: 
    Gross nuclear organization and topography of olivocerebellar 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Abst. 3:59.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Mesulam, M-M. (1976) The blue reaction product in 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: Incubation parameters 
    and visibility.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Cytochem. 24t1273-1280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Mesulam, M-M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue 
    reaction product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neuronal 
    afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Miller, R.A., and N.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Strominger (1973) Efferent connections of the red 
    nucleus in the brainstem and spinal cord of the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Neurol. 152:327-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Mizuno, N. (1966) An experimental study of the 
    spino-olivary fibers in the rabbit and the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Neurol. 127t267-292.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Mizuno, N., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Mochizuki, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Akimoto, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Matsushima (1973) Pretectal projections to the inferior 
    olive in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Neurol. 39:498-506.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Molinari, H.H. (1984) Ascending somatosensory projection 
    to the dorsal accessory olive: An anatomical study in cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Neurol. 223:llO-123.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Oka, H., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Jinnai, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Yamamoto (1979) The parieto-rubro-olivary pathway in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Brain Res. 37:115-125.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Onodera, S. (1984) Olivary projections from the 
    mesodiencephalic structures in the cat studied by means of axonal 
    transport of horseradish peroxidase and tritiated amino acids.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Neurol. 227~37-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Oscarsson, O., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Sjolund (1977a) The ventral spino-olivocerebellar system 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Identification of five paths and their termination in 
    the cerebellar anterior lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Brain Res. 28:469-486.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Oscarsson, 0.. and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Sjolund (1977h) The ventral spino-olivocerehellar system 
    in the cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Termination zones in the cerebellar posterior lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Brain Res. 28:487-503.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Oscarsson, O., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Sjolund (1977~) The ventral spino-olivocerebellar system 
    in the cat. 111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Functional characteristics of the five paths.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Brain Res. 8t505-520.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Payne, J.N., S.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Wharton, and 1.N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Lawes (1985) Quantitative analysis of the topographical 
    organization of olivocerebellar projections in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Neuroscience 15403-415.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Rutherford, J.G., and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Gwyn (1980) A light and electron microscopic study of 
    the inferior olivary nucleus of the squirrel monkey, Saimiri 
    sciureus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Neurol. 189:127-155.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Saint-Cyr, J.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Courville (1979) Projection from the vestibular nuclei 
    to the inferior olive in the cat An autoradiographic and 
    horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Brain Res. 165:189-200.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Saint-Cyr, J.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Courville (1981) Sources of descending afferents to the 
    inferior olive from the upper brain stem in the cat as revealed by 
    the retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Neurol. 198.567-581.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Saint-Cyr, J.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Courville (1982) Descending projections to the inferior 
    olive from the mesencephalon and superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Brain Res. 45333-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Sjolund, B (1978) The ventral spino-olivocerebellar 
    system in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Supraspinal control of spinal transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Brain Res. 33509-522.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Sousa-Pinto, A. (1969) Experimental anatomical 
    demonstration of a corticoolivary projection from area 6 
    (supplementary motor area?)</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Brain Res. 16:73-83.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Sousa-Pinto, A,, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Brodal (1969) Demonstration of a somatotopical pattern 
    in the cortico-olivary projection in the cat: An 
    experimentalanatomical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Brain Res. 8:364-386.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Strominger, N.L., T.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Truscott, R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Miller, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Royce (1979) An autoradiographic study of the 
    ruboolivary tract in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Neurol. 183:33-46.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Sugimoto, T., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Mizuno, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Nomura, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Nakamura (1980) Fastigioolivary fibers in the cat as 
    revealed by the autoradiographic tracing method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Brain Res. 199r443-446.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Swenson, R.S., and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Castro (1983a) The afferent connections of the inferior 
    olivary complex in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">An anterograde study using autoradiographic and axonal 
    degeneration techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Neuroscience 8:259-275.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Swenson, R.S., and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Castro (1983b) The afferent connections of the inferior 
    olivary complex in rats: A study using the retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase. 166:329-341.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Taber, E. (1961) The cytoarchitecture of the brainstem 
    stem nuclei of Cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Neurol. 116:27-69.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Takeda, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Maekawa (1976) The origin of the pretecto-olivary 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">A study using the horseradish peroxidase method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Brain Res. 117:319-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Takeda, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Maekawa (1980) Bilateral visual inputs to the dorsal cap 
    of inferior olive: Differential localization and inhibitory 
    interactions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Brain Res. 39:461-471.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Tolbert, D.L., L.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Massopust, M.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Murphy, and P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Young (1976) The anatomical organization of the 
    cerebello-olivary projection in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Neurol. 170525-544.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Walberg, F. (1956) Descending connections to the 
    inferior olive: An experimental study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Neurol. 104:77-173.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Walberg, F. (1974) Descending connections from the 
    mesencephalon to the inferior olive: An experimental study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Brain Res. 21: 145-156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Walberg, F., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Nordby, K.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Hoffman, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Hollander (1981) Olivary afferents from the pretectal 
    nuclei in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Embryol. 161:291-304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Walberg, F. (1982) The trigemino-olivary projection in 
    the cat as studied with retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Brain Res. 45:lOl-107.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Watson, C.R.R., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Herron (1977) The olivary complex of marsupials.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Neurol. 176:527-538.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Weber, J.T., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Harting (1980) The effrent projections of the pretectal 
    complex: An autoradiographic and horseradish peroxidase 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Brain Res. 194:l-28.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Weber, J.T., G.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Partlow, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Harting (1978) The projection of superior colliculus 
    upon the inferior olivary complex of the cat: An autoradiographic 
    and horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Brain Res. 144:369-377.</S>
  </References>

</File>

