<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Cholinergic Projection to the Dorsal Cap of the Inferior Olive 
  of the Rat, Rabbit, and Monkey</Title>

  <Authors>N.H. BARMACK, M. FAGERSON, AND P. ERRICO</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The inferior olive is divided into several subnuclei that 
    receive specific sensory information.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The caudal dorsal cap of the medial accessory subdivision 
    of the inferior olive receives horizontal optokinetic information 
    from the nucleus of the optic tract.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The immediately subjacent p-nucleus receives vertical 
    vestibular information mediated by a GABAergc pathway originating 
    from the ipsilateral descending and medial vestibular nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">None of the transmitters to the dorsal cap have been 
    identified.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Using choline acetyltransferase (CUT) 
    immunohistochemistry, we have identified a cholinergic pathway that 
    terminates exclusively in the dorsal cap of rats and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">No other division of the inferior olive received a 
    significant cholinergic innervation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">In the rabbit, immunostaining for ChAT reveals a weaker 
    and more diffuse cholinergic innervation of both the dorsal cap and 
    the subjacent p-nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">In rats and rabbits we injected iontophoretically the 
    orthograde tracer Phaseolus vulgaris Ieucoagglutinin (PHA-L) into 
    the medial and descending vestibular nuclei (MVN, DVN) as well as 
    the nucleus prepositus hypoglossi (NPH) in order to trace the 
    possible origin of the cholinergic projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">PHA-L injections into the NPH and medial aspect of the MVN 
    labeled terminals within the contralateral dorsal cap.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">PHA-L injections in the central and lateral aspects of 
    the MVN as well as the DVN labeled the ipsilateral p-nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Pressure injections of wheat germ agglutinin-horseradish 
    peroxidase (WGA-HRP) in the caudal dorsal cap of the rabbit 
    inferior olive demonstrated a predominantly contralateral 
    projection to the dorsal cap from the lateral aspect of the NPH.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">However, pressure injections of HRP into the caudal 
    dorsal cap combined with ChAT immunohistochemistry in the rabbit 
    demonstrated that most of the neurons of the NPH that projected to 
    the dorsal cap were not cholinergic, and that most of the 
    CUT-positive neurons within the NPH occupied a more ventral 
    location than the neurons within the NPH that were retrogradely 
    labeled from the HRP injection into the contralateral dorsal 
    cap.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">In the rat, we made lesions in the MVN, DVN and NPH by 
    injection of ibotenic acid (0.3-0.5 blj, in an attempt to deplete 
    the dorsal cap of the inferior olive of its cholinergic input.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Lesions confined to the NPH and medial aspect of the MVN 
    of the rat caused a loss of ChAT staining in the contralateral 
    dorsal cap.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Lesions placed more laterally within the MVN or DVN 
    failed to deplete ChAT-positive terminals in the contralateral or 
    ipsilateral dorsal caps.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The dorsal cap of the rat and monkey receives a discrete 
    cholinergic projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">In the rat, this projection originates from the 
    contralateral NPH.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">In the rabbit, the caudal inferior olive receives a weak 
    cholinergc projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">The dorsal cap receives a projection from the 
    contralateral NPH.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">However, this projection is mediated by a non-cholinergic 
    transmitter.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">a 19% fi&apos;iiileyLiss.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Inc.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The inferior olivary complex, the exclusive source of 
    climbing fibers to the cerebellum, is characterized by a 
    topographic organization of sensory inputs from visual (Maekawa and 
    Simpson, &apos;73; Alley et al., &apos;75; Frankfurter et al., 
    &apos;76; Weber et al., &apos;78; Maekawa and Takeda, &apos;79; 
    Takeda and Maekawa, &apos;80; Saint-Cyr and Courdle, &apos;82; 
    Kawamura and Onodera, &apos;84; Leonard et al., &apos;88; Kyuhou 
    and Matsuzaki, &apos;911, vestibular (Walberg, &apos;74; Saint-Cyr 
    and Courville, &apos;791, and somatosensory (Martin et al., 
    &apos;75; Berkley and Hand, &apos;78a,b; Gellman et al., &apos;83; 
    Huerta et al., &apos;85; Molinari et al., &apos;91) systems.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">One class of visual input originates from the ipsilateral 
    accessory optic system as well as the ipsilateral nucleus of the 
    optic tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">It consists of physiologically characterized 
    directionally-selective velocity-sensitive visual information and 
    it terminates in the dorsal cap of Kooy and ventrolateral outgrowth 
    of the inferior olive (Kooy, &apos;16; Maekawa and Simpson, 
    &apos;73; Alley et al., &apos;75; Maekawa and Takeda, &apos;79; 
    Takeda and Maekawa, &apos;80; Kawamura and Onodera, &apos;84; 
    Leonard et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">This class of visual input appears to be organized about 
    a visual coordinate system that is congruent with the axes of 
    rotation of the semicircular canals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Each axis of rotation is represented in a different 
    rostral-caudal region within the dorsal cap (Leonard et al., 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">A second visually related input, less well characterized 
    physiologically, originates from the contralateral superior 
    colliculus and terminates within the caudal third of the medial 
    accessory olive just ventral and lateral to the p-nucleus 
    (Frankfurter et al., &apos;76; Weber et al., &apos;78; Saint-Cyr 
    and Courville, &apos;82; Kyuhou and Matsuzaki, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The vestibular input to the inferior olive appears to 
    arise from the ipsilateral medial vestibular and descending 
    vestibular nuclei (MVN, DVN).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">This vestibular input terminates in the ipsilateral 
    p-nucleus (Walberg, &apos;74; Saint-Cyr and Courville, &apos;79) 
    and bilaterally in the dorsal medial cell column (Saint-Cyr and 
    Courville, &apos;79) Immunohistochemical investigations have 
    demonstrated that the vestibular input to the p-nucleus is 
    GABAergic (Nelson et al., &apos;86, &apos;89; Fredette and 
    Mugnaini, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The activity of neurons in the p-nucleus of the rabbit is 
    modulated by vestibular stimulation that activates both the 
    vertical semicircular canals and utricular otoliths (Barmack et 
    al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The polarity of this vestibularly-modulated activity is 
    consistent with the histochemically defined GABAergic 
    vestibulo-olivary pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Activity is decreased during ipsilateral roll and 
    increased during contralateral roll (Barmack et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The inferior olive offers an attractive opportunity for 
    studying the influence of specific neurotransmitters on the 
    processing of sensory information by specific cerebellar pathways 
    for three reasons: 1) The inferior olive is composed of 
    functionally discrete groups of neurons located in physiologically 
    accessible reeons within the inferior olive (Barmack and Hess.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">&apos;Sob; Leonard et al., &apos;88; Barmack et al., 
    &apos;89). 2) It is possible to modulate systematically the 
    discharge of these groups of neurons by parametrically varying the 
    sensory stimuli (see above). 3) The groups of olivary neurons that 
    receive either visual (Barmack and Hess, &apos;80b; Leonard et al., 
    &apos;88) or vestibular (Barmack et al., &apos;89) information 
    project to the cerebellar flocculus (Alley et al., &apos;75) and 
    nodulus (Balaban and Henry, &apos;88; Takeda and Maekawa, 
    &apos;89a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">These cerebellar regions have obvious functional 
    importance for both short-term and long-term control of reflexive 
    movements (Fernandez and Fredrickson, &apos;64; Singleton, 
    &apos;67; Barmack, &apos;79; Ito, &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Recently we have studied the distribution of a 
    cholinergic mossy fiber pathway to the cerebellum of several 
    mammals (Barmack et al., &apos;92b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">We have shown that this cholinergic pathway arises 
    predominantly from secondary vestibular neurons whose cell bodies 
    are located bilaterally in the medial vestibular nucleus (MNV) and 
    the descending vestibular nucleus (DVN), as well as the nucleus 
    prepositus hypoglossi (NPH) (Barmack et al., &apos;92c).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">In the present experiment we have investigated the 
    cholinergic innervation of the dorsal cap of rat, rabbit and 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">In the rat we have traced the origin of this cholinergic 
    projection to the contralateral nucleus prepositus hypoglossi and 
    the medial aspect of the contralateral MVN.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">In the rabbit, the cholinergic innervation of the 
    inferior olive is more diffuse and not restricted to the dorsal 
    cap.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">In the monkey, like the rat, the cholinergic innervation 
    is restricted to the dorsal cap.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">In the rat and rabbit we have used orthograde tracers to 
    demonstrate a projection to the contralateral dorsal cap from the 
    NPH.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">In the rat, this projection is cholinergic.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">In the rabbit, it probably is not.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">A preliminary report of these findings, in which the 
    projection from the NPH to the dorsal cap was incorrectly described 
    as an ipsilateral projection has been published previously (Barmack 
    et al., &apos;91).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s47">METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Fifteen rats, two monkeys, and seven rabbits were used in 
    these experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Some of these animals were also used in previous 
    investigations of the cholinergic innervation of the cerebellum 
    (Barmack et al., &apos;92a-c).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s50">Choline acetyltransferase 
    (ChAT) immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The protocol for CMT imrnunohistochemistry was similar to 
    that reported previously (Eckenstein et al., &apos;88; Barmack et 
    al., &apos;92c).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">A mouse antiserum to rat CUT, Mouse-aRat-CUT, was used to 
    examine the cholinergic projection to the inferior olive of the rat 
    and a rat antiserum to pig CUT, Rat-aPig-ChAT, was used for 
    immunostaining of the inferior olives of rabbits and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">These antibodies were prepared and characterized 
    previously and have been shown to stain cholinergic neurons 
    specifically (Eckenstein et al., &apos;81: &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Deep anesthesia was induced in rats and rabbits with an 
    intramuscular injection of a mixture of ketamine hydrochloride (50 
    mgikg), xylazine (6 mgikg), and acepromazine maleate (1.2 
    mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Anesthesia was induced in monkeys with an intraperitoneal 
    injection of sodium pentobarbital (60 mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Following the induction of anesthesia, the heart was 
    exposed and the descending aorta was clamped.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">A cannula was inserted from the apex of the left 
    ventricle into the dorsal aorta, and the right atrium was 
    opened.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The blood was rinsed with 250-500 ml of saline at 100 cm 
    pressure.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The rinse was followed by perfusion with 500-1,000 ml of 
    4% paraformaldehyde, 0.159 saturated picric acid, in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffered saline (PBS), pH = 7.2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The fixative was given over a period of 30 minutes and 
    was followed by a rinse with cold 0.1 M phosphate buffer (PB), pH = 
    7.2 (4°C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The brain was then removed and cryoprotected in lo%), 
    2094 and 30% sucrose in 0.1 M PB, pH = 7.2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The brainstem was cut into a block that was attached to 
    thin pieces of cork with embedding compound and then frozen by 
    immersion into isopentane cooled with liquid nitrogen.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Frozen sections (30-40 KM) were cut and collected in cold 
    0.1 M PB, pH 7.4, in a small plastic grid divided into separate 
    collection baskets with a floor of nylon mesh.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">ChAT immunohistochemistry was performed on free floating 
    sections as follows: 1) Sections were washed overnight at room 
    temperature in 0.1 M PR, pH = 7.4. 2) Sections were washed with 
    three 5 minute changes of 0.1 M Tris buffered saline (TBS, 0.1 M 
    Tris, 0.15 M sodium chloride, pH = 7.6) and transferred to 96-well 
    microplate tissue wells with a polished glass rod.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">These microplate tissue wells were used for primary 
    antibody, secondary antibody and PAP incubations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The sections were pretreated at room temperature in a 
    10%&apos; normal rabbit serum, 2% bovine serum albumin (BSA), 0.5% 
    Triton X-100 in TBS for 2 hours followed by three 10-minute rinses 
    in TBS.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">They were gently agitated on an orbital shaker during 
    this and subsequent procedures. 3) Brainstem sections were 
    incubated overnight in the primary antiserum, diluted 
    1:1,000-1:2,000 in TBS containing 2% BSA, 10% normal rat serum, 
    0.5% Triton X-100, and 0.1% sodium azide. 4) Sections were 
    transferred to the larger collection baskets and washed with three 
    10-minute changes of TBS. 5 ) Sections were transferred to the 
    microplate tissue wells and incubated for 60 minutes in freshly 
    prepared rabbit or goat a-mouse or a-rat secondary antibodies 
    (Organon Teknika Gorp., Durham, NC) diluted 1:50 in TBS, containing 
    2% BSA, 10% rat serum, and 0.2% Triton X-100. 6 ) Sections were 
    transferred to the larger collection baskets and washed in three 
    10-minute changes of TBS. 7) Sections were then transferred to the 
    microplate tissue wells and incubated for 90 minutes in freshly 
    prepared mouse or rat peroxidaseantiperoxidase (PAP, 
    Sternberger-Meyer Immunocytochemicals, Jnc., Baltimore, MD) diluted 
    1:50 in TBS. 8) Sections were transferred to the larger collection 
    baskets and washed in three 10-minute changes of TBS. 9) Steps 5-8 
    were repeated. 10) Sections were treated for 15 minutes with 
    diaminobenzidine (DAB) 1 mgiml in 0.1 M TBS, pH = 7.6, containing 
    0.01% HzOz.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Sections were then rinsed in 0.1 M PB (pH = 7.41, 
    mounted, dried, cleared, and coverslipped.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The specificities of the primary and secondary antibodies 
    were tested by processing control sections in which these 
    antibodies were omitted.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s70">Orthograde transport of 
    phaseolus leucoagglutinin (PHA-L)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Rats and rabbits were anesthetized with intramuscular 
    injections of ketamine hydrochloride (50 mgikg), xylazine (6 
    mgikg), and acepromazine maleate (1.2 mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">The brainsterns of both rats and rabbits were exposed by 
    making an opening through the dura mater overlying the cisterna 
    magna.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">A micropipette containing a solution of 2.5% PHA-L in 0.1 
    M PBS (pH = 7.4), was inserted under direct vision into the NPH, 
    MVN, or DVN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">PHA-L was iontophoretically injected into the brainstem 
    by means of 10 FA cathodal pulses lasting 10 seconds, with a 50% 
    duty cycle (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; Ter Horst et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Each injection lasted 10 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Several (3-5) injections were made along the 
    medial-lateral and rostral-caudal extent of the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">After a 3-6 day survival period, the animals were 
    anesthetized (see above) and transcardially perfused.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">A brief saline flush was followed by a 4% 
    paraformaldehyde, 0.15% picric acid solution in 0.1 M PBS, pH = 
    7.2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The perfusion was terminated, cryoprotected, and frozen 
    sections (30-40 bm) were cut and collected as described above.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">A double PAP immunohistochemical procedure, with DAB as 
    the chromagen as described above, was used to identify the presence 
    of orthogradely transported PHA-L.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s81">Retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase (HRP) and wheat germ agglutinin-HRP 
    (WGA-HRP)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Four pigmented rabbits (weight 0.8-1.7 kg) were 
    anesthetized intravenously with a-chloralose (50 mgikg) and 
    urethane (500 mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Rectal temperature was also monitored and maintained at 
    37°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">The brainstems of the rabbits were exposed by making an 
    opening through the dura mater overlying the cisterna magna.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">A micropipette containing a 30% solution of horseradish 
    peroximdase (HRP) or a 3% solution of wheat-germ 
    agglutinin-horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRPI NaCl was inserted into 
    the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The electrode was advanced toward the dorsal cap of the 
    inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">The characteristic optokinetically evoked activity of the 
    neurons in the caudal aspect of the dorsal cap was used to localize 
    the tip of the microelectrode (Barmack and Hess, &apos;Sob).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">Subsequently, a pressure injection of HRP or WGAHRP 
    (20-100 nl) was made in the dorsal cap over a period of 10 
    minutes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Following a 2-3 day postoperative survival, the rabbits 
    were deeply anesthetized with sodium pentobarbital (60 mgikg).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">For single label experiments, the rabbits were 
    subsequently perfused transcardially with 0.9% saline, followed by 
    1.0% paraformaldehyde and 1.25% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M PBS (pH = 
    7.4), lasting 20-30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">For combined ChAT-HRP double-label experiments, rabbits 
    were perfused with 0.9% saline, followed by a fixing solution 
    containing 2.5% paraformaldehyde, 0.15% picric acid, and 0.20% 
    glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M PBS, pH = 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">The perfusions were terminated with a rinse of 0.1 M PBS, 
    pH = 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">The brains were removed and cryoprotected with lo%, 20%, 
    and 30% sucrose in 0.1 M PBS, pH = 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">The brainstem was cut, mounted onto cork with OCT 
    compound, and frozen in isopentane cooled with liquid nitrogen.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">Frozen sections (30-40 km) were cut and collected in cold 
    0.1 M PBS; pH = 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">A DAB-stabilized, CoC12intensified, tetramethylbenzidine 
    (TMB) reaction (Rye et a]., &apos;84; Olucha et al., &apos;85) was 
    used to demonstrate the presence of retrogradely transported 
    tracers.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s97">Lesions of the vestibular 
    complex</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">Rats were anesthetized (as above) and the brainstems were 
    exposed through the cisterna magna.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">A glass micropipette with a tip diameter of approximately 
    10 km was advanced under direct vision towards different regions of 
    the vestibular complex without penetrating the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">A total of 0.3-0.5 kl of ibotenic acid (20-40 kgiml) was 
    injected at three separate sites in the MVN andior NPH.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Alternatively, electrolytic lesions were made in these 
    nuclei (50 PA, 60 seconds, electrode negative).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Electrolytic lesions were made in a triangular pattern 
    more laterally into the medial and descending vestibular nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">After a survival period of 5-7 days the rats were 
    reanesthetized and transcardially perfused (as above).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">The brainstem was removed, cryoprotected, and cut on a 
    cryostat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">Sections were processed with a double PAP protocol for 
    ChAT immunohistochemistry as described above.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s106">Histological 
    reconstruction</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">For each histological procedure involving ChAT 
    immunohistochemistry, orthograde and retrograde tracers, and 
    lesion-induced ChAT depletion, the distribution of labeled cells or 
    tracer injections within the vestibular complex was plotted on maps 
    of the vestibular complex and inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">The map of the vestibular complex follows the 
    designation ofMeessen and Olszewski (&apos;49).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s109">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s110">ChAT-immunoreactivity in 
    the dorsal cap of the inferior olive of the rat, rabbit, and 
    monkey</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">l h e entire caudal-rostra1 extent of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal cap</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    of the caudal-rostra1 extent of the dorsal cap of the ChAT-positive 
    terminals (Fig. 1A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">The CUT-</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">rat contained ChAT-positive terminals (Fig. 1A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">The <labelingDescription>CUTpositive 
    immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> was restricted to 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap</labelingLocation> from its most 
    caudal extent to the most rostral aspect where 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal cap</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    merges with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the principal 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLocation> via <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    ventrolateral outgrowth</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 1A-D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The ventrolateral 
    outgrowth</neuroanatomicalLocation> contained only 
    <labelingDescription>a few CUT-positive 
    terminals</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">No <labelingLocation>olivary</labelingLocation> neurons 
    were ChAT-positive.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">In the rat, <labelingLocation>dorsal 
    cap</labelingLocation> neurons were distributed heterogeneously.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">Regions of <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    cap</labelingLocation> were <labelingDescription>free of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> and therefore were 
    <labelingDescription>without ChAT-labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> (Fig. lB-D).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">Unlike the cholinergic innervation of 
    <connxTermination>the dorsal cap</connxTermination> of the rat, the 
    cholinergic innervation of <connxTermination>the dorsal 
    cap</connxTermination> of the rabbit was difficult to 
    differentiate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">It was composed of fine beaded axonal branches.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">These axons were present along the entire caudal 
    asp&amp; of <labelingLocation>the inferior 
    olive</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">A greater concentration of <labelingDescription>these 
    beaded axonal terminals</labelingDescription> could be observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap</labelingLocation>, but also 
    within <labelingLocation>the p-nucleus </labelingLocation>(Fig. 
    2).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">In the monkey, <labelingDescription>a discrete 
    cholinergic projection</labelingDescription> was observed 
    throughout <labelingLocation>the rostral-caudal extent of the 
    dorsal cap</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">Figure 3A illustrates the location and extent of 
    <labelingDescription>ChATpositive terminals</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the monkey inferior 
    olive</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">These 
    <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> were found in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial aspect of the dorsal 
    cap</labelingLocation> at its most rostral extent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">Throughout the remaining rostral-caudal extent of 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    cap</labelingLocation>,<labelingDescription> the 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral third of the dorsal cap</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">This corresponds to <labelingLocation>the region of the 
    inferior olive</labelingLocation> that was retrogradely labeled 
    following <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections into 
    <injectionLocation>the flocculus</injectionLocation> of the monkey 
    (Langer et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128"><labelingDescription>The heterogeneous cell 
    distribution</labelingDescription> within<labelingLocation> the 
    dorsal cap</labelingLocation> of the monkey was less apparent than 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">However, in the monkey there were 
    <labelingDescription>ChAT-positive bands of varying 
    width</labelingDescription>, alternately spaced with bands of 
    terminals that were not stained (Fig. 3C,D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">In both the rat and monkey no other areas of 
    <labelingLocation>the inferior olive</labelingLocation> other than 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap</labelingLocation> contained 
    <labelingDescription>ChAT-positive 
    terminals</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s131">Brainstem projections to 
    the dorsal cap as revealed by the orthograde transport of PHA-L 
    iontophoretically injected into the nucleus prepositus hypoglossi 
    and the medial and descending vestibular nuclei in the rat and 
    rabbit</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132"><exptLabel>Iontophoretic injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    NPH, MVN and DVN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> resulted in 
    orthograde transport of PHA-L to 
    <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap and the beta 
    nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133"><exptLabel>A large injection into <injectionLocation>the 
    NPH, MVN and DVN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> of rat labeled 
    <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> in both 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap and the 
    p-nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A-C,E).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><labelingDescription>Some 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were also labeled in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral aspect of the medial accessory 
    olive</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4B,D).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injections restricted to <injectionLocation>the MVN and the 
    DVN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labeled 
    <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the p-nucleus</labelingLocation> without labeling 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    5).</S></TTE>

    <TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136">However,<exptLabel>small iontophoretic injections of 
      <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> restricted to 
      <injectionLocation>the medial aspect of the MVN and lateral 
      aspect of the NPH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> resulted in 
      labeling of <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> 
      confined to <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 6).</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">Thus, the evidence from these orthograde tracer 
    experiments suggests that the cholinergic input to the dorsal cap 
    arises from the NPH, with a possible, but lesser contribution from 
    the most medial aspect of the MVN.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><exptLabel>Iontophoretic injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    NPH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> of the rabbit resulted in 
    orthograde transport of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> to 
    <labelingDescription>terminals</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal cap that were contralateral to the 
    injection site</labelingLocation> (Fig 7).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139">In 
    Figure 7A an experiment is illustrated in which a 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injection was largely 
    restricted to <injectionLocation>the right 
    NPH</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">It was difficult to confine 
    the injection of a midline structure to just one side and a small 
    amount of the <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> also diffused 
    into <injectionSpread>the left NPH</injectionSpread> (Fig. 
    7&amp;).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141">Some of the tracer diffused 
    laterally into <injectionSpread>the right MVN</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">The <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections 
    labeled <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> that 
    descended towards <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the inferior 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLandmark> primarily to the right of the 
    midline (Fig. 7B).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s143">These fibers crossed the 
    midline just above <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the inferior 
    olive</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to provide <labelingDescription>a 
    dense innervation</labelingDescription> of <connxTermination>the 
    left dorsal cap</connxTermination> (Fig. 7B,C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s144">This 
    midline crossing point is indicated by an arrow in Fig. 7B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145"><labelingDescription>A less dense 
    innervation</labelingDescription> could be observed in 
    <connxTermination>the right dorsal cap</connxTermination> (Fig. 
    7B).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146"><labelingDescription>A sparse 
    innervation</labelingDescription> of <connxTermination>the right 
    p-nucleus and medial accessory olive</connxTermination> could be 
    seen as a result of the lateral spread of the injected 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> into <injectionSpread>the 
    right MVN</injectionSpread> (Fig. 7B).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s147">The 
    projection from <connxOrigin>the MVN</connxOrigin> to 
    <connxTermination>the olive</connxTermination> was predominantly 
    ipsilateral.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s148">Brainstem projections to 
    the dorsal cap as revealed by the retrograde transport of WGA-HRP 
    injected in the dorsal cap of the inferior olive of the rabbit</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">In two rabbits <exptLabel>a 3% solution of 
    <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> (20-50 nl) was pressure 
    injected into <injectionLocation>the caudal dorsal 
    cap</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s150">This 
    injection labeled two major sources of afferents to 
    <connxTermination>the dorsal cap</connxTermination>: 1) 
    <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral nucleus of the optic 
    tract</labelingLocation>, the source of visual directionally 
    specific input to <connxTermination>the caudal dorsal 
    cap</connxTermination>; and 2) <labelingLocation>The contralateral 
    nucleus prepositus hypoglossi (NPH)</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151"><labelingDescription>The retrograde labeling of 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral aspect 
    of the NPH</labelingLocation> is illustrated in Figure 8.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">The schematic illustration in Figure 8A maps the 
    distribution of<labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> within<labelingLocation>the 
    NPH</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s153">This distribution extends 
    slightly into <labelingLocation>the medial aspect of the 
    MVN</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8A).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s154">ChATand HRP-labeled 
    neurons in the nucleus prepositus hypoglossi (NPH) following 
    pressure injections of HRP into the dorsal cap of the rabbit</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">In one rabbit 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> (100 nl) was 
    injected into <injectionLocation>the caudal inferior 
    olive</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s156">The 
    injection site was large.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s157">It included both 
    <injectionSpread>the right dorsal cap and right 
    p-nucleus</injectionSpread>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s158">Smaller amounts of the 
    injected HRP also labeled <injectionSpread>the left dorsal cap and 
    left p-nucleus</injectionSpread> (Fig. 9A).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159"><labelingDescription>Retrograde labeling of 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
    MVN and DVN</labelingLocation> as well as both <labelingLocation>
    the ipsilateral and contralateral NPH</labelingLocation> was 
    observed (Fig. 9).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160"><labelingDescription>Retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
    MVN</labelingLocation> was observed more caudally (Fig. 9C4,5).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161"><labelingDescription>Retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
    DVN</labelingLocation> was observed more rostrally (Fig. 9C1-3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">In agreement with a previous investigation, 
    <labelingDescription>ChA&apos;l&apos;-labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the vestibular 
    complex</labelingLocation> were observed primarily in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal aspect of the MVN</labelingLocation> 
    (Barmack et al., &apos;92c).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s163">While the HRP injection in 
    this experiment was too large to permit conclusion concerning the 
    ipsilateral or contralateral origins of the projection 
    to<connxTermination> the inferior olive</connxTermination> from 
    <connxOrigin>the vestibular complex</connxOrigin>, it did permit us 
    to determine whether any of the projection from <connxOrigin>the 
    NPH</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the dorsal 
    cap</connxTermination> was cholinergic.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s164">A total 
    of <labelingDescription>only two cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the NPH</labelingLocation> were double labeled 
    for both ChAT and HRP.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s165">None of the 
    <labelingDescription>HRP-labeled cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the right MVN, DVN, and NPH</labelingLocation> 
    was also labeled for ChAT.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s166">These data agree with the 
    relative paucity of the ChAT innervation of <connxTermination>the 
    dorsal cap</connxTermination> in the rabbit and suggest that the 
    projection to <connxTermination>the dorsal cap</connxTermination> 
    from <connxOrigin>the contralateral NPH</connxOrigin> and the 
    projection to <connxTermination>the p-nucleus</connxTermination> 
    from <connxOrigin>the ipsilateral MVN and DVN</connxOrigin> must be 
    mediated by another transmitter.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s167">Degeneration of the 
    cholinergic projection to the dorsal cap caused by lesions of the 
    nucleus prepositus hypoglossi and medial vestibular nucleus in the 
    rat</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Unilateral pressure injections of ibotenic acid or 
    electrolytic lesions were made in the region of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the NPH and MVN</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    in four rats (Fig. 10).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Figure 10A indicates the extent of an ibotenic acid 
    lesion in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the NPH and 
    MVN</neuroanatomicalLocation> in one of these rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">The black area indicates the complete absence of neurons 
    while the shaded area indicates partial cell loss.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">Most of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    NPH</neuroanatomicalLocation> was destroyed while only a small 
    portion of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    MVN</neuroanatomicalLocation> was affected.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">This lesion resulted in <labelingDescription>reduced 
    ChAT-immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> ipsilateral to the 
    lesion (Fig.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">IOC).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">This decrease in <labelingDescription>ChAT positive 
    terminals</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    cap</labelingLocation> was observed only if a lesion encroached 
    upon <neuroanatomicalLocation>the NPH</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">In two rats, electrolytic lesions restricted to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral aspect of the MVN and the 
    medial aspect of the DVN</neuroanatomicalLocation> caused no 
    detectable loss of <labelingDescription>ChAT-positive 
    immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilatcral dorsal cap</labelingLocation>.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s176">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s177">the cholinergic 
    projection to the dorsal cap</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">The immunohistochemical findings of the present 
    experiment demonstrate a discrete cholinergic projection to the 
    dorsal cap in the inferior olive of both the rat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">In the rat the region of cholinergc innervation 
    corresponds to a subset of olivary neurons that project to the 
    flocculus (Blanks et al., &apos;83; Ruigrok et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">However the ventrolateral outgrowth also projects to the 
    flocculus, but received only a small cholinergic input (Ruigrok et 
    al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">In the rabbit, there is a weak and diffuse cholinergic 
    innervation of the entire caudal aspect of the inferior olive, 
    including the dorsal cap and p-nucleus (Fig. 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Interestingly, both the rat and monkey have a well 
    defined cholinerpic projection to the uvula-nodulus of the 
    cerebellum originating from the caudal aspect of the MVN (Barmack 
    et al., &apos;92b,c).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">In the rabbit, there is only a weak cholinergc 
    projection to these same regions, although there is a very strong 
    cholinergic innervation of the ventral paraflocculus (Barmack et 
    al., &apos;92b:c).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The origin of the cholinergic projection from the NPH in 
    the rat was supported by both the orthograde transport of PHA-L 
    (Figs. 5,6) and by the reduction of ChAT staining in the 
    contralateral dorsal cap following subtotal unilateral lesions 
    placed in the NPH and MVN (Fig. 10).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">In the rabbit, although both orthograde and retrograde 
    transport experiments revealed a projection from the NPH to the 
    contralateral dorsal cap (Figs. 7-91, both the paucity of ChAT 
    labeling of terminals within the dorsal cap and the lack of HRP 
    retrograde labeling of ChAT-positive neurons within the NPH 
    suggested that this projection is not cholinergic (Figs. 7-9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The projection from the NPH to the contralateral dorsal 
    cap of both rat and rabbit agrees with previous anatomical studies, 
    using orthograde tracers, that demonstrated this same projection in 
    cat (Gerrits et al., &apos;85; McCrea and Baker, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s187">Co-expression of 
    acetylcholine and GABA in NPH neurons?</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">It seems reasonable to conclude that in the rabbit the 
    NPH projection to the contralateral dorsal cap is mediated 
    primarily by a non-cholinergic transmitter system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">A likely alternative transmitter is GABA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">In the rabbit, there is a dense GABAergic innervation of 
    the dorsal cap as revealed by immunohistochemical staining for 
    glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD) (Nelson et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Recently, it has been shown that the NPH projection to 
    the contralateral dorsal cap of the rabbit is at least in part 
    GABAergic (De Zeeuw et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">This raises the interesting possibility that the same 
    anatomical projection in the rat and rabbit is mediated by two 
    different neurotransmitters: acetylcholine in the rat and GABA in 
    the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">However, it is possible that both transmitters are 
    co-expressed in NPH neurons in both species.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Such co-expression of acetylcholine and GABA has been 
    described in amacrine cells of the retina (O&apos;Malley et al., 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Therefore it is possible that the weak ChAT staining of 
    fiber terminals in the dorsal cap of the rabbit and the apparent 
    lack of double-labeled cells in the NPH reflects a low expression 
    of ChAT in NPH neurons in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">The question of co-expression of acetylcholine and GABA 
    by NPH neurons could be addressed directly in the rat by the use of 
    markers for both ChAT and GAD.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s197">Vestibular projections 
    to the p-nucleus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Previous retrograde transport studies in the rat and 
    rabbit demonstrated that the medial aspect of the DVN gives rise to 
    a GABAergic projection to the p-nucleus (Nelson et al., &apos;86, 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">These results are confirmed by the present retrograde 
    transport studies in the rabbit (Fig. 9) and further supported by 
    the orthograde transport of PHA-L in both rat and rabbit (Figs. 4, 
    5, 7).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">The present results suggest that there is also a 
    vestibular projection to the p-nucleus that originates from the 
    caudal and lateral aspect of the MVN.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">However, we do not know if this MVN projection to the 
    p-nucleus is GABAergic.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s202">Receptors for the 
    cholinergic and GABAergic inputs to the inferior olive</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Presently the cholinergic receptors on olivary neurons 
    are not well characterized.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">However, we have obtained preliminary 
    immunohistochemical evidence in both rat and rabbit for the 
    presence of the M2 subclass of muscarinic receptors (Barmack, 
    unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">In the cerebellum there is both pharmacological and 
    irnmunological evidence that indicates that there are M2 receptors 
    on granule cells, the cells that receive the cholinergic 
    innervation from the vestibular complex (Giraldo et al., &apos;87; 
    Ehlert and Tran, &apos;90; Fukamauchi et al., &apos;91; Li et al., 
    &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">In other systems, M2 receptors are coupled via a 
    pertussis toxin-sensitive G protein to a potassium conductance (Ito 
    et al., &apos;91; Lai et al., &apos;91; Richards, &apos;91; Bonner, 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Functionally, this means that activation of M2 receptors 
    hyperpularizes the neurons on which they are located, by driving 
    the membrane potential towards the potassium equilibrium 
    potential.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">If the same transduction mechanism is found for the M2 
    receptors on dorsal cap neurons, then it is possible that the 
    optokinetic sensitivity of dorsal cap neurons contralateral to the 
    NPH could be reduced by the activation of the NPH cholinergic 
    neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Presently, the distribution of GABAergic receptor 
    subtypes within the inferior olive is not known.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">In the rabbit inferior olive, it is possible that the 
    GAEiAergic projection to the dorsal cap would have the same 
    inhibitory effect as would the cholinergic projection in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Namely, if dorsal cap neurons expressed GABAA receptors 
    similar in subunit composition to the GABAA receptors expressed on 
    cerebellar granule cells, the GABAergic pathway from NPH to the 
    dorsal cap could be functionally inhibitory since GABAA receptors 
    are coupled to a chloride conductance (Engblom et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">The cholinergic projection would be functionally 
    inhibitory, coupled by an M2 receptor through a G protein to a 
    potassium conductance.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s213">Functional importance of 
    the cholinergic projection to the dorsal cap</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The dorsal cap has been implicated functionally in an 
    optokinetic circuit that projects to both the flocculus and nodulus 
    (Maekawa and Simpson, &apos;73; Alley et al., &apos;75; Graf et 
    al., &apos;88; Leonard et al., &apos;88; Barmack and Shojaku, 
    &apos;89, &apos;92; Takeda and Maekawa, &apos;89b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">This circuitry when activated by optokinetic stimulation 
    of the contralateral eye in the posterior-anterior direction 
    (Barmack, &apos;79; Barmack and Hess, &apos;Sob; Barmack and 
    Simpson, &apos;80) evokes conjugate eye movements that have a slow 
    phase in the same direction as the optokinetic stimulus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">These optokinetically evoked eye movements null the 
    retinal slip caused by the optokinetic stimulus and consequently 
    reduce the evoked activity in the contralateral dorsal cap.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Microstimulation of the dorsal cap, in the absence of 
    visual feedback, evokes eye movements whose slow phase is towards 
    the stimulated dorsal cap (Barmack and Hess, &apos;80a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Optokinetic stimulation of the left eye in the 
    posterior-anterior direction evokes activity in the right dorsal 
    cap.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">This activity evokes an increase in climbing fiber 
    responses and a decrease in simple spike responses in both the left 
    nodulus and flocculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">This reduction in simple spike activity of the left 
    flocculus and nodulus reduces Purkinje cell inhibition of the left 
    vestibular complex, thereby evoking compensatory eye movements in 
    the rightward direction (Barmack and Pettorossi, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">This horizontal optokinetic reflex is impaired by a 
    unilateral lesion of the left flocculus without reducing the gain 
    of the horizontal vestibuloocular reflex (Barmack and Pettorossi, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Eye movements evoked by either optokinetic stimulation 
    or by electrical stimulation of the dorsal cap can also outlast the 
    natural or electrical stimulus, leading to an afternystagmus 
    (Barmack, &apos;79; Barmack and Hess, &apos;80a; Barmack and 
    Nelson, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">The cholinergic pathway to the dorsal cap from the NPH 
    and the medial aspect of the MVN could provide a more centralized 
    control of visual information mediated by the dorsal cap.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">The signal that originates from the NPH includes 
    vestibular and eye movement-related information (Blanks et al., 
    &apos;77; Lopez-Barneo et al., &apos;82) rather than the purely 
    optokinetic information that originates from the nucleus of the 
    optic tract.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">In the monkey, the signal from neurons in the NPH 
    appears to represent eye position exclusively since NPH neurons are 
    not modulated by either vestibular or optokinetic stimulation when 
    a monkey is trained to maintain fixation during such stimulation 
    (McFarland and Fuchs, &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">It is possible that a better understanding of the 
    importance of this pathway will be revealed by both 
    micropharmacological experiments that further delineate the 
    specific receptor subtypes present on dorsal cap neurons and by 
    behavioral experiments in which it is possible to specify and 
    control the activity of NPH neurons that project to the 
    contralateral dorsal cap.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s227">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s228">We gratefully acknowledge the 
    participation of Ann Burleigh during the early phase of this 
    experiment.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s229">We also appreciate the expert 
    technical assistance of Leta Guptill.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s230">This research was supported 
    by National Institutes of Health Grant EY-04778, the Oregon Lions 
    Sight, and Hearing Foundation and the Consiglio Nazionale delle 
    Ricerche of Italy.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s231">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Alley, K., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Baker, and J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Simpson (1975) Afferents to the vestibulocerehellum and 
    the origin of the visual climbing fibers in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Brain Res. 99:582-589.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Balaban.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">C.D.. and R.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Henry (1988) Zonal organization projeccions in albino 
    rahhits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Neurosci, Res. 5409423.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Barmack, N.H. (1979) Immediate and sustained influences 
    ofvisual olivocerebellar activity on eye movement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">In R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Talbott and D.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Humphrey (eds): Posture and Movement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">New York: Raven Press, pp. 123-167.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Barmack, N.H., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Mugnaini, and B.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Nelson (1989) Vestibularly-evoked activity of single 
    neurons in the beta nucleus of the inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">In P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Strata (ed): The Olivocerebellar System in motor 
    control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Berlin: SpringerVerlag, pp. 313 322.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Barmack.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">N.H., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Burleigh.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Errico, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Fagerson (19911 Acholinergic pathway to the dorsal cap 
    of the inferior olive of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Abst. 17:919.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">(Abstract) Barmack, N.H., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Uaughman, and F.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Eckenstein (1992a) Cholinergic innervation of the 
    cerebellum of the rat by secondary vestibular afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">In B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Cohcn, D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Tomko, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Guedry (edsj: Sensing and Controlling Motion: Vestibular 
    and Sensorimotor Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">New York: New York Academy of Sciences, pp. 566-579.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Rarmack, N.H., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Baughman, and F.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Eckcnstein (1992bl Cholinergic rebellum of rat, rabbit, 
    cat and monkey as revealed by cholinc acctyltransfcrase activity 
    and immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Neurol. 31 7.233-249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Barmack, N.H..</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Baughman, F.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Sckenstein, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Shojaku (1992~) Secondary vestihular cholinergic 
    projection to the cerebellum of rabbit and rat as revealed hy 
    choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry, retrograde and 
    orthograde tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Ncurol. 31 7:250-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Barmack.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">N.H., and D.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Hess (1980a) Eye movements evoked hy microstimulation of 
    dorsal cap of inferior olive in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Neurophysiol. 43: 166-18 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Barmack, N.H., and D.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Hess i1980bj Multiple-unit activity evoked in dorsal cap 
    of inferior olive of the rabbit by visual stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Neurophysiol. 43: 15 1-1 64.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">I&amp;lt;armack, N.H., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Nelson (1987) Infiuence of long-term optokinetic 
    stimulation on eye movements of the rahbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Brain Kes. 437.111-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Barmack, N.H.. andV.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Pettorossi (1981 I Infiuence ofvisualolivocerebellar 
    inactivation on the optokinetic properties of neurons in the 
    vestibular nuclei of rabbits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Fuchs and Becker (eds): Progress in Oculomotor 
    Research.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Amsterdam: Elsevier North Holland, Inc., pp. 455-464.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Rarmack, N.H.: and V.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Pcttorossi (19851 Effects of unilateral lesions of the 
    flocculus on optokinetic and vestibuloocular reflexes of the 
    rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Neurophysiol. 53:481496.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Barmack, N.H., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Shojaku (1989) Topography andanalysis ofvcstibularvisual 
    climbing fiber signals in the rabbit cerehellar nodulus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Ahst. 15: 180.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Barmack, N.H., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Shqjaku (1992) Representation of a postural coordinate 
    system in the nodulus of the rabbit cerebellum by vestibular 
    climbing fiber signals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">In H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Shimazu and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Shinoda (eds): Vestibular and Brain Stem Control of Eye, 
    Head and Body Movements.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Tokyo and Basel: Japan Scientific Societies Press and 
    Karger, pp. 331-338.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Barmack, N.H., and J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Simpson (1980) Effects of microlesions of dorsal cap of 
    inferior olive ofrahhits on optokinetic and vest,ibulo-ocular 
    reflexes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Neurophysiol. 43: 182-205.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Berkley, K.J., and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Hand (1978a) Projections to the inferior olive of the 
    cat 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Comparisons or input from the gracile, cuneate and the 
    spinal trigeminal nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Neurol. 180r253-264.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Berkley, K.J., and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Hand (1978b!</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Projections to the inferior olive of the cat I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Comparisons of input from the dorsal column nuclei, the 
    lateral cervical nucleus, the spino-olivary pathways, the cerebral 
    cortex and the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Neurol. 180237-252.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Blanks, R.H.I., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Volkind, W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Precht, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Baker (1977) Responses of cat prepositus hypoglossi 
    neurons to horizontal angular acceleration.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Neuroscience 2391403.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Blanks.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">R.H.I., W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Prccht, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Torigoe (1983) Afferent projections to the cerebellar 
    flocculus in the pigmented rat demonstrated by retrograde transport 
    of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Brain Res. 52:293-306.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Bonner, T.I. (1992) Domains of muscarinic acetylcholine 
    receptors confer specificity of G protein coupling.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">TINS 13:48-50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Zecuw, C.I., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Wentzel, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Mugnaini (1992) Fine structurc of the dorsal cap of the 
    inferior olive and its GABAergic and non-GAUAergic input from the 
    nucleus prcpositus hypoglossi in rat and rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Neurol. iin press).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Eckenstein, F., Y.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Barde, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Thoenen (1981) Production of specific antibodies to 
    choline acetyltransferase purified from pig brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Neuroscience 6:993-1000.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Eckenstein, F.P., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Baughman, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Quinn (1988) An anatomical study of cholinergic 
    innervation in rat cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Neuroscience 2.5:457474.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Ehlert, F.J., and L.L.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Tran (1990) Regional distribution of M1, M2 and non-MI, 
    nun-A12 subtype of musmrinic binding sites in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Pharmacol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Ther. 2551148-1157.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Engblom, A.C., I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Holopainen, and K.E.O. kerman (1989) Determination of 
    GABA receptor-linked C1 fluxes in rat cerebellar granule cells 
    using a fluorescent probe SPQ.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Lett. 204:326-330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Fernandez, C., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Fredrickson (1964) Experimental cerebellar lesions and 
    their effect on vestibular function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Acta Otolaryngol. iSuppl.1 (Stockh.) 192:52-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Frankfurter, A,, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Weber, G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Royce, N.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Strominger, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Harting (1976) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    tecto-olivary projection in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Brain Res. 118245-257.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Fredette, B.J., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Mugnaini (1991) The GABAergic cerebello-olivary 
    projection in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Emhryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">(Bed) 184:225-243.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Fukamauchi, F., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Hough, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Chuang (1991) Expression and agonist-induced 
    down-regulation of mRNAs of m2and m3-muscarinic acetylcholine 
    receptors in cultured cerebellar granule cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Neurochem. 56:716-719.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Gellman, R., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Houk, andA.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Gibson (1983) Somatosensory properties of the inferior 
    olive ofthe cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Neurnl. 215:228-243.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Sawchenko (19841 An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vnlgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L!.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Brain Res. 290r219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Gerrits, N.M., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Voogd, and 1.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Magras (1985) Vestibular fierents of the inferior olive 
    and the vestibulo-olivo-cerebellar climbing fiber pathway to the 
    flocculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Brain Res. 332:325 -336.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Giraldo, E., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Hammer, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Ladinsky (1987) Distribution of muscarinic receptor 
    subtypes in rat brain as determined in binding studies with AF-DX 
    116 and pirenzepine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Life Sci. 40:833-840.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Graf, W., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Simpson, and C.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Leonard i1988) Spatial organization of visual messages 
    of the rabbit s cerebellar flocculus. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Complex and simple spike responses of Purkinje cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Neurophysiol. 60:2091-2121.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Huerta, M.F., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Hashikawa, M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Gayoso, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Harting (1985) The trigemino-olivary projection in the 
    cat: Contributions of individual subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Neurol. 241:180-190.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">H., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Sugimoto, I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Kobayashi, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Takahashi, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Katada, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Ui, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Kurachi (1991) On the mechanism of basal and 
    agonist-induced activation of the G protein-gated muscarinic K 
    channel in atrial myocytes of guinea pig heart.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Gen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Physiol. 98:517-533.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Ito, AT. (1984) The Cerebellum and Neural Control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">New York: Haven Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Kawamura, K., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Onodera 11984) Olivary projections from the pretectal 
    region in the cat studied with horseradish peroxidase and 
    tritiat,ed amino acids zonal transport.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Ital.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Biol. 122t155-168.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Folia Neurobiol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Kooy, F.H. (1916) The inferior olive in vertebrates. 
    10t205-369.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Kwhou, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">-I., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Matsuzaki (1991) Topographical organization of climbing 
    fiber pathway from the superior colliculus to cerebellar vermal 
    lobules W-VII in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Neuroscience 45:691-699.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">,S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Waite, J.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Bloom.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">H.I.Yamamura, andW.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Roeske (19913 The m2 muscarinic acetylcholine receptors 
    are coupled to multiple signaling pathways via pertussis 
    toxin-sensitive guanine nucleotide regulatory proteins.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Pharmacol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Ther. 258:938-944.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Langer, T., A.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Fuchs, C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Scudder, and M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Chubb (1985) Merents to the fiocculus of the cerebellum 
    in the Rhesus macaque as revealed by retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Neurol, 235: 125.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Leonard, C.S., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Simpson, and W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Graf (1988) Spatial organization of visual messages of 
    the rabbit s cerebellar flocculus. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Typology of inferior olive neurons of the dorsal cap of 
    Kooy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Neurophysiol. 60:2073--2090.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">M., R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Yasuda, S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Wall, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Wellstein, and B.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Wolfe (1991) Distribution of m2 muscarinic receptors in 
    rat brain using antisera selective for m2 receptors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Mol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Pharmacol. 40:28-35.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">I)opz-Barneo, 6., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Darlot, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Berthoz. and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Baker (1982) Neuronal activity in prepositus nucleus 
    correlated with eye movement in the alert cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Neurophysiol. 47:329-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Maekawa, K., and J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Simpson (1973) Climbing fiber responses evoked in 
    vestibulocerebellum of rabbit from visual system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Neurophysiol. 36:649-666.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Maekawa, K., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Takeda (1979) Origin of descending af erents to the 
    rostra1 part of dorsal cap of inferior olivc which transfers 
    contralateral optic activities to the flocculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Brain Res. 172393-405.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Martin, G.F., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Dom, J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">King, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Robards, and C.R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Watson (1975) The inferior olivary nucleus of the 
    opossum (Didelphis marsupialis virginiana), its organization and 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Neurol. 160:507-534.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">McCrea, R.A., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Baker (19853 Anatoniical connections of the nucleus 
    prepositus of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Neurol. 237:377-407.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">McFarland, J.L., and A.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Fuchs (1992) Discharge patterns in nucleus prepositus 
    hypoglossi and adjacent medial vestibular nucleus during horizontal 
    eye movement in behaving Macaques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Neurophysiol. 68:319-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Mecsscn, H., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Olszcwski (1949) A cytoarchitectonic rhombencephalon on 
    the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">New York: S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Karger.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Molinari, H.H., K.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Starr, and R.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Sluyters (1991) Gracile projection to the cat medial 
    accessory olive: Ultrastructural termination patterns and 
    convergence with spino-olivm projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Neurol. 309363374 Nelson, B., N.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Barmack, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Mugnaini (1986) A GAEAergic vestibular projection to rat 
    inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Sac.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Neurosci. i\bst. 12255.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Nelson, B.J., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Adam, N.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Barmack, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Mugnaini (1989) A comparative study of glutamate 
    decarboxylase immunoreactive boutons in the mammalian inferior 
    olive.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Neurol. 286:.514-539.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">O Malley, D.M., J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Sandell, and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Masland (1992) Co-release of acetylcholine and GABA by 
    the starburst amacrine cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Neurosci. 12:1394-1408.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Olucha, F., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Martinez-Garcia. and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Lopez-Garcia (19853 A new stabilizing agent for the 
    tetramethyl benzidine iTMB) reaction product in the histochemical 
    detection of horseradish peroxidase (HRP).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Meth. 13:131-138.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Richards, M.H. (1991) Pharmacology and second messenger 
    interactions cloned muscarinic receptors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Uiochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Pharmacol. 42: 1645-1653.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Ruigrok, T.J.H., R.4.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Osse, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Voogd (1992) Organization of inferior olivary 
    projections to the flocculus and ventral paraflocculus of the rat 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Neurol. 31 6 : 129-150.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Rye, D.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Saper. and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Wainer (1984) Stabilization of tetramethylbenzidine 
    (TMB) reaction product: Application of retrograde and anterograde 
    tracing, and combination with immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Cytochem. 32: 1145-1 153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Saint-Cyr, J.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Courville (1979) Projection from the vestibular nuclei 
    to the inferior olive in the cat: An autoradiographic and 
    horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Brain Res. 165: 189-200.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Saint-Cyr, cJ.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Courville (19821 Descending projections to the inferior 
    olive from the mesencephalon and superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">An autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Brain Res. 45:333-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Singleton, G.T. (1967) Relationships of the cerebellar 
    nodulus to vestibular function: A study of the effects of 
    nodulectomy on habituation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Laryngoscope 77:1579-1619.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Takeda, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Maekawa (1980) Bilateral visual inputs to the dorsal cap 
    of inferior olive: Differential localization and inhihitory 
    interactions, Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Brain Res. 39:461471.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Takeda, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Maekawa (1989aJ Olivary branching projections to the 
    flocculus, nodulus and uvula in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">An electrophysiological study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Brain Res. 74:4742.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Takeda, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Maekawa (198913) Olivary branching projections to the 
    flocculus, nodulus and uvula in the rabbit. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Retrograde double labeling study with fluorescent 
    dyes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Brain Res. 76.323-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Horst, G.J., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Groenewegen, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Karst, and P.G.M.</S>
    <BR />

  </References>

</File>

