<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Topographical Organization and Relationship With Ventral 
  Striatal Compartments of Prefrontal Corticostriatal Projections in 
  the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>HENK W. BERENDSE, YVONNE GALIS-DE GRAAF, AND HENK J. 
  GROENEWEGEN</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The anterograde tracer Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    was used to examine the topographical organization of the 
    projections to the striatum arising from the various 
    cytoarchitectonic subdivisions of the prefrontal cortex in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The relationship of the prefrontal cortical fibres with 
    the compartmental organization of the ventral striatum was assessed 
    by combining PHA-L tracing and enkephalin-immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The prefrontal cortex projects bilaterally with an 
    ipsilateral predominance to the striatum, sparing only the lateral 
    part of the caudate-putamen complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Each of the cytoarchitectonic subfields of the prefrontal 
    cortex has a longitudinally oriented striatal terminal field that 
    overlaps slightly with those of adjacent prefrontal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The projections of the medial subdivision of the 
    prefrontal cortex distribute to rostral and medial parts of the 
    striatum, whereas the lateral prefrontal subdivision projects to 
    more caudal and lateral striatal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The terminal fields of the orbital prefrontal areas 
    involve midventral and ventromedial parts of the caudate-putamen 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The projection of the ventral orbital area overlaps with 
    that of the prelimbic area in the ventromedial part of the 
    caudate-putamen.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">In the shell region of the nucleus accumbens, fibres 
    arising from the prelimbic area concentrate in areas of high cell 
    density that are weakly enkephalin-immunoreactive, whereas fibres 
    from the infralimbic area avoid such areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Rostrolaterally in the core region of the nucleus 
    accumbens, fibres from deep layer V and layer VI of the dorsal part 
    of the prelimbic area avoid the enkephalin-positive areas 
    surrounding the anterior commissure and distribute in an 
    inhomogeneous way over the intervening moderately 
    enkephalin-immunoreactive compartment.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The other prefrontal fierents show only a preference for, 
    but are not restricted to, the latter compartment.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">In the border region between the nucleus accumbens and 
    the ventromedial part of the caudate-putamen complex, patches of 
    strong enkephalin immunoreactivity receive prefrontal cortical 
    input from deep layer V and layer VI, whereas fibres from more 
    superficial cortical layers project to the surrounding matrix.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Individual cytoarchitectonic subfields of the prefrontal 
    cortex thus have circumscribed terminal domains in the striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">In combination with data on the organization of the 
    midline and intralaminar thalamostriatal and thalamoprefrontal 
    projections, the present results establish that the projections of 
    the prefrontal cortical subfields converge in the striatum with 
    those of their midline and intralaminar afferent nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The present findings further demonstrate that the 
    relationship of the prefrontal corticostriatal fibres with the 
    neurochemical compartments of the ventral striatum can be 
    influenced by both the areal and the laminar origin of the cortical 
    afferents, depending on the particular ventral striatal region 
    under consideration.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The prefrontal cortex in mammals is generally defined as 
    the &quot;essential cortical projection area of the mediodorsal 
    nucleus of the thalamus&quot; (Rose and Woolsey, &apos;48; Krettek 
    and Price, &apos;77a; Groenewegen, &apos;88; cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Uylings and Van Eden, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">It comprises several cytoarchitectonic subfields that are 
    reciprocally connected with distinct segments of the mediodorsal 
    nucleus (Leonard, &apos;69; Krettek and Price, &apos;77a; 
    Beckstead, &apos;79; Groenewegen, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Since the mediodorsal nuclear subdivisions are 
    characterized by different sets of afferents (Groenewegen, 
    &apos;88), each of the corresponding prefrontal cortical subfields 
    receives a specific class of information.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">The heterogeneity of the prefrontal cortex manifests 
    itself likewise in the topographical arrangements of its efferent 
    connections (Beckstead, &apos;79; Reep and Winans, &apos;82; Wyss 
    and Sripanidkulchai, &apos;84; Sesack et al., &apos;89) and its 
    afferent projections from the midline and intralaminar thalamic 
    nuclei (Jones and Leavitt, &apos;74; Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;91) and the amygdaloid complex (Krettek and Price, &apos;77b; 
    McDonald, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Physiological and behavioural studies implicate the 
    prefrontal cortex in a variety of functions, ranging from motor to 
    autonomic (for review see Kolb, &apos;84, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">In several of these studies a functional specialization 
    of the various prefrontal subfields has been proposed (e.g., 
    Eichenbaum et al., &apos;83; Shipley and Geinisman, &apos;84; 
    Neafsey et al., &apos;86a,b; Terreberry and Neafsey, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Anatomical investigations in several mammalian species 
    have convincingly demonstrated that functionally different cortical 
    areas project to largely separate striatal regions (rat: Webster, 
    &apos;61; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; rabbit: Carman et al., 
    &apos;63; cat: Webster, &apos;65; Jayaraman, &apos;85; dog: Tanaka, 
    &apos;79, &apos;83, &apos;87; Tanaka et al., &apos;79, &apos;81; 
    monkey: Kemp and Powell, &apos;70; Kunzle, &apos;75, &apos;77, 
    &apos;78; Kunzle and Akert, &apos;77; Yeterian and Van Hoesen, 
    &apos;78; Van Hoesen et al., &apos;81; Selemon and Goldman-Rakic, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">In contrast, the projections of functionally related 
    cortical areas may either overlap Cyeterian and Van Hoesen, 
    &apos;78) or interdigitate in the same striatal region (Selemon and 
    Goldman-Rakic, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">This arrangement suggests that the striatum is 
    functionally heterogeneous, a notion substantiated by the results 
    of physiological and behavioural studies (Winocur, &apos;74; Oberg 
    and Divac, &apos;75; Rosenkilde and Divac, &apos;76; Divac et al., 
    &apos;78; Dunnett and Iversen, &apos;80, &apos;81, &apos;82a,b,c; 
    Rolls and Williams, &apos;87; Pisa, &apos;88; Kelley et al., 
    &apos;88, &apos;89; Pisa and Schranz, &apos;88; Pisa and Cyr, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">On the basis of available anatomical and physiological 
    data in the primate, Alexander et al. (&apos;86) have tentatively 
    identified a number of parallel circuits leading from the cerebral 
    cortex through the basal ganglia, via the thalamus, to the frontal 
    lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Each of these circuits engages distinct parts of the 
    cerebral cortex, the striatum, the pallidum, and the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Most extensively studied is the so-called &quot;motor 
    circuit&quot; characterized by somatotopic channels that each 
    include subchannels, selectively subserving different aspects of 
    motor processing (Alexander and Crutcher, &apos;90; Alexander et 
    al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Whether a parallel functional organization is equally 
    explicit in the prefrontal corticostriatofugal pathways and whether 
    it is present in species other than the primate, are as yet 
    unanswered questions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">To resolve these issues requires a detailed knowledge of 
    the topographical characteristics of the prefrontal corticostriatal 
    projections and the subsequent striatopallidal and pallidothalamic 
    links.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The striatal projections of the prefrontal cortex have 
    previously been examined with both anterograde and retrograde 
    tracing techniques in several species (Johnson et al., &apos;68; 
    Goldman and Nauta, &apos;77; Kunzle, &apos;78; Beckstead, &apos;79; 
    Room et al., &apos;85; Arikuni and Kubota, &apos;86; Tanaka, 
    &apos;87; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; Sesack et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">However, a comprehensive anterograde tracing study 
    including all subfields of the prefrontal cortex in the rat is 
    lacking.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">At another level of complexity, the striatum is typified 
    by its compartmental organization, which is reflected in the 
    heterogeneous distribution of virtually all histochemical markers, 
    receptors, uptake sites, and afferent and efferent systems (Gerfen, 
    &apos;84, &apos;85; Graybiel, &apos;84, &apos;90; Herkenham et al., 
    &apos;84; Penny et al., &apos;88; Groenewegen et al., &apos;89, 
    &apos;91; Voorn et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The compartmentation of the ventral striatum, which is 
    the portion of the striatum most directly associated with the 
    limbic system by virtue of its hippocampal and amygdalar inputs, is 
    different from that of the dorsal striatum for which a 
    bicompartmental (patch/ matrix or striosomeimatrix) structure has 
    been emphasized (Gerfen, &apos;84, &apos;85; Graybiel, &apos;84, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The chemoarchitecture and the organization of the 
    afferent and efferent connections suggest that the compartmental 
    ordering of the ventral striatum varies from one region to the 
    other (Groenewegen et al., &apos;89, &apos;91; Voorn et al., 
    &apos;89; Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a; Berendse et al., 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Initially, the compartmental distribution of the 
    corticostriatal inputs was related to the cytoarchitectonic area of 
    origin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">The prelimbic cortex was considered to project to the 
    patch compartment throughout the striatum, whereas the projections 
    of the other cortical areas examined were thought to be confined to 
    the matrix (Gerfen, &apos;84; Donoghue and Herkenham, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">However, it has recently been suggested that, in addition 
    to the areal origin, the laminar origin of the cortical fibres may 
    influence their relationship to the patch/matrix organization of 
    the dorsal striatum in the rat (Gerfen and Rutherford, &apos;88; 
    Gerfen, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">In the cat and the monkey, a pattern of dorsal fills and 
    ventral avoids of striosomes within a single striatal terminal 
    field, resulting from anterograde tracer injections in the 
    fronto-insular cortex, has been described (Ragsdale and Graybiel, 
    &apos;81, &apos;84, &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The main objective of the present study was to provide a 
    detailed map of the striatal projections of the various 
    cytoarchitectonic and possibly functionally different prefrontal 
    cortical subfields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Subsequent links in the prefrontal corticostriatofugal 
    pathways, viz., the striatopallidal and pallidothalamic 
    connections, have been analyzed in parallel studies (Groenewegen 
    and Berendse, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Furthermore, the organization of the prefrontal 
    corticostriatal connections was compared to that of the midline and 
    intralaminar thalamostriatal and thalamoprefrontal pathways 
    (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a, &apos;91) to determine 
    whether and to what extent the projections of the midline and 
    intralaminar nuclei converge with those of their prefrontal 
    cortical target areas in the same striatal region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Lastly, the relationship of the prefrontal cortical 
    afferent fibres with the compartmental organization of the ventral 
    striatum was assessed, with special consideration of the laminar 
    origin of the fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">To these aims, small deposits of the anterograde tracer 
    Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L; Gerfen and Sawchenko, 
    &apos;84) were placed at various depths in the prefrontal cortical 
    areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The distribution of the opioid peptide enkephalin (ENK), 
    visualized immunohistochemically, was used as a marker for the 
    compartmentation of the ventral striatum (Voorn et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Part of the present results have been reported in 
    abstract form (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90b).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s46">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s47">Anterograde tracing</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The prefrontal corticostriatal projections were analyzed 
    in 56 female Wistar rats (Harlan/CPB, The Netherlands), weighing 
    180-220 g.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Following anaesthesia with an intramuscular injection of 
    a mixture (4/3) of ketamine and 
    2-(2,6-xylidine)5,6-dihydro1,3-thiazine (Rompun), in a dosage of 1 
    ml/kg, small deposits of PHA-L (Vector Laboratories, U.S.A.) were 
    placed stereotaxically in the prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The coordinates were derived from the atlas of Paxinos 
    and Watson (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The tracer was delivered iontophoretically through glass 
    micropipettes (external tip diameter 15-25 m) using a 
    positive-pulsed 7.5 pA current (7 seconds on17 seconds off; CCS-3 
    current source, Midgard, U.S.A.) for 15-30 minutes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Survival times ranged from 6 to 20 days, after which the 
    animals were reanaesthetized with pentobarbital and perfused 
    transcardially with 100 ml saline, followed by 500 ml of 4% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.05% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer 
    (pH 7.4) either with or without 15% picric acid.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">The brains were removed and stored in the same fixative 
    for 1-2 hours, then transferred to a mixture of 20% glycerol and 2% 
    dimethylsulfoxide in distilled water for overnight storage at 
    4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Subsequently, the brains were cut on a freezing microtome 
    at 35 pm, and the sections were collected in 0.1 M phosphate buffer 
    (pH 7.4).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Two series of sections were incubated in rabbit antiPHA-L 
    antiserum (1:2000; Dakopatts, Denmark) for 18 hours at 4&quot;C, 
    followed by incubations in swine anti-rabbit whole serum (1:50; 
    Nordic Immunology, The Netherlands) and in rabbit-PAP (1:800; 
    Dakopatts, Denmark), respectively, each for 1 hour at 20°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">A third, adjacent series was incubated in rabbit 
    anti-leu-enkephalin antiserum (1:2000, Cambridge Research 
    Biochemicals [CRB], England; 1:4000, UCB-Bioproducts [UCB-Bl, 
    Belgium) for 18 hours at 4&quot;C, followed by swine anti-rabbit 
    whole serum (150) and then by rabbit-PAP (1:800 for CRB 
    anti-enkephalin; 1:1600 for UCB-B anti-enkephalin), each for 1 hour 
    at 20°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">All incubations and intervening rinses were in 0.05 M 
    Tris buffered saline (pH 7.6) with 0.5% Triton-X-100 (TBS-T).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Finally, all series were treated with DAB (50 mg in 100 
    ml Tris-HC1, pH 7.61, preceded by three rinses of 15 minutes each 
    in Tris-HC1 (pH 7.6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">One of the PHA-L-stained series was counterstained with 
    cresyl violet before coverslipping; the other series were 
    coverslipped unstained.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The distribution of PHA-L labelled fibres and terminals 
    was charted with the aid of a drawing tube on a standard Zeiss 
    microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Adjacent sections stained for ENK and PHA-L were used to 
    compare the distribution patterns of PHA-L labelled fibres and ENK 
    immunoreactivity (ENK-IR) in the ventral striatum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s62">Double-staining 
    procedure</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">In all experiments, a fourth series of sections was 
    processed according to a double immunoperoxidase procedure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">This procedure involves an incubation in goat anti-PHA-L 
    antiserum (1: 1500, Vector Laboratories, U.S.A.) mixed with rabbit 
    anti-leu-enkephalin (1:1500, CRB; 1:2500, UCB-B) for 18-66 hours at 
    4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Subsequently, sections were treated with 1% H,O, in TBS 
    for 10 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Sections were then incubated in a mixture of donkey 
    anti-goat (150) and swine anti-rabbit (1:50) whole serum, for 1 
    hour at 20°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">After the third incubation, in goat-PAP (1:600) for 1 
    hour at 20&quot;C, sections were treated with Ni-enhanced DAB (12.5 
    mg DAB in 25 mlO.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4 with 1 ml 1% 
    ammonium-Ni-sulfate), resulting in a blue-black reaction product in 
    PHA-L labelled cells and fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">The final step was an incubation in rabbit-PAP (1:800 for 
    CRB anti-enkephalin; 1: 1000 for UCB-B anti-enkephalin) and a 
    routine-reaction with DAB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">ENK-immunoreactive structures were thus stained brown.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">As in the single staining procedures, all incubations and 
    intervening rinses were in TBS-T, whereas the DAB reactions were in 
    Tris-HC1 (pH 7.6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">The double-staining procedure was performed on sections 
    adjacent to those incubated either for PHA-L or for ENK, in order 
    to enable us to compare the staining patterns of singleand 
    double-stained sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">To exclude the possibility of cross-reactivity between 
    the antisera used in the double-staining procedure, and to assess 
    the contribution of secondary and tertiary antibodies to background 
    staining, parallel incubations were performed with various 
    combinations of antisera, omitting one or more of the primary, 
    secondary or tertiary antibodies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The single immunoperoxidase reactions for PHA-L or ENK, 
    carried out on the adjacent sections, provided us with an extra 
    control of the specificity of the double-immunoperoxide 
    reaction.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">PHA-L antisera, that either had been pre-absorbed with 
    rat brain tissue or had been used in prior incubations, yielded the 
    lowest background staining.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s75">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s76"><neuroanatomicalLocation>
    Prefrontal cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">The criteria for the delineation of the various subfields 
    of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the prefrontal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> in the rat were derived from the 
    accounts of Krettek and Price (&apos;77a) and Van Eden and Uylings 
    (&apos;85) that are based on cytoarchitectonic and hodological 
    data.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The prefrontal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> can be partitioned into 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>medial, lateral or sulcal, and orbital or 
    ventral subdivisions</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The medial 
    subdivision</neuroanatomicalLocation> comprises 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the infralimbic area, the prelimbic area, 
    the anterior cingular area, and the medial precentral 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The lateral 
    subdivision</neuroanatomicalLocation> includes 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dorsal, ventral, and posterior 
    agranular insular areas</neuroanatomicalLocation>, whereas 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the orbital 
    subdivision</neuroanatomicalLocation> encompasses 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial orbital area, the ventral 
    orbital area, the ventrolateral orbital area, and the lateral 
    orbital area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The medial 
    precentral</neuroanatomicalLocation> area of Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;77a) is identical to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial 
    agranular field of the motor cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>, as 
    delineated by Donoghue and Parham (&apos;83) and Reep et al. 
    (&apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">In the present account, we will use the term 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>medial agranular 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The medial orbital 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation> will be included in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial prefrontal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>, as it is not possible, on the 
    basis of cytoarchitectonics, to distinguish this area from the 
    infralimbic area with which it is caudally continuous (Van Eden and 
    Uylings, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s84">Compartmental 
    organization of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</neuroanatomicalLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">On the basis of the distribution patterns in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</neuroanatomicalLocation> of a number of neurochemical 
    substances, three regions that each display a characteristic 
    compartmental organization can be distinguished (Herkenham et al., 
    &apos;84; Voorn et al., &apos;86, &apos;89; for reviews see 
    Groenewegen et al., &apos;89, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The distribution of the opioid peptide enkephalin, as 
    seen in the present experimental material, is in agreement with the 
    previous descriptions and is used in this study as the marker for 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral striatal 
    compartments</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">In the three distinct regions mentioned above ENK-IR is 
    distributed as follows.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">In <labelingLocation>the medial and ventral parts (or 
    shell region) of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, areas of 
    <labelingDescription>weak ENK-IR</labelingDescription>are 
    surrounded by <labelingDescription>moderate 
    ENK-IR</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">These areas coincide with <labelingDescription>clusters 
    of densely packed cells and high opiate receptor 
    binding</labelingDescription> (Herkenham et al., &apos;84; Voorn et 
    al., &apos;89; Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">At caudal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the nucleus 
    accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, the weakly ENK-immunoreactive 
    areas delineate the shell region from the core region to some 
    extent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">In the rostrolateral part of the nucleus accumbens, 
    several large areas of strong ENK-IR stand out against a moderately 
    stained background.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">They are most conspicuous in the vicinity of the anterior 
    commissure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">At more caudal levels, in the border region between the 
    caudodorsal part of the nucleus accumbens and the ventral part of 
    the caudate-putamen, smaller patches of strong ENK-IR are present 
    within a moderately stained background.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Although the small and the above-described large areas of 
    strong ENK-IR share a weak immunoreactivity for dopamine, a number 
    of other neurochemical characteristics are different (Voorn et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s95">Injection sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">Most <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposits in 
    <injectionLocation>the prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> are 
    either round or slightly ovoid in shape, with diameters ranging 
    from 200 to 500 Fm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">Examples of injection sites are represented in Figure 
    lA,C,E,F.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">The distribution of the 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposits over the three 
    major subdivisions of the prefrontal cortex is illustrated in 
    Figure 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">The laminar distribution of the projections to the 
    homotopic contralateral cortical area correlates with the laminar 
    location of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> labelled cell 
    bodies at the injection site (Gerfen, &apos;89; present results), 
    and is used as an extra means to assess the laminar origin of the 
    prefrontal projections to the striatum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">In Figure 1A-D, examples of both superficial and deep 
    layer injections in <injectionLocation>the prelimbic 
    area</injectionLocation> are illustrated together with the 
    accompanying label in the homotopic contralateral cortical area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Injections centred in <injectionLocation>deep layer V 
    and layer VI</injectionLocation> produce <labelingDescription>dense 
    contralateral cortical labelling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>deep layer V and layer VI</labelingLocation> and 
    <labelingDescription>sparse labelling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>layers I and 111</labelingLocation>, whereas 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposits in 
    <injectionLocation>layers I through superficial 
    V</injectionLocation> give rise to <labelingDescription>dense 
    labelling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>layers I and 
    I11</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>moderate 
    labelling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>layers I1 and 
    superficial V</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">In the latter cases, <labelingLocation>deep layer V and 
    layer VI</labelingLocation> contain <labelingDescription>sparse 
    terminating fibres amidst a multitude of passing 
    fibres</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s103">
    <labelingDescription>Fibre labelling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the striatum</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104"><connxOrigin>All prefrontal cortical areas</connxOrigin> 
    project bilaterally to <connxTermination>the 
    striatum</connxTermination>, with an ipsilateral predominance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">The contralateral component reaches <connxTermination>
    the same striatal regions</connxTermination> and distributes 
    according to the same pattern as the ipsilateral component.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106"><connxTermination>The most ventral part of the nucleus 
    accumbens and the olfactory tubercle</connxTermination> do not 
    receive a significant contralateral projection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">In other striatal areas, the density of the 
    contralateral projections is variable and may in some cases be 
    equal to that of the ipsilateral projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Although in a few cases with superficial injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> only 
    weak contralateral labelling was observed, we were unable to 
    establish a consistent relationship between the density of the 
    contralateral projection and the laminar origin of the prefrontal 
    corticostriatal fibres.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">The majority of the corticostriatal fibres penetrate the 
    external capsule and directly enter <connxTermination>the striatal 
    neuropil</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">Another portion of the fibres reach <connxTermination>
    the striatum</connxTermination> by way of the bundles of the 
    internal capsule from which they emerge close to their striatal 
    target area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">The latter pathway is taken predominantly by fibres 
    originating from <connxOrigin>deep layer V and layer 
    VI</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">Fibres from <connxOrigin>more superficial cortical 
    layers</connxOrigin> may also join the fibre bundles of the 
    internal capsule, but they appear to course alongside rather than 
    inside the bundles.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">Fibres from <connxOrigin>the lateral and medial 
    subdivisions of the prefrontal cortex</connxOrigin>, destined for 
    <connxTermination>the nucleus accumbens and the olfactory 
    tubercle</connxTermination>, often pass in a ventral direction 
    through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deep cortical layers or the 
    rostra1 part of the septum</neuroanatomicalLocation> to directly 
    enter <connxTermination>these striatal areas</connxTermination>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s114">In 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the striatum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
    two major types of fibres can be observed subsequent to 
    <injectionLocation>prefrontal cortical</injectionLocation> 
    injections.</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s115">The 
    first type is thick and smooth and is arranged in small clusters of 
    fibres that have the same orientation (see Figs. 6B, 8B).</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s116">These 
    fibres generally follow the fibre bundles of the internal capsule 
    and may gave rise to collaterals that terminate in <connxTermination
    >the striatum</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s117">They 
    will be referred to as passing fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s118">The 
    second type of fibre is thinner and more tortuous than the first 
    type.</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s119">These 
    fibres branch frequently and are set with varicosities giving them 
    a beaded appearance (see Figs. 6B, 8B).</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s120">
    Terminal specializations are rare.</S>
    <S avgH="48" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s121">Fibres 
    from the B&apos;</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122"><neuroanatomicalLocation>lateral prefrontal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> are more tortuous and show more 
    terminal specializations than those arising from 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial and ventral subdivisions of the 
    prefrontal cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">The en passant axonal varicosities have diameters 
    ranging from 0.5 to 2.5 +m and are variably spaced.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">Since both en passant axonal varicosities and terminal 
    specializations observed with the PHA-L method in other systems 
    have been demonstrated to represent the light microscopical 
    representations of synaptic contacts (Wouterlood and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;851, we assume that the second fibre type makes synaptic 
    contacts in <connxTermination>the striatum</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">Consequently, we will refer to these fibres as 
    terminating fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">Support for this assumption comes from the electron 
    microscopical observation that non-myelinated fibres in the 
    striatum have vesicle-filled enlargements that make en passant 
    synaptic contacts (Kemp and Powell, &apos;71).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">In general, the projections observed following PHA-L 
    injections in <injectionLocation>the deep layers of the prefrontal 
    cortex</injectionLocation> are more widespread than the projections 
    seen after injections in superficial cortical layers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">The difference is most obvious in cases with PHA-L 
    deposits in <injectionLocation>rostral parts of the prefrontal 
    cortex</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">These observations may be explained by the fact that in 
    the rostral part of the hemisphere, due to the extreme convexity, 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deep layers of the prefrontal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> have a smaller surface area than 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the superficial 
    layers</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">PHA-L deposits of a given size will therefore involve a 
    relatively larger part of a particular cortical field when placed 
    in the deep layers.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s131">Projections from 
    <connxOrigin>the medial prefrontal cortex</connxOrigin></S>
  </Results>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132"><exptLabel>In 35 cases</exptLabel>, 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposits were placed at 
    different sites in <injectionLocation>the medial subdivision of the 
    prefrontal cortex</injectionLocation> (Fig. 2A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Taken as a whole, this subdivision projects 
    predominantly to <connxTermination>rostral and medial parts of the 
    striatum</connxTermination> which include <connxTermination>the 
    rostral and medial parts of the caudate-putamen 
    complex</connxTermination> and <connxTermination>the medial parts 
    of the nucleus accumbens and olfactory 
    tubercle</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">Each of the constituent cytoarchitectonic areas has 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a restricted striatal terminal 
    field</neuroanatomicalLocation> that overlaps to some extent with 
    the target area of the adjacent cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">In addition, <neuroanatomicalLocation>ventral and dorsal 
    parts of the prelimbic</neuroanatomicalLocation> area have 
    differential striatal projections.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Medial orbitallinfralimbic 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s137"><exptLabel>In case 
    RP-90045</exptLabel>, the <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    deposit was placed dorsally in <injectionLocation>the infralimbic 
    area</injectionLocation>, involving layers 11-V (Fig. 3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">The deposit encroaches upon <injectionSpread>the 
    superficial layers of the ventral part of the prelimbic 
    area</injectionSpread>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139">In <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of 
    terminal labelling</labelingDescription> occupies <labelingLocation>
    the most ventromedial part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>, extending via the striatal 
    cell-bridges into <labelingLocation>the medial two-thirds of the 
    olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> where most 
    <labelingDescription>labelled fibres</labelingDescription> are 
    found in <labelingLocation>the pyramidal cell 
    layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3A-C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">In 
    addition,<labelingDescription>a smaller number of 
    fibres</labelingDescription> terminate more dorsally in 
    <labelingLocation>the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, 
    concentrating in the area interposed between the anterior 
    commissure and the lateral ventricle (Fig. 3B,C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141">The 
    latter labelling probably results from the above-mentioned 
    involvement in the injection site of <injectionSpread>the ventral 
    part of the prelimbic area</injectionSpread>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142">In 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, 
    <labelingDescription>a few fibres</labelingDescription> terminate 
    in <labelingLocation>the area immediately adjacent to the bed 
    nucleus of the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the fundus striati</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    3D).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143"><labelingDescription>A dense terminal 
    plexus</labelingDescription> is present in <labelingLocation>the 
    amygdalostriatal transition zone</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3F).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">The fibres from the infralimbic area avoid clusters of 
    densely packed cells in the medial and ventral parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens (Fig. 4A!.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145"><exptLabel>An injection that primarily involves 
    <injectionLocation>the medial orbital area</injectionLocation> 
    (RP-89494)</exptLabel> produces <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>approximately 
    the same striatal areas as described above for the infralimbic 
    area</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s146">However, <labelingLocation>
    the dorsal part of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> 
    receives only <labelingDescription>very few 
    fibres</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s147">Instead, there is 
    <labelingDescription>some terminal labelling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the ventromedial part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, probably as a result of the 
    involvement of <injectionSpread>the adjacent ventral orbital 
    area</injectionSpread> in the injection site (see following 
    section).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s148">Prelimbic area, 
    ventral injections.</S>
  </Results>

  <Results>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s149">Injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> were placed at varying 
    depths in <injectionLocation>the ventral part of the prelimbic 
    area</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s151"><exptLabel>In case 
    RP-89509</exptLabel>, the tracer deposit almost exclusively 
    involves <injectionLocation>deep layer V and layer 
    VI</injectionLocation> (Fig. 5).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Caudally, the injection site encroaches upon 
    <injectionSpread>the infralimbic area</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">The termination pattern in the striatum is distinctly 
    inhomogeneous.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s154">Rostrally in <labelingLocation
    >the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, small offsets of 
    <labelingDescription>PHA-L labelled fibres</labelingDescription> 
    occupy <labelingLocation>the medial half of the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B), whereas, at more caudal 
    levels, most <labelingDescription>fibres</labelingDescription> 
    terminate in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the shell 
    region</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5 0 .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s155">The 
    aggregates of <labelingDescription>PHA-L labelled 
    fibres</labelingDescription> overlie areas of 
    <labelingDescription>high cell density</labelingDescription> in 
    cresyl violet-counterstained sections and coincide with areas of 
    <labelingDescription>weak ENK-IR</labelingDescription> in adjacent 
    sections stained for ENK (Fig. 4B-D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156"><labelingDescription>Fibre concentrations of similar 
    dimensions</labelingDescription> characterize the terminal 
    labelling in <labelingLocation>the border region between the 
    nucleus accumbens and the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    5B,C).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s157">They coincide with patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> both in 
    adjacent and double-stained sections (Fig. 6A-C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158"><labelingDescription>A few fibres</labelingDescription> 
    reach <labelingLocation>the ventromedial part of the nucleus 
    accumbens and the medial part of the olfactory 
    tubercle</labelingLocation>, including the interconnecting 
    cellbridges (Fig. 5A-C).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s159"><labelingDescription>Sporadic 
    terminating fibres</labelingDescription> are present 
    <labelingLocation>caudal to the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5D-F).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">An injection of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    that predominantly involves <injectionLocation>the superficial 
    layers of the ventral part of the prelimbic 
    area</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case RP-89552</exptLabel>) 
    produces <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in approximately <labelingLocation>
    the same striatal regions</labelingLocation> as the injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the deep layers</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161"><labelingDescription>The terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    caudate-putamen complex</labelingLocation> extends somewhat more 
    dorsally and caudally in <labelingLocation>a narrow 
    strip</labelingLocation> adjacent to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    lateral ventricle</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s162">In 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the 
    inhomogeneously distributed terminating 
    fibres</labelingDescription> concentrate in areas of 
    <labelingDescription>weak ENK-IR</labelingDescription>, just as in 
    <exptLabel>the previous case (RP-89509)</exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s163">Contrary 
    to <exptLabel>case RP-89509</exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>PHA-L 
    labelled fibres</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    border zone between the nucleus accumbens and the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> tend to avoid the patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
    6D).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s164">Prelimbic area, 
    dorsal injections.</S>
  </Results>

  <Results>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s165">Tracer injections 
    placed dorsally in <injectionLocation>the prelimbic 
    area</injectionLocation> produce <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> predominantly in <labelingLocation>
    the caudate-putamen complex</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167"><exptLabel>In case RP-89590</exptLabel>, the 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injection is centered in 
    <injectionLocation>layers I1 through superficial 
    V</injectionLocation>, with minor involvement of <injectionSpread>
    deep layer V</injectionSpread> (Figs. lA, 7).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s168">At 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>rostral striatal</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
    levels, <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of terminating 
    fibres</labelingDescription>, interrupted by small areas almost 
    devoid of fibres, occupies <labelingLocation>the medial half of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> and extends into 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsolateral and central parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation> (Figs. 7A,B; 8A).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s169">
    <labelingLocation>Caudal parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation> are <labelingDescription>very sparsely 
    labelled</labelingDescription> (Fig. 7C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170"><labelingDescription>The anterograde 
    label</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the rostral part 
    of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> does not involve the most 
    dorsal part of this nuclear complex and, additionally, spares the 
    extreme medial rim bordering <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the lateral 
    ventricle</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s171">At the 
    level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the major island of 
    Calleja</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, the labelling in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> is 
    restricted to its medial one-fourth (Fig. 7C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s172">Caudal 
    to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the nucleus 
    accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, the labelling is 
    <labelingDescription>much more sparse</labelingDescription> and 
    occupies only <labelingLocation>a very small ventromedial 
    area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7D,E).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s173">
    <labelingLocation>The most caudal part of the 
    caudateputamen</labelingLocation> does not contain 
    <labelingDescription>a significant amount of terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 7F).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s174">Fibres 
    from <injectionLocation>the superficial layers of the dorsal 
    prelimbic area</injectionLocation> avoid the small patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> in the 
    border region between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the nucleus 
    accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
    the caudate-putamen</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 9A,B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Rostrolaterally in <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the majority of 
    the fibres</labelingDescription> terminate outside the ENK-positive 
    areas, <labelingDescription>a small number of fibres 
    terminating</labelingDescription> within these areas (Fig. 
    9C,D).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Following <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injections centred in <injectionLocation>deep layer V and layer VI 
    of the dorsal part of the prelimbic area</injectionLocation> (e.g., 
    <exptLabel>case RP-89474</exptLabel>; Fig. 10, 
    <labelingDescription>the terminal labelling</labelingDescription> 
    occupies <labelingLocation>the same striatal 
    regions</labelingLocation> as the labelling produced by 
    superficially placed injections.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s177">The 
    distribution pattern is characterized by small aggregates of fibres 
    surrounded by unlabelled areas (Fig. 8B; cf Fig. 8A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">These aggregates overlap with the small patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the border region</labelingLocation> between 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the nucleus 
    accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
    the caudateputamen</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 6E).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">In <labelingLocation>the rostrolateral part of the 
    nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>PHA-L 
    labelled fibres</labelingDescription> avoid the large areas of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
    6F).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Interestingly, they are inhomogeneously distributed over 
    <labelingDescription>the moderately ENK-immunoreactive 
    compartment</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s181">In most 
    cases, in which the tracer deposit involves <injectionSpread>the 
    deep layers of the dorsal prelimbic area</injectionSpread>, 
    additional <labelingDescription>sparse label</labelingDescription> 
    is present in <labelingLocation>the extreme dorsal part of the 
    caudomedial shell area of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s182">This label overlies areas of 
    <labelingDescription>low ENK-IR and high cell 
    density</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Ventral anterior cingular 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s184">In <exptLabel>case 
    RP-90278</exptLabel>, a <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injection is centred in <injectionLocation>the ventral anterior 
    cingular area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 10D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s185">The 
    deposit primarily involves <injectionLocation>layers 11,111, and 
    superficial V</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s186">The 
    resulting <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> is <labelingDescription>most 
    dense</labelingDescription> at <neuroanatomicalLandmark>rostra1 
    striatal</neuroanatomicalLandmark> levels and occupies 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187"><labelingDescription>The labelled 
    fibres</labelingDescription> are arranged in several bands that 
    extend in a lateral direction from <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    ventricle</labelingLocation> (Figs. 8C, 11D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s188">Caudal 
    to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the nucleus 
    accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, only <labelingDescription>a 
    small number of fibres</labelingDescription> occupy 
    <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189"><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections that 
    predominantly involve <injectionLocation>deep layer V and layer VI 
    of the ventral anterior cingular area</injectionLocation> produce 
    <labelingDescription>a patchy pattern of terminal 
    label</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial 
    part of the striatum</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8D).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s190">Dorsal anterior 
    cingular arealmedial agranular area.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">The <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposit in 
    <exptLabel>case RP-90216</exptLabel> is centred in 
    <injectionLocation>the supragenual part of the dorsal anterior 
    cingular area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 10B).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s192">The 
    distinctly inhomogeneous <labelingDescription>terminal 
    field</labelingDescription> is largely confined to <labelingLocation
    >the dorsal part of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> and 
    appears to be arranged in a number of bands that are mediolaterally 
    oriented (Fig. 11B).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s193">The label occupies a slightly 
    more lateral position compared to that observed following 
    <injectionLocation>ventral anterior cingular</injectionLocation> 
    injections (<exptLabel>case RP90278</exptLabel>; cf Fig. 11B,D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">At the level of the globus pallidus, only 
    <labelingDescription>a few fibres terminate</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposit in 
    <exptLabel>case RP-90315</exptLabel> is largely restricted to 
    <injectionLocation>the superficial layers of the supragenual part 
    of the medial agranular area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 10A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196"><labelingDescription>The fibre 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation> occupies a more lateral position in 
    comparison to that found in <exptLabel>the previous case 
    (RP-90216)</exptLabel> and is confined to <labelingLocation>the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s197">The 
    density of fibres is highest at intermediate rostrocaudal 
    levels.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198"><labelingDescription>Rostrally</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, 
    <labelingDescription>most fibres</labelingDescription> terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>a dorsolateral strip immediately underneath the 
    external capsule</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingDescription>a 
    few fibres</labelingDescription> terminate more centrally (Fig. 
    11A).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s199">In <labelingLocation>the 
    caudal part of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, the density 
    of the centrally located labelling equals that of the dorsolateral 
    strip.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s200">Labelled fibres reach 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal extreme of the caudate-putamen 
    complex</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injections centred in <injectionLocation>the deep layers of the 
    supragenual parts of the dorsal anterior cingular and medial 
    agranular areas</injectionLocation></exptLabel> produce only 
    <labelingDescription>very scant label</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>dorsal and central parts of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">The labelled fibres are arranged in clusters.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203"><exptLabel>Injections placed in <injectionLocation>the 
    pregenual parts of the dorsal anterior cingular or the medial 
    agranular areas</injectionLocation></exptLabel> result in a pattern 
    of labelling that involves largely <labelingLocation>the same 
    mediolateral striatal regions</labelingLocation> as in the cases 
    with supragenually placed injections.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s204">However, 
    <labelingDescription>the highest density of labelled 
    fibres</labelingDescription> in the former cases is found more 
    ventrally and rostrally in <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">In <exptLabel>case RP-90091</exptLabel>, a 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposit is centred in 
    <injectionLocation>layer V of the pregenual parts of the dorsal 
    anterior cingular and medial agranular areas</injectionLocation> 
    (Figs.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s206">lOC, 12).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Rostrally in the striatum, <labelingDescription>the 
    terminal label</labelingDescription> occupies <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral two-thirds of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> and 
    extends into <labelingLocation>the rostrolateral part of the 
    nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12A,B).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s208">At the 
    level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the major island of 
    Calleja</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, the label is restricted to 
    <labelingLocation>a central region in the dorsal part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, with 
    <labelingDescription>sparse labelling</labelingDescription> 
    dorsolateral to it (Figs. 11C; 12C,D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Caudally, the fibres concentrate in two bands, one 
    adjacent to <labelingLocation>the external 
    capsule</labelingLocation> and the other more ventrally in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial part of the caudateputamen 
    complex</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12E).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s210">In 
    <labelingLocation>the rostrolateral part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>, most fibres coming from 
    <injectionLocation>the pregenual parts of the dorsal anterior 
    cingular and medial agranular areas</injectionLocation> avoid the 
    large areas of strong ENK-IR.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s211">Projections from 
    <connxOrigin>the lateral prefrontal cortex</connxOrigin></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212"><injectionLocation>The lateral prefrontal 
    cortex</injectionLocation> was the target of 13 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections (Fig. 2B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213"><injectionLocation>Lateral prefrontal 
    cortical</injectionLocation> injections typically result in more 
    laterally located <labelingDescription>terminal 
    label</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation> than in the cases of medial prefrontal 
    injections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Two cases with <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    deposits in <injectionLocation>the ventral and dorsal subfields of 
    the agranular insular area</injectionLocation> will be considered 
    in detail.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s215">Following a <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
      injection in <injectionLocation>the posterior agranular insular 
      area</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>RP-90474</exptLabel>; Fig. 
      2B) only <labelingDescription>very weak 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      part of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> was observed.</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Ventral agranular insular 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">A deposit of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    centred in <injectionLocation>layer V of the ventral agranular 
    insular area</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
    RP-89374</exptLabel>; Fig. 131, with some involvement of 
    <injectionSpread>layers I11 and VI</injectionSpread>, results in 
    <labelingDescription>a rather restricted terminal 
    field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s218"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
    fibres terminate</labelingDescription> predominantly in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the nucleus accumbens, 
    the adjacent lateral part of the olfactory tubercle, and the 
    interconnecting cell-bridges</labelingLocation> (Fig. 13A-C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219"><labelingDescription>A modest amount of terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> occupies <labelingLocation>the 
    fundus striati and the midventral part of the caudate-putamen at 
    intermediate rostrocaudal levels</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    13C-E).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s220">In the latter area, passing 
    fibres are more numerous than terminating fibres.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s221">In 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the 
    fibres</labelingDescription> tend to avoid clusters of densely 
    packed cells.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Dorsal agranular insular 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s223">In <exptLabel>case RP-89397</exptLabel>, a 
      <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injection was placed 
      dorsally in <injectionLocation>the caudal part of the dorsal 
      agranular insular area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 14).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s224">Most<labelingDescription>PHA-L labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> lie in <labelingLocation>layers 11, 
      111, and superficial V</labelingLocation>, whereas deep layer V 
      and layer VI are only slightly involved.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s225">In <labelingLocation>the striatum</labelingLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>fibres</labelingDescription> terminate 
      laterally in <labelingLocation>the core region of the nucleus 
      accumbens and in the ventral and ventrolatera1 parts of the 
      caudate-putamen complex</labelingLocation> (Fig. 14B,C).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s226">The terminal field consists of a densely labelled zone 
      with intervening areas of sparse or absent fibre labelling.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s227">Caudal to the nucleus accumbens, 
      <labelingDescription>PHA-L labelled fibres</labelingDescription> 
      in the caudate-putamen occupy a more medial position (Fig. 
      14D,E).</S>
    </TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">A more ventrally placed superficial 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposit (<exptLabel>case 
    RP-89375</exptLabel>) produces <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> that is <labelingDescription>most 
    dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>more rostra1 and 
    medial parts of the core of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>a 
    ventromedial sector of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Due to the involvement in this case of <injectionSpread>
    the ventral agranular insular area</injectionSpread> in the 
    injection site, <labelingDescription>fibre 
    labelling</labelingDescription> is present in <labelingLocation>the 
    areas described for case RP-89374</labelingLocation> as 
    well.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">In <labelingLocation>the border 
    region</labelingLocation> between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    nucleus accumbens</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the adjacent ventromedial part of the 
    caudate-putamen</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>the 
    restricted blank areas within the dense plexus of terminating 
    fibres</labelingDescription> coming from <connxOrigin>the 
    superficial layers of the dorsal agranular insular 
    area</connxOrigin> coincide with patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
    15A,B).</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">In <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, fibres originating from PHA-L 
    deposits that mainly involve<injectionLocation> layers I1 to 
    superficial V of the caudal part of the dorsal agranular insular 
    area</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>cases RP-89376 and 
    RP-89397</exptLabel>) distribute more densely to patches of 
    <labelingDescription>strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> than to 
    the surrounding areas.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">However, more rostrally placed injections, the centres 
    of which are located more superficially such that involvement of 
    the deeper layers can be excluded (e.g., <exptLabel>case 
    RP-895241</exptLabel>, produce a pattern of avoidance of the zones 
    of<labelingDescription> strong ENK-IR</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> (Fig. 16A,B).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">A <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injection in 
    the same part of <injectionLocation>the dorsal agranular insular 
    area</injectionLocation> as in <exptLabel>case 
    RP-89397</exptLabel>, but involving predominantly <injectionLocation
    >deep layer V and layer VI</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
    RP-89398</exptLabel>; Fig. lE), labels approximately 
    <labelingLocation>the same striatal 
    regions</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">However, in <exptLabel>case RP-89398</exptLabel>, 
    <labelingDescription>small fibre concentrations of variable 
    size</labelingDescription> are surrounded by 
    <labelingDescription>more sparsely labelled 
    areas</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="20" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s235">In <labelingLocation>the 
    border region between the nucleus accumbens and the ventromedial 
    part of the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, these fibre 
    aggregates overlap extensively with patches of strong ENK-IR (Fig. 
    17A).</S><S avgH="20" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s236">A similar relationship exists 
    in <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the caudate-putamen 
    complex</labelingLocation> (Fig. 16C,D).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">In <exptLabel>a few cases with caudally placed 
    injections in either <injectionLocation>the deep or the superficial 
    layers of the dorsal agranular insular 
    area</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>PHA-L 
    labelled fibres</labelingDescription> are present in 
    <labelingLocation>the rostrolateral part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s238">They terminate both in and 
    outside <labelingLocation>the large areas of strong ENK-IR that 
    surround the anterior commissure</labelingLocation>, but the 
    density of labelling is 
    <labelingDescription>highest</labelingDescription> outside these 
    areas (Fig. 15C,D).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s239">Projections from 
    <connxOrigin>the orbital prefrontal cortex</connxOrigin></S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240"><exptLabel>In 8 cases</exptLabel>, 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposits were placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the orbital subfields of the prefrontal 
    cortex</injectionLocation> (Fig. 2B).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s241">All of 
    these injections result in <labelingDescription>a terminal 
    plexus</labelingDescription> that is largely restricted to 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s242">The 
    medial-to-lateral gradient in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the orbital 
    prefrontal cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> is maintained in the 
    projections to <connxTermination>the 
    striatum</connxTermination>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Ventral orbital 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">The injection of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    in <exptLabel>case RP-90404</exptLabel> is largely restricted to 
    <injectionLocation>layers 11,111, and superficial V of the ventral 
    orbital area</injectionLocation>(Figs. lF, 18).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245"><labelingDescription>A small number of PHA-L labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the deep layers 
    of the cortex of the frontal pole</labelingLocation> cannot be 
    attributed to any particular cortical area.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246"><labelingDescription>The resulting terminal 
    plexus</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    striatum</labelingLocation> is largely confined to <labelingLocation
    >the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> where it occupies a 
    <labelingLocation>ventromedial region</labelingLocation> adjacent 
    to the <neuroanatomicalLandmark>lateral 
    ventricle</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 18).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247"><labelingDescription>This plexus</labelingDescription> 
    extends throughout <labelingLocation>the rostrocaudal extent of the 
    caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> and is most dense at 
    intermediate levels (Fig. 18B-F).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s248">Several 
    circumscribed <labelingDescription>unlabelled 
    areas</labelingDescription> within the terminal plexus coincide 
    with <labelingDescription>patches of strong 
    ENK-IR</labelingDescription> (Fig. 17B).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249"><labelingDescription>A small amount of terminal 
    labelling</labelingDescription> is present rostrally in 
    <labelingLocation>the olfactory tubercle and in the ventrolateral 
    part of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    18A-C).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Ventrolateral orbital 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s251"><exptLabel>Injections in <injectionLocation>the 
      ventrolatera1 orbital area</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      produce <labelingDescription>very sparse fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> centrally in <labelingLocation>
      the caudate-putamen complex</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Lateral orbital 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s253">The 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> deposit in <exptLabel>case 
    RP89363</exptLabel> predominantly involves <injectionLocation>
    layers 11,111, and superficial V of the lateral orbital 
    area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 19).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s254">The 
    resulting <labelingDescription>terminal label</labelingDescription> 
    is distinctly inhomogeneous and is located centrally in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation> at 
    intermediate rostrocaudal levels (Fig. 19C,D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Caudally, <labelingDescription>labelled 
    fibres</labelingDescription> shift to a more dorsal and medial 
    position (Fig. 19E).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s256">In addition to 
    <labelingDescription>the terminal plexus</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate-putamen</labelingLocation>, there is 
    <labelingDescription>sparse terminal label</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the nucleus accumbens, 
    the lateral part of the olfactory tubercle, and the fundus 
    striati</labelingLocation> (Fig. 19A-D).</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s257">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">In line with previous reports, the results of the 
    present anterograde tracing study in the rat demonstrate that the 
    prefrontal cortex projects bilaterally to the striatum, sparing 
    only the lateral part of the caudate-putamen complex (Beckstead, 
    &apos;79; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; Sesack et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Moreover, our results confirm that the prefrontal 
    corticostriatal projection is topographically organized (Johnson et 
    al., &apos;68; Beckstead, &apos;79; Reep and Winans, &apos;82; 
    McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; Sesack et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">However, due to the placement of PHA-L deposits 
    throughout the prefrontal cortex, a more detailed map of the 
    projections from the various cytoarchitectonic, and possibly 
    functionally different, prefrontal cortical subfields to the 
    striatum could be provided.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">In particular, the organization of the projections to 
    the ventral striatum has been clarified.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Furthermore, it could be demonstrated that the 
    topography of the prefrontal corticostriatal projections is 
    maintained within a given cortical area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">In combination with our data on the organization of the 
    midline and intralaminar projections to the prefrontal cortex 
    (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;91) and the striatum (Berendse and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;90a), the present results show that the 
    projections of individual prefrontal cortical areas converge in the 
    striatum with those of their midline and intralaminar afferent 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Last and perhaps most important, the present account 
    describes the relationship of the prefrontal cortical afferent 
    fibres with the ventral striatal compartments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Throughout most of the ventral striatum, the laminar 
    origin of the cortical fibres is the major factor determining their 
    relationship with the compartments (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Gerfen and Rutherford, &apos;88; Gerfen, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">In contrast, in the shell region of the nucleus 
    accumbens, the areal origin appears to be more important.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s268">Methodological 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">The use of the PHA-L tracing technique offers many 
    advantages when studying in detail the organization of projections 
    in small experimental animals (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; 
    Groenewegen and Wouterlood, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">However, potential drawbacks of the method are the 
    uptake of PHA-L by fibres of passage (Cliffer and Giesler, 
    &apos;88; Schofield, &apos;90) and the retrograde transport of 
    PHA-L (Shu and Peterson, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">In the present experiments, injections restricted to 
    deep cortical layers, through which fibres from more superficial 
    layers course towards the subcortical white matter, result in a 
    projection pattern in the striatum that is quite different from 
    that observed after more superficial PHA-L injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Therefore, it is quite unlikely that uptake of PHA-L by 
    fibres of passage is a confounding factor in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Retrograde neuronal labelling was limited to an 
    occasional cortical neuron at some distance from the injection 
    site.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s274">Topographical 
    organization of prefrontal corticostriatal projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">The organization of the prefrontal corticostriatal 
    projections is illustrated in Figure 20.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Each of the various cytoarchitectonic subfields of the 
    prefrontal cortex has a quite restricted terminal field in the 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Although it is likely that the projections from other 
    cortical areas will, in some parts of the striatum, overlap with 
    those of the prefrontal cortex (McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89), 
    there appears to be only a limited degree of overlap between the 
    projections of adjacent prefrontal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">The precise extent of the overlap can only be determined 
    by means of double anterograde tracing.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">The medial subdivision of the prefrontal cortex projects 
    predominantly to rostral and medial parts of the caudateputamen 
    complex, the nucleus accumbens, and the olfactory tubercle (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Beckstead, &apos;79; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; 
    Sesack et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">The lateral subdivision of the prefrontal cortex issues 
    fibres to the ventral part of the caudateputamen complex, the 
    central and lateral parts of the nucleus accumbens, and the lateral 
    part of the olfactory tubercle (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Beckstead, &apos;79; Newman and Winans, &apos;80a,b; 
    Reep and Winans, &apos;82; Christie et al., &apos;87; Fuller et 
    al., &apos;87; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Within the projections of the medial and lateral 
    prefrontal subdivisions, a ventral-todorsal gradient in the cortex 
    corresponds to a ventromedialto-dorsolateral gradient in the 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">The orbital or ventral subdivision of the prefrontal 
    cortex projects to the midventral and ventromedial parts of the 
    caudate-putamen (Beckstead, &apos;79; McGeorge and Faull, 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">The projections of the orbital subdivision are 
    topographically organized along a mediolateral axis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">The terminal zones in the striatum of the ventral and 
    ventrolateral orbital areas overlap with those of the prelimbic and 
    anterior cingular areas (compare Figs. 18 and 20).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">The present results demonstrate that the projections of 
    the medial orbital and infralimbic cortical areas reach identical 
    striatal areas, viz., the most ventromedial part of the nucleus 
    accumbens, the medial two-thirds of the olfactory tubercle, and the 
    amygdalostriatal transition zone (Fig. 20).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Taking together the similarities in cytoarchitecture 
    (Van Eden and Uylings, &apos;851, thalamic afferents (Berendse and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;9 11, and striatal efferents (present results), 
    it can be argued that the medial orbital and infralimbic areas 
    should be considered as a single cortical field.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">If the presence of projections from the mediodorsal 
    nucleus is a prerequisite for the inclusion of a particular 
    cortical area in the prefrontal cortex, the medial orbital and 
    infralimbic areas should not be denoted as prefrontal (Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77a; Groenewegen, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">However, since the projections from the parataenial 
    thalamic nucleus to both areas (Krettek and Price, &apos;77a; 
    Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;91) seem to be comparable to those 
    of the mediodorsal nucleus to the prefrontal cortex, the medial 
    orbital and infralimbic areas are here included in the prefrontal 
    cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Considering the projections of the prelimbic area as a 
    whole, the present findings are in agreement with those of previous 
    anterograde and retrograde tracing studies (Beckstead, &apos;79; 
    Room et al., &apos;85; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; Sesack et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Although the prelimbic area is cytoarchitonically 
    homogeneous, differential striatal projections were found for its 
    ventral versus its dorsal part (Fig. 20).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">The former issues fibres predominantly to the medial 
    part of the nucleus accumbens and the adjoining, most ventromedial 
    portion of the caudate-putamen, whereas, the latter projects 
    densely to a medial sector of the caudate-putamen and, at rostral 
    levels, to central and dorsolateral parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Deep layer V and layer VI of the dorsal part of the 
    prelimbic area project in addition to the most dorsomedial part of 
    the shell of the nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Similar dorsoventral differences in the corticofugal 
    connections have been reported earlier for the rostral part of the 
    prelimbic area (Sesack et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">The present results demonstrate that this 
    differentiation holds for the entire prelimbic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">In view of the differential inputs from the 
    paraventricular and central medial thalamic nuclei to the ventral 
    versus the dorsal part of the prelimbic area, and to their 
    respective striatal target zones (Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90a, &apos;91) it is tempting to suggest that the prelimbic 
    area is functionally heterogeneous.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">The observations that only the ventral part of the 
    prelimbic area projects to brainstem autonomic centres (Terreberry 
    and Neafsey, &apos;83, &apos;87; Neafsey et al., &apos;86b) and 
    receives projections from the CA1 field of the hippocampus and the 
    subiculum (Jay and Witter, &apos;91) lend additional support to 
    this assumption.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">The present results confirm the differences between the 
    striatal projections of the anterior cingular and medial agranular 
    areas (Beckstead, &apos;79; Veening et al., &apos;80; Kubozono et 
    al., &apos;86; Reep et al., &apos;87; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; 
    Sesack et al., &apos;89; Tehovnik et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Presently, these projections could be further 
    differentiated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">First, the ventral and dorsal subfields of the anterior 
    cingular area were found to have differential projections (Fig. 
    20).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Furthermore, rostrocaudal differences were observed 
    within the projections of both the dorsal anterior cingular and the 
    medial agranular areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Rostra1 (pregenual) parts of these areas project 
    ventrally and rostrally within the striatum, whereas the fibres 
    from caudal (supragenual) parts terminate in more dorsal and caudal 
    striatal regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">A similar pattern is apparent when the projections of 
    the ventral part of the anterior cingular area are compared with 
    those of the rostrally adjacent, dorsal part of the prelimbic 
    area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Consistent with the report by Reep and Winans (&apos;82) 
    in the hamster, we found differential striatal projections for the 
    ventral and dorsal agranular insular areas (see also McGeorge and 
    Faull, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">However, our data indicate that, in the rat, the 
    terminal field of the ventral agranular insular area is restricted 
    to the most ventrolateral parts of the nucleus accumbens and 
    olfactory tubercle, and that the striatal projection of the dorsal 
    subfield includes part of the nucleus accumbens (Fig. 20; cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Reep and Winans, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">The fibre labelling we observed in the midventral part 
    of the caudate-putamen, following an injection in the ventral 
    agranular insular area, most probably is the result of involvement 
    in the injection site of the rostrally adjacent lateral orbital 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Consistent with this interpretation, the lateral orbital 
    area, but not the ventral agranular insular area, displays labelled 
    cells following retrograde tracer injections in the caudate-putamen 
    (McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Conversely, the sparse terminal label that was observed 
    in the ventrolateral part of the nucleus accumbens, the lateral 
    part of the olfactory tubercle, and the fundus striati, in cases 
    with injections in the lateral orbital area, probably results from 
    the involvement in the injection site of the caudally adjacent 
    ventral agranular insular area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">The present study is the first to describe the 
    topography in the projections from the orbital subdivision of the 
    prefrontal cortex to the ventral part of the caudate-putamen 
    (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Beckstead, &apos;79).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s313">Parallel arrangement of 
    basal ganglia-thalamocortical circuits</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Previously, we have described the topographical 
    organization of the projections from the midline and intralaminar 
    thalamic nuclei to both the striatum and the cerebral cortex 
    (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">A comparison of the organization of these projections 
    with that of the prefrontal corticostriatal projections reveals 
    that the projections from interconnected parts of the prefrontal 
    cortex and the midline and intralaminar nuclear complex converge in 
    the same part of the striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">For instance, the intermediodorsal thalamic nucleus 
    projects both to the caudal part of the core region of the nucleus 
    accumbens and to the dorsal agranular insular area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">The latter cortical area projects to the caudal part of 
    the accumbal core as well (present results).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">A similar arrangement has been described in Tupaza for 
    the afferents from the pulvinar and the visual cortex to the caudal 
    part of the putamen (Matelli et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Since the pathways from the striatum via the pallidum 
    and the thalamus back to the prefrontal cortex are also 
    characterized by a high degree of segregation (Groenewegen, 
    &apos;88; Groenewegen and Berendse, &apos;90; Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;goal, the available anatomical data indicate that, in the 
    rat, the prefrontal cortex, the related parts of the midline and 
    intralaminar nuclei and their striatal targets, are involved in 
    multiple parallel circuits that lead via the basal ganglia back to 
    the prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Specific parts of the basolatera1 amygdaloid nucleus may 
    be differentially involved in such circuits (Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Thus, the concept of a parallel organization of basal 
    forebrain circuitry, as originally suggested by Alexander et al. 
    (&apos;86, &apos;90) in the primate, is strengthened and can be 
    broadened to include the projections of the midline and 
    intralaminar nuclear complex to both the striatum and the 
    prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">The fact that the projections from the midline and 
    intralaminar thalamic nuclear complex to the cortex fit in with 
    this organization, leads us to speculate that a parallel 
    arrangement of connections is not restricted to basal ganglia 
    circuitry, but may represent a more general characteristic of 
    forebrain connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Our findings therefore support the ideas put forward by 
    Goldman-Rakic (&apos;88) based on the existence of several parallel 
    networks of corticocortical connections that process distinct 
    classes of information.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s324">Contralateral prefrontal 
    corticostriatal projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">In our experiments, the contralateral projections to the 
    most ventral parts of the nucleus accumbens and to the olfactory 
    tubercle were minimal.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">In other striatal areas, the contralateral projections 
    were generally less dense than the ipsilateral projections, but in 
    a few cases both components had equal densities.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Although superficially placed PHA-L deposits tend to 
    result in less dense contralateral labelling of the striatum, it is 
    not possible to establish an unequivocal relationship between the 
    laminar origin of the cortical afferents and the density of the 
    contralateral projections in the present material.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Previous studies by means of retrograde tracing 
    techniques have shown that the projections to the contralateral 
    striatum originate exclusively from layers I11 and superficial V 
    (Wilson, &apos;87; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">In contrast, the results of our experiments demonstrate 
    that injections of PHA-L restricted to deep layer V and layer VI 
    produce bilateral labelling of the striatum and, in addition, of 
    the corresponding layers of the contralateral homotopic cortical 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Moreover, in experiments in which injections of the 
    sensitive retrograde tracer choleratoxin subunit B were placed in 
    various parts of the nucleus accumbens, the density of label in the 
    deep layers of the contralateral prefrontal cortex equals that of 
    the ipsilateral side (unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">These results strongly suggest that crossed 
    corticostriatal neurons are present in deep layer V and layer VI as 
    well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Crossed corticostriatal neurons do not respond to 
    stimulation of the ipsilateral cerebral peduncle or thalamus 
    (Wilson, &apos;86, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Therefore, unless in the latter experiments the 
    placement of the recording electrodes was biased towards neurons in 
    the superficial cortical layers, it is unlikely that the crossed 
    corticostriatal neurons in the deep layers of the cerebral cortex 
    are identical to neurons projecting to the brainstem or 
    thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s334">Relationship of 
    prefrontal cortical fibres with ventral striatal compartments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Figure 21 summarizes the compartmental relationships of 
    the prefrontal corticostriatal fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">In each of the three previously defined regions of the 
    ventral striatum (see Results) these relationships are 
    different.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Therefore, the present results again emphasize that, 
    contrary to the situation in the dorsal striatum (see Gerfen, 
    &apos;84, &apos;85; Graybiel, &apos;84, &apos;go), the ventral 
    striatum has a compartmental ordering that varies from one region 
    to the other (Voorn et al., &apos;89; for reviews see Groenewegen 
    et al., &apos;89, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Within each of the three ventral striatal regions 
    considered, the differential input-output characteristics of the 
    compartments permit specific sets of cortical and thalamic inputs 
    to interact with neurons projecting to distinct targets in the 
    mesencephalon (Groenewegen et al., &apos;87; Berendse et al., 
    &apos;88, &apos;92; Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a; present 
    results).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">The present results show that, throughout the shell 
    region of the nucleus accumbens, fibres from the ventral part of 
    the prelimbic area concentrate inside areas of high cell density 
    and weak ENK-IR (Fig. 21).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Since the cell clusters in the nucleus accumbens 
    coincide with opiate receptor patches (Herkenham et al., &apos;84), 
    the present results confirm and extend the observation of Donoghue 
    and Herkenham (&apos;86) that prelimbic cortical fibres in the 
    caudomedial part of the nucleus accumbens overlie opiate receptor 
    patches.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">It could furthermore be established that both deep and 
    superficial layers of the ventral prelimbic area project to the 
    cell clusters.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">The deep layers of the dorsal part of the prelimbic area 
    issue fibres towards the most dorsomedial cell clusters only.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Contrary to the fibres from the prelimbic area, fibres 
    from the infralimbic area avoid the cell clusters.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Thus, in the shell region of the nucleus accumbens, the 
    areal origin of the fibres seems to be more important than their 
    laminar origin in determining the compartmental relationships.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">The neurons in the shell region of the striatum that 
    project to the ventral mesencephalon are located outside the cell 
    clusters (Berendse et al., &apos;921, and therefore lie in the 
    compartment receiving afferents from the infralimbic cortex, the 
    midline thalamic nuclei, and the ventral subiculum (Herkenham et 
    al., &apos;84; Groenewegen et al., &apos;87; Berendse and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;90a; present results).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">The same afferents may also establish contacts with 
    neurons inside the cell clusters, as their dendrites extend up to 
    50-100 km outside the clusters (Herkenham et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Unfortunately, our current knowledge of the output of 
    these clusters of small cells is limited to the observation that 
    they do not project to the ventral mesencephalon (Berendse et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Unpublished observations indicate that neurons inside as 
    well as outside the cell clusters project to the ventral 
    pallidum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">The projections of different parts of the amygdaloid 
    complex either selectively innervate or avoid the cell clusters 
    (Groenewegen et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">In the border region between the nucleus accumbens and 
    the ventral part of the caudate-putamen, the laminar origin of the 
    prefrontal afferent fibres determines their relationship with the 
    small patches of ENK-IR.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Fibres originating in layers I1 through superficial V 
    avoid the patches, whereas fibres arising from deep layer V and 
    layer VI selectively terminate inside the patches (Fig. 21).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Since the patches of ENK-IR in this part of the striatum 
    coincide with patches of weak calbindin D28ku-IR (Voorn et al., 
    &apos;89), the present findings confirm the observations by Gerfen 
    (&apos;89) that the laminar origin of fibres from the medial 
    prefrontal cortex determines their relationship to patches of weak 
    calbindin DL,,,-IR.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">The present results further indicate that, in the border 
    region between the nucleus accumbens and the caudate-putamen, the 
    compartmental relationships of fibres from the lateral and orbital 
    subdivisions of the prefrontal cortex are similar to those of 
    fibres from the medial prefrontal cortex (Fig. 21).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Fibres originating in layers I1 through superficial V of 
    both the lateral and orbital prefrontal subdivisions avoid patches 
    of strong ENK-IR within their terminal field, whereas fibres from 
    deep layer V and layer VI of the lateral prefrontal subdivision 
    terminate inside the patches.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Since none of our PHA-L deposits were confined to the 
    deep layers of the orbital subfields, we can only speculate that 
    the deep layers of these subfields project to the patches of strong 
    ENK-IR.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Considering the abovedescribed data, it would seem that, 
    at least in some parts of the striatum, the ontogenetically older, 
    deep layers of the prefrontal cortex project to the older patch 
    compartment, whereas younger, more superficial layers are related 
    to the younger matrix compartment (Fishell and van der Kooy, 
    &apos;87; van der Kooy and Fishell, &apos;87; Bayer, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">In this respect, it is interesting to note that the 
    paraventricular thalamic nucleus, which projects to the patches of 
    ENK-IR in the ventromedial part of the caudate-putamen and the 
    dorsal part of the nucleus accumbens (Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90a), sends fibres to deep layer V and layer VI of the dorsal 
    part of the prelimbic area (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">The other midline and intralaminar thalamic nuclei that 
    send fibres to the striatal neuropil surrounding the ENK-patches 
    (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a), project to superficial layer 
    V and layer I of this prefrontal area (Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;91 J.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Although conclusive evidence can only be provided by 
    means of electron microscopy, these findings seem to indicate that 
    in the border region of the nucleus accumbens and the 
    caudate-putamen, both the midline and intralaminar thalamic nuclei, 
    and the cortical neurons most directly influenced by these thalamic 
    nuclei, project to the same striatal Compartment.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Recent observations indicate that the great majority of 
    the ventral striatal neurons projecting to the ventral 
    mesencephalon have a dendritic tree that is confined to the 
    compartment in which the parent cell body resides (Groenewegen et 
    al., &apos;90b; cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Penny et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Therefore, fibres from the deep layers of the prefrontal 
    cortex may selectively contact neurons projecting to the substantia 
    nigra pars compacta, whereas fibres from more superficial layers 
    may reach neurons innervating the pars reticulata (Gerfen, 
    &apos;84, &apos;85, &apos;89; Berendse et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">In the rostrolateral part of the nucleus accumbens, 
    fibres coming from the deep layers of the prelimbic area distribute 
    in an inhomogeneous way over the moderately ENKimmunoreactive 
    compartment (Fig. 21).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Since the neurons that project to the ventral tegmental 
    area and the substantia nigra pars compacta are located in the 
    latter compartment (Groenewegen et al., &apos;89, &apos;91; 
    Berendse et al., &apos;92), only the afferents from the deep layers 
    of the prelimbic area may be selectively related to these 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">This is even more likely in view of the fact that, also 
    in this ventral striatal region, the dendritic tree of neurons 
    projecting to the mesencephalon is confined to the compartment in 
    which the cell body resides (Groenewegen et al., &apos;90b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">The other prefrontal afferents show only a preference 
    for, but are not restricted to, the moderately ENK-immunoreactive 
    compartment and may therefore additionally contact neurons 
    projecting to the substantia nigra pars reticulata (Berendse et 
    al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">In addition to the above-mentioned clustering of fibres 
    from the deep layers of the medial prefrontal cortex within a 
    single neurochemical striatal compartment, patterns of dense versus 
    extremely dense labelling occur within the termination fields of 
    the superficial cortical layers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">This type of arrangement suggests the presence of 
    additional compartments in the striatum (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Malach and Graybiel, &apos;86; Jimenez-Castellanos and 
    Graybiel, &apos;89; GimenezAmaya and Graybiel, &apos;90) or, 
    alternatively, indicates that the inhomogeneities are related to a 
    columnar organization in the cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Differences in the density of striatal labelling could 
    thus be explained by a variable involvement of adjacent columns by 
    a single tracer injection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">In cats and monkeys, a pattern of dorsal fills and 
    ventral avoids of the striosomal compartment was reported following 
    large injections of tritiated amino acids in the frontoinsular 
    cortex (Ragsdale and Graybiel, &apos;81, &apos;84, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">It is unclear to what extent this pattern is comparable 
    to the differential relationships of prelimbic cortical fibres with 
    ENK-positive areas in different striatal sectors, observed in the 
    present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">More likely, the pattern is caused by the differential 
    involvement of cortical layers in adjacent cortical columns.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s374">Functional 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">An overall topographical organization of corticostriatal 
    projections has been demonstrated previously in several species 
    (rat: Webster, &apos;61; McGeorge and Faull, &apos;89; rabbit: 
    Carman et al., &apos;63; cat: Webster, &apos;65; Jayaraman, 
    &apos;85; dog: Tanaka, &apos;79, &apos;83, &apos;87; Tanaka et al., 
    &apos;79, &apos;81; monkey: Kemp and Powell, &apos;70; Kunzle, 
    &apos;75, &apos;77, &apos;78; Kunzle and Akert, &apos;77; Yeterian 
    and Van Hoesen, &apos;78; Van Hoesen et al., &apos;81; Seiemon and 
    Goldman-Rakic, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Thus, functionally different cortical regions have, at 
    least to some degree, separate projection fields in the 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">This arrangement indicates that the striatum is 
    functionally heterogeneous, which is in agreement with the results 
    of physiological and behavioural studies (Winocur, &apos;74; Oberg 
    and Divac, &apos;75; Rosenkilde and Divac, &apos;76; Divac et al., 
    &apos;78; Dunnett and Iversen, &apos;80, &apos;81, &apos;82a,b,c; 
    Rolls and Williams, &apos;87; Pisa, &apos;88; Kelley et al., 
    &apos;88, &apos;89; Pisa and Schranz, &apos;88; Pisa and Cyr, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">The presently observed detailed topographical 
    organization of the projections from the prefrontal cortex to the 
    striatum may therefore be considered as the anatomical substrate 
    for an even more fine-grained functional heterogeneity of those 
    parts of the striatum that receive prefrontal cortical 
    afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">The above-discussed convergence in the striatum of 
    afferents from parts of the prefrontal cortex and the midline, and 
    intralaminar thalamic nuclear complex that are interconnected, as 
    well as the degree of segregation in the subsequent 
    striatopallidal, pallidothalamic (Groenewegen and Berendse, 
    &apos;90; Groenewegen et al., &apos;90a) and mediodorsal-prefrontal 
    (Groenewegen, &apos;88) pathways, lend further support to this 
    assumption.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">In order to define the functional attributes of the 
    anatomical circuits involving the prefrontal cortex in the rat, a 
    detailed knowledge of the functions in which individual 
    cytoarchitectonic prefrontal cortical areas and single midline and 
    intralaminar nuclei are involved is a prerequisite.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">In spite of the fact that many different functions have 
    been ascribed to the prefrontal cortex (for review see Kolb, 
    &apos;84, &apos;go), the information on functional specialization 
    of individual subfields is still fragmentary.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">The infralimbic area and the ventral part of the 
    prelimbic area are considered to function as visceral motor 
    cortical regions, involved in the control of a variety of autonomic 
    functions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">They project directly to autonomic centres of the 
    brainstem, including the nucleus of the solitary tract (Terreberry 
    and Neafsey, &apos;83, &apos;87; van der Kooy et al., &apos;84; 
    Neafsey et al., &apos;86b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Moreover, stimulation of these cortical areas results in 
    changes in heart rate, blood pressure, and gastric motility 
    (Terreberry and Neafsey, &apos;84; Hurley-Gius and Neafsey, 
    &apos;86; Hardy and Holmes, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Other brain areas involved in cardiovascular andlor 
    respiratory responses, such as the paraventricular thalamic 
    nucleus, project to the infralimbic and/or ventral prelimbic areas 
    (Ruit and Neafsey, &apos;88, &apos;90; Buchanan et al., &apos;89; 
    Jay and Witter, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">The functions of more dorsal parts of the medial 
    prefrontal cortex, viz., the dorsal part of the prelimbic area, the 
    anterior cingular area, and the medial agranular area, are rather 
    diverse.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">The medial agranular area, particularly its rostra1 
    part, is generally considered as the rodent homologue of the 
    frontal eye field, with additional supplementary motor and premotor 
    characteristics (Hall and Lindholm, &apos;74; Neafsey et al., 
    &apos;86a,b; Reep et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Furthermore, lesions of both the medial agranular and 
    anterior cingular area induce contralateral neglect (Cowey and 
    Bozek, &apos;74; Crowne et al., &apos;83; Kolb, &apos;84; Corwin et 
    al., &apos;86; Vargo et al., &apos;88; Christie et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Last, the medial wall of the hemisphere appears to be 
    involved in spatial tasks and blood pressure control (Eichenbaum et 
    al., &apos;83; Kolb, &apos;84, &apos;90; Burns and Wyss, &apos;85; 
    Verberne et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">The connections of the agranular insular area suggest 
    that it takes part in the regulation of visceral processes (Saper, 
    &apos;82; van der Kooy et al., &apos;84; Terreberry and Neafsey, 
    &apos;87; Ruggiero et al., &apos;87; Krushel and van der Kooy, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">It has been suggested that, contrary to the infralimbic 
    and ventral prelimbic areas which are involved in visceral motor 
    functions (see above), the agranular insular area participates in 
    visceral sensory processes only (Saper, &apos;82; Terreberry and 
    Neafsey, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">More specifically, gustatory (Saper, &apos;82; Shipley 
    and Geinisman, &apos;84; Kosar et al., &apos;86a,b) and olfactory 
    (Price and Slotnick, &apos;83; Eichenbaum et al., &apos;83) 
    functions are subserved by this prefrontal area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Cardiovascular effects of stimulation of the agranular 
    insular area have also been reported (Buchanan and Powell, 
    &apos;87; Ruggiero et al., &apos;87; Hardy and Holmes, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">The functional characteristics of the orbital areas of 
    the prefrontal cortex have as yet not been elucidated in any 
    detail.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Some of the subfields may be involved in olfactory 
    functions (Price and Slotnick, &apos;83; Eichenbaum et al., 
    &apos;83) or in agression and feedingidrinking behaviours (Reep, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">The above-described functional differentiation in the 
    prefrontal cortex, though at present rather crude, should be 
    parallelled by a similar functional specialization in the striatum; 
    that is, if we assume that functions are coupled to specific 
    prefrontal corticostriatofugal pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Although the general principle of functional 
    heterogeneity associated with the topical input from the cerebral 
    cortex has been demonstrated quite convincingly in physiological 
    and behavioural studies (for references see above), the 
    differential effects of striatal lesions involving the different 
    projection fields of distinct prefrontal cortical areas have not 
    been studied in detail.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">B0t.h in the monkey (Rosvold, 68, 72) and in the rat 
    (Dunnett and Iversen, 80, 81, 82a,b) the striatal target of the 
    medial subdivision of the prefrontal cortex has been functionally 
    differentiated from that of the orbital and lateral 
    subdivisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Dunnett and Iversen found disturbed oral functions 
    following lesions ventrolaterally in the caudate-putamen of the rat 
    (see also Kelly et al., 88, 891, whereas, disturbances on delayed 
    response tasks resulted from dorsomedial caudate-putamen 
    lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">More detailed behavioural and pharmacological analyses 
    of the prefrontal cortical areas and their related striatal sectors 
    are required for a better understanding of the functions executed 
    by the various basal ganglia-thalamocortical circuits that involve 
    distinct parts of the prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">In these analyses, the midline and intralaminar thalamic 
    afferents and the inputs from other cortical areas to the same 
    striatal sectors will also have to be taken into account.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">The results of the present and previous tracing studies, 
    in which the organizations of the thalamostriatal, thalamocortical, 
    and prefrontal corticostriatal projections have been analyzed, 
    provide an anatomical map that may facilitate future 
    investigations.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s403">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s404">We thank Drs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s405">A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s406">Lohman, Pieter Voorn and 
    Gerrit Docter, Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s407">Dirk de Jong, and Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s408">M.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s409">Arts for their help in the 
    preparation of the manuscript.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s410">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Alexander, G.E., and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Crutcher (1990) Functional architecture of basal ganglia 
    circuits: neural substrates of parallel processing.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">TINS 13:266271.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Alexander, G.E., M.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">DeLong, and P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Strick (1986) Parallel organization of functionally 
    segregated circuits linking basal ganglia and cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Neurosci. 9:357-381.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Alexander, G.E., M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Crutcher, and M.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">DeLong (1990) Basal gangliathalamocortical circuits: 
    Parallel substrates for motor, oculomotor, prefrontal and limbic 
    functions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">In H.B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Uylings, C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Van Eden, J.P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">De Bruin, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Corner, and M.G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Feenstra (eds): The Prefrontal Cortex: Its Structure, 
    Function, and Pathology (Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Brain Res. 85).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 119-146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Arikuni, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Kubota (1986) The organization of prefrontocaudate 
    projections and their laminar origin in the macaque monkey: A 
    retrograde study using HRP-gel.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Neurol. 244:492%510.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Bayer, S.A. (1990) Neurogenetic patterns in the medial 
    limbic cortex of the rat related to anatomical connections with the 
    thalamus and striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">IO7r132-142.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Beckstead, R.M. (1979) An autoradiographic examination 
    of corticocortical and subcortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal-projection (prefrontal) cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Neurol. 184:4342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Groenewegen (1990a) Organization of the thalamostriatal 
    projections in the rat, with special emphasis on the ventral 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Neurol. 299:187-228.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Groenewegen (1990b) Parallel arrangement of forebrain 
    circuits in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Prefrontal cortex, midline and intralaminar thalamic 
    nuclei, and ventral striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Neurosci. 16:426 (Abstract).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Groenewegen (1991) Restricted cortical termination 
    fields of the midline and intralaminar thalamic nuclei in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Neuroscience 4273-102.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Berendse, H.W., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Voorn, A. te Kortschot, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Groenewegen (1988) Nuclear origin of thalamic afferents 
    of the ventral striatum determines their relation to patch/matrix 
    configurations in enkephalin-immunoreactivityin the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Chem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Neuroanat. 1:3-10.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Berendse, H.W., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Groenewegen, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Lohman (1992) Compartmental distribution of ventral 
    striatal neurons projecting to the mesencephalon in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Neurosci., in press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Buchanan, S.L., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Powell (1987) 3H-2-Deoxyglucose uptake after electrical 
    stimulation of cardioactive sites in insular cortex and mediodorsal 
    nucleus of the thalamus in rabbits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Bull. 19r439-452.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Buchanan, S.L., R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Thompson, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Powell (1989) Midline thalamic lesions enhance 
    conditioned bradycardia and the cardiac orienting reflex in 
    rabbits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">PsychobiologV 17:300306.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Burns, S.M., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Wyss (1985) The involvement of the anterior cingulate 
    cortex in blood pressure control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Brain Res. 34Ot71-77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Carman, J.B., W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Cowan, and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Powell (1963) The organization cortico-striate 
    connexions in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Brain 86:525-564.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Christie, D., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Terry, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Oakley (1990) The effect of unilateral anteromedial 
    cortex lesions on prey-catching and spatio-motor behaviour in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Brain Res. 37:263-268.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Christie, M.J., R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Summers, J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Stephenson, C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Cook, and P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Beart (1987) Excitatory amino acid projections to the 
    nucleus accumbens septi in the rat: A retrograde transport study 
    utilizing DL3H1aspartate and c3H1GABA.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Neuroscience 22:425439.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Cliffer, K.D., and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Giesler, Jr. (1988) PHA-L can be transported 
    anterogradely through fibers of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Brain Res. 458:185-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Corwin, J.V., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Kanter, R.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Watson, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Heilman, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Valenstein, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Hashimoto (1986) Apomorphine has a therapeutic effect on 
    neglect produced by unilateral dorsomedial prefrontal cortex 
    lesions in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Neurol. 94t683-698.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Cowey, A,, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Bozek (1974) Contralateral neglect after dorsomedial 
    prefrontal lesions in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Brain Res. 725343.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Crowne, D.P., C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Richardson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Ward (1983) Brief deprivation of vision after unilateral 
    lesions of the frontal eye field prevents contralateral 
    inattention.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Science 220:527-530.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Divac, I., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Markowitsch, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Pritzel (1978) Behavioral and anatomical consequences of 
    small intrastriatal injections of kainic acid in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Brain Res. 151r523-532.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Donoghue, J.P., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Herkenham (1986) Neostriatal projections from individual 
    cortical fields conform to histochemically distinct striatal 
    compartments in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Brain Res. 365:397403.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Donoghue, J.P., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Parham (1983) Afferent connections of the lateral 
    agranular field of the rat motor cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Neurol. 21 7:390404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Dunnett, S.B., and S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Iversen (1980) Regulatory impairments following 
    selective kainic acid lesions of the neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Brain Res. 1;497-506.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Dunnett, S.B., and S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Iversen (1981) Learning impairments following selective 
    kainic acid-induced lesions within the neostriatum of rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Brain Res. 2189-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Dunnett, S.B., and S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Iversen (1982a) Regulatory impairments following 
    selective 6-OHDA lesions of the neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Brain Res. 4:195202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Dunnett, S.B., and S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Iversen (198213) Neurotoxic lesions of ventrolateral but 
    not anteromedial neostriatum impair differential reinforcement of 
    low rates (DRL) performance.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Brain Res. 6r213-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Dunnett, S.B., and S.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Iversen (198%) Sensorimotor impairments following 
    localized kainic acid and 6-hydroxydopamine lesions of the 
    neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Brain Res. 248:121-127.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Eichenbaum, H., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Clegg, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Feeley (1983) Reexamination of functional subdivisions 
    of the rodent prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Neurol. 79:43445 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Fishell, G., and D. van der Kooy (1987) Pattern 
    formation in the striatum: Developmental changes in the 
    distribution of striatonigral neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Neurosci. 7:1969-1978.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Fuller, T.A., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Russchen, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Price (1987) Sources of presumptive 
    glutamergiciaspartergic afferents to the rat ventral 
    striatopallidal region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Neurol. 258.317-338.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Gerfen, C.R. (1984) The neostriatal mosaic: 
    Compartmentalization of corticostriatal input and striatonigral 
    output systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Nature 31 1:461464.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Gerfen, C.R. (1985) The neostriatal mosaic.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Compartmental organization of projections from the 
    striatum to the substantia nigra in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Neurol. 236:454-476.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Gerfen, C.R. (1989) The neostriatal mosaic: Striatal 
    patch-matrix organization is related to cortical lamination.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Science 246:385-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Gerfen, C.R., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Rutherford (1988) Laminar origin of patchand 
    matrix-directed corticostriatal projections in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Neurosci. 14:76 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Gimenez-Amaya, J.M., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Graybiel(1990) Compartmental origins of the 
    striatopallidal projection in the primate.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Neuroscience 34:lll-126.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Goldman-Rakic, P.S. (1988) Topography of cognition: 
    Parallel distributed networks in primate association cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Neurosci. 11:137-156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Goldman, P.S., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Nauta (1977) An intricately patterned prefrontocaudate 
    projection in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Neurol. 171 :369-386.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Graybiel, A.M. (1984) Neurochemically specified 
    subsystems in the basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">In D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Evered and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">O Connor (eds): Functions of the Basal Ganglia (Ciba 
    Foundation Symposium 107).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">London: Pitman, pp. 114149.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Graybiel, A.M. (1990) Neurotransmitters ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">TINS 132444254, Groenewegen, H.J. (1988) Organization of 
    the afferent connections of the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus in the 
    rat, related to the mediodorsalprefrontal topography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Neuroscience 24r37943 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Groenewegen, H.J., and H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Berendse (1990) Parallel arrangement of forebrain 
    circuits in the rat. 2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Ventral striatum, ventral pallidum, and mediodorsal 
    thalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Neurosci. 16:426 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Groenewegen, H.J., and F.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Wouterlood (1990) Light and electron microscopic tracing 
    of neuronal connections with Phaseolus uulgarisleucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L), and combinations with other neuroanatomical techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Hokfelt, F.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Wouterlood and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Van den Pol (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 
    Vol. 8: Neuronal Microcircuits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Amsterdam, Elsevier, pp. 47-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Groenewegen, H.J., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Vermeulen-Van der Zee, A. te Kortschot, and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Witter (1987) Organization of the projections from the 
    subiculum to the ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">A study using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Neuroscience 23: 103-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Groenewegen, H.J., G.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Meredith, H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Berendse, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Voorn, and J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Wolters (1989) The compartmental organization of the 
    ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">In A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Crossman and M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Sambrook (eds): Neural Mechanisms in Disorders of 
    Movement (Current Problems in Neurology, Vol. 9).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">London: John Libbey, pp. 45-54.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Groenewegen, H.J., H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Berendse, J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Wolters, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Lohman (1990a) The anatomical relationship of the 
    prefrontal cortex with the striatopallidal system, the thalamus and 
    the amygdala: Evidence for a parallel organization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">In H.B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Uylings, C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Van Eden, J.P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">De Bruin, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Corner, and M.G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Feenstra (eds): The Prefrontal Cortex: Its Structure, 
    Function, and Pathology (Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Vol. 85) Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 95-118.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Groenewegen, H.J., M.P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Arts, and H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Berendse (1990b) A cellular basis for the compartmental 
    structure of the ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Suppl. 3294 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Groenewegen, H.J., H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Berendse, G.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Meredith, S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Haber, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Voorn, J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Wolters, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Lohman (1991) Functional anatomy of the ventral, limbic 
    system-innervated striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">In P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Willner and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">ScheelKriiger (eds): The Mesolimbic Dopamine System: 
    From Motivation to Action.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, pp. 19-59.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Hall, R.D., and E.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Lindholm (1974) Organization of motor and somatosensory 
    neocortex in the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Brain Res. 66223-38.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Hardy, S.G.P., and D.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Holmes (1988) Prefrontal stimulus-produced hypotension 
    in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Brain Res. 73349-255.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Herkenham, M., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Moon Edley, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Stuart (1984) Cell clusters in the nucleus accumbens of 
    the rat, and the mosaic relationship of opiate receptors, 
    acetylcholinesterase and subcortical afferent terminations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Neuroscience 11:561593.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Hurley-Gius, K.M., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Neafsey (1986) The medial frontal cortex and gastric 
    motility: Microstimulation results and their possible significance 
    for the overall pattern of organization of rat frontal and parietal 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Brain Res. 365.241-248.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Jay, T.M., and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Witter (1991) Distribution of the hippocampal CA1 and 
    subicular efferents in the prefrontal cortex of the rat: A study 
    using anterograde transport of Phaseolus uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Neurol., in press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Jayaraman, A. (1985) Functional compartments Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Neurosci. 11:199 (Abstract).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Jimenez-Castellanos, J., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Graybiel(1989) Compartmental origins of striatal 
    efferent projections in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Neuroscience 32.297-321.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Johnson, T.N., H.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Rosvold, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Mishkin (1968) Projections from behaviorally-defined 
    sectors of the prefrontal cortex to the basal ganglia, septum, and 
    diencepbalon of the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Neurol. 21r20-34.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Jones, E.G., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Leavitt (1974) Retrograde axonal transport and the 
    demonstration of non-specific projections to the cerebral cortex 
    and striatum from thalamic intralaminar nuclei in the rat, cat and 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Neurol. 154:349-378.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Kelley, A.E., C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Lang, and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Gauthier (1988) Induction of oral stereotypy following 
    amphetamine microinjection into a discrete subregion of the 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Psychopharmacology 95:556-559.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Kelley, A.E., A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Gauthier, and C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Lang (1989) Amphetamine microinjections into distinct 
    striatal subregions cause dissociable effects on motor and 
    ingestive behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Brain Res. 35.27-39.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Kemp, J.M., and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Powell (1970) The cortico-striate projection in the 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Brain 93:525-546.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Kemp, J.M., and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Powell (1971) The connexions of the striatum and glohus 
    pallidus: Synthesis and speculation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Phil.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Trans.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Lond.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">B. 262:441457.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Kolb, B. (1984) Functions of the frontal cortex of the 
    rat: A comparative review.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Rev. 8r65-98.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Kolb, B. (1990) Prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">In B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Kolb and R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Tees (eds): The Cerebral Cortex of the Rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, pp. 437-458.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Kosar, E., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Grill, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Norgren (1986a) Gustatory cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Physiological properties and cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Brain Res. 379t329-341.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Kosar, E., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Grill, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Norgren (1986b) Gustatory cortex in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Thalamocortical projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Brain Res. 379:342-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Price (1977a) The cortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus and adjacent thalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Neurol. 171:157-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Price (1977b) Projections from the amygdaloid complex to 
    the cerebral cortex and thalamus in the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Neurol. 172687-722.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Krushel, L.A., and D. van der Kooy (1988) Visceral 
    cortex: Integration of the mucosal senses with limbic information 
    in the rat agranular insular cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Neurol. 270:39-54.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Kuhozono, T., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Nakano, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Tokushige, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">Hasegawa, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Kohno (1986) Topographical organization of the 
    projections from the cerebral cortex to the head of the caudate 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">A horseradish peroxidase study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Neuroscience 19: 113-123.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Kunzle, H. (1975) Bilateral projections from precentral 
    motor cortex to the putamen and other parts of the basal 
    ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">An autoradiographic study in Macaca fusczularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Brain Res. 88:195-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Kunzle, H. (1977) Projections from the primary 
    somatosensory cortex to basal ganglia and thalamus in the 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Brain Res. 30:481492.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Kunzle, H. (1978) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    efferent connections from premotor and adjacent prefrontal regions 
    (areas 6 and 9) inMacaca fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Evol. 15:185-234.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Kunzle, H., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Akert (1977) Efferent connections of cortical area 8 
    (frontal eye field) in Macaca fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">A reinvestigation using the autoradiographic 
    technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Neurol. 173:147-164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Leonard, C.M. (1969) The prefrontal cortex of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Cortical projection of the mediodorsal nucleus. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">Efferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Brain Res. 12:321343.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Malach, R., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Graybiel (1986) Mosaic architecture of the somatic 
    sensory-recipient sector of the cat s striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Neurosci. 6:34363458.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Matelli, M., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Luppino, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Fitzpatrick, and I.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Diamond (1988) The pulvinar nucleus of Tupaia: 
    Comparative study of its connections with the superior colliculus, 
    the neocortex and the corpus striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Bentivoglio and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Spreafico (eds): Cellular Thalamic Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 207-220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">McDonald, A.J. (1987) Organization of amygdaloid 
    projections to the mediodorsal thalamus and prefrontal cortex: A 
    fluorescense retrograde transport study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">Neurol. 26246-58.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">McGeorge, A.J., and R.L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Faull (1989) The organization of the projection from the 
    cerebral cortex to the striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Neuroscience 29:503-537.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">Merker, B. (1983) Silver staining of cell bodies 
    development.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Meth. 9r235-241.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Neafsey, E.J., E.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Bold, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Haas, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Hurley-Gius, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Quirk, C.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">Sievert, and R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Terreberry (1986a) The organization of the rat motor 
    cortex: A microstimulation mapping study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">Rev. 11:77-96.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">Neafsey, E.J., K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Hurley-Gius, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Arvanitis (1986b) The topographical organization of 
    neurons in the rat medial frontal, insular and olfactory cortex 
    projecting to the solitary nucleus, olfactory bulb, periaqueductal 
    gray and superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Brain Res. 377,261-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Newman, R., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Winans (1980a) An experimental study of the ventral 
    striatum of the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Neuronal connections of the nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Neurol. 191:167-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">Newman, R., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Winans (1980b) An experimental study of the ventral 
    striatum of the golden hamster. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Neuronal connections of the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Neurol. 191:193-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Oberg, R.G.E., and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Divac (1975) Dissociative effects of selective lesions 
    in the caudate nucleus of cats and rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Acta Neurobiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">Exp. 35:647-659.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates, 
    Second Edition.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">Penny, G.R., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Wilson, and S.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Kitai (1988) Relationship of the axonal and dendritic 
    geometry of spiny projection neurons to the compartmental 
    organization of the neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">Neurol. 269275-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Pisa, M. (1988) Motor somatotopy in the striatum of rat: 
    manipulation, biting and gait.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Brain Res. 272-35.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">Pisa, M., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Cyr (1990) Regionally selective roles of the rat s 
    striatum in modality-specific discrimination learning and forelimb 
    reaching.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">Brain Res. 37:281-292.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Pisa, M., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Schranz (1988) Dissociable motor roles of the rat s 
    striatum conform to a somatotopic model.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">I02:429440.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Price, J.L., and B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Slotnick (1983) Dual olfactory representation in the rat 
    thalamus: An anatomical and electrophysiological study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">Neurol. 2 15:63-7 7.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Ragsdale, C.W., Jr., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Graybiel(1981) The fronto-striatal projection in the cat 
    and monkey and its relationship to inhomogeneities established by 
    acetyl-cholinesterase histochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Brain Res. 208r259-266.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Ragsdale, C.W., Jr., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">Graybiel (1984) Further observations on the striosomal 
    organization of frontostriatal projections in cats and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Neurosci. 10:514 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">Ragsdale, C.W., Jr., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Graybiel(1990) A simple ordering of neocortical areas 
    established by the compartmental organization of their striatal 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">USA 87:619&amp;6199.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Reep, R.L. (1984) Relationship between prefrontal and 
    limbic cortex: A comparative anatomical review.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Evol. 25r5-80.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Reep, R.L., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Winans (1982) Efferent connections of dorsal and ventral 
    agranular insular cortex in the hamster, Mesocricetus auratus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Neuroscience 72609-2635.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">Reep, R.L., J.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Corwin, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">Hasbimoto, and R.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Watson (1987) Efferent connections of the rostra1 
    portion of medial agranular cortex in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Bull. 19:203-221.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Rolls, E.T., and G.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Williams (1987) Sensory and movement-related neuronal 
    activity in different regions of the primate striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">In J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">Schneider and T.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Lidsky (eds): Basal Ganglia and Behavior: Sensory 
    Aspects of Motor Functioning.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Toronto: Hans Huber Publishers, pp. 37-59.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Room, P., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">Russchen, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Groenewegen, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Lohman (1985) Efferent connections of the prelimbic 
    (area 32) and the infralimbic (area 25) cortices: An anterograde 
    tracing study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Neurol. 242:40-55.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Rose, J.E., and C.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Woolsey (1948) Structure and anterior thalamic nuclei in 
    rabbit 89: 2 79-347.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Rosenkilde, C.E., and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Divac (1976) Time-discrimination performance in cats 
    with lesions in prefrontal cortex and caudate nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Psychol. 90:343-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Rosvold, H.E. (1968) The prefrontal cortex and caudate 
    nucleus: A system for effecting correction in response 
    mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">In C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Rupp (ed): Mind as a Tissue.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">New York: Hoeber, pp. 21-38.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Rosvold, H.E. (1972) The frontal lobe system: 
    Cortical-subcortical interrelationships.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Acta Neurobiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">Exp. 32:439460.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Ruggiero, D.A., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Mraovitch, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">Granata, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Anwar, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">Reis (1987) A role of insular cortex in cardiovascular 
    function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Neurol. 257:189-207.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">Ruit, K.G., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Neafsey (1988) Cardiovascular and respiratory responses 
    to electrical and chemical stimulation of the hippocampus in 
    anesthetized and awake rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Brain Res. 457:310-321.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Ruit, K.G., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Neafsey (1990) Hippocampal input to a visceral motor 
    corticobulbar pathway: An anatomical and electrophysiological study 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Brain Res. 82:606-616.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">Saper, C.B. (1982) Convergence of autonomic and limbic 
    connections in the insular cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Neurol. 21Ot163-173.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">Schofield, B.R. (1990) Uptake ofPhaseolus uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) by axons of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Meth. 35:47-56.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Selemon, L.D., and P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Goldman-Rakic (1985) Longitudinal topography and 
    interdigitation of corticostriatal projections in the rhesus 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Neurosci. 5:776-794.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">Sesack, S.R., A.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">Deutch, R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">Roth, and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">Bunney (1989) Topographical organization of the efferent 
    projections of the medial prefrontal cortex in the rat: An 
    anterograde tract-tracing study with Phaseolus uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">Neurol. 290:213-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">Shipley, M.T., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">Geinisman (1984) Anatomical evidence for convergence of 
    olfactory, gustatory, and visceral afferent pathways in mouse 
    cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">Bull. 12:221-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Shu, S.Y., and G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Peterson (1988) Anterograde and retrograde axonal 
    transport of Phaseolus uulgan s-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) from the 
    globus pallidus to the striatum of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">Meth. 25175-180.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Tanaka, D., Jr. (1979) Differential projections to the 
    neostriatum from the arm areas of the primary and supplementary 
    motor cortices in the dog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Brain Res. 172:150-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">Tanaka, D., Jr. (1983) Corticostriate projections from 
    reciprocally connected sectors of areas 4 and 5 in the dog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Neurol. 80:613-621.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Tanaka, D., Jr. (1987) Neostriatal projections from 
    cytoarchitectonically defined gyri in the prefrontal cortex of the 
    dog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">Neurol. 261:48-73.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">Tanaka, D., Jr., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Gorska, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Dutkiewicz (1979) Differential projections to the 
    neostriatum from the arm areas of the primary and supplementary 
    motor cortices in the dog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">Brain Res. 172: 150-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">Tanaka, D., Jr., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">Gorska, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Dutkiewicz (1981) Corticostriate projections from the 
    primary motor cortex in the dog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">Brain Res. 209:287-303.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">Tehovnik, E.J., S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Spence, and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">Saint-Cyr (1989) Efferent projections of the 
    anteromedial cortex of the rat as described by Phaseolus uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">Brain Res. 35: 153-162.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">Terreberry, R.R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Neafsey (1983) Rat medial frontal cortex: a visceral 
    motor region with a direct projection to the solitary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">Brain Res. 278:245-249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">Terreberry, R.R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Neafsey (1984) The effects of medial prefrontal cortex 
    stimulation on heart rate in the awake rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">Neurosci. 10:614 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">Terreberry, R.R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Neafsey (1987) The rat medial frontal cortex projects 
    directly to autonomic regions of the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">Bull. 19:639-649.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">Uylings, H.B.M., and C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">Van Eden (1990) Qualitative and quantitative comparison 
    of the prefrontal cortices in rat and in primates, including 
    humans.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">In H.B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Uylings, C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">Van Eden, J.P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">De Bruin, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">Corner, and M.G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">Feenstra (eds): The Prefrontal Cortex: Its Structure, 
    Function, and Pathology (Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Brain Res. 85) Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 31-62. der Kooy, 
    D., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">Fishell (1987) Neuronal birthdate underlies the 
    development of striatal compartments in the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">Brain Res. 401:155161.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">der Kooy, D., L.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Koda, J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">McGinty, C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">Gerfen, and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">Bloom (1984) The organization of projections from the 
    cortex, amygdala, and hypothalamus to the nucleus ofthe solitary 
    tract in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">Neurol. 224: 1-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">Van Eden, C.G., and H.B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Uylings (1985) Cytoarchitectonic development of the 
    prefrontal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">Neurol. 241.253-267.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">Van Hoesen, G.W., E.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">Yeterian, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Lavizzo-Mourey (1981) Widespread corticostriate 
    projections from temporal cortex of the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">Neurol. 199:205-219.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Vargo, J.M., J.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Corwin, V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">King, and R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Reep (1988) Hemispheric asymmetry in neglect produced 
    by unilateral lesions of dorsomedial prefrontal cortex in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">I02:199-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">Veening, J.G., F.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Cornelissen, and P.A.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">Lieven (1980) The topical organization of the derents 
    to the caudatoputamen of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Neuroscience 5: 1253-1268.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">Verberne, A.J.M., S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Lewis, P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">Worland, P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Beart, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">Jarrott, M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">Christie, and W.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Louis (1987) Medial prefrontal cortical lesions 
    modulate baroreflex sensitivity in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Brain Res. 426.243-249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Voorn, P., C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">Gerfen, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Groenewegen (1989) The compartmental organization of 
    the ventral striatum of the rat: Immunohistochemical distribution 
    of enkephalin, substance P, dopamine and calcium-binding 
    protein.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">Neurol. 289:189-201.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">Voorn, P., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Jorritsma-Byham, C. van Dijk, and R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Buijs (1986) The dopaminergic innervation of the 
    ventral striatum in the rat: A lightand electron-microscopical 
    study with antibodies against dopamine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Neurol. 251:84-99.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Wehster, K.E. (1961) Cortico-striate interrelations 
    95t532-544.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Webster, K.E. (1965) The 99:329-337.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Wilson, C.J. (1986) Postsynaptic potentials evoked in 
    spiny neostriatal projection neurons by stimulation of ipsilateral 
    and contralateral neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Brain Res. 367:201-213.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">Wilson, C.J. (1987) Morphology and synaptic connections 
    of crossed corticostriatal neurons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">Neurol. 263r567-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Winocur, G. (1974) Functional dissociation within the 
    caudate nucleus rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">Psychol. 86r423-439.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">Wouterlood, F.G., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Groenewegen (1985) Neuroanatomical tracing by use of 
    Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L): Electron microscopy of 
    PHA-L filled neuronal somata, dendrites, s o n s and axon 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">Brain Res. 326r188-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">Wyss, J.M., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">Sripanidkulchai (1984) The topography of the 
    mesencephalic and pontine projections from the cingulate cortex of 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">Brain Res. 29311-15.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Yeterian, E.H., and G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Van Hoesen (1978) Cortico-striate projections in the 
    rhesus monkey: The organization of certain cortico-caudate 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">Brain Res. 139:43-63.</S>
  </References>

</File>

