<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>The Organization of the Efferent Projections From the Pontine 
  Parabrachial Area to the Amygdaloid Complex: A Phaseolus vulgaris 
  Leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) Study in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>JEAN-FRANCOIS BERNARD, MARIE ALDEN, AND JEAN-MARIE 
  BESSON</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The organization of the efferent projections from the 
    pontine parabrachial (pPB) area to the amygdala has been studied in 
    the rat by using microinjections of Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHA-L), a sensitive and selective anterograde 
    axonal marker, into restricted subregions of the pPB area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The results confirmed that the pPB area primarily 
    projected onto the ipsilateral nucleus centralis of the amygdala 
    (Ce), and to a lesser extent onto the ipsilateral posterior 
    basolateral (BLP), anterior basomedial (BMA), and amygdaloid 
    cortical (ACo) nuclei of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Substantial projections were also found in the substantia 
    innominata dorsaliventral portion of the globus pallidus (SIdlGPv), 
    substriatal (SStr), and fondus striatal (FStr) regions which 
    continue the amygdala rostrally.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The results demonstrated that the projections of the pPB 
    area onto the Ce were topically organized: 1) The region of the pPB 
    area mainly including the medial subnucleus (pPBm), the waist area 
    (pPBwa), and a thin rostral lamina of the ventral lateral 
    subnucleus (pPBvl) projects primarily to the medial portion of the 
    Ce (CeM).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Dense projections were also found in the BLP, BMA, and ACo 
    nuclei of the amygdala, and in the SIdlGPv, SStr, and FStr rostral 
    areas. 2) The region of the pPB mainly including the rostral 
    portion of the central lateral subnucleus (pPBcl) and the 
    outer-rostra1 portion of the external lateral subnucleus (pPBel) 
    projects primarily to the lateral portion of the Ce (CeL). 3) The 
    region of the pPB mainly including the dorsolateral subnucleus 
    (pPBdl), the remaining pPBel, and the external medial (pPBem) 
    suhnuclei projects primarily to the lateral capsular portion of the 
    Ce (CeLC) and bilaterally to its rostral portion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Dense projections were also found in the regions which 
    extend the CeLC rostrally and in the SIdlGPv, SStr, and FStr 
    rostral areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The possible role of each of the three 
    parabrachio-amygdaloid pathways described is discussed.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">It was suggested that the pPB-CeM pathway is mainly 
    implicated in gustatory processes; the pPB-CeL pathway is mainly 
    implicated in visceral and chemosensitive processes; and the 
    pPB-CeLC pathway is mainly implicated in respiratory, 
    cardiovascular, and nociceptive processes. c 1993 Wiley-Liss, 
    Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s9">The pontine parabrachial (pPB) 
  area is a group of cells that surrounds the brachium conjunctivum 
  (bc) in the dorsolateral pons up to the mesencephalon where it 
  continues into the mesencephalic parabrachial area (mPB).</S>
  <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s10">Thc pPB area was considered for a long time to be a 
  gustatory relay (Herrick, &apos;05; Barnard, &apos;36; Norgren and 
  Leonard, &apos;71, &apos;73; Norgren and Pfaffmann, &apos;75; 
  Norgren, &apos;78; Ogawa et al., &apos;87; see review in Travers et 
  al., &apos;87).</S><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s11">More recently it has also been 
  implicated in an increasing number of autonomic regulations (Bertrand 
  and Hugelin, &apos;71; Mraovitch et al., &apos;82; Cechetto and 
  Calaresu, &apos;83; Darlington and Ward, &apos;85a,h; Lumh and 
  Morrison, &apos;87; Ohman and Johnson, &apos;89; see also Herbert et 
  al., &apos;90).</S><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s12">Increasing evidence has shown 
  that this area is also implicated in nociceptive processes.</S>
  <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s13">Indeed, several authors (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Hylden 
  et al., &apos;85, &apos;86b; Panneton and Burton, &apos;85; Light et 
  al., &apos;87; Blomqvist et al., &apos;89; Hayashi and Tabata, 
  &apos;89) have found that a portion of this area receives a large 
  input from neurons located in lamina I of the spinal and medullary 
  dorsal horns, which are driven by noxious stimuli.</S><S avgH="21"
   class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s14">Bernard and Besson (&apos;88, &apos;90a) have recently 
  demonstrated that a high proportion of neurons located in the 
  external pPB (pPBe) area [i.e., external lateral (pPBel) and external 
  medial (pPBem) subnuclei], and antidromically driven from the nucleus 
  centralis of the amygdala (Ce), respond specifically to noxious 
  stimuli.</S><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s15">Further investigations at the Ce 
  level (Bernard et al., &apos;90, &apos;92) showed that numerous 
  neurons responded to noxious stimuli.</S><S avgH="21"
   class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s16">However, these nociceptive neurons were not homogeneously 
  distributed in and around the Ce.</S><S avgH="21"
   class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s17">We 
  hypothetized that such a distribution could be linked to the pattern 
  of projection from the pPB area to the Ce.</S><S avgH="21"
   class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s18">However, despite numerous anatomical studies demonstrating 
  the efferent projection from the pPB area to the Ce, in the rat 
  (Norgren, &apos;76; Ottersen and Ben-Ari, &apos;78; Saper and Loewy, 
  &apos;80; Ottersen, &apos;81; Voshart and van der Kooy, &apos;81; 
  Fulwiler and Saper, &apos;84; Bernard et al., &apos;89; Moga et al., 
  &apos;901, the cat (Nomura et al., &apos;79; Russchen, &apos;82; Ma 
  et al., &apos;89; Berkley and Scofield, &apos;901, the hamster 
  (Halsell, &apos;921, the rabbit (Kapp et al., &apos;891, the monkey 
  (Mehler, &apos;80), the detailed location of terminal fibres in the 
  Ce subdivisions from the pPB subnuclei is so far to a large extent 
  unknown.</S><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s19">In the present study, we 
  therefore used the very sensitive and selective anterograde axonal 
  marker, Phaseolus r?</S><S avgH="21" class="introduction.body"
   format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s20">ulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) 
  (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84), injected into very restricted 
  sites, in order to determine projections from subregions of the pPB 
  onto the amygdaloid subnuclei.</S><S avgH="21"
   class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
   id="s21">Preliminary reports of some of this work have been 
  published (Bernard and Besson, &apos;90b; Bernard et al., 
  &apos;91).</S></Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s22">METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Surgical procedures were performed on 68 male 
    SpragueDawley albino rats, weighing 275-300 g, under chloral 
    hydrate anaesthesia (400 mg/kg, i.p.1.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The animals were mounted in a stereotaxic frame.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The head was fixed in a dorsiflexed position (incisor bar 
    elevated 10 mm above the standard position) (Paxinos and Watson, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">A craniotomy was performed on the right side, at the 
    frontoparietalis suture level and the dura was opened.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Iontophoretic application of a 10% solution of PHA-L 
    (Vector Labs, Burlingame, CA) were made through glass micropipettes 
    (25-40 pm diameter tips) inserted in the brain on the right side 
    1.0-3.0 mm rostral to the Lambda, as defined in the stereotaxic 
    atlas of Paxinos and Watson (&apos;86), and 1.2-2.8 mm lateral to 
    the midline.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">The depth was between 6,500 and 8,000 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">A positive 15 seconds on-15 seconds off pulsed DC current 
    (3-6 FA) was used for a time period between 15 and 30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Following a postoperative survival time of 2-3 weeks, the 
    animals were re-anaesthetized and perfused with i) a warm (37°C) 
    heparinized phosphate-buffered saline solution (= 3 minutes 
    duration) followed by ii) a cold (3 10°C) phosphate buffer solution 
    (0.1 M; pH 7.4) containing 4% paraformaldehyde, 0.1% 
    glutaraldehyde, and 0.05% picric acid (0.8 liter; &apos;LO minutes 
    duration), followed by iii) a 20% sucrose, phosphate-buffered 
    solution ( 10 minutes duration).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The brain and the spinal cord were removed and soaked in 
    this last solution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">One day later, 50 pm thick coronal sections were cut on a 
    freezing microtome.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The sections were rinsed several times with a phosphate 
    buffer solution (PBS) (0.15 M; pH 7.4).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">These sections were divided into three groups and 
    processed for PHA-L immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">All of the groups of sections were incubated for 2-4 
    hours in PBS containing 0.4% Triton X-100 and 2% normal rabbit 
    serum (NRS).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">They were then incubated overnight in the primary anti 
    serum. i.e., l/l,OOO-l/2,000 goat anti PHA-L (Vector Labs, 
    Burlingame, CAI, in PBS containing 0.4% Triton X-100,2% NRS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">After rinsing for 20 minutes with PBS the sections were 
    incubated for 1 hour in the secondary anti serum, i.e., 11200 
    anti-goat-IgG (Vector Labs, Burlingame, CAI in PBS containing 0.4% 
    Triton X-100,2% NRS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">After rinsing again for 20 minutes with PBS, the sections 
    were placed in the avidin-biotin-HRP complex solution (kit vector, 
    recommended dilution x 1.5, in PBS) for 1 hour.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The sections were then once more rinsed for 10 minutes 
    with PBS, followed by two different types of peroxidase 
    histochemical revelations: 1) The sections processed only with 
    3,3&apos;-diaminobenzidine (DAB, Sigma Chemical Co., St.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Louis, MO) were once more rinsed for 10 minutes with PBS 
    and then they were incubated in PBS containing 0.05% DAB for 2 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Next, increasing doses of H202 were added every 5 minutes 
    to the latter DAB solution in order to obtain the following Hz02 
    concentrations (0.003%, 0.015%, 0.045%, 0.075%, and 0.225%).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">The reaction was stopped by a 10 minutes rinse in PBS.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">2) The two series of sections where the processes were 
    enhanced with nickel were now rinsed 10 minutes with Tris buffer 
    (0.15 M; pH 7.41, followed by an incubation in a Tris buffer 
    solution containing 0.05% DAB and 0.2% amonium nickel sulfate 
    (Sigma Chemical Co., St.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">Louis, MO) for 2 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Then, increasing doses of H20z were added every 5 minutes 
    to the latter DAB solution in order to obtain the following Ha02 
    concentrations (O.OOl%, 0.005%, 0.015%, 0.02596, and 0.075%).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The reaction was stopped by a 10 minutes rinse in Tris 
    buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Finally, one of these two series was counterstained with 
    neutral red.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The injection sites, labelled fibres, and terminals were 
    observed under brightand darkfield illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Delineation of the parabrachial area and the amygdala was 
    based upon observation of two Nissl-stained (one with cresylviolet 
    and the other with thionin) series (50 pm thick) not processed for 
    PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Two series of drawings (50 pm apart between adjacent 
    drawings) of the parabrachial area and the amygdala were made with 
    the camera lucida drawing tube.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">These drawings were used to make a standard drawing (150 
    pm apart) of both the parabrachial area and the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The delineation and nomenclature of this region was 
    adopted from relevant literature (McDonald, &apos;82; Fulwiler and 
    Saper, &apos;84; Cassel et al., &apos;86; Paxinos and Watson, 
    &apos;86) with some minor modifications (see, in Discussion, the 
    section devoted to the nomenclature).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Each injection site was analyzed from a series of camera 
    lucida drawings (150 pm apart) of the coronal section through the 
    site (processed only with DAB).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The coronal plane where the inferior colliculus merges 
    with the pons was used as reference plane (Pr) (this plane 
    corresponds to the interaural -0.30 mm plane in the atlas of 
    Paxinos and Watson &apos;86) and the distance was measured (50 pm 
    units) between each coronal plane drawing and the Pr (the distance 
    was negative or positive for drawings caudal or rostra1 to the Pr, 
    respectively); special attention was devoted, at the cutting stage, 
    to obtain a well-standardized coronal plane of section.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">For illustrative purposes the injection sites (delineated 
    from the labelled cells) were grouped on standard drawings of two 
    representative coronal sections (300 pm apart) of the parabrachial 
    area (see Fig. 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">In selected cases (see Figs. 5A, 7A, 9A-13A) camera 
    lucida drawings of one or two coronal sections (300 pm apart), 
    demonstrating the injection site, were presented according to the 
    size of the injection site.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Each amygdaloid area (with special attention to the Ce) 
    was analyzed from a series of camera lucida drawings (300 pm apart) 
    of the labelled area (revealed with the enhanced nickel 
    reaction).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">In current cases the delineation of the subnuclei of the 
    amygdala, the white matter fasciculi and the blood vessels were 
    precisely drawn (with the use of adjacent counterstained sections), 
    before the labelling was applied (with the camera lucida drawing 
    tube) by different intensities of grey according to the density of 
    labelled terminals in different areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">In more interesting cases individual fibres were drawn, 
    but even in those cases, taking into account the very high density 
    of very thin terminal fibres, we drew only a representative 
    subgroup of fibres in order to give a better representation of the 
    density of terminals in different areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Consequently, it must be emphasized that, despite the 
    undisputable labelling observed in direct microscopic observations, 
    a clear and reliable representation of the labelled area was 
    difficult to obtain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The photomicrographs (see Figs. 2, 3) illustrated this 
    well: the more densely labelled areas appeared as black areas, 
    whereas in the areas with a lower density of labelling the very 
    thin (diameter &amp;lt; 1 pmj black labelled terminals were weakly 
    visible.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">With a higher magnification it was possible to improve 
    the quality of fibre details but further information, especially on 
    the extent and the comparative density of labelled terminals, could 
    no longer be illustrated.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s63">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">The present results are based on 63 experiments in which 
    the <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injection sites were 
    located in (n = 43) or around (control experiments; n = 20) 
    <injectionLocation>the pontine parabrachial area 
    (pPB)</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">In each of the 63 selected experiments the injection 
    sites (size between 150 and 800 pm) contained densely labelled 
    cells around a dense stained core (Fig, 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Away from the injection site at least one cluster of 
    densely labelled terminals was observed (Figs. 2, 3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The injection sites presented here covered most, if not 
    all, of the subnuclei of the pPB area (Fig. 4) [the nomenclature 
    was for the main part adopted from Fulwiler and Saper (&apos;841, 
    see also Fig. 14Al.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s68">It was primarily observed that 1) most of the 
      injections of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> in the 
      <injectionLocation>pPB</injectionLocation> give rise to 
      <labelingDescription>a high or very high density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>subdivisions 
      of the ipsilateral nucleus centralis of the amygdala 
      (Ce)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s69">In these regions the labelling appeared as a dense 
      network of very thin, black stained fibres, with numerous 
      ramifications and varicosities.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s70">In the more dense areas the labelling appeared as a 
      cluster of entangled fibres in which it was difficult to identify 
      individual fibres (see Figs. 2, 3).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s71">A higher magnification photomicrograph of 
      <labelingLocation>a Ce region</labelingLocation> containing 
      <labelingDescription>a high density of labelled terminal 
      fibres</labelingDescription> is illustrated in Figure 3C3.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s72">Medium and low density were comparatively illustrated 
      in Figure 3C2 and C1, respectively.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s73">2) in the Ce, <labelingDescription>the dense network of 
      labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was often restricted to 
      one of its three subdivisions: <labelingLocation>the medial 
      portion (CeM)</labelingLocation> (Figs. 2A, 3A), <labelingLocation
      >the lateral portion (CeL)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 2B), and 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral capsular portion 
      (CeLC)</labelingLocation> (Figs. 2C, 3B) [the nomenclature was 
      for the main part adopted from McDonald (&apos;82) and Cassel et 
      al. (&apos;861, see also Fig. 14BI.</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The location of the labelled area in one of these 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>Ce subdivisions</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    was closely linked to the location of the injection site in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the pPB</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">In Figure 4 the more representative injection sites (27 
    among the 43 located into <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    pPB</neuroanatomicalLocation>) were grouped according to the 
    subdivision of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    Ce</neuroanatomicalLocation> in which the dense network of labelled 
    terminals was observed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Thus, the injection sites shown in Figure 4A projected 
    mainly or exclusively to <connxTermination>the 
    CeM</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">Figure 4B shows the injection sites which projected both 
    to <connxTermination>the CeM and the CeL</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">The groups in Figure 4C,D illustrate the sites projecting 
    to <connxTermination>the CeL and the CeLC</connxTermination>, 
    respectively.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The results were presented according to the grouping of 
    sites made in Figure 4.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s80">Experiments exhibiting a 
    high density of labelling mainly in the CeM</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">These experiments exhibited a quite similar pattern of 
    labelling in <labelingLocation>the Ce</labelingLocation>: the 
    labelled terminals were located mainly or exclusively in 
    <labelingLocation>the CeM subdivision</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">The injection sites of ten representative experiments are 
    shown in Figure 4A.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">These injections covered <injectionLocation>the whole 
    medial subnucleus of the pPB area (pPBm), the waist area (pPBwa), 
    and the more medial portion of the pPBem</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Among these injection sites, three subgroups could be 
    distinguished according to the location of the area with the 
    densest labelling in <labelingLocation>the CeM</labelingLocation>: 
    the central subgroup included sites No. 13 and 37, which primarily 
    projected to <connxTermination>the centre of the 
    CeM</connxTermination>; the ventral peripheral subgroup included 
    sites No. 11, 21, and 23, which primarily projected to 
    <connxTermination>the medial periphery of the 
    CeM</connxTermination>; and the dorsal peripheral subgroup included 
    sites No. 16,32,36, and 40, which primarily projected to 
    <connxTermination>the lateral periphery of the 
    CeM</connxTermination>, near <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    CeL</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">The central subgroup.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The corresponding injection sites (<exptLabel>No. 13 and 
    37</exptLabel>) were located in <injectionLocation>the central 
    portion of the pPBm</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">The main common feature of this group was the location of 
    <labelingDescription>densest labelling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the centre of the CeM</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">The <exptLabel>experiment No. 13</exptLabel> in which the 
    site was exclusively located inside <injectionLocation>the 
    pPBm</injectionLocation> was chosen as the representative case and 
    described in detail.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 37</exptLabel> was briefly 
    described in comparison to <exptLabel>case No. 13</exptLabel>.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 13</exptLabel> is illustrated 
      in Figures 5 and 6.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">The injection site had a small dense core in 
      <injectionLocation>the caudal portion of the 
      pPBm</injectionLocation> (Figs. lA, 5Al).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92"><labelingDescription>The numerous and densely labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were almost exclusively located in 
      <labelingLocation>the pPBm</labelingLocation> where they covered 
      a large portion [Fig. 5A1,2; 200-900 km caudal to the coronal 
      plane of reference (Prj where the inferior colliculus merges with 
      the pons].</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">Only <labelingLocation>the more medial and the more 
      rostral portion of the pPBm</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>did not contain labelled 
      cells</labelingModifier>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">The area of 
      <labelingDescription>termination</labelingDescription>, in 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdaloid complex</labelingLocation>, was 
      primarily located in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
      CeM</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5B, 6).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95"><labelingDescription>The anterograde 
      labelling</labelingDescription> occupied almost exactly the whole 
      of <labelingLocation>the CeM</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5Bl-B2, 
      6B3-B5) with <labelingDescription>a very high density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in its centre (Figs. 5B2, 
      6B3-B4).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">A thin lamina with <labelingDescription>a high density 
      of fibre labelling</labelingDescription> surrounds 
      <labelingLocation>the CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">This region which does not correspond neither to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the CeL</neuroanatomicalLandmark> nor to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the CeLC</neuroanatomicalLandmark> was 
      here considered as an extension of the CeM.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>This intense 
      labelling</labelingDescription> contrasted strongly to 
      <labelingDescription>the almost complete absence of 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the other 
      subregions of the Ce: the CeL and the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99"><labelingDescription>The few labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> encountered in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B1,BZ) and in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6B3-B5) looked like 
      <labelingDescription>fibres of passage</labelingDescription> (few 
      ramifications, absence of varicosities, thicker than the other 
      terminals, and all extended in the same direction).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">The labelling in <labelingLocation>the 
      Ce</labelingLocation> was continuous (Fig. 6B5,B6) with labelling 
      i) in <labelingLocation>the transition area between the dorsal 
      portion of the substantia innominata and the ventral portion of 
      the globus pallidus</labelingLocation> (SId/GPv), and ii) in 
      <labelingLocation>the substriatal area 
      (SStr)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">At this level, <labelingDescription>a lower density of 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was also found i) in 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior amygdaloid 
      area</labelingLocation>, ii) in <labelingLocation>the fondus 
      striatum (FStr)</labelingLocation>, and iii) in <labelingLocation>
      the transition area between the globus pallidus and the caudate 
      putamen (GPICPu)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation>, 
      outside <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      Ce</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>a medium 
      density of labelling</labelingDescription> was found mainly in 
      <labelingLocation>the basomedial anterior nucleus 
      (BMA)</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the adjacent portion 
      of the anterior cortical amygdaloid nucleus 
      (ACo)</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5B2, 6B3-B4) and <labelingLocation
      >the basolateral posterior nucleus (BLP)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> the location of 
      <labelingDescription>the labelled terminals</labelingDescription> 
      was symmetrical to that on the ipsilateral side, but the density 
      of labelling was considerably lower.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">The labelling was observed in <labelingLocation>the 
      SidiGPv and the SStr</labelingLocation> with 
      <labelingDescription>a mehum to low density</labelingDescription> 
      and in <labelingLocation>the CeM</labelingLocation> with only 
      <labelingDescription>a low density</labelingDescription>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 37</exptLabel>, which had an 
    injection site located in <injectionLocation>the medial portion of 
    the pPBm</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4421, had 
    <labelingDescription>an area of termination</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the amygdaloid complex</labelingLocation> 
    quite similar to that in <exptLabel>case No. 13</exptLabel> but 
    with an even greater density of labelling.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">Specifically, as in <exptLabel>case No. 13</exptLabel>, 
    <labelingDescription>the fibre labelling</labelingDescription> 
    occupied <labelingLocation>the whole CeM</labelingLocation>, with 
    <labelingDescription>the highest density of labelled 
    terminal</labelingDescription> being in <labelingLocation>the 
    centre of this area</labelingLocation> (Figs. 2A, 3A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107"><labelingDescription>Labelled terminals were completely 
    absent</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeLC</labelingLocation> but, in slight contrast to <exptLabel>case 
    No. 13</exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>a few fibres were 
    labelled</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 2A).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s108">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>The ventral periphera1 
      subgroup</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s109">The 
      corresponding injection sites (<exptLabel>No. 11, 21, and 
      23</exptLabel>) were located in <injectionLocation>the lateral 
      and ventral portion of the pPBm</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111"><labelingDescription>The terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription>was found, as in case No. 13, 
      primarily in <labelingLocation>the CeM</labelingLocation>, but 
      <labelingDescription>the most densely labelled 
      area</labelingDescription> was located in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial portion of the CeM</labelingLocation>: it surrounded the 
      commissural stria terminalis (cst) in the caudal portion of the 
      CeM and was located over the cst in the rostral CeM.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">In the other regions of the amygdala the distribution 
      of labelling was basically the same as that in the central 
      subgroup.</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT"
     id="s113"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The dorsal peripheral 
    subgroup</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT"
     id="s114">The corresponding injection sites were located in 
    <injectionLocation>the more medial portions of the 
    pPBm</injectionLocation> (site No. 40) and in <injectionLocation>
    the pPBwa</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>site No. 16, 32, and 
    36</exptLabel>) (Fig. 4A).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s116">The main area of 
    <labelingDescription>termination</labelingDescription> was, as in 
    experiment No. 13, primarily located in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeM</labelingLocation> but, in all experiments in this group, 
    <labelingDescription>the most densely labelled 
    area</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral portion of the CeM on the border of the 
    CeL</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s117">In <labelingLocation>the 
    other regions of the amygdala</labelingLocation> the distribution 
    of labelling was also basically the same that in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the central 
    subgroup</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">Thus, when considering the sites from 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventrolateral 
    pPBm</neuroanatomicalLocation> towards <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    dorsomedial pPBm</neuroanatomicalLocation> and 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the pPBwa</neuroanatomicalLocation>, the 
    location of the densest projection area changed from the more 
    medial to the more lateral portion of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    CeM</neuroanatomicalLocation> adjacent to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the CeL</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s119">Experiments exhibiting 
    <labelingDescription>a high density of 
    labelling</labelingDescription> both in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeM</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">In these cases, the area containing a high density of 
    labelled terminals included not only <labelingLocation>the 
    CeM</labelingLocation> but also a portion of <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">The injection sites of five representative experiments 
    were presented in Figure 4B.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">All these large injection sites overlapped 
    <injectionLocation>the brachium conjunctivum</injectionLocation> 
    and covered a portion of <injectionLocation>the lateral pPB area 
    (pPB1)</injectionLocation>; some of them also covered 
    <injectionLocation>a large portion of the pPBm 
    area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">These experiments made it possible to observe the 
    transition area or the boundary between the region of pPB which 
    projected primarily to the CeM (see section 1) and the region of 
    pPB which primarily projected to the CeL (see section 3).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">Chosen among these experiments, the case No. 34 (Fig. 
    4B) has been described in detail.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">The other cases (No. 39,56,2, and 64) are described in 
    comparison to the former.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 34</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figures 7 and 8.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">The injection site had a dense core in 
      <injectionLocation>the pPBwa</injectionLocation> surrounded by 
      numerous and densely labelled cells over a relatively large area 
      (Fig. 7A1,A2; 700-100 pm caudal to the Pr).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128">This injection covered a large portion of 
      <injectionLocation>the pPBwa</injectionLocation>, the portion 
      adjacent to <injectionLocation>the pPBm</injectionLocation> and 
      in addition to the injections of section 1 (Fig. 4A1, 
      <injectionLocation>a relatively large and rostral portion of the 
      ventral lateral pPB subnucleus (pPBvl)</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129">The area of 
      <labelingDescription>termination</labelingDescription>, in 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdaloid complex</labelingLocation>, was 
      primarily located in <labelingLocation>an ipsilateral area 
      overlapping both the CeM and the CeL</labelingLocation> (Figs. 
      7B, 8).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130">The density of <labelingDescription>terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was <labelingDescription>very 
      high</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>this area, 
      especially at the junction between the CeM and the 
      CeL</labelingLocation> (Figs. 7BI-B2, 8B3).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131"><labelingDescription>The labelled 
      area</labelingDescription> occupied only <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral half of the CeM and a small adjacent portion of the 
      CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">A thin lamina with <labelingDescription>a high density 
      of fibre labelling</labelingDescription> surrounded 
      <labelingLocation>the laterocaudal portion of the 
      CeL</labelingLocation>, but the contrast to the centre of CeL was 
      not as marked as in case No. 13 since <labelingLocation>the 
      adjacent lateral portion of CeL</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>a medium density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133"><labelingDescription>The intense 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the CeM and 
      the CeL</labelingLocation> contrasted with 
      <labelingDescription>the complete absence of 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134"><labelingDescription>The labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> encountered in <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral portion of the CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7Bl,B2) 
      appeared clearly as <labelingDescription>fibres of 
      passage</labelingDescription> (probably from the Ce towards the 
      BMA).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">The labelling in <labelingLocation>the 
      Ce</labelingLocation> was continued rostrally (Fig. 8B5,B6) with 
      a distribution similar to that observed in case No. 13.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136">In the amygdala, outside the Ce, 
      <labelingDescription>a high to medium density of 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was found mainly in 
      <labelingLocation>the BMA, the ACo (Figs. 7B2, 8B3,B4) and the 
      basolateral posterior nucleus (BLP; Fig. 
      7BO)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137"><labelingDescription>A low density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> was also observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial anterior amygdaloid nucleus (MeA) 
      and the piriform cortex (Pir)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> the location of 
      <labelingDescription>the labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription>, as in case No. 13, was 
      symmetrical to that on the ipsilateral side, but the density of 
      labelling was <labelingDescription>considerably 
      lower</labelingDescription>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 39</exptLabel> had a large 
    injection site with an extent basically similar to the 
    <exptLabel>injection No. 34</exptLabel> but in a more lateral 
    location (Fig. 4B).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">The projection to 
    <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> was similar to 
    that in <exptLabel>case No. 34</exptLabel>, although 
    <labelingDescription>even more 
    dense</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Thus, most of the areas of termination (primarily 
    <connxTermination>the CeM</connxTermination>, and 
    <connxTermination>the BMA, ACo, and BLP</connxTermination>) 
    observed in <exptLabel>experiments No. 34 and 39</exptLabel> were 
    similar to those described in the previous section.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">The only striking difference from experiments in that 
    section was <labelingDescription>the intense 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation> on the border of 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the CeM</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">A comparison of injection sites No. 34 and 39 (Fig. 4B) 
    to the injections in the previous section (Fig. 4A) suggested that 
    the more dorsal extension of the injections No. 34 and 39 in 
    <injectionSpread>the pPBvl</injectionSpread> could be responsible 
    for the labelling observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 56</exptLabel> was for the 
    most part similar to case No. 39.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s145">The only 
    noticeable difference was a larger extent of the injection site 
    into <injectionSpread>the dorsal lateral pPR 
    subnucleus</injectionSpread> (pPBdl) (Fig. 4B) which appeared to be 
    associated to an additional labelling in a small portion of 
    <labelingLocation>the rostral CeLC, adjacent to the 
    CeL</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146"><exptLabel>Experiments No. 2 and 64</exptLabel> included 
    the most lateral injection sites of this serie (Fig. 4B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">The main labelling in <labelingLocation>the 
    Ce</labelingLocation> had a distribution similar to those of 
    previous cases of this serie at <labelingLocation>the junction 
    between the CeM and the CeL</labelingLocation>, but with a 
    predominance in this latter subdivision.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s148">In 
    addition in case No. 2 <labelingDescription>a small but significant 
    labelling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
    the caudal portion of the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">Thus, experiments in this series, as compared to the 
    previous one, primarily suggested that <connxOrigin>the 
    pPRvl</connxOrigin> contained neurons which send axonal projections 
    to <connxTermination>the CeL</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">To a lesser extent it also suggests (<exptLabel>cases 
    No. 2 and 56</exptLabel>) that caudally,<connxOrigin> the pPBvl and 
    the pPBe</connxOrigin>l contain neurons projecting to 
    <connxTermination>the CeLC</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">These suggestions are sustained and completed by 
    experiments in the following section (sites projecting to 
    <connxTermination>the CeL</connxTermination>) and subsequent 
    section (sites projecting to <connxTermination>the 
    CeLC</connxTermination>).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s152">Experiments exhibiting 
    <labelingDescription>a high density of 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    CeL</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Among experiments with injection sites located in 
    <injectionLocation>the pPB</injectionLocation>, three of them 
    exhibited, in <labelingLocation>the Ce</labelingLocation>, an area 
    of <labelingDescription>intensely labelled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> located mainly in 
    <labelingLocation>the CeL subdivision</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">These injection sites (Fig. 4C) mainly covered 
    <injectionLocation>the central lateral subnucleus of the pPB 
    area</injectionLocation> (pPBcl; experiments No. 27 and 65) and 
    <injectionLocation>the outer portion of the 
    pPBel</injectionLocation> (experiment No. 60).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 27</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figure 9.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156">The injection site had a small dense core in 
      <injectionLocation>the rostral portion of the pPBcl surrounded by 
      numerous densely labelled cells which covered almost all the 
      pPBcl and an adjacent portion of the pPBvl</injectionLocation> 
      (Fig. 9A; 0-400 p,m caudal to the Pr).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157"><labelingDescription>The area of 
      termination</labelingDescription>, in <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdaloid complex</labelingLocation>, was primarily located in 
      <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral CeL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      9B).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">As shown in Figure 9Bl-B5 <labelingDescription>a high 
      density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> occupied 
      almost <labelingLocation>the whole CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159">This intense labelling strongly contrasted with 
      <labelingDescription>the weak labelling</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the other subregions of the Ce: the CeM and the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">Only <labelingDescription>a small cluster of labelled 
      terminal fibres</labelingDescription> was observed 
      <labelingLocation>below the CeL, on the border between the CeM 
      and the CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9Bl-B3).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161"><labelingDescription>The few other labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> encountered in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeM and the CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9Bl-B5) looked like 
      <labelingDescription>fibres of passage</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">Only <labelingDescription>a few labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the SIdiGYv 
      and the SStr</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9B6) were labelled rostral 
      to the Ce.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation>, 
      outside the Ce, <labelingDescription>a few labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation
      >the medial nucleus of the arnygdala (Me)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s164">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> only <labelingDescription>a few 
      labelled terminals</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the CeL</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 65</exptLabel> had an 
    injection site centred in <injectionLocation>the 
    pPBcl</injectionLocation> as did the <exptLabel>injection No. 
    27</exptLabel> (Fig. 4C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">The rostrocaudal extent of this injection site was 
    larger and slightly more caudal (100-600 km caudal to the Pr) than 
    that of the injection No. 27.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">The area of termination (Fig. 2B) was quite similar to 
    that in case No. 27.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s168"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 60</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figure 10.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s169">The small injection site had a dense core surrounded 
      by several densely labelled cells which covered <injectionLocation
      >the outer-rostral restricted portion of the 
      pPBel</injectionLocation> (Figs. lB, 10A; extent: 250600 pm 
      caudal to the Pr).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170">The area of termination, in the amygdaloid complex, 
      primarily occupied <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
      CeL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 10B).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s171">In this area we found <labelingDescription>a very high 
      density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> restricted to 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral half of the CeL</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 10Bl-B4).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s172">This dense projection extended ventrally into 
      <labelingLocation>a small adjacent portion of the caudal 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 10Bl-B4).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">Rostrally this labelling had a lower density (Fig. 
      10B5).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174"><labelingDescription>This intense 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeL</labelingLocation> strongly contrasted with 
      <labelingDescription>the almost complete absence of 
      labelling</labelingDescription>in <labelingLocation>the other 
      subregions of the Ce and the other amygdaloid 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> only <labelingDescription>a few 
      labelled terminals</labelingDescription> were observed, 
      symmetrically to the ipsilateral side, in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeL and CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Thus, these experiments showed that <connxOrigin>the 
    rostral pPBcl and the outer portion of the pPBel</connxOrigin> 
    projected, in <connxTermination>the amygdala</connxTermination>, 
    primarily onto <connxTermination>the CeL 
    subregion</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">In addition, experiment No. 60 showed that 
    <connxOrigin>the pPBel</connxOrigin> contained neurons which 
    projected to <connxTermination>the CeLC</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">It must be noticed that the injection site No. 60 was 
    very close to the site No. 31 (see next section) which projected 
    almost exclusively to <connxTermination>the 
    CeLC</connxTermination>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s179">Experiments exhibiting a 
    high density of labelling in the CeLC</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">In Figure 4D, <exptLabel>ten experiments with injection 
    sites located in <injectionLocation>the 
    pPB</injectionLocation></exptLabel> exhibited, in <labelingLocation>
    the Ce</labelingLocation>, an area of <labelingDescription>intense 
    labelling of terminals</labelingDescription>, located mainly or 
    only in <labelingLocation>the CeLC 
    subdivision</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The injection sites (Fig. 4D) covered all of 
    <injectionLocation>the pPBd1, the inner-rostral, and the caudal 
    portion of the pPBel and the pPBem</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Among these injection sites, two subgroups could be 
    distinguished according to their location in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the pPB area</neuroanatomicalLocation>: 
    The external subgroup (Fig. 4D) included experiments <exptLabel>No. 
    31,3, 1,24,54, and 26</exptLabel> which contained injection sites 
    located in <injectionLocation>the pPBel and the 
    pPBem</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The dorsal superficial subgroup (Fig. 4D) included 
    experiments <exptLabel>No. 66,45,55, and 50</exptLabel> which had 
    their injection sites located in <injectionLocation>the dorsal 
    superficial portion of the pPB1: the pPBdl and the dorsal-caudal 
    portion of the pPBel</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">It must be noticed that the external subgroup and the 
    superficial subgroups corresponded to two separate areas of 
    <connxOrigin>the pPB</connxOrigin>, each of them projecting onto 
    <connxTermination>the whole CeLC</connxTermination>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The external subgroup.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">The corresponding injection sites (<exptLabel>No. 31, 3, 
    1,24, 54, and 26</exptLabel>) were located in <injectionLocation>
    the pPBel and the pPBem</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4D).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">The common feature of all these experiments was 
    <labelingDescription>the dense or extremely dense 
    labelling</labelingDescription> observed primarily and often 
    exclusively into <labelingLocation>the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">These experiments were described from cmes No. 31 
    (described in detail) and 3, in which 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde labelling</labelingDescription> 
    primarily occupied <labelingLocation>the caudal 
    CeLC</labelingLocation>, via the transitional cases No. 1 and 24, 
    to the cases No. 54 (described in detail) and 26, in which 
    labelling occupied <labelingLocation>the rostral 
    CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s190"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 31</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figure 11.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s191">The small injection site had a very small dense core 
      surrounded by several densely labelled cells, in 
      <injectionLocation>the inner portion of the 
      pPBel</injectionLocation> (Fig. 11A; extent 200-400 pm caudal to 
      the Pr).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s192">The area of termination, in the amygdaloid complex, 
      was primarily located in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> (Figs.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s193">ZC, 11B).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s194">As shown in Figure llBl-B4 <labelingDescription>a very 
      high density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> occupied 
      <labelingLocation>a large caudal portion of the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation>, up to <labelingLocation>the more rostral 
      portion</labelingLocation> where <labelingDescription>the density 
      of labelled terminals was lower</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
      llB5).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s195"><labelingDescription>The intense 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> strongly contrasted with 
      <labelingDescription>the few labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> found in <labelingLocation>the 
      other subregions of the Ce: the CeL and the 
      CeM</labelingLocation> (Fig. 11Bl-B5).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s196">Only <labelingLocation>the portion of CeL and CeM 
      adjacent to the rostral CeLC</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>some densely labelled 
      clusters</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s197">Continuing with the labelling of <labelingLocation>the 
      ce</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a low density of 
      labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was found in 
      <labelingLocation>an indefinite area which ran from the CeLC 
      rostrally</labelingLocation> (Fig. llB6).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s198"><labelingDescription>Only sparse labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation
      >the SStr and the SIdiGPv</labelingLocation> (Fig. llB5,B6).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s199">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala, outside the 
      Ce</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a small but dense 
      cluster of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was found in
      <labelingLocation>the rostral portion of the dorsolateral 
      subdivision of the lateral amygdaloid 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s200">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>a medium to high 
      density of labelling</labelingDescription> was found in 
      <labelingLocation>the rostral CeLC</labelingLocation> 
      (corresponding to the levels 4 and 5 in Fig. 11B), whereas 
      <labelingDescription>a low density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>
      the caudal CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Thus in this case, although the labelling was less dense 
    than on the ipsilateral side, there were fewer differences between 
    the two sides than in all the previously described experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 3</exptLabel> had a very small 
    injection site located in <injectionLocation>the medial-inner 
    portion of the pPBel</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4D), which 
    projected, as did the site No. 31, to <labelingDescription>the 
    caudal portion of the ipsilateral 
    CeLC</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203"><exptLabel>Experiments No. 1 and 24</exptLabel> had 
    injection sites which overlapped <injectionLocation>the pPBel and 
    pPBem</injectionLocation>, the former with a relatively large 
    caudal extent and the latter with a rather rostral position (Fig. 
    4D).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">The labelling primarily covered <labelingLocation>the 
    whole ipsilateral CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s205">In 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral amygdala</labelingLocation>, 
    <labelingDescription>a labelling almost as dense as the one on the 
    ipsilateral side</labelingDescription> occupied <labelingLocation>
    the rostral portion of the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s206"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 54</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figure 12.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s207">The injection site had a dense core surrounded by 
      numerous and densely labelled cells, in <injectionLocation>the 
      rostral portion of the pPBem</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s208">This injection site was restricted in the coronal 
      plane (Fig. 12A; diameter &amp;lt;300 pm), but its rostrocaudal 
      extent was larger: 50 pm rostral to 400 pm caudal to the Pr.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s209">As in previous cases of this section 
      <labelingDescription>the area of 
      termination</labelingDescription>, on the ipsilateral side, was 
      primarily located in <labelingLocation>the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12B).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s210">But differing from case No. 31 (see Fig.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s211">ZC), <labelingDescription>the most densely labelled 
      area</labelingDescription> was almost exclusively located in 
      <labelingLocation>the rostral half of the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation>, as demonstrated by the photomicrograph 
      in Figure 3B and the Figure 12B4,B5.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s212">This labelling of <labelingDescription>very high 
      density</labelingDescription> was rostrally continued by two 
      clusters of dense labelling (Fig. 12B6).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s213">Differing also from the previous cases the labelling 
      was bilateral without an ipsilateral predominance.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s214">Thus the most rostral portions of <labelingLocation>
      the contralateral CeLC</labelingLocation> (corresponding to 
      levels 5 and 6 in Fig. 12) also contained <labelingDescription>a 
      very high density of labelling</labelingDescription>, whereas in 
      <labelingLocation>its other portions</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingDescription>the labelling had a low 
      density</labelingDescription> (level 4) or was completely absent 
      (caudal levels 1-3).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s215">On both side <labelingDescription>a medium to low 
      density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was also 
      observed in <labelingLocation>the SIdiGPv, the SStr (Fig. 12B6), 
      the rostral portion of the ACo, and the cortex-amygdala 
      transition zone ( C d )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 26</exptLabel> had a small 
    injection site located in <injectionLocation>the most caudal 
    portion of the pPBel and pPBem</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4D) which 
    primarily and bilaterally projected, as did site No. 54, to 
    <labelingLocation>the more rostral portion of the 
    CeLC</labelingLocation> (levels 4-6).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s217">The dorsal 
    superficial subgroup.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s218">The corresponding 
    injection sites (Fig. 4D) were located in <injectionLocation>the 
    main pPBd</injectionLocation>l (<exptLabel>NO. 66 and 
    45</exptLabel>) and <injectionLocation>the external 
    pPBdl</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>No. 55 and 
    50</exptLabel>).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s220">As in the external subgroup, 
    the common feature of these experiments was 
    <labelingDescription>the dense labelling</labelingDescription> 
    primarily and often quite exclusively observed in <labelingLocation>
    the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">These experiments were described from cases 
    <exptLabel>No. 66</exptLabel> (described in detail) and 
    <exptLabel>45</exptLabel> which primarily projected to 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal CeLC</labelingLocation>, via the 
    transitional cases No. 55, to the case No. 50 which primarily 
    projected to the rostral CeLC.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s222"><exptLabel>Experiment No. 66</exptLabel> is 
      illustrated in Figure 13.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s223">The injection site had a small dense core in 
      <injectionLocation>the dorsal and caudal portion of the main 
      pPBdl</injectionLocation> (Fig. 13A1) and the labelled cells 
      extended ventrally to the dense core in the pPBdl.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s224">The labelled cells were mostly restricted to this thin 
      lamina (about 100 wn thickness) but had a relatively l a w extent 
      direction (Fig. 13A; extent: 0-700 pm in the rostrocaudal caudal 
      to the Pr).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s225"><labelingDescription>The area of 
      termination</labelingDescription>, primarily in <labelingLocation>
      the ipsilateral CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 13B) was almost 
      similar to that in case No. 31 (external subgroup).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s226"><labelingDescription>The high density of 
      labelling</labelingDescription> mainly occupied <labelingLocation>
      the caudal portion of the CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      13Bl-B3).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s227"><labelingDescription>Some clusters of lower density in 
      labelling</labelingDescription> were also found in 
      <labelingLocation>the other portions of the 
      CeLC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 13B4,B5).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s228">Continuous with the labelling of the Ce, 
      <labelingDescription>a low to medium density of labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>an 
      indefinite area (see Discussion) which prolonged the CeLC 
      rostrally (Fig. 13B61, into the SStr and the SId/GPv (Fig. 
      13B5,B6)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s229"><labelingDescription>Some labelled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> were also observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the Me and the ACo</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">In <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>the labelled 
    terminals were almost absent</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The site <exptLabel>No. 45</exptLabel> located in 
    <injectionLocation>the main pPBdl</injectionLocation>(Fig. 4D) 
    projected primarily as did the sites No. 66, to <labelingLocation>
    the caudal portion of the ipsilateral 
    CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232"><exptLabel>Experiments No. 55 and 50</exptLabel> had 
    very superficial injection sites located lateral and very lateral, 
    respectively, to both the injections No. 45 and 66 (Fig. 4D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The site No. 55 primarily projected to 
    <connxTermination>the intermediate portion of the 
    CeLC</connxTermination> (levels 3 and 4), whereas the site No. 50 
    exclusively projected to <connxTermination>the more rostral portion 
    of the CeLC</connxTermination> (levels 4-6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">In <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the contralateral 
    amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>low and 
    medium density of labelling</labelingDescription> was observed 
    rostrally in <labelingLocation>the CeLC</labelingLocation>, in 
    cases No. 55 and 50, respectively.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Thus, these experiments showed that <connxOrigin>the 
    pPBdl, the caudal and the rostral-inner portion of the pPBel and 
    the PBem</connxOrigin> projected, in <connxTermination>the 
    Ce</connxTermination>, primarily if not exclusively, to 
    <connxTermination>the CeLC subregion</connxTermination>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">The anterograde labelling observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the Cewas</labelingLocation> always more dense 
    than that observed, in the same animal, in other regions also 
    receiving a strong projection from <connxOrigin>the 
    pPB</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Such a conclusion was drawn by analyzing each of the 43 
    experiments where the injection was located in 
    <injectionLocation>the pPB area</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">In these latter experiments, the density of labelled 
    terminals was always higher in one subdivision of the Ce than in 
    other regions, outside the amygdala of the same animal, but also 
    exhibiting a high density of labelling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Of course, in a few cases where the injection site was 
    very small (less than 200 Kmj, the density of labelled terminals in 
    the Ce was low but in these cases the labelling in the other 
    regions was absent or lower than in the Ce.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Likewise, in some other cases where the density of 
    labelling in other regions of the brain was very high, the density 
    of labelling in the Ce was still higher.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Although the aim of the study was not to describe the 
    extraamygdaloid sites of projection of the pPB area, it is 
    interesting to briefly present them in order to permit a better 
    understanding of this complex region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">These main projections, as numerous other, will be 
    described in detail in following papers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">These main sites of projection were the substantia 
    innominata, the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, the thalamus, 
    the hypothalamus, and the region of the ambiguous nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">The main labelling in <labelingLocation>the substantia 
    innominata</labelingLocation> was ipsilateral in its dorsal 
    portion, arising, in <injectionLocation>the 
    pPB</injectionLocation>, mainly from the sites displayed in Figure 
    4A,B,D.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">The main labelling in <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus 
    of the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> was ipsilateral, in its 
    most lateral portion, arising, in <injectionLocation>the 
    pPB</injectionLocation>, mainly from sites presented in Figure 4A, 
    B, C.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The main labelling in the thalamus was bilateral and 
    median, and included <labelingLocation>the gustatory thalamus, the 
    rhomboid, the reuniens, and a portion of the submedius 
    nuclei</labelingLocation>, arising, in <injectionLocation>the 
    pPB</injectionLocation>, mainly from the sites shown in Figure 
    4A,B, D.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">The main labelling in <labelingLocation>the 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> was ipsilateral in the lateral 
    caudal hypothalmus and median or bilateral <labelingLocation>in the 
    median and medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation>, arising, in 
    <injectionLocation>the pPB</injectionLocation>, mainly from the 
    sites displayed in Figure 4C.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">The main labelling in <labelingLocation>the region of 
    ambigous nucleus</labelingLocation> was ipsilateral, originating 
    mainly in site No. 54.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">The control experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">The twenty control experiments can be divided into three 
    groups: The first group included <exptLabel>11 experiments with 
    injection sites caudal to the PPB (in or near <injectionLocation>
    the superior vestibular nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel>) 
    with (n = 6) or without (n = 5) spread into <injectionSpread>the 
    most caudal portion of the pPB</injectionSpread>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s251">The main 
    labelling was found in <labelingLocation>the cerebellum, 
    vestibullar nuclei, and related regions (oculomotor nuclei, red 
    nucleus, and thalamus)</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Experiments with injection sites that did not spread 
    into the pPB <labelingDescription>did not exhibit any 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s253">Experiments with spread into 
    <injectionSpread>the pPB</injectionSpread> caudal portion (a few 
    hundred km) exhibited only <labelingDescription>a few labelled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    Ce.</labelingLocation></S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s254">In two cases, where the 
    spread of the injection site clearly extended 200-300 pm in 
    <injectionSpread>the dorsal and external portion of the more caudal 
    portion of the pPBI</injectionSpread>, <labelingDescription>a few 
    clusters of fibre labelling</labelingDescription> were observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">The second group included <exptLabel>two experiments 
    with injection sites ventral to <injectionLocation>the pPBm and the 
    pPBem</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s256">In one 
    case no labelling was observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s257">In the other case where the 
    injection site was below the caudal portion of the pPBem with a 
    small spread into <injectionSpread>this latter 
    area</injectionSpread>, <labelingDescription>a few clusters of 
    fibre labelling</labelingDescription> were observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral CeLC</labelingLocation> and 
    only <labelingDescription>a few labelled 
    fibres</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilateral CeLC</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">The third group included <exptLabel>seven experiments 
    with an injection site rostral to the pPB</exptLabel>, in 
    <injectionLocation>the mesencephalic PB area 
    (mPB)</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s259">In four cases where the 
    injection site was weakly spread into <injectionSpread>the pPB 
    area</injectionSpread> (200-300 km), <labelingDescription>a low to 
    medium density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was 
    observed in <labelingLocation>one subregion of the 
    Ce</labelingLocation> according to the description of the 
    projection of the pPB area onto the Ce made in the previous 
    sections.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">In the <exptLabel>three other experiments</exptLabel> 
    without spread into <injectionSpread>the pPB area</injectionSpread> 
    no projection was observed to <labelingLocation>the 
    Ce</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s261">It must be pointed out that 
    in most of these seven experiments <labelingDescription>a high to 
    very high density of labelled terminals</labelingDescription> was 
    found in <labelingLocation>the medial nucleus of the amygdala and 
    in the hypothalamus (primarily in the ventromedial and 
    retochiasmatic nuclei)</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s262">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">The present results showed that in the amygdaloid 
    complex: i) the pPB area projected primarily onto the ipsilateral 
    side in the Ce nucleus, and to a lesser extent onto the BMA, BLP, 
    and ACo nuclei of the amygdala and to the SId/GPv, SStr, and FStr 
    regions which extend the amygdala rostrally, and ii) the 
    projections of the pPB area to these latter regions were 
    topographically organized.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">This organization, suggested by the grouping of 
    injection sites in Figure 4 is summarized in Figure 14.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">This diagram, which interprets the results of the 
    present study, shows that three compartments of connectivity can be 
    recognized: 1) the region of the pPB filled in grey (Fig. 14A, 
    including the pPBm, the pPBwa, the neurons in and medial to the 
    brachium conjunctivum, and a thin lamina of neurons in the rostral 
    pPBvl) projects very densely to the CeM (Fig. 14Bl-B5, grey region) 
    and densely to the BMA, BLP, and ACo nuclei of the amygdala (Fig. 
    14B0, B2-R5, light grey region) and to the SIdlGPv, SStr, and FStr 
    rostral regions (Fig. 14B4-B6, light grey region); 2) the region of 
    the pPB filled with dots (Fig. 14A, including the pPBcl, an 
    adjacent portion of the pPBvl and the outer portion of the pPBel) 
    projects very densely to the CeL (Fig. 14B1-B4, region filled with 
    dots); and 3) the hatched region of the pPB (Fig. 14A, including 
    the pPBdl, a thin dorsal portion of the pPBcl, the more caudal 
    portion of the pPBv1, all of the remaining pPBel and the pPBem) 
    projects VerY densely onto the CeLC (Fig. 14B1-B5, hatched region) 
    and densely in the region which continues the CeLC rostrallY and in 
    the SIdiGPv, SStr, and FStr rostral regions (Fig.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">14B5,B6, hatched region).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">In addition (this is not illustrated in Fig. 141, it 
    must be emphasized, that differing from other amygdaloid areas of 
    termination, the dense projection onto the rostral portion of the 
    CeLC is bilateral without an ipsilateral predominance.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Figure 14 shows a schematic division into three 
    regions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">However, this description will need to be further 
    investigated since it is probable that there exists other 
    subregions in this organization.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">The ventral portion of the pPBm appears to project 
    mainly onto the medial portion of the CeM, the portion of the pPBm 
    adjacent to the bc onto the central portion of the CeM, and the 
    pPBwa with the ventral portion of the pPBvl onto the lateral 
    portion of the CeM adjacent to the CeL.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">This analysis needs to be continued, taking into account 
    the fact that the transition area between two regions in the pPB 
    projected to the transition area of the two corresponding regions 
    in the Ce.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Finally, the special organization of the hatched region 
    must be described in further detail.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Thus, the pPB hatched region could be divided into two 
    regions: the superficial region (the main and the external pPBdl 
    and the outer-caudal pPBel) and the external region (the caudal and 
    the inner-rostra1 portion of the pPBel and the pPBem).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Each of the two regions projected on the whole CeLC, but 
    in each subregion one portion (the main pPBdl and the inner-rostra1 
    pPBel) projects onto the caudal portion of the ipsilateral CeLC, 
    and the other portion (the external pPBdl, the caudal pPBel, and 
    the pPBem) projects bilaterally onto the rostral portion of the 
    CeLC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">In addition, from the comparative analysis of the 
    density of projection of each injection site, it was possible to 
    evaluate i) the rostrocaudal extent of the subregions in the pPB 
    area and ii) the relative density of parabrachial neurons 
    projecting to the Ce (pPB-Ce neurons).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">The rostrocaudal extent of the pPB region projecting to 
    the CeM was approximately 800 to 200 pm caudal to the Pr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">In this region the density of pPB-Ce neurons was 
    probably at a maximum in and around the medial half of the brachium 
    conjunctivum, whereas it seemed relatively low in the ventrolateral 
    portion near the pPBem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">The rostrocaudal extent of the pPB region projecting to 
    the CeL was approximately 600 to 0 pm caudal to the Pr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">The rostrocaudal extent of the pPB region projecting to 
    the CeLC was approximately 800 to 100 pm caudal to the Pr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Both the PBel and the PBem seemed to contain a high 
    density of pPB-Ce neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s281">Nomenclature and 
    subdivision of the regions</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">The nomenclature and main divisions of the PB area (see 
    Fig. 14A) was adopted from the description of Fulwiler and Saper 
    (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">The division in the pPB area (caudal to the coronal 
    plane where the inferior colliculus merges with the pons) and in 
    the mPB area (rostral to the latter plane) does not modify this 
    nomenclature.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Nevertheless a small modification was adopted for the 
    pPBem: in the present study the pPBem extends slightly more 
    rostrally (up to 100 I-Lm behind the Prj than in the study of 
    Fulwiler and Saper (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">This modification was adopted because the rostral pPBem 
    was rather undefined and all of the pPBem as defined in the present 
    study projected to the same subdivision of the Ce.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">The following points of the nomenclature were adopted: 
    i) The pPBdl often included two (or more) dorsal superficial islet 
    of cells, well separated by a thin fibre fasciculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">In the present study, the main pPBdl corresponded to the 
    main group of cells which extended dorsally to the pPBvl (in the 
    caudal portion of the pPB area) and to the pPBcl (in the 
    rostralportion of the pPB area) (see Fig. 4D, sites No. 45 and 
    66).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">The external pPBdl corresponded to the other group which 
    surrounded the rostral portion of the pPBel dorsolaterally (see 
    Fig. 4D2, site No. 55). ii) The pPBel was currently divided into an 
    inner portion (adjacent to the bc) and an outer portion (in dorsal 
    and lateral position, see Fig. 4D1, sites No. 55 and 50 and Fig. 
    4C2, site No. 60).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">The nomenclature and division of the amygdala (see Fig. 
    14B) was for the main nuclei adopted from the atlas of Paxinos and 
    Watson (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">For the Ce nucleus we adopted the main subdivision of 
    McDonald (&apos;82) and Cassel et al. (&apos;861, i.e., the CeL, 
    the CeLC, and the CeM, with the following adaptation: The CeL 
    subdivision in the present study corresponds well to the lateral 
    subdivision of the Ce (CL) described by Cassel et al. 
    (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">As these authors, we included the intermediate 
    subdivision (CI) described by McDonald (&apos;82) in the CeL.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Nevertheless, the rostral extension of the CeL in this 
    study was generally found a little less rostral than in the 
    description of Cassel et al. (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">It must be emphasized that this circular region was 
    generally easy to identify on Nissl-counterstained sections due to 
    a thin &quot;capsule&quot; of fibres which surrounds most of this 
    subdivision and also to the intense labelling of well grouped 
    neurons in this area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Thus, this subdivision was an important anatomical mark 
    used in order to determine the topographic organization between the 
    pPB and the Ce.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">The CeM subdivision in the present study corresponds in 
    general to the medial subdivision (CM) of McDonald (&apos;82) and 
    to the medial (CM) and ventral (CV) subdivisions of Cassel et al. 
    (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">However, we have included a thin dorsal lamina in the 
    CeM, which roughly corresponds to the dorsal portion of the lateral 
    capsular subdivision (CLC) described by McDonald (&apos;82); in 
    fact, in the present study, this thin lamina surrounded dorsally, 
    then laterally, the CeL (see Figs. 5Bl,B2, 6B3,B4, 14Bl-B4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">This minor change was adopted in the study because the 
    labelling in the CeM always included this dorsal and lateral 
    lamina.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">This slight modification permitted a more simple 
    description of the projections to the Ce and provided an objective 
    delineation of the dorsal border of the CeM which was not clearly 
    determined by the Nissl.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">The CeLC subdivision in the present study corresponds 
    for the main portion to the lateral CLC of McDonald (&apos;821, 
    with a rostro-caudal extent a little bit larger.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Indeed, the CeLC included a thin lamina of cells in the 
    more caudal portion of the Ce (see Fig. 14B1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">In addition, at the rostral level the CeLC included the 
    amygdalostriatal transition (AStr) area as described in the atlas 
    of Paxinos and Watson (&apos;86) (see also DeOlmos et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">This more noticeable modification in the delineation of 
    the CeLC was adopted because the dense projection to the CeLC 
    always included this region on the border to the more restricted 
    CLC area previously described.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">This slightly modified description of the Ce was of 
    interest for two reasons: 1) it made possible a simple description 
    of the Ce afferents and 2) it gave a direct anatomical description 
    of afferent regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Additionally, it must be pointed out that the small 
    anatomical subdivisions recognized on a Nissl-stained section are 
    difficult to identify on a Nissl-counterstained section, containing 
    a dense black stained projection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">The region dorsal and rostral to the Ce was named 
    transition area between the dorsal portion of the substantia 
    innominata and the ventral portion of the globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">This SIdiGPv region included the ventral portion of the 
    globus pallidus and the amygdalopallidal transition rostral to the 
    Ce (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Nevertheless, the delineation as well as the 
    nomenclature of this area is indefinite and therefore a matter of 
    discussion among authors.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Thus, this area also corresponds to a large part of the 
    substantia innominata dorsalis (Grove, &apos;88a); it includes a 
    part of the cholinergic cells of the nucleus basalis of Meynert 
    (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;86; Grove, &apos;88a) and it largely 
    overlaps the sublenticular area (De Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s309">The validity and limits 
    of the topical organization</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">The artefactual labelling, due to an uptake of PHA-L by 
    fibres of passage, was described as absent or very low by Gerfen 
    and Sawchenko (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">This observation was confirmed by the results of the 
    present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Indeed, in some cases where a strongly labelled 
    injection site was precisely centred in the bc, none or only a few 
    labelled terminals were observed in the nuclei (red nucleus, 
    ventrolateral, and ventromedial thalamic nuclei), which are the 
    main targets of the fibres passing through the bc, and arising from 
    the deep cerebellar nuclei (Fad and Carman, &apos;78; Haroian et 
    al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Thus, it appears that such a phenomenon cannot be 
    misleading in the present study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">At the level of the amygdala, the identification of the 
    labelled terminals with the PHA-L technique using the 
    intensification with nickel was very reliable, and artefactual 
    labelling does not appear to occur.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">In addition, the identification of labelled terminals 
    (very thin fibres with numerous ramifications and varicosities) as 
    compared to fibres of passage (thicker fibres without ramifications 
    and varicosity) was generally easy.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">The comparison of the density of terminal labelling was 
    also easily made.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">In fact, the only difficulty was to compare the areas of 
    termination in the Ce in different animals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Such a comparison was made with the use of the following 
    anatomical marks: the optic tract, the stria terminalis, the 
    cornmissural stria terminalis, and the fibres delineating the 
    basolateral and lateral group of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">In addition, the counterstained section permitted us to 
    clearly identify the CeL subnucleus, the basolateralilateral group, 
    and the intercalated main nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Thus, despite the fact that the borders of the CeM and 
    CeLC were often not very well defined, it was possible to compare 
    the labelled areas in different experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">At the level of the PB area the injection sites were 
    often restricted (diameter between 400-600 prn) or very restricted 
    (diameter &amp;lt; 400 Fm) and the extent of the injection site can 
    be reliably estimated as the area which contained densely stained 
    labelled cells around a small dense core.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">The comparison of several adjacent (with or without 
    overlapping area) injection sites with their respective projections 
    shows that this evaluation of the injection site permitted a 
    determination of the extent with an error that probably does not 
    exceed 100 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">With such precision it was possible to recognize, 
    without ambiguity, three different regions in the pPB area, 
    although it was not possible to decide with certainty the 
    boundaries between the three regions in the pPB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Thus, the limit and the extent of the three regions 
    represented in Figure 14A were only an estimation made by a careful 
    comparison of the 43 injection sites made in the pPB (a selection 
    of 29 of them is presented in Fig. 4).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">In fact, it appears that with this type of strategy the 
    regions were more precisely determined at the level of the amygdala 
    than at the pPl3 level.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">It is probable that a retrograde study with very small 
    injection sites in several portions of the Ce could add further 
    precision on the location of the pPB-Ce neurons in the pPB area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">However, such an extensive investigation was not in the 
    field of the present study, and with the numerous data in the 
    literature where retrograde studies have been performed, it is 
    possible to obtain a relatively precise view of the question.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s328">Comparison with data in 
    the literature on the rat</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Our results are in good agreement with data in the 
    literature on the rat which demonstrated, using an anterograde 
    marker, a strong projection of the pontine parabrachial area on the 
    nucleus centralis of the rat (Norgren, &apos;76; Saper and Loewy 
    &apos;80; Bernard et al., &apos;89; Moga et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">In more detail our results are in full agreement with 
    the study by Norgren (&apos;76) which demonstrated an intense 
    projection in the ipsilateral Ce and the substantia innominata 
    after injection of tritiated proline centred in the bracliium 
    conjunctivum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">The present results are also in general agreement with 
    the study of Saper and Loewy (&apos;80) who used tritiated proline 
    and leucine with injections in the lateral and medial parabrachial 
    areas.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">They found on the ipsilateral side, an intense 
    projection in the Ce and the substantia innominata and a more 
    sparse projection in the anterior, the medial, the basomedial, and 
    the posterior basolateral amygdaloid nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Indeed, in the present study we show that the pPBm, the 
    pPBwa, and the portion of the pPBvl project onto all these latter 
    nuclei except for the medial amygdaloid nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">However, the adjacent rnPB area densely projects onto 
    this area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Finally, the present results fully confirm both the 
    studies of Bernard et al. (&apos;89) and Moga et al. (&apos;90) 
    which demonstrated a strong projection to the ipsilateral amygdala 
    restricted to the Ce after wheat germ-HRP injections restricted to 
    the pPBel.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">It is interesting to note that in both cases (see Fig. 
    11C in Moga et al., &apos;90) the anterograde labelling was in the 
    CeL and probably also in the CeLC, but not in the CeM.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Thus, the present study is in accordance with all 
    previous studies in the rat, but it extends the previous results 
    considerably by providing a detailed and more complete mapping of 
    the projections of the pPB area onto the amygdala, showing separate 
    projections to the CeM and CeL and finding out a new and separate 
    projection onto the CeLC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Our results are also in good agreement with data in the 
    literature on the rat which demonstrate numerous retrogradely 
    labelled neurons in the pPB after injection of HRP or wheat 
    germ-HRP in the ipsilateral Ce (Ottersen and Ben-Ari, &apos;78; 
    Ottersen, &apos;81; Voshart and Van der Kooy, &apos;81; Fulwiler 
    and Saper, &apos;84; Ma and Peschanski, &apos;88; Moga et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">However, the analysis of data in the literature could 
    lead to the conclusion that there exists a discrepancy between our 
    results and others; in the present study all the injection sites in 
    the pPB gave rise to a substantial labelling in the Ce, whereas 
    most of the previous studies with a retrograde strategy showed 
    retrogradely labelled cells only in restricted portions of the pPB 
    (more often in the pPBel).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">In fact, an analysis of individual experiments in these 
    latter studies shows that the injection site was generally 
    restricted to a subregion of the Ce which corresponds well to the 
    topographic projection demonstrated by the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Thus, Ottersen (&apos;81, case RX6) found numerous 
    retrogradely labelled cells in the pPBm, the pPBem, the pPBwa, and 
    the pPBel after an injection in the caudal CeM and CeLC.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">After an injection restricted to the CeLC he found 
    numerous labelled cells in the pPBem (case RT 307); in addition, 
    after an injection outside the Ce in the medial amygdaloid nucleus 
    (case RZ10) the labelled cells were located outside the pPB, that 
    is, in the mPB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Fulwiler and Saper (&apos;84) found numerous labelled 
    cells only in the pPBel and pYBvl after an injection based on the 
    entire Ce centred in the caudal CeL (case R159).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">In a more recent study (Moga et al., &apos;go), numerous 
    labelled cells in the caudal pPBwa, the inner pPBel, and the mPB 
    area from an injection covering both the Ce (spreading probably 
    into the CeM and CeLC) and the medial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">This study also showed that an injection centred in the 
    caudal CeL (and spreading probably into the CeLC) gives rise to a 
    very dense labelling in the pPBel (outer-rostra1 and caudal 
    portions) and the pPBwa.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Finally, it is interesting to observe (Fig. 1B in Ma and 
    Peschanski, &apos;88) that a large injection in the Ce labels 
    numerous neurons in almost all the subnuclei of the pPB area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">The present results, as summarized in Figure 14, were 
    compatible with all these data in the literature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Nevertheless, the present results (experiments 45, 50, 
    55, and 66; see Figs. 4, 13) suggest that, in the pPB, a 
    superficial group of neurons (in the pPBdl and the outercaudal 
    portion of the pPBel) projects additionally onto the Ce (the 
    CeLC).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Furthermore, two points must be noted: i) The CeL 
    subnucleus corresponds to the centre of the Ce and so an injection 
    centred in the Ce was primarily in the CeL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Thus, it is not surprising that, in the literature (see 
    above), the cases most frequently presented, which correspond to 
    injections well centred in the Ce, show numerous labelled cells in 
    the pPBel.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Indeed, the present results demonstrated that the pPBel 
    project densely onto the CeL, the CeLC, and for neurons on the 
    border to the brachium conjunctivum, probably to the portion 
    adjacent to the CeM. iil The problem of the precise rostrocaudal 
    distribution of pPB-Ce neurons was not covered in detail because 
    neither in the present study nor in the previous studies has this 
    aspect been systematically studied.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">We can only conclude that the present study is 
    compatible with the two cases presented by Moga et al.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">(&apos;go), which showed a high density of pPB-Ce 
    neurons in the caudal pPBwa and in the two thirds rostra1 of the 
    pPBel.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Thus, despite a relative lack of precision at the pPB 
    level, the present study gives a mapping of pPB projections to the 
    amygdala which allows us to give a coherent interpretation of 
    previous data in the literature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">In addition, it suggests that the number of pPB-Ce 
    neurons is probably higher than has been described in the 
    literature.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s356">Comparison with data in 
    the literature concerning other mammals</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Our results are generally in agreement with the data 
    obtained in the hamster, the rabbit, the cat, and the monkey 
    (Nomura et al.; &apos;79; Mehler, &apos;80; Russchen, &apos;82; 
    Kapp et al., &apos;89; Ma et al., &apos;89; Berkley and Scofield, 
    &apos;90; Halsell, &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">In all these other studies a strong projection from the 
    pPB area to the Ce was described.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">In most of them, after an injection of HRP or Weat 
    germ-HRP in the Ce, numerous retrogradely labelled cells were found 
    mostly in the pPBel.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">These results could correspond to injections centred in 
    an area corresponding to the CeL of the rat (see previous 
    section).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Further analysis is difficult because the mapping of 
    parabrachio-amygdaloid projections was not as detailed in these 
    species as in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Nevertheless, it is interesting to note that our results 
    are compatible with those found in the cat, in three experiments 
    with injection sites in the Ce, and a detailed mapping of the pPB 
    area (Nomura et al., &apos;79; Ma et a]., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Indeed, considering these studies together, it can be 
    observed that numerous retrogradely labelled cells were found in 
    most of the pPB area (pPBm, pPBem, pPBwa, pPBel, pPBvl, and 
    probably pPBcl).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s364">Functional implication 
    of the topic organization</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">As discussed in the beginning of the Discussion, the 
    projections from the pPB area to the Ce were divided into three 
    separate pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">The analysis of anatomical, electrophysiological, and 
    behavioral data in the literature suggest a specific functional 
    implication for each one of the pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Thus, three different basic functions can be suggested: 
    The pPB-CeLC pathway (Fig. 14, regions filled with hatched lines) 
    would primarily be implicated in the processing of nociceptive and 
    cardio-respiratory messages.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">The pPB-CeL pathway (Fig. 14, regions filled with black 
    dots) would primarily be implicated in the processing of autonomic 
    and visceral messages.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">The pPB-CeM pathway (Fig. 14, regions filled with grey) 
    would primarily be implicated in the processing of gustatory 
    messages.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">As compared to these rather organized pathways, the 
    pPB-SId/GPv pathway, on the other hand, has a larger convergence of 
    information from the pPB subnuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Clearly, the parabrachial area is a very complex region 
    which probably processes a variety of different information.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Thus, the proposed division is obviously schematic and 
    the overlapping and/or the interrelation of functions between 
    subgroups of neurons in the pPB and in the Ce area is very 
    possible.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s373">The pPB-CeLC 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s374">A recent 
    electrophysiological</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">study (Bernard and Besson, &apos;88, &apos;90a) shows 
    that numerous neurons located in the pPBel and pPBem and backfired 
    from the Ce were exclusively driven by noxious stimuli.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Other recent electrophysiological investigations 
    (Hayashi and Tabata, &apos;90; Slugg and Light, &apos;90) such as 
    the study using a marker of neuronal activity (C-fosikrox-24) 
    (Bullitt, &apos;90; Herdegen et al., &apos;90) confirmed that 
    numerous PB neurons receive noxious input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">This is in agreement with the electrophysiological 
    demonstration that numerous dorsal horn lamina I nociceptive 
    specific neurons project to the PB nucleus (Hayashi and Tabata, 
    &apos;89; Hylden et al., &apos;85, &apos;86b; Light et al., 
    &apos;87; McMahon and Wall, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">The existence of nociceptive input in the PB area is 
    also supported by several anatomical studies in the rat (Zemlan et 
    al., &apos;78; Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Ma and Peschanski, 
    &apos;88; Bernard et al., &apos;89; Hylden et al.. &apos;891, the 
    cat (Bjorkeland and Boivie, &apos;84; Wiberg and Blomqvist, 
    &apos;84; Panneton and Burton, &apos;85; Hylden et al., &apos;86a; 
    Blomqvist et al., &apos;891, and the monkey (Mehler, &apos;69; 
    Kerr, &apos;75; Wiberg et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">These studies show primarily that numerous neurons 
    located in lamina I of the spinal and medullary dorsal horn, which 
    receive nociceptive inputs (see references in Besson and Chaouch, 
    &apos;871, reach the lateral and external portion of the pPB 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">A detailed analysis of data in the literature shows that 
    in the pPB i) several nociceptive pPB-Ce neurons were recorded, in 
    the rat, in the pPBel and in the caudal pPBem (Bernard and Besson, 
    &apos;90a); ii) the spinoparabrachial terminal fibres are mainly 
    located caudally in most of the pPBl and rostrally in the pPBdl and 
    the dorsal portion of the pPBcl (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; 
    Blomqvist et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">These data were confirmed by personal results in the 
    rat; iii) the trigeminoparabrachial terminal fibres were mainly 
    located in the pPBel and pPBem (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Saxon 
    and Hopkins, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">This indicates that the pPB region (Fig. 14A, filled 
    with grey) which projects onto the CeLC receives a strong 
    nociceptive input and plays probably an important role in the 
    processing of nociceptive messages.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Furthermore, this conclusion is strongly supported by a 
    recent study (Bernard et al., &apos;90, &apos;92) which 
    demonstrates that a very high proportion of neurons located in the 
    CeLC (which receives afferent projections from the present pPB 
    region) strongly respond to noxious stimulation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">In addition to the spinal and trigeminal inputs, this 
    pPB region also receives an important input from the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract (NTS) (Norgren, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">The projections from the NTS to the pPB area were 
    described in detail in the rat, in a recent study by Herbert et al. 
    (&apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">This study shows that this pPB region receives some 
    afferent projections from i) the ventrolateral NTS and the 
    periambiguous nucleus, which primarily receive respiratory 
    afferents (Herbert et al., &apos;90; see also Ellenberger and 
    Feldman, &apos;90); ii) the medial NTS which receives visceral 
    afferents (Torvik, &apos;56; Contreras et al., &apos;82; Kalia and 
    Sullivan, &apos;82; Norgren and Smith, &apos;88; Altshuler et al., 
    &apos;89) and also lamina I afferent projections (Menetrey and 
    Basbaum, &apos;87; Men&amp; trey and De Pommery, &apos;91); and 
    iii) the rostral NTS (for the pPBem) which receives gustatory as 
    somesthetic intraoral afferent projections (Hamilton and Norgen, 
    &apos;84; see discussion in Herbert et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">It must be pointed out that the neurons recorded in the 
    pPBem were not gustatory (Norgen and Pfaffmann, &apos;75) but 
    responded exclusively to intraoral noxious stimuli (Bernard and 
    Besson, &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">The dorsal portion of the pPBl also receives a dense 
    projection from the Al, A5 areas, the Gigantocellular reticular 
    formation, and the ventrolateral medulla implicated in 
    cardiovascular regulation (Byrum and Guyenet, &apos;87; Guyenet and 
    Young, &apos;87; Haselton and Guyenet, &apos;90; Woulff et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">The precise role of these latter afferents and the NTS, 
    in this presumably nociceptive pPB region, is not clear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">It could be hypothetized that they bring nociceptive 
    visceral and aversive autonomic (respiratory and cardiovascular) 
    information into this &quot;nociceptive&quot; pPB area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Thus, this analysis strongly suggests that the 
    nociceptive spino(trigemin0)-ponto-amygdaloid pathway (Bernard and 
    Besson, &apos;88, &apos;90a; Bernard et al., &apos;89) relays in 
    the region of the pPB (Fig. 14A, grey) which project to the 
    CeLC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Interestingly, at least three peptides, substance P 
    (SP), neurotensin (NT), and calcitonin gene related peptide (CGRP), 
    label this nociceptive pathway with relative specificity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">The superficial laminae of the spinal and medullary 
    dorsal horn contain a high level of SP and CGRP (Ljungdahl et al., 
    &apos;78; Schwaber et al., &apos;88; Skofitsch and Jacobowitz, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">The pPB region which projects to the CeLC contains both 
    numerous SP and NT immunoreactive terminals and neurons 
    immunoreactive to SP and/or NT andlor CGRP, some of them identified 
    as projecting to the Ce (Milner et al., &apos;84; Block and 
    Hoffman, &apos;87; Schwaber et al., &apos;88; Yamano et al., 
    &apos;88a,b; Block et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">The CeLC also contains a high density of SP, CGRP, and 
    NT terminals (Wray and Hoffman, &apos;83; Kruger et al., &apos;88; 
    Yasui et al., &apos;91) of which a large proportion arises from the 
    pPB area (Yamano et al., &apos;88a,b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">In the cat, Berkley and Scofield, (&apos;90) have 
    identified a parabrachial relay from the solitary nucleus to the 
    amygdala but they failed to find an important relay from the spinal 
    cord to the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Such discrepancies could be due to the species 
    difference between the rat and the cat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">However, from the results of the present study, it could 
    be hypothetized that the amygdaloid injections in the former study 
    was centred in the CeL and/or the CeM and thus revealed the 
    solitaro-ponto-amygdaloid pathway but not the 
    spino-ponto-amygdaloid pathway which deal with the CeLC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">The pPB-CeL pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">The afferent projections in the corresponding pPB region 
    (Fig. 14A, regions filled with black dots) were not completely 
    different from those in the nociceptive area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">This pPB region also receives afferents from the lamina 
    I spinal neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">However, the density of projections appears to be 
    considerably lower in this region (pPBcl) than in the previous 
    region (pPBdl) (Cechetto et d., &apos;85; Blomqvist et al., 
    &apos;89); these data were confirmed by personal results in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Accordingly, the amount of afferent projections from the 
    lamina I trigeminal neurons seems lower in this regon 
    (outer-rostra1 pPBel) than in the previous region (caudal pPBel and 
    pPBem) (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Panneton and Burton, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">However, these data do not permit us to evaluate this 
    projection definitely.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">On the other hand, this region receives a strong 
    afferent projection from the NTS: i) the pPBcl receives a strong 
    projection from the medial NTS and the area postrema (Herbert et 
    al., &apos;90) and ii) the outer-rostra1 pPBel (see Fig. 10 in the 
    present study) receives a strong projection from the shell portion 
    of the area postrema (van der Kooy and Koda, &apos;83; Shapiro and 
    Miselis, &apos;85; see Fig. 31 in Herbert et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Furthermore, the difference between this region and the 
    previous one was sustained by the electrophysiological studies of 
    Bernard et al. (&apos;90, &apos;92) which show that the proportion 
    of neurons activated by noxious, somesthetic stimuli was much lower 
    in the CeL (which receives afferent projections from this pPB 
    region) than in the CeLC (which receives afferent projections from 
    the previous &quot;nociceptive&quot; pPB region).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Thus, this pPB region could relay visceral information 
    from the medial NTS (Torvik, &apos;56; Contreras et al., &apos;82; 
    Kalia and Sullivan, &apos;82; Norgren and Smith, &apos;88; 
    Altshuler et al., &apos;89) and chemoceptive information from the 
    area postrema (Gallo et al., &apos;90; Adachi et al., &apos;91) to 
    the CeL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">This region could be considered as a transitional area 
    between the previous nociceptive region (common processing of 
    visceral information) and the gustatory region (common processing 
    of chemosensitive information).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">ThepPB-CeMpathway.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">The afferent projections in the corresponding pPB region 
    (Fig. 14, regions filled with grey) were in fact different from the 
    two previous regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Thus, this pPB region does not receive afferents from 
    the lamina I spinal neurons (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Panneton 
    and Burton, &apos;85; Blomqvist et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">In the same way, despite some afferent projections from 
    the trigeminal nucleus (interpolar subnucleus and paratrigeminal 
    and/or the promontorium) in the caudal pPBm and the pPBvl on the 
    border of the bc, it does not receive afferents from the lamina I 
    trigeminal neurons (Cechetto et al., &apos;85; Panneton and Burton, 
    &apos;85; Blomqvist et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">In fact, the main afferent projections of the gustatory 
    portion of the pPB area arise from the rostral portion of the NTS 
    (Norgren, &apos;78; Herbert et al., &apos;90) which receives 
    gustatory afferent messages (Hamilton and Norgen, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">The gustatory portion of the pPB area is usually 
    associated with the whole pPBm, the pPBwa, and an adjacent portion 
    in the pPB1.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">However, Herbert et al. (&apos;90) found that the 
    gustatory NTS projects to a more restricted area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">In fact, electrophysiological studies show that neurons 
    responding to gustatory stimuli are located in a region which 
    extends over an intermediate range that is in between these two 
    estimates (Norgren and Pfaffmann, &apos;75; Ogawa et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">In the present study, the region of pPB which projects 
    to the CeM corresponds well to the gustatory region.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">It is interesting to point out that the regions which 
    received the highest density of rostral NTS afferents (Herbert et 
    al., &apos;90) also showed dense projections to the CeM (the 
    present study).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Thus, this third pPB region relays gustatory messages 
    from the rostral NTS to the CeM acd some other amygdaloid nuclei 
    (basomedial anterior, corticoamygdaloid, and basolateral 
    posterior).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">It is interesting to point out that the pPBem which is 
    included in the nociceptive pPB region could be considered as an 
    area of transition with the gustatory pPB region because it 
    processes intraoral nociceptive information (Norgren and 
    Pfaff&apos;mann, &apos;75; Bernard and Besson, &apos;90a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">The pP3-SIdlGPu pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">The present results show that all the pPBwa, the pPBm, 
    the pPBem, the pPBel, and the pPBdl subnuclei projected 
    substantially onto the SId/ GPv (Fig. 14).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">In fact, all the pPB subnuclei send at least some 
    projections onto this area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">In addition, the control injections show that the mPR 
    also substantially projected onto the SIdiGPv.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">These results are in good agreement with the recent 
    study by Moga et al. (&apos;90) which emphasizes the heavy input to 
    the substantia innominata from the PB area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">In addition to the parabrachial input, the SId/GYv 
    receives numerous afferent projections from the Ce itself, from the 
    thalamus, the zona incerta, and the mesencephalic reticular 
    formation (Grove, &apos;88a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Thus, the SIdiGPv is the centre of a large convergence 
    of gustatory, visceral, and somesthetic information in which the 
    pPB-SIdiGPv pathway has an important role.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Since the SIdiGPv includes part of the nucleus basalis 
    of Meynert known for its cholinergic projections toward several 
    areas of the cortex and its role in memory (Everitt et al., 
    &apos;87; Grove, &apos;88a,b; see also references in Koliatsos et 
    al., &apos;90 and Wainer and Mesulam, &apos;901, it could be 
    hypothetized that the pPB-SIdiGPv pathway is implicated in the 
    memorization of events in relation to gustatory, visceral, or 
    nociceptive sensations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Interestingly, a very high proportion of neurons 
    strongly and specifically activated by noxious stimuli were 
    recorded in the SId/GPv (Bernard et al., &apos;90, &apos;92).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s430">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s431">We thank Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s432">A.H.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s433">Dickenson for advice in the 
    preparation of the manuscript and J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s434">Carroue for histological 
    help.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s435">This study was supported by 
    I&apos;Institut National de la Sant6 et de la Recherche Medicale 
    (INSERM).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Adachi, A., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Kohachi, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Miyoshi, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Tsukamoto (1991) Chemosensitive neurons in the area 
    postrema of the rat and their possible functions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Bull. 26:137-140.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Altschuler, S.M., X.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Bao, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Bieger, D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Hopkins, and R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Miselis (1989) Viscerotopic representation of the upper 
    alimentary tract in the rat: Sensory ganglia and nuclei of the 
    solitary and spinal trigcminal tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Neurol. 283t248-268.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Barnard, J.W. (1936) A phylogenetic study of the 
    visceral afferent areas associated with the facial, 
    glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves and their fiher connections: The 
    efferent facial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Neurol. 6.5503602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Beaulieu, S., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Di Paolo, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">CMC, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Barden (1987) Participation of the central amygdaloid 
    nucleus in the response of&apos; adrenocorticotropin secretion to 
    immobilization stress: Opposing roles of the noradrenergic and 
    dopaminergic systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Neuroendocrinology 4.5:37-46.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Ben-hi, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">(ed) (1981) The Amygdaloid Complex, INSERM Symposium 
    N&quot;20, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Berkley, K.J., and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Scofield (1990) Relays from the spinal cord and solitary 
    nucleus through the parabrachial nucleus to the forebrain in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Brain Res. 529:333-338.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Bernard, J.F., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Besson (1988) Convergence d&apos;informations 
    nociceptives sur des neurones parabachio-amygdaliens chez le 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Ser. 111-Vie 307:841-847.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Bernard, J.F., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Besson (1 990ai The spino(trigemino)pontoamygdalotd 
    pathway: Electrophysiological evidence for an involvement in pain 
    processes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Neurophysiol. 63:473490.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Bernard, J.F., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Besson (1990hi Amygdaloid projections of the external 
    parabrachial area in the rat: A PHA-L study wlth reference to pain 
    transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Ahstr. 16:705.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Bernard, J.F., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Carroue, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Besson (1991) Efferent projections from the external 
    parabrachial area to the forebrain: A phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Lett. 122:257-260.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Bernard, J.F., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Huang, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Besson (1990) Effect of noxious somesthetic stimulation 
    on the activity of neurons of the nucleus centralis of the 
    amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Brain Res. 523:347-350.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Bernard, J.F., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Huang, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Resson (1992) Thc nucleus centralis of the amygdala and 
    the globus pallidus ventralis: Electrophysiological evidence for an 
    involvement in pain processes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Neurophysiol. 68:551569.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Bernard, J.F., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Peschanski, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Besson (1989) A possible spinottrigemino)pontoamygdaloid 
    pathway for pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Lett. 100:83-88.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Bertrand, F., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Hugelin (1971) Respiratory synchronizing function of 
    nucleus parabrachialis medialis: Pneumotaxic mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Neurophysiol. 134: 189-207.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Bertrand, F., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Hugelin, and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Vibert (1973) Quantitative study of anatomical 
    distribution of respiration related neurons in the pons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Brain &amp;s.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">I6:383-399.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Besson, J.M., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Chaouch (1987) Peripheral nociception.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Rev. 67:67-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Bjorkeland, M., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Boivie (19841 The termination of spinomesencephalic 
    fibers in cat: An expximental anatomical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Embryol. 170:265277.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Block, C.H., and G.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Hoffman (1987) Neuropeptide and monoamine components of 
    the parabrachial pontine complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Peptides 8:267-283.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Block, C.H., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Hoffman, and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Kapp (1989) Peptide-containing pathways from the 
    parabrachial complex to the central nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Peptides 10:465-471.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Blomqvist, A., W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Ma, and K.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Berkley (19891 Spinal input to the parabrarhial nucleus 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Brain Res. 480:29-36.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Bul1it.t E. (1990) Expression of C-fos-like protein as a 
    marker for neuronal activity following noxious stimulation in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Z96:5 17-530.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Byrum, C.E., and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Guyenet (1987) Afferent and efferent connections of the 
    A5 noradrenergic cellgroup in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Neurol. 261329542.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Cassel, M.D., T.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Gray, and J.Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Kiss (1986) Neurorial architecture in the rat central 
    nucleus of the amygdala: A cytological, hodological, and 
    immunocytochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Neurol. 246:47%499.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Cechetto, D.F., and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Calaresu (1983) Response of single units in the amygdala 
    to stimulation of buffer nerves in cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Physiol. 244:R64&amp;R651.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Cechetto, D.F., and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Calaresu (1984) Units in the amygdala responding to 
    activation of carotid haroand chemoreceptors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Physiol. 246:R832-R836.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Cechetto, D.F., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Standaert, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Saper (1985) Spinal and trigeminal dorsal horn 
    projections lo the parabrachial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Gxnp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Neurol. 240:153-160.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Contreras, R.J., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Beckstead, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Norgren (1982) The central projections of the 
    trigeminal, facial, glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves: An 
    autoradiographic study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Autonom.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">New.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Syst. 6:303322.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Cox, G.E., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Jordan, J.F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Paton, K.M Spyer, and L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Wood (1987) Cardiovascular and phrenic nerve responses 
    to stimulation of&apos; the amygdala central nucleus in the 
    anaesthetized rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Physiol. 389541556.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Creutzfeldt, O.D., F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Bell, and W.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Adey (19631 Thc activity of neurons in the amygdala of 
    the cat following atferent stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Brain Res. 3:31-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Darlington, D.N., and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Ward (1985a) Rostra1 pontine and caudal mesencephalic 
    control of arterial pressure and iliac, celiac and renal vascular 
    resistance. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Anatomic regions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Brain Res. 361:284-300.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Darlington, D.N., and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Ward (1985h) Rustral pontine and caudal mesencephalic 
    control of arterial pressure and iliac, celiac and renal vascular 
    resistance. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Separate control and topographic organization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Brain Res. 36P301-308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">De Olmos, J., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Beltraniino Paxinos, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">(ed): &apos;The Rat Nervous System, Academic Press, pp. 
    223-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Edwards, G.L., and A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Johnson (1991) Enhanced drinking after excitotoxic 
    lesions of the parabrachial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Physiol. 261: 1039-1044.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Eguchi, K., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Tadaki, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Simhulan Jr, andT.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Kumazawa (1987) Respiratory depression caused by either 
    morphine microinjection or repetitive electrical stimulation in the 
    region of the nucleus parahrachialis of cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Euro.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Physiol. 409,367-373.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Ellenberger, H.H., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Feldman (1990) Brainstem connections of the rostra1 
    ventral respiratory group of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Brain Res. 513:35-42.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Everitt, B.J., T.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Robbins, J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Evenden, H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Marston, G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Jones, and T.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Sirkia (1987) The effects of cxcitotoxic lesions of the 
    suhstantia innominata, ventral and dorsal globus pallidus on the 
    acquisition and retention of a conditional visual discrimination: 
    Implications for cholinergic hypotheses of learning and memory.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Neuroscience 22441-469.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Faul, R.L.M., and d.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Carman (1978) The cerchellofugal projections in the 
    hrachium conjunctivum of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">The contralateral ascending pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Neurol. 178:495-5 18.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Flynn, F.W., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Schwartz, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Grill, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Norgren (1991a) Central gustatory lesions: Preference 
    and taste reactivity tests.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Neurosci. 105,933-943.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Flynn, F.W., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Schulkin, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Grill, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Norgren (1991h) Central gustatory lesions: Effects on 
    sodium appetite, taste aversion learning and feeding behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Neurosci. 105344-954.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Fulwiler, CX., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Saper (1984) Subnuclear organization of the efferent 
    connections of the parabrachial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Bran Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Rev. 7229-259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Galaverna, O., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Laurival, J.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">De Luca, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Schulkin, S.Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Yao, and A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Epstein (1991) Deficits in NaCl ingestion after damage 
    to the central nucleus of the amygdala in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Bull. 28:89-98.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Galeno, T.M., G.W. van Hoesen, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Brody (1984) Central amygdaloid nucleus lesion 
    attenuates exaggerated hemodynamic responses to noise stress in the 
    spontaneously hypertensive rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Brain Res. 291:249-259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Gallagher, M., P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Graham, andP.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Holland (1990) &apos;The amygdala central nucleus and 
    appetitive Pavlovian conditioning: Lesions impair one class of 
    conditioned behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Neurosci. 70:1906-1911.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Gallo, M., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Arnedo, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Agiiero, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Puerto (1990) The functional relevance of the area 
    postrema in drug-induced aversion learning.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Pharmacol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Biochcm.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Behav. 35543551.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (Pm-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Brain Kes. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Grove, E.A. (1988a) Neural associations of the 
    substantia innominata rat: Afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Neurol. 277:315346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Grove, E.A. (1988h) Efferent connections of the 
    suhstantia the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Neurol. 277:347-364.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Guyenet, P.G., and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Young (1987) Projections of nucleus 
    paragigantoccllularis lateralis to locus coeruleus and other 
    structures in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Brain Res. 406: 17 1-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Halsell, C.B. (1992) Organization of parabrachial 
    nucleus efferents to the thalamus and amygdala in the golden 
    hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Neurol. 31 7:57-78.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Hamilton, R.B., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Norgren (1984) Central projections nerves in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Neurol. 222560477.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Haroian, A.J., L.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Massopust, and P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Young (1981) Cerebellothalaniic projections in the rat: 
    An autoradiographic and degeneration study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Neurol. 197:217-236.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Haselton, J.R., and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Guyenet (1990) Ascending collaterals of medullary 
    barosensitive neurons and C1 cells in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Physiol. 258:10511063.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Hayashi, H., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Tabata (1989) Physiological properties of sensory 
    trigeminal neurons projecting to mesencephalic parabrachial area in 
    the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Neurophysiol. 67:1153-1160.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Hayashi, H., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Tabata (1990) Pulpal and cutaneous inputs t.o 
    somatosensory neurons in the parabrachial area of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Brain Res. 57 7:177-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Henke, P.G., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Ray, and R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Sullivan (1991) The amygdala: Emotions and gut 
    functions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Digest.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Diseases Sci. 36:1633-1643.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Herbert, H., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Moga, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Saper il990) Connections of the parabrachial nucleus 
    with the nucleus uf the solitary tract and medullary reticular 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Neurol. 293~540-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Herdegen, T., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Walker, d.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Leah, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Bravo, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Zimmerman (1990) The KROX-24 protein, a new 
    transcription regulating factor: Expression in the rat central 
    nervous system following afferent somatosensory stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Neuroscience Lett. 720:21-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Hermann, G.E., and R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Rogers (1985) Convergence ofvagal and gustatory afferent 
    input within the parabrachial nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Autonom.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Nerv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Syst. 13:l-17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Herrick, C.J. (1905) The centralgustatorypaths J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Neurol. 15:375456.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Hitchcock, J.M., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Davis (1986) Lesions of the amygdala, but not of the 
    cerebellum or red nucleus block conditioned fear as measured with 
    the potentiated startle paradigm.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Rehav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">I00:ll-22.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Hitchcock, J.M., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Davis (1987) Fear-potentiated startle using an auditory 
    conditioned stimulus: Effect of lesions of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Behav. 39403-408.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Hylden, J.L.K., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Anton, and R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Nahin (1989) Spinal lamina I projection neurons in the 
    rat: collateral innervation of parabachial area and thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Neuroscience 28:27-37.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Hylden, J.L.K., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Hayashi, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Bennett (1986a) Lamina I spinomesencephalic neurons in 
    the cat ascend via the dorsolateral funiculi.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Somatosens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Res. 4~31-41.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Hylden, J.L.K., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Hayashi, G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">Bennett, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Dubner (1985) Spinal lamina 1 neuruns projecting to the 
    parabachial area of the cat midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Brain Res. 336:195-198.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Hylden, J.L.K., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Hayashi, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Dubner, arid G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Bennett (1986b) Physlology and morphology of the lamina 
    I spinomesencephalic projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Neurol. 24 7:505-5 15.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Ivanova, S.F., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Bures (1990) Acquisition of conditioned taste aversion 
    in rats is prevented by tetrodoxin blockade of a small midbrain 
    region centered around the parabrachial nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Behav. 48543-549.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Iwata, J., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Chida, and J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">LeDoux (1987) Cardiovascular responses elicited by 
    stimulations of neurons in the central amygdaloid nucleus in awake 
    but not anesthetized rats resemble conditioned emotional responses, 
    Brain Rcs. 418:183-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Jhamandas, J.H., S.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Aippersbach, and K.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Harris (1991) Cardiovascular influences on rat 
    parabrachial nucleus: An electrophysiological study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">Physiol. 260:225-231.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Jiang, L.H., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Oomura (1988) Effect of catecholamine-receptor 
    antagonists on feedings-related neuronal activity in the central 
    amygdaloid nucleus of the monkey: A microiontophoretic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Neurophysiol. 60:536-548.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Kaada, B.K. (1972) Stimulation and regional ablation of 
    the amygdaloid complex with reference to functional 
    representations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">In B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Eleftheriou (ed): The Neurobiology of the Amygdala, New 
    York: Plenum, pp. 205-282.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Kalia, M., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Sullivan (1982) Brainstem projections of sensory and 
    motor components of the vagus nerve in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Neurol. 21 7r248-264.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Kapp, B.S., C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Markgraf, J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Schwaber, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Bilyk-Spafford (1989) The organization of dorsal 
    medullary projections to the central amygdaloid nucleus and 
    parabrachial nuclei in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">Neuroscience 30t717-732.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">Kerr, F.W.L. 11975) The ventral spinothalamic tract and 
    other ascending systems of the ventral funiculus of the spinal 
    cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">Neurol. 159:335-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Koliatsos, V.E., L.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Martin, and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Price (1990) Efferent organization of mammalian basal 
    forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Steriade and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Biesold (eds): Brain Cholinergic Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. 120-152.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Kruger.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">L., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Sternini, N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Brecha, and P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">Mantyh (1988) Distribution of calcitonin Gene-related 
    peptide immunoreactivity in relation to the rat central 
    somatosensory projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Neurol. 273:149-162.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Lico, M.C., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Hoffmann, and M.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Covian (1974) Influence of some limbic structures upon 
    somatic and autonomic manifestations of pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Behav. 12:805-811.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">Light, A.R., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Casale, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Sedivec (1987) The physiology and anatomy of spinal 
    laminae I and I1 neurons antidromically activated by stimulation in 
    the parabrachial region of the midbrain and pons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">In R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Schmidt, H.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Schaible, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">Vahle-Hinz (eds): Fine Afferent Nerve Fibers and Pain: 
    Weinheim, FRG: VCH, pp. 347-3.56.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Ljungdahl, A., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Hokfelt, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Nilsson (1978) Distribution of substance P-like 
    immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Cell bodies and nerve terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">Neuroscience 3:861-943.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Lumb, B.M., and J.F.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Morrison (1987) An excitatory influence of dorsolatera1 
    puntine structures on urinary bladder motility in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Brain Res. 435:363-366.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">Ma, W., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Blomqvist, and K.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Berkley (1989) Spino-diencephalic relays through the 
    parabrachial nucleus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Brain Res. 480:37-50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">Ma, W., arid M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">Peschanski (1988) Spinal and trigeminal projections to 
    the parabrachial nucleus in the rat: electron-microscopic evidene 
    of a spino-punto-amygdalian somatosensory pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Somatosens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Res. 5247-257.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">McDonald, A.J. (1982) Cytoarchitecture of the central 
    amygdaloid nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Neurol.208:401-418.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">McMahon, S.B., and P.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Wall (1985) Electrophysiological mapping of brainstem 
    projections of spinal cord lamina I cells in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Brain Res. 333: 19-26.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Mehler: W.R. (1969) Some neurological Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">N.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Sci. 167:424-468.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Mehler, W.R. (1980) Subcortical afferent connections to 
    the amygdala in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">Neurol. 190:733 762.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Menetrey, D., and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Basbaum (1987) Spinal and trigeminal projections to the 
    nucleus of the solitary tract: A possible substrate for 
    somatovisceral and viscerovisceral reflex activation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">Neurol. 255:439-450.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Menetrey, D., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">De Pommery (1991) Origins of spinal ascending pathways 
    that reach central areas involved in visceroception and 
    visceronociception in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Neurosci. 3:249-259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Miczek, K.A., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">Brykczynski, and S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Grossman (1974) Differential effects of lesions in the 
    amygdala, periamygdaloid cortex, and stria terminalis on aggressive 
    behaviors in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Psychol. 875&apos;60-771.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Milner, T.A., T.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Joh, R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Miller, and V.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Pickel (1984) Substance P, neurotensin, enkephalin, and 
    catecholamine-synthesizing enzymes: Light microscopic localizations 
    compared with autoradiographic label in solitary efferents to the 
    rat parabrachial region.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">Neurol. 226:434447.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Moga, M.M., H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Herbert, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Hurley, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Yasui, T.S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Gray, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">Saper (1990) Organization of cortical, basal forebrain, 
    and hypothalamic afferents to the parahrachial nucleus in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Neurol. 295:624-661.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Mogenson, G.J., and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">Calaresu (1973) Cardiovascular responses to elect,rical 
    stimulation of the amygdala in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Neurol. 39:166180.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Mraovitch; S., M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Kumada, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Reis (1982) Role of the nucleus parahrachialis in 
    cardiovascular regulation in cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Rrain Res. 232:57-75.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Nomura, S., N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Mizuno, K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Itoh, K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Matsuda, T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Sugimoto, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Nakamura (1979) Localization of parabrachial neurons 
    projecting to the thalamus or the amygdala in the cat using 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Ncurol. 64i4.375-385.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">Norgren, R. (1976) Taste pathways Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Neurol. l66:17-30.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">Norgren, R. (1978) Projections from the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Neuroscience, 3:207-218.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Norgren, R., and C.?</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">L Leonard (1971) Taste Science 273:1136-1139.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Norgren, R., and C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Leonard 11973) Ascending central ways.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">Neurol. 150:217-238.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Norgren, R., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Pfaffmann (1975) The pontine Brain Res. 91:99-117.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Norgren, R., and G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">Smith (1988) Central distribution of suhdiaphragmatic 
    vagal branches in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Neurol. 273:207-223.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Ogawa, H., T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">Hayama, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Ito (19871 Response properties of the 
    parahrachio-thalamic taste and mechanoreceptive neurons in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">Brain Kes. 68:449457.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">Ohman, L.E., and A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Johnson (1989) Brain stem mechanisms and the inhibition 
    of angintensin-induced drinking.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">Am. d.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">Physiol. 256:264269.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">Ottersen, O.P. (1981) Afferent connections to the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat with some observations in the cat. 
    111.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Afferents from the lower brain stem. d.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Neurol. 202:335-356.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">Ottersen, O.P., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Ben-Ari (1978) Pontine and mesencephalic afferents to 
    the central nucleus of the amygdala of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">Neurosci. 1,ett. 8:329-334.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">Panneton, W.M.: and H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">Burton (1985) Projections from the paratrigeminal 
    nucleus and the medullary and spinal dorsal horns to the 
    peribrachial area in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">Neuroscience. 25779-797.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">Pascoe, J.P., and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">Kapp (1985a) Electruphysiological characteristics uf 
    amygdaloid central nucleus neurons during Pavlovian fear 
    conditioning in the rahhil.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">Brain Res. 16:117-133.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">Pascoe, J.P., and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Kapp 1198%) Electrophysiological characteristics of 
    amygdaloid central nucleus neurons in thc awake rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Bull. 14:331-338.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Pascoe, J.P., and B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">Kapp (1987) Responses of amygdaloid central nucleus 
    neurons to stimulation of the insular cortex in awake rabbits.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">Neuroscience21:471-485.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Watson (198 he Kat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Sydney, Australia: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">Roozendaal, B., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Koolhaas, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Bohus (1990a) Differential effect of lesioning of the 
    central amygdala on the hradycardiac and behavioral response of the 
    rat in relation to conditioned social and solitary stress.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">Brain Res. 41:39-48.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Rnozendaal, R., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">Koolhaas, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">Bohus (1991a) Attenuated cardiovascular, neuruenducrine 
    and behavioral responses after a single footshock in central 
    amygdala lcsioncd male rats.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Behav. 50,771-775, Roozendaal, B., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">Koolhaas, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">Bohus (199lh) Central amygdala lesions affect bohaviiird 
    and autonomic balance during stress in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Behav. 50:777-781.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">Roozendaal, B., W.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">Oldenburger, J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Struhbe, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">Koolhaas, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">Bohus (1990b) The central amygdala is involved in the 
    conditioned hut not in the meal-induced cephalic insulin response 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">Lett. 116:210-215.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Rosen, J.B., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">Dams ( 1990) Enhancement of electrically elicited 
    startle hy amygdaloid stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Behav. 48:343-349.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Russchen, F.T. (1982) Amygdalopetal projections in the 
    caL. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">Suhwrtical afferent connections: A study with retrograde 
    tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">J Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">Neurol. 207: 157-176.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Saper, C.R., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections of the parahrachial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">Brain Res. 197r291-317.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">Saxon, D.W.; and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">Hopkins (1990) Brainstem connections of the 
    paratrigeminal islands in thc rat: a fluorescent tracer study with 
    tetraniethylerhodamine dextran and fluorogold.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">Soc Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Ahstr. 16:223.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">Schwaber, J.S., C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">Sternini.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">Brecha, W.T.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Rogers, and J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">Card 11988) Neurons containing calcitonin gene-related 
    peptide in the parahrachial nucleus project to the central nucleus 
    of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Neurol. 270:416426.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">Shapiro, K.E., and K.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">Miselis 11985) The central neural connections of the 
    area postrema of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">Neurol. 234:344-364.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">Shihata, K., Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">Kataoka, K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Yamashita, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">Ueki (1986) An important role of the central amygdaloid 
    nucleus and mamillary body in the mediation of conflict behavior in 
    rats.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">Brain Res. 372159-162.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">Skofitsch, G., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">Jacobowitz (1985) Calcitonin gene-related peptide.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">Detailed immunohistochemical distribution in the 
    central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Peptides 6:721-745.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">Slugg, R.M., andA.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">Light (1990) Physiology and morphology of nociceptive 
    and thermoreceptive parabrachial neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Abstr. 16: 1144.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">Torvik, A. (19563 Afferent connections to the sensory 
    trigeminal nuclei, the nucleus of thc. solitary tract and adjacent 
    structures: An experimental study in t,he rat. d.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">IOfi:51-141.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">Travers, J.B., S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">Travers, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Norgren (1987) Gustatory processing in the 
    hindbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Neurosci. 10:595-632.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">der Kooy, D.. and L.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Koda (1983) Organization of the projections of a 
    circumventricular organ: The area postrema in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">Neurol. 219:328-338.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">Voshart, K.. and D. van der Kooy 11981) The 
    organization of the efferent projections of the parahrachial 
    nucleus to the forebrain in the rat: A retrograde fluorescent 
    double-laheling study.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Brain Res. 212:271-286.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Wainer, B I&amp;lt;., and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Mesulam (1990) Ascending cholinergic pathways in the 
    rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Steriade and D.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">Biesold (edl: Brain Cholinergic Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. fi5-119.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">Ward.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">D.G. (1988) Stirnulatiori uf the parabrachial nuclei 
    with monosodium glutamate increases arterial pressure.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Brain Rcs. 462383-390.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Ward, D.G. (1989) Neurons in the parahrachial nuclei 
    respond to hemorrhage.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">Brain Res. 491:80-92.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">Wiberg, %I., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Blomqvist f 1984) The spinomesencephalic tract in the 
    cat. its cells of origin and termination pattern as demonstrated by 
    the intraaxonal transport method.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Brain Re&amp;lt;. 291:1-18.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Wiberg, M., J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Westman, and il.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Blomqplst (19871 Somatosensory projection to the 
    mesencephalon: an anatomical study in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Neurol. 264:92-117.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">Woulff, J.M., U.A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Flumerfelt, and A.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">Mrycyshyn (1990) Efferent connections of the A1 
    nuradrcncrgic cell group: A DBH immunohistochemical and PHA-L 
    antcrograde tracing study.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Keurol. 109:308 322.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">Wray, S., and G.E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">Hoffman (1983) Organization and interrelationship of 
    neuropeptides in the central amygdaloid nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Peptides 4:525-54 1.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">Yamano, M., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">Hillyard, S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">Girgis, P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">Emson, I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Macintyre, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Tohyama (1988aJ Projection of neurotensin-like 
    immunoreactive neurons from the lateral parabrachial area to the 
    central amygdaloid nucleus of the rat with refcrence to the 
    Coexistence with calcitonin gene-related peptide.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1064">Brain Res. 71:603%fi10.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1065">Yamano, M., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1066">Ilillyard, S.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1067">Girgis, 1.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1068">Macintyre, P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1069">Emson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1070">Tohyama (1YS8bi Presence of a substance P-like 
    immrinoreactive neurone system from the parahrachial area to the 
    central amygdalnid nucleus of the rat with reference to coexistence 
    with calcitonin generelated peptide.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1071">Brain Res. 451,179-188.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1072">Yasui, Y., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1073">Saper, and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1074">Cechetto (1991) Calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP3 
    Immunoreactive projections from the thalamus to the striatum and 
    amygdala in the rat J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1075">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1076">Neurol. 308:293-310.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1077">Zemlan, F.P., C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1078">Leonard, L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1079">Kow, and U.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1080">Pfaff (1978) Ascending tracts of the lateral column of 
    the rat spinal cord: A study using silver impregnation and 
    horseradish peroxidasc tcchnique.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1081">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1082">Neurol. 62298 334.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1083">Zhang.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1084">J.X., K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1085">Harper, and R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1086">Frysinger (1986) Respiratory modulation of neuronal 
    discharze in the central nucleus of the amygdala during sleep and 
    waking states.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1087">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1088">Neurol. 91:193-207.</S>
  </References>

</File>

