<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Origin of Spinal Projections to the Anterior and Posterior 
  Lobes of the Rat Cerebellum</Title>

  <Authors>SABINA BERRETTA, VINCENZO PERCIAVALLE, AND RICHARD E. 
  POPPELE</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The present study was carried out to analyze the 
    topography of spinal projections to the anterior and posterior 
    lobes of the cerebellum and to investigate whether projections to 
    the two lobes come from different spinocerebellar neurons or from 
    branching axons of the same cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">We used orthograde transport of horseradish peroxidase 
    conjugated with wheat germ agglutinin (WGA-HRP) to identify the 
    cerebellar areas where spinocerebellar axons terminate and 
    retrograde double-labeling techniques to estimate the incidence of 
    spinocerebellar neurons projecting to both anterior and posterior 
    lobes via axon collaterals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Orthograde labeling confirmed that the rat, like other 
    mammalian species, has spinocerebellar projections to two different 
    regions of cerebellar cortex, i.e., lobules I-V of the anterior 
    lobe and lobule VIII of the posterior lobe, with the highest 
    incidence in lobules 11,111, and VIII.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">We did not observe a clear difference in the distribution 
    of afferents coming from different spinal segments to either of the 
    two lobes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The double-labeled cells were located primarily in the 
    lower thoracic and upper lumbar segments, almost exclusively in 
    Clarke&apos;s column and in the dorso-lateral part of lamina 7 (in 
    the region of the spinal border cells).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">It is likely that most or all of the spinocerebellar 
    neurons in these structures project to both anterior and posterior 
    lobes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Therefore, the two lobes of the cerebellum are likely to 
    receive common information from these cells, but different 
    information from the separate populations of spinocerebellar 
    neurons that project only to one lobe or the other.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">It has been well demonstrated that information carried by 
    spinocerebellar systems reaches two different regions of 
    paleocerebellar cortex in several mammalian species, namely, 
    lobules I-V of the anterior lobe and lobule VIII of the posterior 
    lobe (Snyder et al., &apos;78; Matsushita and Ikeda, &apos;80, 
    &apos;81; Klinkachorn and Culberson, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Electrophysiological experiments have shown that the 
    response patterns of Purkinje cells to passive hind-foot rotations 
    are different in these two cerebellar areas (Perciavalle et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">However, it is not yet known whether the spinocerebellar 
    projections to the two cerebellar lobes arise from different 
    neurons or from neurons which send axon branches to both lobes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">A recent study of the projections to anterior and 
    posterior lobes in the cat examined spinocerebellar neurons in the 
    lower lumbar and sacral segments, and found very few cells 
    projecting to both cerebellar areas (Xu and Grant, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The present investigation examines this possibility 
    further for spinocerebellar projections from the entire spinal cord 
    in the rat by using orthograde transport of horseradish peroxidase 
    conjugated with wheat germ agglutinin (WGAHRP) to identify the 
    cerebellar areas reached by spinocerebellar fibers and the 
    retrograde double-labeling techniques to identify and quantify the 
    incidence of spinocerebellar neurons projecting to both areas via 
    axon collaterals.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s13">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Experiments were carried out on 21 male Wistar rats (200 
    to 280 g) deeply anesthetized with urethane (Sigma; 1.2 
    g/kgi.p.).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s15">Methods for orthograde 
    labeling</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Twelve rats were given hydraulic injections of a 4% 
    solution of WGA-HRP dissolved in 0.9% saline through glass 
    micropipettes with 40-60 pm tips connected to a 1 pl Hamilton 
    syringe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">The assembly was inserted into the spinal cord under 
    microscopic guidance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Injections of 40-50 nl were made unilaterally into 
    several cord levels: cervical (3 cases; Cl-C2, C2-C4, and C5-C6), 
    cervico-thoracic (1 case; C8-T2), thoracic (2 cases; Tl-T2 and 
    T7-T8), thoracolumbar (2 cases; I ll-L1 and T12-L3), lumbar (2 
    cases; L2-L5 and L3-L5 I , lumbo-sacral(1 case; L5-S2) and sacral 
    (1 case; Sl-S3).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Each area was exposed by laminectomy of the two adjacent 
    vertebrae and particular care was taken to control a possible 
    spread of enzyme in the subarachnoid space.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">All animals in which spread was detected were excluded 
    from the analysis.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">After a 3-4 day survival period, the rats were 
    reanesthetized with urethane and perfused sequentially with 500 ml 
    of 0.9% saline at 42 C, 500 ml of 1.25% gluteraldehyde-1% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) at room 
    temperature, and 500 ml of an ice-cold 10% sucrose solution in 0.1 
    M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">The brains and injected spinal cord sections were removed 
    and placed in the same 10% sucrose and phosphate buffer at 4°C 
    until sectioned.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Frozen sections (20 pm) were cut, collected in 0.1 M pH 
    7.4 phosphate buffer, processed with tetramethylbenzidine (Sigma) 
    and incubated with hydrogen peroxide, according to the method of 
    Mesulam ( 78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Sections through the injection site were treated with 
    benzidine dihydrochloride (Sigma) according to the protocol of 
    Mesulam ( 76) in order to determine the core uptake area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">This method reduces the axonal labeling characteristic of 
    the tetramethylbenzidine method and thus does not blur the limits 
    of the injection sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">The sections were transferred into a sodium acetate 
    buffer solution at 4°C and mounted on glass slides coated with 
    chrome alurn.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">To facilitate the identification of cytoarchitectonic 
    details, half of the sections processed for HRP were counterstained 
    with 1% neutral red (pH 4.81, while the other half were left 
    uncounterstained to reduce the loss of reaction product.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Finally, all sections, counterstained or not, were 
    dehydrated with ethanol, cleared with xylene, and covered using 
    Entellan (Merck) and glass coverslips.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The slides were examined with both brightand darkfield 
    illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Crossed polarizers were placed in the light path to 
    produce an intensified image of reaction products.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The effective uptake areas were considered as the zones 
    surrounding the HRP injection sites where deposition of 
    reaction-product was very dense and where individual labeled axons 
    and perikarya could not be detected (Horton et al., 79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The pattern of orthogradely transported label, judged by 
    conventional criteria (Mesulam, 821, was plotted on camera lucida 
    drawings of the sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">In cases of uncertainty, i.e., fine dust-like label which 
    might represent either terminal labeling or fibers cut in 
    cross-section, the areas were examined with high magnification 
    (1,188~) to identify possible terminal ramifications.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Photographs were taken of salient features.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s35">Method for 
    double-labeling</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">We used two different protocols for double-labeling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">In the first, five animals were given hydraulic 
    injections of two fluorescent tracers: the cytoplasmic tracer Fast 
    Blue (FB; 2 ~ 1 3% , w/v, Sigma) and the nuclear tracer Diamidin0 
    Yellow dihydrochloride (DY; 2 ~ 1 2% , w/v, Sigma; Kuypers et al., 
    80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">In three rats, FB was injected unilaterally in the 
    anterior lobe and DY ipsilaterally in the posterior lobe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">In two other rats the DY was injected anterior and the FB 
    posterior.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">In the second protocol, four rats were injected with a 
    fluorescent tracer, Fluoro Gold (FG; Schmued and Fallon, 86) and a 
    non-fluorescent and non-diffusible retrogradely transported marker, 
    colloidal gold (Au) conjugated with wheat germ agglutin 
    (WGA)-enzymatically inactive horseradish peroxidase (apoHRP) 
    complex (WGAapoHRP-Au; Basbaum and Menetrey, 87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Gold particles approximately 10-12 km in diameter were 
    prepared according to Muhlpfordi s ( 82) protocol by treating 100 
    ml of cholroauric acid (Sigma; 0.01% w/v in distilled water) with 
    reducing agents (2 ml sodium citrate and 0.1 ml tannic acid, each 
    1% wiv in distilled water).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Liophilized WGAapoHRP (Sigma) was coupled to the 
    colloidal gold according to the procedure of Basbaum and Menetrey ( 
    87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Briefly, the gold solution was added to diluted 
    (WGAapoHRP (1 mg protein per ml distilled water) and stirred.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">After 5 minutes, filtered polyethylene glycol (MW 20,000; 
    Sigma) was added in a proportion of 1% (v/v) and the complex was 
    centrifuged for 120 minutes at 18,000 rpm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">The supernatant was aspirated and discarded and a soft 
    10-15 ~1 pellet containing WGAapoHRP-Au complex was ready for 
    injection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The FG (Fluorochrome) was dissolved in distilled water 
    (4% v/v).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">In two rats, FG was injected unilaterally in the anterior 
    lobe and WGAapoHRP-Au in the posterior.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">In the other two animals the injection sites were 
    reversed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The injections were made by pressure through glass 
    micropipettes cemented to a 5 ~1 Hamilton syringe inserted 
    according to the stereotaxic coordinates of Paxinos and Watson s 
    atlas ( 86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">After a 5-7 day survival period the rats were 
    reanesthetized with urethane and perfused according to the protocol 
    described above for the HRP studies.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The brains and spinal cords were removed and placed 
    overnight in the same ice-cold 10% sucrose in phosphate buffer 
    solution and then for 3-4 days in a 30% sucrose in phosphate buffer 
    solution at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Sagittal (brain) and transverse (spinal cord) frozen 
    sections (30 pm) were cut and mounted on glass slides coated with 
    chrome alum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Half the slides were counterstained with 1% neutral red 
    and all were dehydrated, cleared and covered as described above.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The sections were analyzed using an Axioplan microscope 
    (Zeiss) with brightand darkfield illumination as well as 
    fluorescent emission.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Labeled cells in the spinal cord were drawn on camera 
    lucida outlines and the number in each spinal area was counted.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The boundaries of the injection sites in the cerebellum 
    were traced using a 2 . 5 ~ objective.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The fluorescent injection areas had two concentric 
    fluorescent zones around the needle track.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The uptake of tracers by terminals and damaged fibers 
    appears to occur only in the inner zone (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Huisman et al., 82, 83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Injected areas were quantitatively evaluated by adapting 
    the method of Wolf and Gollob ( 80).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s61">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s62">Orthograde labeling 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63"><exptLabel>Hydraulic injections of 
    <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> solution in 
    <injectionLocation>the spinal cords of 12 
    rats</injectionLocation></exptLabel> were distributed from 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the upper cervical to lower sacral 
    levels</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64"><labelingDescription>Orthogradely labeled 
    axons</labelingDescription> from each level of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the spinal cord</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    entered <neuroanatomicalLocation>the restiform 
    body</neuroanatomicalLocation> and 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>brachium 
    conjunctivum</neuroanatomicalLocation> to reach 
    <connxTermination>the cerebellar cortex</connxTermination> with 
    <labelingDescription>dense terminal labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the medial parts of the anterior and posterior 
    lobes</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s65">In general, we found that 
    <labelingLocation>anterior lobules I1 through V and posterior 
    lobule VIII</labelingLocation> contained 
    <labelingDescription>labeled terminals</labelingDescription> from 
    every major spinal cord level.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s66"><labelingDescription>The 
    densest terminal labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation
    >the cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> was found following 
    injections that included <injectionLocation>the lumbar spinal 
    segments</injectionLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">Projections from the rostral cord segments were less 
    dense and some injections failed to label terminals in the most 
    medial areas (e.g., rat3; see below).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Labeled terminals from all injection sites were confined 
    to within 2 mm of the midline (see Table 1).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Figure 1 shows <exptLabel>an experiment (rat 
    7)</exptLabel> in which the enzyme injection involved nearly 
    <injectionLocation>all of laminae 3-7 of Rexed (&apos;54) in the 
    lower thoracic and upper lumbar segments 
    (Tll-L2)</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s70"><labelingDescription>Heavy 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> was present in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial parts of lobules I through V of the 
    anterior lobe (&amp;amp;lt; 1 mm from the midline) and in lobule 
    VIII of the posterior lobe</labelingLocation> (cf. Larsell, 
    &apos;52).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s72">Between 1 and 2 mm from the 
    midline, we found <labelingDescription>labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> only in <labelingLocation>lobule 
    VIII</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>no 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found more laterally.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Morphological features of the orthogradely labeled 
    terminations are illustrated in Figure 2, which shows typical mossy 
    fiber terminals in the granule layer.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Beginning with <injectionLocation>the most rostral spinal 
    segments (Cl-C4</injectionLocation>, e.g., <exptLabel>rats 
    1,2</exptLabel>; Table 11, injections of enzyme produced 
    <labelingDescription>a small number of labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    parts of lobules I, 11, 111, and V of the anterior lobe and in 
    lobules VTI, VIII, and IX of the posterior 
    lobe</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s75"><labelingDescription>A few 
    labeled terminals</labelingDescription> were also detected in 
    <labelingLocation>lobules IV and V between 1 and 2 mm from the 
    midline</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Injections that included <injectionLocation>lower 
    cervical segments (C5-C6</injectionLocation>; <exptLabel>rat 
    3</exptLabel>) yielded <labelingDescription>very few labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    areas</labelingLocation> which were detectable only in 
    non-counterstained sections.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s77"><labelingDescription>More 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was detected laterally (between 1 
    and 2 mm), but only in <labelingLocation>lobule VIII of the 
    posterior lobe</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">When the injection included <injectionLocation>the upper 
    thoracic levels (C8-T2</injectionLocation>; <exptLabel>rat 
    41</exptLabel>, there was <labelingDescription>more 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>lobules 11, 
    111, V and VIII</labelingLocation> which was primarily between 1 
    and 2 mm from the midline.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Injections confined to <injectionLocation>the upper 
    thoracic level (Tl-T2</injectionLocation>; <exptLabel>rat 
    5</exptLabel>) produced <labelingDescription>a similar pattern of 
    labeling</labelingDescription> between 1 and 2 mm from the midline 
    and also a <labelingDescription>moderate number of labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    parts of lobules I1 and 111</labelingLocation>, and 
    <labelingDescription>to a lesser degree</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>lobules IV and V</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Injections that included <injectionLocation>the middle 
    thoracic segments (T7-T8</injectionLocation>; <exptLabel>rat 
    6</exptLabel>) labeled only <labelingDescription>a few 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>lobules I1 and 
    VIII</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s81">As 
    indicated in Table 1, injections involving <injectionLocation>the 
    lower thoracic and upper lumbar levels (Tll-L3</injectionLocation>; 
    <exptLabel>rats 7,8</exptLabel>) produced <labelingDescription>the 
    heaviest labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s82">In these 
    experiments, <labelingLocation>the anterior lobe (lobules 
    I-V)</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>labeled 
    medially</labelingDescription> and <labelingLocation>the posterior 
    lobe (lobule VIII)</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>more 
    laterally</labelingDescription> (Fig. 1).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="ArialMT"
     id="s83">When <injectionLocation>the middle lumbar 
    segments</injectionLocation> were injected (<injectionLocation
    >L2-L5</injectionLocation>; <exptLabel>rats 9,lO</exptLabel>) 
    <labelingDescription>dense labeling</labelingDescription> was found 
    <labelingLocation>in the medial parts of both anterior and 
    posterior lobes</labelingLocation> with <labelingDescription>the 
    heaviest labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
    lobules 11, 111, and VIII</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="ArialMT"
     id="s84">Injections covering <injectionLocation>the lower lumbar 
    and upper sacral segments (rat 11; L5-S2)</injectionLocation> also 
    produced <labelingDescription>heavy labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the more medial parts of lobules I1 and 
    I11</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>a small amount of 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>lobule 
    VIII</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingDescription>The few labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> detected with injections of 
    <injectionLocation>the lower sacral cord</injectionLocation> 
    (<exptLabel>rat 12</exptLabel>; SlS3) were also in <labelingLocation
    >the medial parts of lobules 11, I11 and 
    VII</labelingLocation>I.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s95">Retrograde 
    double-labeling experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">Figures 3 and 4 illustrate the results obtained in two 
      of the nine rats in which two retrograde tracers were used.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97"><exptLabel>In one (rat 14)</exptLabel>, 
      <tracerChemical>FB</tracerChemical> was injected in 
      <injectionLocation>the left anterior lobe</injectionLocation> and 
      <tracerChemical>DY</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
      left posterior lobe</injectionLocation> (Fig. 3).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98">In the other (<exptLabel>rat 20</exptLabel>), 
      <tracerChemical>WGAapoHRP-Au</tracerChemical> was injected in the 
      <injectionLocation>left anterior lobe</injectionLocation> and 
      <tracerChemical>FG</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
      left posterior lobe</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">The two sets of tracers gave comparable results.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100"><injectionLocation>The anterior 
      lobe</injectionLocation> injections <labelingDescription>labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>laminae 4-8 
      and 10 (Rexed, &apos;54) of the cervical, thoracic, lumbar, and 
      sacral spinal cord</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">In <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the upper cervical levels 
      ((2144)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were generally found in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral central cervical 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102"><labelingDescription>Fewer cells</labelingDescription> 
      were labeled in <labelingLocation>the C5-T6 
      segments</labelingLocation> and they were mainly within 
      <labelingLocation>laminae 5 and 7 on the ipsilateral 
      side</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103"><labelingLocation>Middle thoracic levels 
      (T5-T9)</labelingLocation> showed <labelingDescription>very few 
      labeled cells</labelingDescription>, in agreement with our 
      finding that orthograde labeling of these segments produced 
      <labelingDescription>very few labeled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      cerebellum</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">In <labelingLocation>the lower thoracic and lumbar 
      segments</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were <labelingDescription>very 
      numerous</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>laminae 
      4-7</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105"><labelingDescription>The maximal incidence of 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was in <labelingLocation>
      Clarke&apos;s columns</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>
      the dorso-lateral parts of lamina 7</labelingLocation> with a 
      slight prevalence on the ipsilateral side.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">In <labelingLocation>Clarke&apos;s 
      column</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were <labelingDescription>medium 
      and small elongated cells</labelingDescription>, while in 
      <labelingLocation>the doso-lateral part of lamina 
      7</labelingLocation>, they were <labelingDescription>large round 
      neurons</labelingDescription> with clearly labeled dendrites.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">In <labelingLocation>the sacral cord 
      segments</labelingLocation> there were only 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled cells</labelingDescription> 
      located in <labelingLocation>laminae 5 and 7</labelingLocation>, 
      mainly within <labelingLocation>the contralateral sacral nucleus 
      of Stilling</labelingLocation> (Snyder et al., &apos;78).</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Between 55% and 70% of labeled cells in each section 
    were labeled with tracer from <labelingLocation>the anterior 
    lobe</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">The distribution of cells which were retrogradely 
    labeled by tracer injected into <injectionLocation>the posterior 
    lobe</injectionLocation> was very similar to that described above 
    for anterior lobe tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">However, as noted, the incidence of labeled cells from 
    <labelingLocation>the posterior lobe</labelingLocation> was always 
    lower.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">A significant fraction of the double-labeled neurons, 
    i.e., neurons projecting to <connxTermination>both anterior and 
    posterior lobes</connxTermination>, were found bilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>Clarke&apos;s column</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsolateral part of lamina 7 in the 
    thoraco-lumbar segments</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3,4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">The only other double-labeled cells were the few that 
    were found in <labelingLocation>upper cervical 
    segments</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">In the <labelingLocation>thoracolumbar 
    segments</labelingLocation>, double-labeling in each section ranged 
    between 13% and 40% of the labeled cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">In <labelingLocation>Clarke s columns and the 
    dorsolateral parts of lamina 7</labelingLocation> their incidence 
    was between 40 and 50% of the labeled cells with the FB and DY 
    tracers (Fig. 3) and between 50 and 70% with the WGAapoHRP-Au and 
    FG (Fig. 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">Examples of double-labeled cells in these areas are 
    illustrated in Figure 5 (left: Clarke s column; right: Spinal 
    border).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">Table 2 summarizes the results obtained in the 9 rats 
    used for the double-labeling study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">It shows that with the FG and WGAapoHRP-Au tracers we 
    were able to detect about twice as many double-labeled cells as 
    with the other tracers (average of about 19% of the total labeled 
    cells compared with about 10% for the other two tracers).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">The FB, DY tracers consistently labeled more cells from 
    the anterior injection site regardless of which of the two tracers 
    was injected there.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">The WGAapoHRP-Au, however, seemed to be less effective 
    than the FG in labeling cells in <labelingLocation>either anterior 
    or posterior lobe</labelingLocation> (compare rats 18,19 with 
    20,21, for example), but the differences could be readily accounted 
    for by the smaller volume of tissue infused with the colloidal 
    tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">With these small differences taken into account, the 
    results in 9 rats with 4 different tracer combinations were all 
    consistent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">Figure 6 summarizes the data in Table 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">It shows that more cells are 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled</labelingDescription> in 
    every spinal segment from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the anterior 
    lobe</neuroanatomicalLocation> than from 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the posterior 
    lobe</neuroanatomicalLocation> and that cells projecting to both 
    <connxTermination>the anterior and posterior 
    lobes</connxTermination> are confined primarily to <connxOrigin>the 
    lower thoracic and upper lumbar spinal segments</connxOrigin>.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s123">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">In all mammalian species studied thus far, 
    spinocerebellar fibers are found to project to lobules I-V of the 
    anterior lobe and lobule VIII of the posterior lobe (Snyder et al., 
    &apos;78; Matsushita and Ikeda, &apos;80, &apos;81; Klinkachorn and 
    Culberson, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">We observed the same pattern in the rat, where the 
    densest spinocerebellar projections are in lobules 11,111, and 
    VIII.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">Moreover, we were unable to demonstrate a difference in 
    the rostral-caudal distribution of projections from different 
    spinal segments in either of the two lobes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">Orthograde tracer injections into different spinal cord 
    levels each produced terminal labeling in nearly the same cortical 
    areas, with no demonstrable segregation in rostralcaudal extent and 
    only a small difference medio-laterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">For example, projections from T2-T4 to lobule VIII are 
    found in the more lateral parts, between 1 and 2 mm from the 
    midline, whereas those from T12-L2 are found more medially (see 
    Table 1).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">In contrast with earlier electrophysiological studies in 
    the cat which suggested a clear rostral-caudal separation between 
    forelimb and hindlimb portions to the cerebellar cortex (Oscarsson, 
    &apos;73), this study is consistent with more recent data (e.g., 
    Leicht and Schmidt, &apos;77) which suggest there may be a 
    substantial convergence of projections from various somatotopic 
    areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">Such convergence would allow Purkinje cells associated 
    with a particular movement to receive information concerning a 
    large peripheral area, which may play a role in the 
    cerebellum&apos;s contribution to motor coordination.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">The double-labeling experiments showed that the 
    projections to the anterior and posterior lobes arise primarily 
    from different neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">Double-labeled neurons were found almost exclusively 
    within Clarke&apos;s column and the dorsolateral part of lamina 
    7.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Outside of these structures nearly every spinocerebellar 
    neuron exhibited a single label.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">Between 40% and 70% of the neurons in the lower thoracic 
    and upper lumbar levels of Clarke&apos;s column, which contribute 
    to the dorsal spinocerebellar tract, and of the neurons in the 
    dorso-lateral part of lamina 7 (the spinal border cells; Cooper and 
    Sherrington, &apos;401, which contribute to the ventral 
    spinocerebellar tract, were retrogradely labeled from both anterior 
    and posterior lobes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">The clear and consistent differentiation of a population 
    of cells that were double-labeled implies that the double-labeling 
    observed was not artifactual, for example, not due to the labeling 
    of fibers of passage projecting to the anterior lobe with the 
    posterior label.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">If that were the case, we would expect to see a similar 
    percentage of double-labeling in other spinocerebellar neurons as 
    well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">We did find, however, that the WGAapoHRP-Au + FG labeled 
    almost twice as many doubly projecting neurons as did the FB + DY 
    labeling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">This difference may be due to the more intense 
    dye-leaching of the latter tracers (Skirboll et al., &apos;84) and 
    thus the percentage of branching projections may be more accurately 
    indicated by the gold tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">It seems reasonable that the greatest percentage of 
    double-labeling represents a lower limit on the actual incidence of 
    branching spinocerebellar neurons since the tracer cannot reach 
    every afferent axon.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">Therefore, the results reported here suggest that most, 
    if not all, of the spinocerebellar neurons in these two nuclei 
    project to both anterior and posterior lobe targets, while most or 
    all of the spinocerebellar neurons outside these nuclei and outside 
    the central cervical nucleus project separately to either the 
    anterior lobe or to the posterior lobe.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">The possible functional significance of this arrangement 
    is not clear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">However, it is reasonable to suppose that since the 
    majority of the spinocerebellar projections to the anterior or 
    posterior lobe are from separate neurons, these two parts of the 
    cortex may receive qualitatively and/or quantitatively different 
    information and consequently may operate in a different manner.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">In support of this view, we recently reported that 
    responses to passive hind foot rotations of Purkinje cells located 
    in the anterior and posterior lobes of the cat cerebellum were 
    qualitatively different (Perciavalle et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">From a functional point of view it would be interesting 
    to know what role the branching projections play in supplying 
    identical information to these two areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">It would also be of interest to know if the outputs from 
    these two cortical areas converge on the same cerebellar nuclear 
    cells or if there are also separate neuronal populations at the 
    nuclear level.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s146">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s147">We thank Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s148">Rosario Giuffrida for 
    suggesting the use of Fluoro Gold together with the WGAapoHRP-Au 
    for the double-labeling studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s149">This research was partly 
    supported by grants from the Minister0 della Pubblica Istruzione 
    and the National Institutes of Health, NS 21143.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s150">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Basbaum, A.I., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Menetrey (1987) Wheat germ agglutinin-apoHRP gold: A new 
    retrograde tracer for lightand electronmicroscopic singleand 
    double-label studies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">Neurol. 261:306-318.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Cooper, S., and C.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">Sherrington (1940) Gower s tract and spinal border 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Brain 63:123-134.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Horton, J.C., M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">Greenwood, and D.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Hubel (1979) Non-retinotopic arrangement of fibers in 
    cat optic nerve.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">Nature282.720-722.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">Huisman, A.M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Kuypers, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Verburgh (1982) Differences in collateralization of the 
    descending spinal pathways from red nucleus and other brain stem 
    cell groups in cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">In H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">Kuypers and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Martin (eds): Descending Pathways to the Spinal Cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Progress in Brain Research.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Amsterdam: Elsevier, vol. 57, pp. 185-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">Huisman, A.M., H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Kuypers, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">CondB, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">Keizer (1983) Collaterals of rubrospinal neurons to the 
    cerebellum in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">A retrograde fluorescent double labeling study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Brain Res. 2641181-196.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Klinkachorn, P.S., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Culberson (1988) Cerebellar projection fields of spinal 
    cord segments in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Neurosci. 202.5 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Kuypers, H.G.J.M., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Bentivoglio, C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Catsman-Berrevoets, and T.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Bharos (1980) Double retrograde labeling through 
    divergent axon collaterals using two fluorescent tracers with the 
    same excitation wavelength which label different features of the 
    cell.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">40:383-392.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Larsell, 0. (1952) The morphogenesis and adult pattern 
    of the lobules and fissures of the cerebellum ofthe white rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Neurol. 97.281-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Leicht, R., and R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Schimdt (1977) Somatotopic studies on the vermal cortex 
    of the cerebellar anteriol lobe of unanaesthetized cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Brain Res. 27:479490.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Matsushita, M., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Ikeda (1980) Spinocerebellar projections to the vermis 
    of the posterior lobe and the paramedian lobule in the cat, as 
    studied by retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Neurol. 192: 143-162.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Matsushita, M., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Ikeda (1981) Spinocerebellar projections to lobules I 
    and I1 of the anterior lobe in the cat, as studied by retrograde 
    transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Neurol. 197:411-424.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Mesulam, M.M. (1976) The blue reaction product in 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: Incubation tochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Cytochem. 24:1273-1280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Mesulam, M.M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue 
    reaction-product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural 
    derents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Cytochem. 26: 106-1 17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Mesulam, M.M. (1982) Principles of horseradish 
    peroxidase neurochemistry and their application for tracing neural 
    pathways-axonal transport enzyme histochemistry and light 
    microscopic analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">In M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Mesulam (ed): Tracing Neural Connections With 
    Horseradish Peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">New York Wiley, pp. 1-152.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Muhlpfordi, H. (1982) The preparation of colloidal gold 
    particles using tannic acid as an additional reducing agent.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Experientia 38:1127,1128.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Oscarsson, 0. (1973) Functional organization of 
    spinocerebellar paths.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Iggo (ed): Handbook of Sensory Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Vol. 11, Somatosensory System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 339-380.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates 
    (Second Edition).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Perciavalle, V., R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Poppele, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Shen (1989) Responses of Purkinje cells in anterior and 
    posterior cerebellar lobules to hindlimb rotation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Neurosci. 245r13 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Rexed, B. (1954) A cytoarchitectonic atlas of the spinal 
    cord in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Neurol. 100.297-379, Schmued, L.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Fallon (1986) Fluoro-Gold: A new fluorescent retrograde 
    axonal tracer with numerous unique properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s239">377~147-154.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Skirboll, L., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Hokfelt, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Norell, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Phillipson, H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Kuypers, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Bentivoglio, C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Catsman-Berrevoets, T.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Visser, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Steinbush, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Verhofstad, A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Cuello, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Goldstein, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Brownstein (1984) A method for specific transmitter 
    identification in retrogradely labeled neurons: Immunofluorescence 
    combined with fluorescence tracing.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Brain Res. 8:49-127.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Snyder, R.L., R.M.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Faull, and W.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Meheler (1978) A comparative study of the neurons of 
    origin of the spinocerebellar fierents in the rat, cat and squirrel 
    monkey based on the retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Neurol. 181333-852.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Wolf, G., and H.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Gollob (1980) Quantitative Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Behav. 24:1195-1199.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Q., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Grant (1988) Collateral projections of neurons from the 
    lower part of the spinal cord to anterior and posterior cerebellar 
    termination areas.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">A retrograde fluorescent double labeling study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Brain Res. 72r562-576.</S>
  </References>

</File>

