<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Are There Connections Between the Thalamic Reticular Nucleus 
  and the Brainstem Reticular Formation?</Title>

  <Authors>D.J. BERRY, P.T. OHARA, G. JEFFERY, AND A.R. 
  LIEBERMAN</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Increasing awareness that the thalamic reticular nucleus 
    (TRN) plays an important role in controlling the output of 
    cortically projecting cells in nuclei of the dorsal thalamus has 
    focused attention on the question of whether there exist ascending 
    projections to the TRN from the mesencephalic or other parts of the 
    brainstem reticular formation (BRF).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">We have examined this and the related question of whether 
    the neurons of TRN project to the BRF, by anterograde and 
    retrograde tracing experiments with horseradish peroxidase (HRP) 
    and HRP conjugated to wheat germ agglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Injections of tracer were placed stereotaxically in the 
    BRF at various depths and rostrocaudal and mediolateral 
    coordinates, and the TRN and adjacent nuclei were examined in 
    serial coronal sections, using tetramethylbenzidine as the 
    principal chromogen.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Retrogradely labelled cell bodies were consistently seen 
    in hypothalamus and zona incerta but never in TRN, suggesting that, 
    in the rat, TRN neurons do not project caudal to the thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">After 54 out of 60 injections, no terminal label was 
    detected in any part of the TRN although such label was present in 
    other parts of the thalamus, including the intralaminar nuclei, in 
    the same sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">We therefore conclude that direct projections from the BRF 
    to the TRN must be extremely sparse, and that those effects of BRF 
    stimulation upon thalamocortical transmission that are mediated by 
    the TRN (rather than by direct projections to dorsal thalamic 
    nuclei) probably depend chiefly on indirect polysynaptic 
    pathways.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">It has long been believed that the brainstem reticular 
    formation (BRF) is involved in determining states of 
    consciousness.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Moruzzi and Magoun ( 49) stimulated the BRF of encephale 
    isole cats and found that this evoked a change in the 
    electroencephalogram (EEG) from a pattern of highvoltage slow waves 
    to one of low-voltage fast waves.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">This desynchronization of the EEG was found to duplicate 
    the change in the EEG obtained on arousal (for reviews and 
    references see Rossi and Zanchetti, 57; Singer, 77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Directly related to cortical desynchronization is 
    facilitation of transmission through the thalamic relay nuclei 
    (see, for example, Steriade, 70; Singer, 77).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The subset of neurons that brings about these effects on 
    the EEG afbr stimulation of the BRF has been termed the ascending 
    activating system.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">It has long been thought that the thalamic reticular 
    nucleus (TRN) has an important role in this system, and for many 
    years it was believed that the TRN represented the final common 
    pathway of the ascending system from the BRF to the cerebral cortex 
    (Jasper, 49).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Now, however, it is known that the TRN projects to the 
    dorsal thalamus and that there is no direct projection from the TRN 
    to cerebral cortex (Minderhoud, 71; Jones, 75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Nevertheless, a role for the TRN in determining the 
    pattern and extent of cortical activity remains very probable, for 
    it has been shown in a number of studies that projections from the 
    TRN to the dorsal thalamus exert an inhibitory effect on 
    thalamocortical projection cells (e.g., Schlag and Waszak, 
    &apos;71; Frigyesi and Schwartz, &apos;72; Waszak, &apos;74; French 
    et al., &apos;841 and thus, indirectly, on the activity of cortical 
    neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The last few years have also seen the accumulation of 
    much additional information about the organization of the TRN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Evidence for the inhibitory effect of neurons in the TRN 
    on thalamocortical projection cells has been supported by 
    anatomical evidence that the axons of these cells (reticulothalamic 
    axons) terminate by establishing Gray type 2 (symmetrical) synapses 
    with the dendrites of thalamocortical projection cells (Ohara et 
    al., &apos;80; Montero and Scott, &apos;81; Peschanski et al., 
    &apos;83) and by immunohistochemicaI evidence that the transmitter 
    at these endings is GABA mouser et al., &apos;80; Ohara et al., 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">It is also now established from both physiological and 
    anatomical studies that reticulothalamic neurons are 
    monosynaptically excited by thalamic and cortical inputs, both 
    almost certainly in the form of collaterals of thalamocortical and 
    corticothalamic projection cells (Schlag and Waszak, &apos;71; 
    Ohara and Lieberman, &apos;81, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">In addition, it is also now apparent that the 
    reticulothalamic projections may be more highly organized than 
    would appear to be the case from the studies of Scheibel and 
    Scheibel(&apos;66) and Jones (&apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Thus small injections of horseradish peroxidase (HRP) or 
    fluorescent tracers into the dorsal thalamus label only small 
    patches of adjacent neurons in the ipsilateral TRN (O&apos;Connell 
    et al., &apos;82, rat; Frassoni et al., &apos;84, rat; Steriade et 
    al., &apos;84, cat), suggesting that such cells project discretely 
    to the small regions of dorsal thalamus from which they receive 
    input.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In the light of findings such as these, and of evidence 
    that the activity of TRN neurons is closely linked to the firing 
    pattern of thalamocortical projection cells, it can now be accepted 
    as established that although the circuitry may be very different 
    from that originally envisaged, the TRN does indeed influence 
    cortical physiology, functioning as part of a feedback circuit by 
    which thalamocortical cell activity is regulated.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">But there remains the question of the precise nature of 
    the relationship between the TRN and the BRF.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">There is some anatomical evidence for projections from 
    the BRF to the TRN (e.g., Scheibel and Scheibel, &apos;58; Shute 
    and Lewis, &apos;67; Edwards and De Olmos, &apos;76; Kromer and 
    Moore, &apos;80; Robertson and Feiner, &apos;82; Mackay-Sim et al., 
    &apos;83; Cropper et al, &apos;84; Peschanski and Besson, 
    &apos;841, but the evidence is sparse and not entirely satisfactory 
    (see Discussion).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The physiological evidence is more extensive and supports 
    more strongly than the anatomical evidence the existence of 
    projections, but it is no less difficult to interpret.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">There are several studies that strongly suggest that in 
    the cat there is a direct input to the TRN from the mesencephalic 
    reticular formation (MRF) that is both inhibitory and cholinergic 
    (Ben-hi et al., &apos;76; Dingeldine and Kelly, &apos;77; Godfraind 
    and Veraart, &apos;781, and evidence such as this leads to the 
    conclusion that the facilitation of thalamocortical transmission 
    underlying cortical arousal following BRF stimulation depends upon 
    a disinhibition of the thalamocortical projection cells brought 
    about by ascending input from the BRF to the TRN that reduces the 
    inhibitory output of the latter (Singer, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Plausible though this suggestion may be (Fig. lA), there 
    are other data that suggest that the facilitatory effects of BRF 
    stimulation may be mediated by direct excitatory inputs to 
    thalamocortical projection cells (Kayama et al., &apos;82) (Fig. 
    lB), or by disinhibition involving intrathalamic inhibitory 
    interneurons (e.g., Fukuda and Iwama, &apos;71) (Fig. 1C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Furthermore, the anatomical evidence fur direct 
    projections from the BRF to the specific nuclei of the dorsal 
    thalamus is more extensive and less open to doubts than is the 
    evidence for direct projections to the TRN (e.g., Kromer and Moore, 
    &apos;80; Pasquier and Villar, &apos;82; Ahlsen and Lo, &apos;82; 
    Hughes and Mullikin, &apos;84, Sofroniew et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The present study, undertaken against this confused and 
    uncertain background, is an attempt to establish if projections 
    from the BRF to the TRN are present in the rat, and if so to 
    determine their origins more precisely.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">A second question we were interested in clarifying is 
    that of whether there are projections from TRN that descend caudal 
    to the diencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Axons extending from the TRN to the midbrain are 
    described by Scheibel and Scheibel(&apos;66) in Golgi material from 
    various species, by Grofova et al. (&apos;78) on the basis of 
    retrograde HRP labelling studies in the cat, and by Parent and 
    Steriade (&apos;84) on the basis of electrophysiological and 
    retrograde labelling studies in cat and squirrel monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">On the other hand, Minderhoud (&apos;71), in experimental 
    degeneration studies in the rat, Jones (&apos;79, in 
    autoradiographic studies in various species after injection of 
    labelled amino acids into the TRN, and others in retrograde HRP 
    labelling studies (Morel1 et al., &apos;81; Shammah-Lagnado et al., 
    &apos;83; Frassoni et al., &apos;84) found no such projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">We have employed anterograde and retrograde tracing 
    methods, using both HRP and HRP conjugated to wheat germ 
    agglutinin, to examine these questions in adult albino rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">A preliminary report of the findings has been published 
    (Berry et al., &apos;83).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s33">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s34">Animals</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Albino rats of the Wistar strain, 170-200 g in weight, 
    were used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">In thirty-five of these animals injections of HRP or of 
    HRP conjugated with wheat germ agglutinin (WGAHRP) were made into 
    various parts of the BRF.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Five animals were used to prepare reference series of 
    coronal sections stained to show the presence of 
    acetylcholinesterase (AChE).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s38">Injection procedures</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s39">
    The rats were lightly anaesthetized with ether and placed in a 
    David Kopf small-animal stereotaxic frame.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s40">
    Deep anaesthesia was then induced and maintained with either a 
    mixture of halothane, nitrous oxide, and oxygen or an 
    intraperitoneal injection of Chlor-Nembutal (3.0 ml/kg of 2.1 g 
    chloral hydrate and 0.5 g sodium pentabarbital in 50 ml of water) 
    or of chloral hydrate alone.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s41">A 
    total of 60 injections (ten unilateral or midline and 50 bilateral) 
    were made into the brainstem of the thirty-five animals.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s42">
    Forty-one injections were with HRP and 19 with WGA-HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s43">In 
    33 injections HRP (Sigma type VI) was used as a 15% solution in 
    TRIS buffer and was injected by iontophoresis using stereotaxically 
    positioned micropipettes with tip diameters of 50-70 pm and 
    currents of 5-15 pA over periods of 2.5-5 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s44">
    Eight injections of HRP (0.1 pl of 30% HRP in normal saline) were 
    made by using a pressure system and a stereotaxically positioned 
    1-pl Hamilton microsyringe with an outside diameter of 1 mm.</S>
    <S avgH="31" class="methods.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s45">
    Nine of the WGA-HRP injections were made iontophoretically by using 
    a 3% sohA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">tion of WGA-HRP in TRIS buffer, stereotaxically 
    positioned micropipettes with tip diameters of 50-70 pm, and 
    currents of 5-15 pA for 2.5-5 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">The other ten injections were of 10% (six injections) and 
    4% (four injections) WGA-HRP in TRIS buffer with a pressure 
    ejection system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s48">Preparation of tissue</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Twenty-four to 48 hours after injection, animals were 
    again deeply anaesthetized (with ether) and killed by transcardiac 
    perfusion of 50 ml of 0.1 M phosphate buffer followed by 200 ml of 
    a solution of 1% glutaraldehyde and 1% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer (pH 7.3; room temperature).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The brains were removed and stored in fresh fixative 
    solution for 5-12 hours at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Brains to be cut on the freezing microtome were stored in 
    0.1 M phosphate buffer containing 20% sucrose overnight at 4°C 
    prior to sectioning.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Serial coronal sections 50 pm thick were cut on a 
    freezing microtome with solid carbon dioxide as a refrigerant or in 
    a Vibratome (Oxford Instruments) and were collected in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Alternate sections were processed by using 
    diaminobenzidine (DAB) or tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) as chromogens 
    (LaVail and LaVail, &apos;74; Mesulam, &apos;78) and mounted on 
    gelatinized slides.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Some sections treated with TMB were counterstained with 
    neutral red and DAB sections were counterstained with cresyl 
    violet.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">In some experiments only TMB was used and alternate 
    sections were counterstained with neutral red.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The slides were coverslipped and examined by light 
    microscopy in both brightfield and darkfield illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Sections treated with DAB and TMB were used to identify 
    the injection sites and the extent of spread of the HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Labelling of cell bodies, fibres, and terminals at levels 
    rostral to the superior colliculus was assessed only in TMB 
    sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The results were recorded on line drawings of frontal 
    sections of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Special attention was paid to the area of, and adjacent 
    to, the TRN, where labelling was recorded in detail with the aid of 
    a camera lucida.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The atlases of Pellegrino et al. (&apos;671, Konig and 
    Klippel (&apos;63), and Paxinos and Watson (&apos;82) were used.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s62">AChE staining</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The animals were perfused as described above.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Serial coronal sections of the brains, 25 pm thick, were 
    cut on a freezing microtome and stained for AChE according to 
    Hanker et al. (&apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Some sections were counterstained with cresyl violet.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The boundaries of the TRN were traced from these series 
    of sections with a camera lucida.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="25" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s67">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Injections were placed throughout <injectionLocation>the 
    brainstem</injectionLocation>, from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    medulla</neuroanatomicalLocation> caudally to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the midbrain</neuroanatomicalLocation> at 
    the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> rostrally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Although many injections were centred on nuclear groups 
    which have been implicated as possible sources of ascending 
    projections to <connxTermination>the TRN</connxTermination> 
    (viz.<neuroanatomicalLocation>locus coeruleus, raphe nuclei, 
    nucleus cuneiformis, and other parts of the 
    MRF</neuroanatomicalLocation>) few parts of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the BRF and MRF</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    were not included within at least some injection sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">The coordinates used for the injections are summarized in 
    Table 1 and representative injection sites into 
    <injectionLocation>the MRF</injectionLocation> at the level of 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, into <injectionLocation>the 
    periaqueductal gray PAG</injectionLocation>) at the level of 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the inferior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, into <injectionLocation>the 
    lateral BRF</injectionLocation> at the level of 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the facial nerve 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and into the midline at the 
    level of transition between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>pons and 
    midbrain</neuroanatomicalLandmark> are shown in Figure 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Further details of the structures included within 
    individual injection sites are given where appropriate in the 
    text.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">For convenience of description, the findings are 
    presented in three groups according to the rostrocaudal level of 
    the injections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s74">Injections into the MRF 
    at the level of the superior colliculus</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s75"><exptLabel>Thirteen injections-ten of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> and three of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> were placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the MRF at the level of the superior 
      colliculus</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s76">Sections treated with DAB showed that the diffusion 
      zone extended ventrally beyond <injectionSpread>the deepest layer 
      of the superior colliculus (stratum album 
      profundum)</injectionSpread> in all 13 injections, involved the 
      MRF in eight injections and <injectionSpread>the 
      PAG</injectionSpread> in three out of 13 injections (Figs. 2A, 
      3).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s77">In TMB sections the diffusion zone included 
      <injectionSpread>the MRF and adjacent PAG</injectionSpread> in 
      every case.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s78">One centrally placed injection included both 
      <injectionLocation>rostral dorsal raphe and raphe 
      medianus</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79">Figure 5 summarises the pattern of diencephalic 
      labelling in one experiment following an injection very similar 
      to the one depicted in Figure 3.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80">These findings and the findings from all other animals 
      in this group are summarised in Table 1.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81">Labelling within <labelingLocation>the 
      TRN</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82"><labelingDescription>No labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were observed within <labelingLocation
      >the TRN</labelingLocation> after any injections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s83"><labelingDescription>Sparse fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      TRN</labelingLocation> was seen after three injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in three different 
      animals.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s84">All of these injections were centred at approximately 
      <injectionLocation>the midrostrocaudal level of the superior 
      colliculus</injectionLocation> and in every case involved 
      <injectionSpread>deep superior colliculus (to the level of the 
      stratum album profundum) and the dorsal MRF</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85">In every case the labelled fibres ran diagonally and 
      roughly horizontally from <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      ventrolateral part of the ventral 
      thalamus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, through
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the TRN</neuroanatomicalLocation>, to 
      enter <connxTermination>the internal capsule</connxTermination> 
      laterally.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86"><labelingDescription>The fibres were 
      sparse</labelingDescription> and confined to <labelingLocation>
      the ventral part of the caudal TRN</labelingLocation> (A/p t 3.9 
      to A/P +4.1), just dorsal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      junction of the latter with the zona incerta 
      (ZI)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> as determined by comparison of TMB 
      treated sections with AChE-stained sections cut at the same level 
      (Fig. 4).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="50" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s87">
      <labelingDescription>Sparse terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>
      TRN</labelingLocation> was seen after five injections-two of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> and three of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone.</S>
      <S avgH="50" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s88">The 
      injection sites involved both <injectionLocation>dorsal and 
      ventral levels in the MRF</injectionLocation> and included none 
      of the injections after which <labelingDescription>sparse fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>
      TRN</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="50" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s89">The 
      terminal label consisted of fine granules of reaction product 
      over the neuropil and cell islands of <labelingLocation>the 
      caudal half of the TRN</labelingLocation> (ALP +3.9 to A/P +4.6) 
      in the interstices of the fibre bundles running between 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>thalamus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>internal 
      capsule</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="50" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s90">In 
      all five 2 cases there was evidence of leakage of HRP into 
      <injectionSpread>the cerebral cortex</injectionSpread> from the 
      pipette track, and in four of the five cases there were labelled 
      cell bodies in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral dorsal lateral 
      geniculate nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">Labelling in other sites. (1) After almost every 
      injection, <labelingDescription>cell, fibre, and terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen within <labelingLocation>
      the ZI</labelingLocation> (Table 1, Fig. 5).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93"><labelingDescription>Terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation>, the lateral boundary of which was defined 
      by the AChE technique (Fig. 41, was most obvious in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal part of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingDescription>labelled 
      cell bodies</labelingDescription> were seen predominantly in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral half of the 
      ZI</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94"><labelingDescription>Cell body 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was granular in nature and 
      extended into the dendrites to reveal that many of the labelled 
      cells were bipolar with processes emerging at either end of an 
      elongate soma (Fig. 6).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">In most cases it was apparent that 
      <labelingDescription>heavily labelled cells</labelingDescription> 
      within <labelingLocation>the ZI</labelingLocation> were arranged 
      as two bands parallel to one another and to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the dorsal edge of the crus 
      cerebri</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> were seen throughout 
      <labelingLocation>the ZI</labelingLocation> running parallel with 
      the cells in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      half</labelingLocation> and forming a plexus in <labelingLocation>
      the dorsal half</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">This plexus consisted of fibres running horizontally, 
      and perpendicular to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial border 
      of the medial lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98">In <labelingLocation>the area H1 of Forel s 
      field</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the horizontally 
      running fibres</labelingDescription> passed dorsally into 
      <labelingLocation>the medial thalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Labelling disappeared from <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation> approximately one-third of the distance 
      along the caudorostral axis of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      TRN</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">(2) In all but two cases,<labelingDescription>terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was observed within 
      <labelingLocation>the intralaminar nuclear complex (nucleus 
      medialis thalami, pars lateralis of Konig and Klippel, 
      63)</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5, 7) (Table 1).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">(3) In all but two cases, in one of which labelling 
      was <labelingDescription>generally weak</labelingDescription>, 
      <labelingDescription>labelled cell bodies</labelingDescription> 
      were present within <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5, 8) (Table 1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">Such <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> 
      were located in <labelingLocation>both the posterior and middle 
      groups of hypothalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> as described by 
      Christ ( 69).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">(4) In most cases, <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> could be seen running vertically and 
      dorsomedially through <labelingLocation>the ventral lateral 
      geniculate nucleus and dorsal lateral geniculate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral part of the ventral lateral geniculate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> in several cases.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s105">Injections into the PAG 
    and caudal MRF</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106"><exptLabel>Eight injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> and two of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> were placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the PAG</injectionLocation></exptLabel> at 
      levels between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the caudal superior 
      colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
      the inferior colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and in all 
      cases the diffusion zone around the site of the injection 
      extended into <injectionSpread>the medial part of the adjacent 
      MRF</injectionSpread> (Figs. 2B, 9).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">Four injections of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> were made into 
      <injectionLocation>the lateral MRF</injectionLocation>, and one 
      into <injectionLocation>the midline</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">In the anteroposterior dimension the injections 
      extended from the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the caudal 
      superior colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to the level of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the caudal inferior 
      colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Table 1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">Four injections were made into <injectionLocation>the 
      most caudal part of the PAG</injectionLocation> and into its 
      caudal extension, <injectionLocation>the periventricular 
      gray,</injectionLocation> at approximately the midlevel of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the locus 
      coerulus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>: two of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone, two of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">The diffusion zones of the midline injection (Fig. 2D) 
      and of the two most medial and rostral injections into 
      <injectionLocation>the pons</injectionLocation> involved 
      <injectionLocation>the dorsal raphe nucleus and nucleus raphe 
      medianus</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">Diencephalic labelling following this group of 
      injections is summarised in Table 1 and Figure 13 shows the 
      labelling pattern on the left side in the case of the experiment 
      illustrated in Figure 2D.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">Labelling within <labelingLocation>the 
      TRN</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113"><labelingDescription>No cell, fibre, or terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was observed within 
      <labelingLocation>the TRN</labelingLocation> after any of these 
      injections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">In Figure 10 <labelingDescription>the absence of 
      label</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      TRN</labelingLocation> may be contrasted with 
      <labelingDescription>the adjacent terminal 
      labe1</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the thalamic 
      ventrobasal complex</labelingLocation> following the injection 
      illustrated in Figure 2D, which involved <injectionLocation>a 
      substantial caudorostral extent of the raphe nuclei (including 
      raphe medianus) and adjacent parts of the MRF and 
      BRF</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Labelling in other sites.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">In nine cases <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsal ZI</labelingLocation> (Table 1) passing rostromedially 
      toward <labelingLocation>the medial thalamus</labelingLocation> 
      through <labelingLocation>the fields of Forel</labelingLocation>, 
      in which <labelingDescription>fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen after 11 injections.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117"><labelingDescription>Terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      intralaminar nuclei</labelingLocation> after 14 injections (Table 
      1, Figs. 11, 13) and sporadically in <labelingLocation>the ZI and 
      lateral geniculate nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118"><labelingDescription>Cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was found consistently in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsocaudal part of the 
      ZI</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>to a lesser 
      extent</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the central 
      part of the ZI</labelingLocation> along its entire rostrocaudal 
      length (Table 1, Figs. 12,13).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119"><labelingDescription>Cell bodies</labelingDescription> 
      were labelled in <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> after 17 of the 19 injections 
      (Table 1).</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s120">Injections into the 
    pontomedullary reticular formation</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><exptLabel>Twenty-eight injections were made into 
      <injectionLocation>the pontomedullary reticular 
      formation</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, seven with 
      <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">Injection sites (e.g., Fig. 2C) ranged from 
      <injectionLocation>the midline to the lateral 
      BRF</injectionLocation> and from <injectionLocation>the most 
      rostral part of the facial nucleus</injectionLocation> to 
      <injectionLocation>the inferior cerebellar 
      peduncle</injectionLocation>, and were at a range of heights such 
      that <injectionLocation>both ventral and dorsal 
      BRF</injectionLocation> were included in the injections (Table 
      1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">One injection of 
      <tracerChemical>WGAHRP</tracerChemical> was centered on 
      <injectionLocation>the locus coeruleus</injectionLocation> and 
      the diffusion zone of HRP in DAB-treated sections after two other 
      injections included <injectionSpread>the locus 
      coeruleus</injectionSpread> (Fig. 14).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">Six midline injections involved <injectionLocation>the 
      nucleus raphe magnus</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">Seven injection tracks passed through <injectionSpread>
      the brachium conjuctivum</injectionSpread>, and the larger of 
      these injections produced a diffusion zone that extended to 
      <injectionSpread>the spinal tract of the trigeminal 
      nerve</injectionSpread> in TMBtreated sections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">Six injections were made at the level of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the inferior cerebellar 
      peduncle</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">The findings for this group of injections are 
      summarized in Table 1 and Figure 16 shows the pattern of 
      diencephalic labelling for an experiment in which the injection 
      site (HRP alone) was in <injectionLocation>the 
      pons</injectionLocation> caudal to the level of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the inferior 
      colliculi.</neuroanatomicalLandmark></S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128">Labelling in <labelingLocation>
      TRN</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129"><labelingDescription>No 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen within <labelingLocation>
      the TRN</labelingLocation> except for <labelingDescription>very 
      sparse terminal labelling</labelingDescription> within 
      <labelingLocation>the most rostral part of TRN</labelingLocation> 
      after the <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> injection 
      centred on <injectionLocation>the locus 
      coeruleus</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130">Labelling in other sites.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131"><labelingDescription>Fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation> in 19 cases and in <labelingLocation>the HI 
      area of the fields of Forel</labelingLocation> in nine cases 
      (Table 1, Fig. 16).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
      fibres</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation> passed medially and dorsally within 
      <labelingLocation>the field of Forel H1</labelingLocation> toward 
      <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 15, 16).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133"><labelingDescription>Sporadic fibre 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was also seen in <labelingLocation
      >the lateral geniculate nuclei and 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, and in the case of three 
      injections that involved <injectionSpread>the locus 
      coeruleus</injectionSpread> <labelingDescription>sparse terminal 
      label</labelingDescription> was seen within <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsal and ventral lateral geniculate 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134">In 17 cases <labelingDescription>terminal 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was also seen within 
      <labelingLocation>the intralaminar nuclei</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 16), in eight cases in <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation>, and in six cases in <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135"><labelingDescription>Cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was found in only two sites: 
      <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus (ten cases) and the 
      21</labelingLocation> (ten cases).</S>
    </TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s136">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s137">question of descending 
    efferents from TRN</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s138">to the brainstem</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">Scheibel and Scheibel ( 66) reported that in their Golgi 
    material (chiefly rodent brains) 20% of all axons of TRN neurons 
    could be traced to the mesencephalic tegmentum, where they were 
    lost among the cells of the MRF.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">These findings are difficult to evaluate because Golgi 
    material is not ideal for tracing axonal projections and because 
    the Scheibels relied heavily on very young animals in which the 
    spread of axonal arbors of TRN neurons may have been more extensive 
    than in adult animals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Nevertheless, support for such a projection has emerged 
    from more recent experimental studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">Thus Grofova et al. ( 78) have reported that labelled 
    cells are consistently found in the TRN of cats, following 
    injection of HRP into the deep layers of the superior colliculus, 
    into the PAG, and into the MRF.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">More recently, Parent and Steriade ( 84) have reported 
    antidromic activation of cells in the TRN of cats following 
    electrical stimulation of the MRF, and retrograde cell labelling in 
    the rostra1 pole and lateral part of TRN in cats and squirrel 
    monkeys, following injection of HRP or fluorescent tracers in the 
    MRF, and in the posteroventral part of the TRN following injection 
    into the superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">These authors also present evidence, based on double 
    labelling experiments with fluorescent dyes injected into both MRF 
    and dorsal thalamus, that the axons projecting to the MRF do not 
    arise, for the most part, from the same neurons that send axons to 
    the dorsal thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">However, other data in the recent literature raise 
    doubts about the extent and ubiquity of axonal projections from the 
    TRN to the MRF.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">Thus in an earlier study Steriade et al. ( 82) also made 
    HRP injections into the MRF of cats but found very few labelled 
    cells in the TRN: they concluded that the projection described by 
    Grofova et al. ( 78) must be directed chiefly to the PAG, which had 
    not been included in their injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">This conclusion, however, seems not to be entirely in 
    keeping with the findings of Grofova et al. ( 781, who did indeed 
    find labelled cells in the TRN after injections into the PAG, but 
    concluded that the projections to the MRF were stronger.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Furthermore, Mantyh ( 82) found few if any labelled 
    cells in the TRN of cat, rat, or monkey following small injections 
    of HRP confined to the PAG.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">In other recent HRP studies, no labelled cells were 
    found in the TRN of rats after injections into a number of MRF 
    sites (Morrell et al., 81; Shammah-Lagnado et al., 83; Frassoni et 
    al., 84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">Finally, in other experimental studies, Minderhoud ( 71) 
    found no retrograde changes in TRN neurons of rat following large 
    lesions of the midbrain and no terminal degeneration in the latter 
    after lesions of the TRN, while Jones (&apos;75) found no sign of 
    terminal label caudal to the thalamus following injections of 
    labelled amino acids into the TRN in cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Thus a considerable body of previously published work, 
    and our own findings, are difficult to reconcile with other 
    evidence favouring the existence of a substantial descending 
    projection from the TRN to the midbrain (or to more caudal levels 
    of the brainstem).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Since most of the evidence in favour of the existence of 
    such projections derives from studies on cats and monkeys (Grofova 
    et al., &apos;78; Parent and Steriade, &apos;84) whereas many of 
    the negative findings reported relate to work on rodents 
    (Minderhoud, &quot;71; Morel1 et al., &apos;81; Shammah-Lagnado et 
    al., &apos;83; Frassoni et al., &apos;84; present study), it would 
    seem reasonable to suppose that there may be differences between 
    species in the organization of efferents from the TRN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s153">The question of 
    afferents to the TRN from the BRF</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">The evidence for projections from the BRF to the TRN is 
    extensive and some of it reasonably strong.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">One of the most widely cited studies is that of Edwards 
    and De Olmos (&apos;76), who reported terminal labelling in the TRN 
    of the cat after injection of tritiated leucine into the nucleus 
    cuneiformis, a nucleus of the MRF that has also been identified in 
    the rat (Valverde, &apos;621, and described as the &quot;deep 
    mesencephalic nucleus&quot; by others (Veazey and Severin, 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">The findings of Edwards and De Olmos (&apos;76) have 
    been influential because they fit very well with histochemical 
    evidence for an AChE-rich projection arising from the nucleus 
    cuneiformis and extending to or through the TRN (Shute and Lewis, 
    &apos;67; Hoover and Jacobowitz, &apos;79), with 
    immunohistochemical evidence for cholinergic cell bodies in the 
    mesencephalic (and pontine) tegmentum (Armstrong et al., &apos;83) 
    and for projections from such cells to the thalamus (Sofroniew et 
    al, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">These findings are also consonant with 
    electrophysiological and pharmacological evidence for the existence 
    of a cholinergic inhibitory input to the TRN from the midbrain in 
    the cat (Ben-Ari et al., &apos;76; Dingeldine and Kelly, 
    &quot;77).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">There is also evidence for projections to the TRN from 
    more caudal levels of the BRF.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Scheibel and Scheibel (&apos;58), in one of the earliest 
    studies providing anatomical evidencc for such projections, 
    reported that axons of neurons in thc BRF at the level of the 
    caudal pons, and in the rostra medulla (magnocellular medullary 
    area), reached the TRN There is also evidence for a noradrenergic 
    input to the TRN from the locus coeruleus: Kromer and Moore 
    (&apos;80) reported that ascending noradrenergic axons from the 
    locus coeruleus in the rat displayed terminallike varicosities 
    within the caudal TRN, adjacent to the lateral geniculate nucleus, 
    and noradrenergic axons within the TRN have also been identified by 
    Lindvall et al. (&apos;74) and Swanson and Hartman (&apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">We found no terminal labelling in this part of the TRN 
    and sparse terminal label was identified only in the rostra1 part 
    of the TRN after an injection of WGA-HRP centred on the locus 
    coeruleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">No terminal or fibre labelling was seen in the TRN after 
    any of the injections involving raph6 nuclei, although a serotonin 
    input to the TRN from the raph6 nuclei has also been described 
    (Chan-Palay, &apos;77; Moore et al., &apos;78; Cropper et al., 
    &apos;841, which, according to Bobillier et al. (&apos;76), in the 
    cat arises only in the nucleus raph6 pontis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">More recently Peschanski and Besson (&apos;84) have 
    demonstrated sparse anterograde labelling in the TRN following 
    iontophoretic injections of 10% WGA-HRP into the nucleus raph6 
    medianus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">However, it is not clear from the data presented whether 
    the label identified in the TRN was in fibres of passage or in 
    terminals, and the possibility that the label may have been 
    transneuronal will be considered below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Finally, Robertson and Feiner (&apos;82) reported sparse 
    fibre and terminal labelling in the ventral TRN (extending into the 
    ZI and fields of Forel) after injections of tritiated leucine into 
    the pontine BRF in the cat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">All of the above findings have been made with 
    anterograde labelling methods: there are also some important data 
    based on retrograde labelling studies, the interpretation of which, 
    however, is bedevilled by the shape and size of the TRN, which 
    makes it difficult to be certain that injections centred on the TRN 
    result in labelling of only axom terminating in this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Recently, Mackay-Sim et al. (&apos;83) have reported on 
    the results of making small injections of HRP and WGA-HRP into the 
    visual portion of the TRN of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">They found sparse cell labelling in the deep, lateral 
    MRF, in the PAG, and in the dorsal tegmental nucleus, but, 
    curiously, not in the locus coeruleus (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Kromer and Moore, &apos;80) or raphe (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Cropper et al., &apos;84; Peschanski and Besson, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">It is also relevant to point out that Ahlsen and Lo 
    (&apos;82) have presented evidence for the existence, in the cat, 
    of a projection from the MRF and raphe nuclei to the perigeniculate 
    nucleus (PGN).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">The latter nucleus is a thin sheet of cells and neuropil 
    overlying the lateral geniculate nucleus intercalated between the 
    latter and the TRN, and regarded by some authors as a specialized 
    protion of the TRN with specifically visual system associations 
    (e.g., Szentagothai, &apos;72; Singer, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Small injections of HRP into the PGN produced labelled 
    cells in the deep MRF at the border between midbrain and pons 
    (Ahlsen and Lo &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">Our findings, however, are difficult to reconcile with 
    these results, and indicate that there are few, if any, major 
    direct projections from the brainstem reticular core to the TRN in 
    the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">In only six out of 60 injections was convincing terminal 
    label seen in the TRN, and such labelling was sparse.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">One of these injections was into locus coeruleus 
    (WGA-HRP) and produced sparse terminal label in the rostral TRN 
    (see comments above).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">The other five involved injections at the level of the 
    superior colliculus, with injection tracks traversing the occipital 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Since other injections at the same or similar 
    rostrocaudal coordinates did not result in terminal labelling in 
    the TRN we consider that the five positive cases are better 
    explained either as the result of spread of HRP to the pretectal 
    region and nucleus of the optic tract (Weber and Harting, &apos;80; 
    Holstege and Collewijn, &apos;82), or as the result of leakage of 
    HRP within the cerebral cortex with subsequent labelling of 
    collaterals to the TRN of corticofugal axons (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Jones, &apos;75; Ohara and Lieberman, &apos;79, 
    &apos;81), than as evidence for a projection to the TRN from this 
    part of the midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">The presence of labelled cell bodies in the dorsal 
    lateral geniculate nucleus in four of these five cases supports the 
    latter interpretation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">This general conclusion is consistent with several other 
    studies, notably those of Veazey and Severin (&apos;801, Sotgiu et 
    al. (&apos;811, and Frassoni et al. (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Sotgiu et al. (&apos;81) found no cell labelling in any 
    part of the BRF after injection of HRP into various regions of TRN 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Veazey and Severin (&apos;80), working with rats, 
    injected tritiated leucine into what they refer to as the deep 
    mesencephalic nucleus, pars lateralis (equivalent to the lateral 
    MRF in the present study and including the region of the MRF 
    containing labelled cells in the study of Mackay-Sim et al. 
    (&apos;83)) and observed no terminal labelling within the TRN: 
    furthermore, they also refer to a single experiment in which 
    injection of HRP into the TRN was not followed by cell labelling in 
    the deep mesencephalic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Frassoni et al. (&apos;84) found no anterograde 
    labelling in the rat TRN after injection of HRP into the 
    brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">There are other degeneration and autoradiographic 
    studies in the cat and rat that reinforce these negative findings 
    (e.g., Chi, &apos;70; Bowsher, &apos;75).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The disagreements in the anatomical literature as to 
    whether the TRN receives an input or inputs from the BRF, and if so 
    from precisely where, are very considerable.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">We believe that it is impossible to explain the 
    discrepancies in terms of species differences, and difficult to 
    reconcile them in terms of differences in the sites injected in the 
    various anterograde and retrograde tracing experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Although there is a natural tendency for positive 
    findings to weigh more heavily than negative ones, the evidence for 
    such projections rests most heavily on three studies: the 
    autoradiographic study of anterogradely labelled terminals after 
    injections of tritiated leucine in the cat MRF by Edwards and De 
    Olmos (&apos;76); the anterograde tracing study of Peschanski and 
    Besson (&apos;84) with WGA-HRP and the retrograde HRP (WGA-HRP) 
    transport study of Mackay-Sim et al. (&apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">So far as the study of Edwards and De Olmos (&apos;76) 
    is concerned, (1) Jones (&apos;81) has already drawn attention to 
    the possibility that spread of injected label to the pretectal 
    region-which projects to the TRN in the cat (Berman, &apos;77bmight 
    complicate interpretation of their findings, and (2) the 3H-leucine 
    injections of Veazey and Severin (&apos;80) and our HRP and WGA-HRP 
    injections in the rat certainly included the region of the MRF 
    corresponding to the nucleus cuneiformis.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Peschanski and Besson (&apos;84) used 10% WGA-HRP in 
    their injections of the raphe nuclei and the animals were allowed 
    to survive for 48 hours.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">The propensity for WGA-HRP to be transneuronally 
    transported is now well documented, and given the high 
    concentration of WGA-HRP and the long survival time used by 
    Peschanski and Beson ( 84) it seems to us possible that at least 
    some of the diffuse label found throughout much of the thalamus in 
    their study may have been transneuronal in origin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">None of our four injections into the raphe medianus 
    resulted in terminal or fibre labelling in TRN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Why Mackay-Sim et al. ( 83) were able to label cells in 
    the PAG, MRF, and dorsal tegmental nucleus while Veazey and Severin 
    ( 80), Sotgiu et al. ( 811, we, and others have failed to find 
    evidence for such projections is not clear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Mackay-Sim et al. ( 83) consider but discount the 
    possibility that the labelling they obtained might be due to spread 
    of injectate beyond the confines of the visual TRN-for example, to 
    the dorsal lateral geniculate nucleus-for they found no labelling 
    in the retina, optic tract, or brachium of the superior colliculus 
    after such injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">However, they do not adequately dispose of the question 
    of possible labelling of damaged axons of passage in a region of 
    the brain where such possibilities cannot be readily discounted, 
    and it is relevant to point out that in similarly designed studies 
    of the brainstem projections to the PGN in the cat, Ahlsen and Lo ( 
    82) were unable to be certain that the PGN could be injected 
    without involvement of the superficial part of the subjacent 
    lateral geniculate nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The existence of a body of experimental anatomical 
    evidence for projections from the BRF to the TRN, supported by 
    physiological evidence for effects on TRN neurons and on 
    thalamocortical transmission of BRF stimulation (e.g., Singer, 77), 
    reinforces the general uncertainty associated with negative 
    findings in a study such as this.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Nevertheless, we believe that our findings merit serious 
    consideration, not only because of some of the conflicts and 
    weaknesses in the antecedent literature (reviewed above), but also 
    in view of the facts that (1) we used sensitive tracing methods 
    (HRP and WGA-HRP with TMB); (2) the injections were large, some 
    were placed specifically in the regions thought to give rise to 
    ascending derents to the TRN, and in total covered a large 
    proportion of the BRF; and (3) the presence of terminal labelling 
    in areas of the diencephalon other than the TRN codirmed that 
    absence of label in the latter was unlikely to be due to general 
    technical factors.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">We are therefore led to conclude that, in the rat, 
    direct ascending pathways from the BRF to the TRN are absent or at 
    best extremely sparse.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">We suggest that if the physiological effects on cortical 
    activity of brainstem stimulation are mediated by the TRN rather 
    than by direct routes to dorsal thalamic nuclei (Introduction) or 
    to the cortex itself, then such effects must depend primarily upon 
    indirect, polysynaptic pathways to the TRN.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s199">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s200">We thank the Medical Research 
    Council and Wellcome Trust for financial support, M.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s201">Gilbert and A.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s202">Meier for printing the 
    photographs, K.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s203">Wiedemann for drawing Figure 
    1, and s.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s204">Thomsen, s.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s205">Jayasuriya, and s.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s206">Lester for secretarial 
    help.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s207">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Ahlsen, G., and F-S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Lo (1982) Projection of brainstem neurons to the 
    perigeniculate nucleus and the lateral geniculate nucleus in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Brain Res. 238:433-438.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Armstrong, D.M., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Saper, A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Levey, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Wainer, and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Terry (1983).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Distribution of cholinergic neurons in rat brain 
    demonstrated by the immunocytochemical localization of choline 
    acetyltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Neurol. 21653-68.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">Ben-Ari, Y., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Dingledine, I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Kanazawa, and J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">Kelly (1976) Inhibitory effects of acetylcholine on 
    neurones in the feline nucleus reticularis thalami.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">(Lond.) 261.647-671.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Berman, N. (1977) Connections of the pretectun 
    174:227-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Berry, D.J., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Jeffery, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Lieberman, and P.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Ohara (1983) Relationships between the thalamic 
    reticular nucleus and the brainstem reticular formation in the r a 
    t A retrograde and anterograde tracing study using horseradish 
    peroxidase (HRP) and wheat germ agglutinin-HRP (WGAHRP). 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">(Lond.) 34154P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Bobillier, P., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Seguin, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Petitjean, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Salvert, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Touret, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Jouvet (1976) The raphe nuclei of the cat brainstem: A 
    topographical atlas of their efferent projections as revealed by 
    autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">113:449-486.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Bowsher, D. (1975) Diencephalic projections from the 
    formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Brain Res. 9.5211-220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Chan-Palay, V. (1977) Indoleamine neurons and their 
    processes in the normal rat brain and in chronic diet-induced 
    thiamine deficiency demonstrated by uptake of 3H-serotonin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Neurol. 176:467-494.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Chi, C.C. (1970) An experimental silver study of the 
    ascending projections of the central gray substance and adjacent 
    tegmentum in the rat with observations in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Neurol. 139t259-272.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Christ, J.F. (1969) Derivation and boundaries of the 
    hypothalamus, with atlas of hypothalamic grisea.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">In W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Haymaker, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Anderson, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Nauta (edsf: The Hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Illinois: Charles C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Thomas, pp. 13-60.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Cropper, E.C., J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Eisenman, and E.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Azmitia (1984) An immunocytochemical study of the 
    serotonergic innervation of the thalamus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Neurol. 224:38-50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Dingledine, R., and J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Kelly (1977) Brain stem stimulation and the 
    acetylcholine-evoked inhibition of neurons in the feline nucleus 
    reticularis thalami.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">(Lond.) 271:135-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Edwards, S.B., and J.S. de Olmos (1976) Autoradiographic 
    studies of the projections of the midbrain reticular formation: 
    Ascending projections of nucleus cuneiformis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Neurol. 165:417-432.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Frassoni, C., Spreafico, R., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Baltaglia (1984) Afferent and efferent connections of 
    the nucleus reticularis thalami of the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">[Suppl] 18:S51.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">French, C.R., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Sefton, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Mackay - Sim (1984) The inhibitory role of the visually 
    responsive region of the thalamic reticular nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Brain Res. 57:471-479.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Frigyesi, T.L., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Schwartz (1972) Cortical control of thalamic 
    sensorimotor relay activities in the cat and squirrel monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">In Frigyesi, T.L., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Rinvik, and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Yahr (eds): Corticothalamic Projections and Sensorimotor 
    Activities.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">New York Raven Press, pp. 161-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Fukuda, Y., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Iwama (1971) Reticular inhibition of internuncial in the 
    rat lateral geniculate body.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Brain Res. 35:107-118.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Godfraind, J-M, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Veraart (1978) Possible role of acetylcholine in the 
    mediation of non-retinal input to the lateral geniculate nucleus 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Ital.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Biol. 116,262-272, Grofova, I., O.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Ottersen, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Rinvik (1978) Mesencephalic and diencephalic afferents 
    to the superior colliculus and periaqueductal grey substance 
    demonstrated by retrograde axonal transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Brain Res. 146:205-220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Hanker, J.S., L.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Thornburg, P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Yates, and H.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Moore 111 (1975) The demonstration of cholinesterases by 
    the formation of osmium blacks at the sites of Hatchett s brown.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Histochemistry 37:223-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Holstege, G., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Collewijn (1982) The efferent connections of the nucleus 
    of the optic tract and the superior colliculus in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurol. 209:139-175.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Hoover, D.B., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Jacobowitz (1979) Neurochemical and histological studies 
    of the effect of a lesion of the nucleus cuneiformis on the 
    cholinergic innervation of discrete areas of the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Brain Res. 170r113122.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Houser, C.R., J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Vaughn, R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Barber, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Roberts (1980) GABA neurones are the major cell type of 
    the nucleus reticularis thalami.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Brain Res. 2OOr341-354.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Hughes, H.C., and W.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Mullikin (1984) Brainstem afferents to the lateral 
    geniculate nucleus of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Brain Res. 54t253-258.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Jasper, H. (1949) Diffuse projection systems: The 
    integrative action of the thalamic reticular system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Electroencephalogr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Clin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Neurophysiol. 1:405-420.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Jones, E.G. (1975) Some aspects of the organization of 
    the thalamic reticular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Neurol. 262t285-308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Jones, E.G. (1981) Functional subdivision and synaptic 
    organisation of the mammalian thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">In R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Porter (ed): International Review of Physiology, Volume 
    25 NeurophysioZogy IV: Baltimore: University Park Press, pp. 
    173-245.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Kayama, Y., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Negi, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Sugitani, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Iwama (1982) Effects of locus coeruleus stimulation on 
    neuronal activities of dorsal lateral geniculate nucleus and 
    perigeniculate reticular nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Neuroscience 7t655-666.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Konig, J.F.R., and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Klippel (1963) The Rat Brain: A Stereotaxic Atlas of the 
    Forebrain and Lower Parts of the Brain Stem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">New York: R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Krieger Publishing Co.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Inc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Kromer, L.F., and R..Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Moore (1980) A study of the organisation of the locus 
    coeruleus projections to the lateral geniculate nuclei in the 
    albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Neuroscience 5255-271.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">LaVail, J.H., and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">LaVail(1974) The retrograde intraaxonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase in the chick visual system: A light and 
    electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Neurol. 157:303-358.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Lindvall, O., A Bjorklund, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Nobin, and U.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Stenevi (1974) The adrenergic innervation of the rat 
    thalamus as revealed by the glyoxylic acid fluorescence method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Neurol. 154,317-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Mackay-Sim, A., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Sefton, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Martin (1983) Subcortical projections to lateral 
    geniculate and thalamic reticular nucleus in the hooded rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neurol. 21324-35.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Mantyh, P.W. (1982) Forebrain projections to the 
    periaqueductal grey in the monkey, with observations in the cat and 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Neurol. 206:146158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Mesulam, M-M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue 
    reaction-product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural 
    afferents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Minderhoud, J.M. (1971) An anatomical study of the 
    efferent connections of the thalamic reticular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Brain Res. 12:435-446.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Montero, V.M., and G.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Scott (1981) Synaptic terminals in the dorsal lateral 
    geniculate nucleus from neurones of the thalamic reticular nucleus: 
    A light and electron microscope autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Neuroscience 6:2561-2577.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Moore, R.Y., A.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Halaris, and B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Jones (1978) Serotonin neurones of the midbrain raphe: 
    Ascending projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Neurol. 180:417-438.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Morrell, J.I., L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Greenberger, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">F&apos;faff (1981) Hypothalamic, other diencephalic, and 
    telencephalic neurons that project to the dorsal midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Neurol. 201:589-620.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Moruzzi, G., and H.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Magoun (1949) Brain stem reticular formation and 
    activation of the EEG.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Electroencephalogr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Clin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Neurophysiol. 2:455473.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">OConnell, M., P.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Ohara, and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Lieberman (1982) Connections of the thalamic reticular 
    nucleus in the adult rat: A study using horseradish peroxidase 
    (HRP) techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Anat. 134.610 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Ohara, P.T., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Lieberman (1979) Experimental identification and 
    synaptic relationships of terminals of corticofugal afferents to 
    the visual portion of the thalamic reticular nucleus in the albino 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">I29:863 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Ohara, P.T., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Lieberman (1981) Thalamic reticular tomical evidence 
    that cortico-reticular axons establish contact with 
    reticulo-geniculate projection cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Brain 156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Ohara, P.T., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Lieberman (1985) The thalamic reticular nucleus of the 
    adult rat: Experimental anatomical studies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Neurocytol. 14:365411.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Ohara, P.T., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Sefton, and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Lieberman (1980) Mode of termination of afferents from 
    the thalamic reticular nucleus in the dorsal lateral genicdate 
    nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Brain Res. 197:503-506.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Ohara, P.T., A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Lieberman, S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Hunt, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">-Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Wu (1983) Neural elements containing glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase (GAD) in the dorsal lateral geniculate nucleus of the 
    rat; immunohistochemical studies by light and electron 
    microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Neuroscience 8:189-211.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Parent, A,, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Steriade (1984) Midbrain tegmental projections of 
    nucleus reticularis thalami of cat and monkey: A retrograde 
    transport and antidromic invasion study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Neurol. 229:548-558.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Pasquier, D.A., and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Villar (1982) Subcortical projections to the lateral 
    geniculate body in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Brain Res. 48:409-419.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Paxinos, G., and Watson, C. (1982) The Rat Brain in 
    Stereotaxic nates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Pellegrino, L.J., A.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Pellegrino, and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Cushman Atlas of the Rat Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">New York Plenum Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Peschanski, M., and J-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Besson (1984) Diencephalic connections of the raphe 
    nuclei of the rat brainstem: An anatomical study with reference to 
    the somatosensory system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Neurol. 224:509-534.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Peschanski, M., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Ralston, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Roudier (1983) Reticularis thalami afferents to the 
    ventrobasal complex of the rat thalamus: An electron microscope 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Brain Res. 270:325-329.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Robertson, R.T., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Feiner (1982) Diencephalic projections from the pontine 
    reticular formation: autoradiographic studies in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Brain Res. 239:3-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Rossi, G.F., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Zanchetti (1957) The brain Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Ital.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Biol. 95199-435.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Scheibel, M.E., and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Scheibel(1958) Structural substrates for integrating 
    patterns in the brain stem reticular core.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">In H.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Jasper, L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Proctor, R.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Knighton, W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Noshay, and R.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Costello (eds): Reticular Formation of the Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">London: Churchill, pp. 31-68.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Scheibel, M.E., and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Scheibel (1966) The organization reticularis thalami: A 
    Golgi study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Brain Res. 2:43-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Schlag, J., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Waszak (1971) Electrophysiological properties of units 
    of the thalamic reticular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Neurol. 32:79-97.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Shammah-Lagnado, S.J., J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Ricardo, N.T.M.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Sakamoto, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Negrao (1983) Afferent connections of the mesencephalic 
    reticular formation: A horseradish peroxidase study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Neuroscience 9:391-409.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Shute, C.C.D., and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Lewis (1967) The ascending cholinergic reticular system: 
    Neocortical, olfactory and subcortical projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Brain 90:497520.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Singer, W. (1977) Control of thalamic transmission by 
    corticofugal and ascending reticular pathways in the visual 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Rev. 57:386420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Sofroniew, M.V., J.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Priestley, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Consolazione, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Eckenstein, and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Cuello (1985) Cholinergic projections from the midbrain 
    and pons to the thalamus in the rat, identified by combined 
    retrograde tracing and choline acetyltransferase 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Brain Res. 329213223.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Sotgiu, M.L., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Marini, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Eposti, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Fava (1981) A horseradish idase study of afferent 
    projections to nucleus reticularis thalami cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Ital.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Biol. 119:151-159.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Steriade, M. (1970) Ascending control of thalamic 
    ness.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Int.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Neurobiol. 1237-144.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Steriade, M., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Parent, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Ropert, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Kitsikis (1982) Zona incerta and lateral hypothalamic 
    afferents to the midbrain reticular core of cat-an HRP and 
    electrophysiological study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Brain Res. 238:13-28.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Steriade, M., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Parent, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Hada (1984) Thalamic projections of nucleus reticularis 
    thalami of cat: A study using retrograde transport of horseradish 
    peroxidase and fluorescent tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Neurol. 229:531547.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Swanson, L.J., and B.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Hartman (1975) The central adrenergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">An immunofluorescence study of the location of cell 
    bodies and their efferent connections in the rat utilizing 
    dopamine-hydroxylase as a marker.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurol. 163:467-506.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Szentagothai, J. (1972) Lateral geniculate ment.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Bibl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Ophthalmol. 82t178-188.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Valverde, F. (1962) Reticular formation of the albino 
    rat&apos;s brain stem: Cytoarchitecture and corticofugal 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Neurol. 219:2553.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Veazey, R.B., and C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Severin (1980) Efferent projections of the mesencephalic 
    nucleus (pars lateralis) in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">rol. 190231-244, Waszak, M. (1974) Firing patterns of 
    neurons in the rostra1 and ventral part of nucleus reticularis 
    thalami during EEG spindles.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Neurol. 43:3859.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Weber, J.T., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Harting (1980) The efferent projections of the pretectal 
    complex: An autoradiographic and horseradish peroxidase 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Brain Res. 194:l-28.</S>
  </References>

</File>

