<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>The Nigral Projection to Predorsal Bundle Cells in the 
  Superior Colliculus of the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>M.E. BICKFORD AND W.C. HALL</Authors>

  <Title>ABSTRACT</Title>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s0">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">For ease of description, the experiments have been divided 
    into three parts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The goal of the first part was to determine, by retrograde 
    and anterograde tracers, the laminar distribution and extent of 
    overlap of the predorsal bundle cells and the terminal field of the 
    nigrotectal tract.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">In the second part, the nigrotectal tract and the 
    predorsal bundle cells were labeled for electron microscopy either 
    in separate or in single animals in order to characterize the 
    synaptic contacts between these two pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">In the final part, immunocytochemical methods were used to 
    characterize, with the light and electron microscopes, the 
    GAEiAergic terminals in contact with predorsal bundle cells that 
    had been labeled by retrograde transport.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s5">Laminar distribution of 
    predorsal bundle cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">For the purpose of comparing the laminar distribution of 
    predorsal bundle cells with that of a source of input, the 
    nigrotectal tract, it was important to label the dendrites as well 
    as the somas of the predorsal bundle cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">For this reason, injections of horseradish peroxidase 
    (HRP) were placed into the predorsal bundle as it decussates 
    beneath the oculomotor nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Injections at this site homogeneously fill the somas and 
    dendrites of large numbers of cells in the superior colliculus by 
    retrograde transport and/or diffusion (May and Hall, &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Nine rats were used for these experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Prior to surgery, the rats were anesthetized with either 
    intraperitoneal injections of sodium pentobarbital (55 mg/kg) 
    supplemented by intramuscular injections of chloral hydrate 
    (0.1-0.4 cc), or with a combination of intraperitoneal injections 
    of sodium pentobarbital (16.25 mg/kg) and ketamine hydrochloride 
    (67 mg/kg).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The surgical procedure consisted of exposing the 
    cerebellum caudal to the injection site and then, under stereotaxic 
    control, advancing a horizontal Hamilton syringe rostrally to the 
    level of the decussation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The final placement of the syringe was checked by 
    stimulating electrically through the tip of the insulated syringe 
    needle to initiate eye movements.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">A total volume of 0.4-1 p1 of either 60% HRP and 2% 
    dimethylsulfoxide in saline or 60% HRP in saline was injected while 
    the syringe tip was moved horizontally over a distance of 1 mm from 
    rostra1 to caudal along the midline of the decussation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Following survival times of 2-4 days, the rats were 
    deeply anesthetized with 1 cc of sodium pentobarbital and perfused 
    through the heart with phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4), followed 
    by a solution of 1.5% paraformaldehyde and 1.5% glutaraldehyde in 
    0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The brains were postfixed overnight, then blocked in the 
    coronal or sagittal plane, and cut with a vibratome into 50 or 100 
    p,m thick sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The sections were treated with 3,3&apos;-diaminobenzidine 
    and intensified with heavy metals, either nickel or a combination 
    of nickel and cobalt (Adams, &apos;811, and imidazole (Straw, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">The sections then were mounted on slides and 
    counterstained.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Selected labeled cells were drawn with the aid of a 
    camera lucida.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Most of our data concerning inputs to predorsal bundle 
    cells were obtained by studying one component of this crossed 
    pathway, the tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">To determine the distribution and morphology of the 
    tectospinal cells, a 0.5-2 pl solution of 50% HRP dissolved either 
    in saline or in saline with 2% dimethylsulfoxide was injected into 
    the spinal cord between the first and second vertebrae in eight 
    rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The general surgical and histological procedures were the 
    same as those followed for the animals with injections into the 
    decussation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Labeled cells were drawn at a magnification of 1,000 
    times with the aid of a camera lucida, and their areas were 
    measured with an electronic planimeter to obtain an estimate of 
    their size distribution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Of the eight rats in this series of experiments, seven 
    also were used in the study of the inputs to tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">These latter brains were processed both for retrograde 
    transport from the spinal cord and, in addition, for anterograde 
    transport of either Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L), 
    HRP, or wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to HRP (WGA-HRP) from 
    substantia nigra, or for glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD) 
    immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Some of the sections from each of these cases were 
    processed for electron microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">The additional procedures for these cases will be 
    described in later sections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s27">Terminal distribution of 
    the nigrotectal pathway</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">The terminal distribution of the nigrotectal pathway was 
    examined with the use of either HRP (five rats), WGA-HRP (six 
    rats), or PHA-L (five rats) as an anterograde tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">In all cases, either a syringe (2 rats) or a pipette (14 
    rats) was oriented at an angle of 20&quot; from vertical in the 
    coronal plane and lowered through the cortex and medial geniculate 
    body to reach substantia nigra pars reticulata.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">For the iontophoretic injections, the HRP or WGA-HRP was 
    dissolved in a solution of 0.3 M tris buffer with 0.05 M KCl (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The injections were made by passing a positive current of 
    2 pA through a 30 pm diameter pipette tip for from 20 to 60 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The pressure injections were made with a Hamilton syringe 
    and consisted of 0.2 p1 of 50% or 70% HRP in saline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The survival times and HRP histochemical methods were the 
    same as those described in the previous section.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">In the experiments that utilized PHA-L, a 2.5% solution 
    of biotinylated PHA-L (Vector) was dissolved in distilled water and 
    injected by passing a current of 5 pA through the 30 pm tip of a 
    pipette for periods ranging from 40 to 60 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">After survival times of 3-5 days, the rats were deeply 
    anesthetized and perfused through the heart.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">In material containing PHA-L, several combinations of 
    fixatives were tried in an effort to optimize preservation of the 
    fine structure for subsequent electron microscopy, while optimizing 
    the immunocytochemical labeling of the PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">These combinations were: 3.5% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer (one rat), 4% paraformaldehyde and 0.25% 
    glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (one rat), 
    periodate-lysine-paraformaldehyde (McLean and Nakane, &apos;74) 
    (one rat), and 2.5% paraformaldehyde and 0.05% glutaraldehyde in 
    phosphate buffer (two rats).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Volumes of fixative ranging from 600 to 700 ml were 
    used.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Of the fixative solutions we tried, the 2.5% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.05% glutaraldehyde gave the best 
    ultrastructural preservation of the tissue while maintaining good 
    immunocytochemical labeling.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">In every case, the fixatives were flushed from the rat 1 
    hour following perfusion with a solution of phosphatebuffered 
    saline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Fifty micron thick sections were cut on a vibratome.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Sections were incubated in solutions of 5, 10, and 20% 
    dimethylsulfoxide (10 minutes each), and then frozen and thawed 
    from 2 to 5 times in the final solution to increase penetration of 
    the antibodies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Two rounds of freezing and thawing of the tissue was the 
    best compromise between good penetration of the antibodies and 
    preservation of fine structure.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">For the PHA-L immunocytochemistry, the primary antibody 
    solution was 1:1,000 biotinylated anti-PHA-L from goat in phosphate 
    buffer with 1% normal goat serum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">The sections were incubated in this solution for 2 hours 
    at room temperature, with agitation, overnight at 4&quot;C, and 
    then for 1 hour the next day at room temperature, again with 
    agitation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Next, the sections were washed in phosphate buffer and 
    incubated with agitation in a solution of 1:lOO avidin and 
    phosphate buffer with 0.1% bovine serum albumin for 1 hour at room 
    temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">This procedure was repeated with 1:lOO biotinylated 
    HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">After rinsing in phosphate buffer, the sections were 
    placed in a solution of 0.1% glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer for 
    5 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">They were then washed in phosphate buffer and incubated 
    with diaminobenzidine as described for the experiments that used 
    HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">PHA-L label was found throughout the thickness of the 50 
    pm thick sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The sections were either mounted on slides and 
    counterstained with cresyl violet to demonstrate the tectal layers 
    or processed for electron microscopy, according to the methods 
    described below.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s52">Nigrotectal terminations 
    on predorsal bundle cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">To characterize the synaptic contacts between nigrotectal 
    terminals and the predorsal bundle cells, the retrograde transport 
    of HRP from the spinal cord was combined with the anterograde 
    transport of either WGA-HRP or PHA-L from the substantia nigra in 
    single animals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">When WGAHRP was used as the anterograde tracer (one rat), 
    reaction of the tissue with diaminobenzidine could be used to 
    demonstrate both the nigrotectal terminals and the tectospinal 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">When PHA-L was used as the anterograde tracer (three 
    rats), immunocytochemical procedures were used to link the PHA-L 
    with HRP; then, a reaction with diaminobenzidine was used to 
    demonstrate both the nigrotectal terminals and the tectospinal 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The latter method had the advantage of allowing control 
    sections to be prepared that were reacted with diaminobenzidine 
    without undergoing the preceding PHA-L immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The control sections were examined to ensure that the 
    spinal cord injections did not also label spinotectal terminals 
    that could be confounded with nigrotectal terminals (see below).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">When the reactions were completed, the sections were 
    either mounted on slides and counterstained, or processed for 
    electron microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">For electron microscopy, the sections were postiixed in 
    osmium tetroxide, stained en bloc with uranyl acetate, dehydrated 
    in an ethanol series, and embedded in Epon or Durcupan resin 
    between glass slides coated with dimethyldichlorosilane.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Regions were selected for examination with the electron 
    microscope by drawing with a camera lucida all of the labeled 
    tectospinal cells and adjacent terminals in the sections that were 
    embedded between dimethyldichlorosilane-coated slides.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Interesting regions of these 50 pm sections were also 
    photographed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Areas of the sections that contained labeled terminals in 
    close apposition to labeled cells were mounted on blocks of resin 
    and cut into 5 pm thick sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">These thinner sections were dried onto slides and 
    examined with the light microscope to locate terminals that had 
    been drawn in the 50 pm sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">The areas containing these terminals were drawn again and 
    occasionally photographed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Selected 5 pm sections were remounted on resin blocks and 
    cut into serial thin sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The serial sections were collected on formvarcoated slot 
    grids and examined with the electron microscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">This procedure for examining the same structures with 
    both the light and electron microscopes is illustrated in Figures 1 
    and 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Figure 1 shows a sequence of pictures following a 
    terminal found in close apposition to a tectospinal cell in a 50 pm 
    section with the light microscope (Fig.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">lA), to a 5 Fm thick section (Fig. lB), and finally to 
    electron micrographs of thin sections (Fig. lC,D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">The terminal was labeled with WGA-HRP from an injection 
    in substantia nigra and the tectospinal cell was labeled from an 
    injection of HRP in the spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Figure 2A illustrates a camera lucida drawing of a 
    tectospinal cell filled with HRP by retrograde transport and 
    closely associated terminal arbors that were labeled with PHA-L 
    following an injection in substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Figure 2B and C shows two focal planes through the 50 pm 
    section drawn in A.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Two distinct segments of the terminal arbors indicated by 
    long and short arrows in Figure 2A can be identified in the 
    photographs of Figure 2B and C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Figure 2D and E illustrates two focal planes of a 5 pm 
    section subsequently taken from the 50 pm section.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">The asterisks indicate two terminal segments that can be 
    identified in both the 50 and 5 Fm sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Parts of these latter two segments are illustrated again 
    in the electron micrographs of Figure 2F and G.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s77">GABAergic input to 
    predorsal bundle cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">In a find part of the study, GAD-immunoreactive terminals 
    that contact identified predorsd bundle cells were examined to 
    provide a basis for comparisons with the nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">In one rat, only the GAD-immunoreactive terminals were 
    labeled, whereas in three rats both the terminals and tectospinal 
    cells were labeled in the same sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">In these experiments, the rats were perfused with 600-700 
    ml of a solution of 2.5% paraformaldehyde and 0.05% glutaraldehyde 
    in phosphate buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">After 1 hour, the fixative was flushed from the brain 
    with phosphatebuffered saline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">The brain was stored in this solution overnight.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The next day 50 pm thick sections were cut using a 
    vibratome.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">The sections from animals in which the tectospinal cells 
    had been labeled by retrograde transport of HRP were processed with 
    diaminobenzidine.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Subsequently, the sections were soaked for 10 minutes in 
    each of a series of solutions of 5, 10, and 20% dimethylsulfoxide 
    in phosphate buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">Then, to increase penetration, the sections were frozen 
    and thawed from 2 to 5 times while in the 20% solution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">For the immunocytochemistry, the sections were washed in 
    the phosphate buffer and incubated in the primary antibody solution 
    of 1:2,000 GAD antiserum from sheep (Oertel et al., &apos;81) and 
    phosphate buffer with 1% normal rabbit serum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">The sections were incubated in this solution for 2 hours 
    at room temperature with agitation, overnight at 4&quot;C, and 1 
    hour the next day at room temperature with agitation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Control sections were incubated in a solution of 1:1,000 
    preimmune sheep serum and buffer with 1% normal rabbit serum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">Following incubation in the primary antibody solution, 
    the sections were washed in phosphate buffer and incubated with 
    agitation in a solution of 1:lOO anti-sheep IgG from rabbit and 
    buffer with 1% normal rabbit serum for 1 hour at room 
    temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">Then, the sections were washed in phosphate buffer and 
    incubated in a solution of 1:500 peroxidase-antiperoxidase from 
    sheep and phosphate buffer with 1% normal rabbit serum for 1 hour 
    at room temperature with agitation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">The sections were washed again and postfixed in a 
    solution of 0.1% glutaraldehyde in buffer for 5 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">After a buffer rinse, the sections were reacted with 
    diaminobenzidine.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">When the retrograde transport of HRP and GAD 
    immunocytochemistry were combined in single sections, only the 
    first of the diaminobenzidine reactions was intensified with a 
    heavy metal.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">After the reactions, the sections were either mounted on 
    slides and counterstained or processed for electron microscopy 
    using the methods described in the previous section.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s96">Control experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">The combinations of methods used in these experiments 
    permitted the use of certain types of control experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">In the experiments with paired injections, spinotectal 
    terminals could be mistaken for nigrotectal terminals if the spinal 
    cord injections of HRP labeled the spinotectal tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">We used two controls for this potential source of 
    error.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">First, we looked for terminals in cases with spinal cord 
    injections that were not paired with injections in substantia 
    nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Second, in the cases in which the spinal cord injection 
    of HRP was paired with an injection of PHA-L in substantia nigra, 
    some sections were reacted with diaminobenzidine to reveal the HRP 
    reaction product, but were not processed immunocytochemically to 
    reveal the PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">These control sections were then examined for labeled 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">An additional source of error might be injections of the 
    substantia nigra that labeled tectal efferent cells that could be 
    mistaken for tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">Controls for this possibility were provided by the 
    experiments in which injections into substantia nigra were not 
    paired with spinal cord injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">Finally, in our cases in which GAD immunocytochemistry 
    was combined with HRP injections in the spinal cord, control 
    sections were labeled with diaminobenzidine to reveal the HRP 
    reaction product and then incubated in a solution of preimmune 
    serum (1:1,000) instead of the GAD antibody, and examined for 
    spuriously labeled terminals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s106">Definition of the layers 
    in the superior colliculus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">For the layers of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLocation> in the rat, we have used the 
    designations suggested by Weiner (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">The justification for this choice and its relationships 
    to the designations used in other studies have been discussed in 
    previous papers (Wallace, &apos;86; Bickford and Hall, 
    &apos;89).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="46" class="results.heading" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
     id="s109">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s110">Laminar distribution of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>predorsal bundle</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    cells</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111"><exptLabel>Following injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
      decussation of the predorsal 
      bundle</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, 
      <labelingDescription>large numbers of cells</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the intermediate grey 
      layer</labelingLocation> were filled with reaction product.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">The cells filled by this procedure varied in size.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">The dendrites as well as the somas of many of the 
      labeled cells were homogeneously filled and, as a result, with 
      these injections it was possible to estimate the laminar 
      distribution of the receptive surfaces of a large sample of the 
      cells that give rise to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the predorsal 
      bundle</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">Most of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the predorsal 
      bundle</neuroanatomicalLocation> cells had four or five primary 
      dendrites, which, for the largest cells, extended as far as 800 
      pm in the mediolateral or dorsoventral dimensions.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Photographs of a sample of these cells are shown in 
      Figure 3.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">Reaction product filled even the finely tapered tips 
      of the dendrites; while the density of spines was variable, they 
      were filled on many of the cells.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">Most of these spines were located on the distal 
      dendrites.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">Many of the distal dendrites also had a beaded 
      appearance.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">In <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the 
      intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation>, the dendrites 
      extended radially from the somas, whereas in the more compressed 
      medial part of the layer, the dendrites extended primarily in the 
      medial, lateral, and dorsal dimensions.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">Regardless of their size or the orientation of their 
      dendrites, <labelingDescription>the vast majority of predorsal 
      bundle cells</labelingDescription> was restricted to 
      <labelingLocation>the intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation> 
      as defined by Weiner (&apos;86).</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">This distribution, which was described in detail in a 
    previous paper (Bickford and Hall, &apos;89), is illustrated in 
    Figure 4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">This figure is a composite drawing of a sample of cells 
    labeled in one animal following an injection into <injectionLocation
    >the predorsal bundle decussation</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">The most distal dendrites of a few cells extended 
    dorsally into <labelingLocation>stratum opticum</labelingLocation> 
    or ventrally into <labelingLocation>the intermediate white and deep 
    grey layers</labelingLocation>, but none extended through 
    <labelingLocation>stratum opticum</labelingLocation> to reach 
    <labelingLocation>the superficial grey layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">In our material, predorsal bundle cells were most 
    numerous in <labelingLocation>the lateral extreme, or flank 
    (Weiner, &apos;86), of the intermediate grey 
    layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">The arrows in Figures 3A and 4 indicate this area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">In the flank, there is no overlying superficial grey 
    layer and the dendrites of some predorsal bundle cells extended to 
    the pial surface (Figs. 3 and 4).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127"><exptLabel>In several experiments, the injections were 
    placed in <injectionLocation>the cervical spinal 
    cord</injectionLocation></exptLabel> rather than the decussation in 
    order to label just the tectospinal component of the predorsal 
    bundle pathway.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s128">Following these injections, 
    the <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> reaction product was 
    granular and was confined primarily to the somas and proximal 
    dendrites of the cells in <labelingLocation>the superior 
    colliculus</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s129">However, as in the cases with 
    decussation injections, cell somas that varied over a wide size 
    range were labeled.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">In one experiment, all of the labeled tectospinal cells 
    in alternate sections through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLocation> were drawn and measured.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">In this sample of 178 cells, the soma areas ranged from 
    127 to 877 km2 (mean = 375 pm2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">This size distribution is shown in Figure 5.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Also, as in the cases with decussation injections, the 
    somas of the labeled cells were restricted almost entirely to the 
    intermediate grey layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">Since these cells were labeled with a granular reaction 
    product that was confined to the somas and proximal dendrites, we 
    could not determine the extent of their dendritic fields.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s135">Terminal distribution of 
    the nigrotectal pathway</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">The trajectory of the axons from <connxOrigin>substantia 
    nigra pars reticulata</connxOrigin> and their terminal distribution 
    in <connxTermination>the superior colliculus</connxTermination> are 
    illustrated for <exptLabel>a case with a <injectionLocation>
    nigral</injectionLocation> injection of 
    <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical></exptLabel> in Figure 6 
    and for a case with an injection of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> in Figure 7.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">Photographs of the series of <injectionLocation>
    substantia nigra</injectionLocation> injection sites from the cases 
    that will be described are shown in Figures 7 and 8.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s138">In all 
    of these cases, the axons exited from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    dorsal border of substantia nigra pars 
    reticulata</neuroanatomicalLocation> and then extended 
    dorsomedially, in the direction of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    central grey</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139">Just 
    beneath <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ipsilateral superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> the axons turned to reach 
    <connxTermination>the lateral border of the deep tectal 
    layers</connxTermination>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">In each case, 
    <labelingDescription>a large number of axons 
    terminated</labelingDescription> in <connxTermination>the lateral 
    flank of the intermediate grey layer</connxTermination>, whereas 
    others continued medially in the mediolaterally oriented band of 
    fibers that forms <connxTermination>the intermediate white 
    layer</connxTermination>, and terminated in more medial parts of 
    the overlying grey layer.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141"><labelingDescription>Other 
    axons</labelingDescription> traveled medial within <labelingLocation
    >the intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation> itself to reach 
    their terminal zone.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142"><labelingDescription>The 
    terminals in this layer were particularly 
    dense</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>sublayer 
    b</labelingLocation>, which is distinguished by bundles of 
    rostrocaudal fibers (Weiner, &apos;86; Bickford and Hall, 
    &apos;89).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s143">Here, they formed a patchy 
    distribution.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s144"><labelingDescription>A small 
    number of fibers</labelingDescription> crossed in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the commissure of the superior 
    colliculus</neuroanatomicalLocation> to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral intermediate grey 
    layer</labelingLocation> (see Figure 6, sections 1800 to 1000).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">As they entered the intermediate grey layer, the 
    nigrotectal axons divided into smaller branches that gave rise to 
    boutons from 1 to 2 pm in diameter (Fig. 9A).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s146">The 
    terminal swellings were aligned in series along the small branches 
    or formed clusters of terminal boutons (Fig. 9B).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s147">In the 
    series, the boutons were often connected by short lengths of very 
    fine fibers (Fig. 9C).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s148">Occasionally, the boutons 
    appeared to be in close apposition to, and even encircling, cell 
    somas (Fig. 9D,E).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s149">The laminar distribution of 
    the nigrotectal terminals was very similar to that of the predorsal 
    bundle cells; although some terminal labeling was present below 
    <labelingLocation>the intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation>, 
    <labelingDescription>the vast majority of the nigrotectal 
    axons</labelingDescription> terminated within <labelingLocation>
    this layer</labelingLocation>, particularly within <labelingLocation
    >the sublayer b</labelingLocation> (Figs. 6, 7).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s150">
    <labelingLocation>The layers below the intermediate grey 
    layer</labelingLocation> primarily contained 
    <labelingDescription>axon trunks</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151"><labelingDescription>No nigrotectal 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    layers superficial to the intermediate grey 
    layer</labelingLocation>, and the question of the terminal 
    distribution of projections from <connxOrigin>a lateral subdivision 
    of substantia nigra</connxOrigin> (May and Hall, &apos;86a; Harting 
    et al., &apos;88) was not addressed.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Similar conclusions concerning the terminal distribution 
    of the nigrotectal pathway were obtained with all three tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">However, the <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> was 
    the most sensitive; <labelingDescription>many more axons and 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were labeled in <labelingLocation>
    the superior colliculus</labelingLocation> following 
    <injectionLocation>nigral</injectionLocation> injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> than following 
    <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections of a similar 
    size.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">The <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
    labeled slightly more axons and terminals than injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">The morphology of the terminal arbors revealed by these 
    different methods was also similar (Fig. 9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Individual s o n s and terminals could be densely 
    labeled with all three methods and the only difference was in the 
    number of processes labeled.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s157">Nigrotectal terminations 
    on tectospinal cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Before describing the actual synaptic contacts between 
    nigrotectal terminals and tectospinal cells, we will describe the 
    prominent features of the preand postsynaptic processes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Fine structure of nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">The following description is based on the examination of 
    110 terminals labeled with <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP</tracerChemical> 
    (case 85-105 in Fig. 8) and 58 terminals labeled with 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> (cases 87-57 in Fig. 8 and 
    88-35 in Fig. 7).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Spinal cord injections were not made in these cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">Tissue from <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the 
    intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation> was scanned with the 
    electron microscope and all terminal profiles that included a 
    synaptic contact were photographed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">The grids were not stained in order to make it easier to 
    locate the labeled terminals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">With both methods, <labelingDescription>labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>
    the intermediate grey layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Examples are presented in Figure 10.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">The terminals were usually from 1 to 2 pm in length 
    along the side making a synaptic contact, but longer lengths were 
    seen where they merged with the fine processes that connect serial 
    boutons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">The nigrotedal terminals typically contained multiple 
    mitochondria and pleomorphic vesicles, and formed synaptic contacts 
    with modest postsynaptic densities that were usually less that 0.5 
    pm long, Often, the preterminal unmyelinated axon was also filled 
    with pleomorphic vesicles.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">The majority (63%) of the terminals contacted dendrites 
    less than 3 pm in diameter.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">The remaining terminals contacted either larger 
    dendrites-up to 6 pm in diameter (14%) or somas (23%) with 
    diameters ranging from 8 to 24 pm (mean = 14.1 bm).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">The nigrotectal terminals were neither presynaptic nor 
    postsynaptic to other terminals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">In many cases, the nigrotectal terminals were surrounded 
    by unlabeled processes that separated the terminals and their 
    postsynaptic processes from the surrounding neuropil.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Appendages of these processes invaginated into the 
    terminals so that in some sections one or more unlabeled 
    membrane-bound profiles were contained within the profile of the 
    labeled terminals (see Fig. 10B,D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">In a few instances, the unlabeled profiles could be 
    identified as originating from the postsynaptic process or from 
    adjacent synaptic terminals, but in most cases these profiles 
    appeared to originate from the glial-like processes that surround 
    the nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">Synaptic contacts between and these unlabeled profiles 
    were the nigrotectal terminals never observed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s175">Fine structure of 
    tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Twenty-nine tectospinal cells that were labeled with HRP 
    following injections in the cervical spinal cord were examined with 
    the electron microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">The observations confirmed the light microscopic 
    observation that tectospinal cells vary in size and demonstrated 
    further that several features of the fine structure of these cells 
    are correlated with size.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Of particular significance to the present study was a 
    direct correlation between soma size and the density of axosomatic 
    synaptic contacts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Specifically, in a given section, the largest 
    tectospinal cell somas were contacted by numerous terminals, the 
    medium-size by fewer, and the smallest by only an occasional 
    terminal.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Most of the surfaces of the smaller cell somas were 
    apposed by either other small cells, blood vessels, myelinated 
    axons, or glial cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">The large and small cells also could be distinguished by 
    their cytoplasmic inclusions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The largest cells contained a large quantity of 
    cytoplasm, many well-developed Nissl bodies, and a nucleus with a 
    smooth, round profile.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">The large cells also often contained fibrillary 
    inclusion bodies (Peters et al., &apos;76); these were located in 
    the cytoplasm adjacent to the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">In contrast, the medium-size tectospinal cells contained 
    less cytoplasm, smaller Nissl bodies, and a lobulated nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The smallest tectospinal cells contained very little 
    cytoplasm; a lobulated nucleus occupied most of the soma (Fig. 
    1).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Sgnaptic contacts between nigrotectal terminals and 
    tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">To characterize the synaptic contacts between 
    nigrotectal terminals and tectospinal cells, we examined tissue 
    from one animal in which <injectionLocation>a spinal 
    cord</injectionLocation> injection of HRP was combined with a 
    WGA-HRP injection into <injectionLocation>substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation> (case 88-5, Fig. 8) and one in which 
    <injectionLocation>the spinal cord</injectionLocation> injection 
    was paired with a <injectionLocation>nigral</injectionLocation> 
    injection of PHA-L (case 88-48, Fig. 8).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">In both cases, the distribution of labeled nigrotectal 
    terminals overlapped extensively the distribution of tectospinal 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Light microscopic examination of sections from the 
    experiment that used PHA-L as the anterograde tracer indicated that 
    nigrotectal terminals were closely apposed to 73% of the labeled 
    tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Examination of these cells (n = 40) suggested that the 
    majority of the nigrotectal terminals were closely associated with 
    the dendrites, but that a significant number were apposed to the 
    somas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Drawings of 14 of these tectospinal cells and their 
    associated nigrotectal terminals are presented in Figure 11.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">The majority of terminals that appeared to be closely 
    apposed to the tectospinal cells when examined with the light 
    microscope were found to form synaptic contacts with these cells 
    when they were examined subsequently with the electron 
    microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Thirty-three synaptic contacts between nigrotectal 
    terminals and eight tectospinal cells were examined with the 
    electron microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Several examples are shown in Figures 1,2,12,13, and 
    14.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">In agreement with the observations made with the light 
    microscope, most (21/33) were axodendritic and the remaining 
    (12/33) were axosomatic.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Examples of axodendritic contacts are presented in 
    Figure 13, while examples of axosomatic contacts are shown in 
    Figures 1, 12, and 14.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The fine structure of these terminals and their synaptic 
    contacts was the same as that observed in the cases in which only 
    an anterograde tracer was used.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">In particular, the synaptic contacts shown in Figures 
    12, 13, and 14 illustrate their characteristic pleomorphic 
    vesicles, modest postsynaptic densities, and multiple 
    mitochondria.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">The nigrotectal terminals contacted tectospinal cells of 
    different sizes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">The areas of our sample of eight tectospinal cells that 
    were contacted by nigrotectal terminals ranged from 247 to 769 km2 
    as measured in 50 pm sections through the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Even though no relationship was established between the 
    presence of nigrotectal contacts and soma size, tectospinal cells 
    may vary in their amount of nigrotectal input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Some cells within a dense zone of labeled terminals did 
    not appear to receive any contacts, whereas others received 
    multiple contacts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Figure 14 illustrates a tectospinal cell that was 
    surrounded by nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">The input to this cell was the maximum that we observed 
    in contact with an individual cell.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Control experiments.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">In the experiments in which<exptLabel><injectionLocation
    >spinal cord</injectionLocation> injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical></exptLabel> were not paired 
    with an injection in <injectionLocation>substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation>, <labelingDescription>no labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    superior colliculus</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s207">In 
    addition, <labelingDescription>no labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were found in the control sections 
    from the experiments in which <injectionLocation>spinal 
    cord</injectionLocation> <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injections were paired with <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injections in <injectionLocation>substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s208">The control sections in these 
    cases were processed with the diaminobenzidine to reveal the 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> reaction product, but were not 
    processed immunocytochemically to reveal the 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s209">These 
    two types of controls indicate that the spinal cord did not 
    contribute to the population of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> we observed in <labelingLocation>
    the superior colliculus</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s210">Finally, 
    our cases in which an injection in <injectionLocation>substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation> was not paired with an injection in 
    <injectionLocation>the spinal cord</injectionLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>did not label cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the superior colliculus</labelingLocation>, 
    indicating that the <injectionLocation>nigral</injectionLocation> 
    injections do not label 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> that could be 
    confounded with tectospinal cells in the experiments with paired 
    injections.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s211">GABAergic input to 
    predorsal bundle cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">In our material, <labelingDescription>GAD-immunoreactive 
    terminals</labelingDescription> were distributed throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the intermediate grey 
    layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">With the light microscope, many tectospinal cells 
    labeled with HRP could be seen to have multiple GAD-positive 
    terminals closely apposed to their somas and proximal dendrites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">An example is shown in Figure 15.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Electron microscopic examination of thin sections 
    through tissue containing labeled tectospinal cells and 
    GAD-positive terminals showed that synaptic contacts were made 
    between the labeled terminals and ceils (Fig. 16).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Similar to nigrotectal terminals, the GAD-positive 
    terminals contained pleomorphic vesicles and many mitochondria, and 
    formed synaptic contacts with modest postsynaptic densities on the 
    somas and proximal dendrites of tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Control sections incubated with preimmune serum instead 
    of the GAD antibody contained no labeled terminals.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s218">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">By utilizing the anterograde transport of either WGAHRP 
    or PHA-L in combination with the retrograde transport of HRP, the 
    present study directly demonstrates that the tectospinal component 
    of the predorsal bundle is synaptically contacted by nigrotectal 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">Thus, this study confirms the findings of Williams and 
    Faull(&apos;88) in the rat and Tokuno and Nakamura (&apos;87) in 
    the cat by demonstrating an anatomical basis for the influence of 
    substantia nigra over tectospinal cells (Chevalier et al., 
    &apos;81, &apos;84, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">These methods also allow us to examine the morphology of 
    a large number (201) of nigrotectal terminals and to compare them 
    to the GAD-immunoreactive terminals in contact with tectospinal 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">We will discuss the functional significance of these 
    observations in later sections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">As the present experiments showed, the anterograde 
    transport of WGA-HRP and PHA-L, when combined with the retrograde 
    transport of HRP, can be used to characterize with the light 
    microscope a terminal arbor in terms of its morphology and its 
    location with respect to the soma or dendritic process of a 
    putative postsynaptic cell, and then, with the electron microscope, 
    to confirm and describe the synaptic contacts formed by the same 
    array of terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Since whenever we saw terminals in close apposition to 
    labeled cells at the light microscopic level, they were found to 
    make synaptic contacts with those cells when examined with the 
    electron microscope, the light microscopic observations were useful 
    or answering questions about the relative distribution of 
    nigrotectal terminals on the dendrites and somas of the cells, 
    about the range in the sizes of cells contacted by the nigrotectal 
    tract, about the percentage of cells that receive nigral input, 
    and, finally, about variations among cells in the density of their 
    nigral input.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Although similar observations were made in our 
    experiments with both anterograde methods, the WGA-HRP method 
    provided better ultrastructural preservation, because higher 
    glutaraldehyde concentrations could be used and because no freezing 
    and thawing of the tissue was necessary.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Nevertheless, we found that the combination of PHA-L 
    with the retrograde transport of HRP was the most powerful for 
    examining the afferent connections of a cell identified by the 
    target of its axon.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">The PHA-L method was more sensitive than the WGA-HRP and 
    the preservation of the tissue with the PHA-L method was adequate 
    to examine ultrastructural details of synaptic contacts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Our confidence that we were indeed examining nigra 
    terminals was increased by the observations that all the terminals 
    had a similar fine structure, and that they resembled the 
    GADimmunoreactive terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">In addition, omitting the immunocytochemical step in 
    alternate sections provided a simple and effective control for the 
    possibility that the HRP injections labeled spinotedal terminals 
    that could be mistaken for nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s230">Potential sources of 
    error</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The most serious potential sources of error are the 
    possibilities that our procedures labeled terminals in the 
    intermediate grey layer that arose from a structure other than 
    substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">We have already mentioned the possibility that the HRP 
    injections in the spinal cord might label spinotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The controls for this possibility were necessary since 
    the spinotectal pathway terminates in the same layer that contains 
    the tectospinal cells (Antonetty and Webster, &apos;751, and since 
    spinotectal cells are located in the region of the spinal cord 
    injections (Edwards et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Nevertheless, in our control sections, we were unable to 
    find any terminals in the intermediate grey layer that were labeled 
    by the spinal cord injections, nor were we able to find labeled 
    terminals in more rostral targets of the spinal cord, such as the 
    ventrobasal, posterior, and intralaminar nuclei of the dorsal 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">The absence of significant label in these pathways might 
    be due to a failure of the HRP to transport in sufficient quantity 
    over the distance from the spinal cord to the midbrain and thalamus 
    or, perhaps, to different optimal survival times for the retrograde 
    and anterograde transport.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">A similar type of error could result if the substantia 
    nigra injections labeled fibers of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Indeed, in the cat, corticotectal fibers that originate 
    in the prefrontal region leave the cerebral peduncle and then turn 
    dorsal to pass through substantia nigra on their way to the 
    superior colliculus (Segal et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Furthermore, physiological studies in the cat have 
    suggested that some of the effects that have been attributed to 
    substantia nigra stimulation are, in fact, results of stimulating 
    these fibers of passage (Karabelas and Moschovakis, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">However, involvement of the corticotectal fibers does 
    not appear to be a risk in the rat, since the available evidence 
    suggests that these fibers do not traverse substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">In particular, studies using the anteroerade transDort 
    of tritiated amino acids or HR6 from the irefrontal *cortex have 
    shown that the pathway follows a more dorsal, transthalamic route 
    through the ventral and posterior nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Only the fibers from prefrontal cortex that terminate in 
    substantia nigra or the ventral tegmental region travel in the 
    cerebral peduncle (Beckstead, &apos;79; Hardy, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">These results imply that there are separate populations 
    of neurons in prefrontal cortex that project to the midbrain, and 
    that only those that project to the substantia nigra and ventral 
    tegmentum traverse the cerebral peduncle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">This separation of pathways is supported by experiments 
    using retrograde transport to locate the cells of origin of these 
    pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Cells labeled after substantia nigra injections are 
    located in the lateral prefrontal cortex (Bunney and Aghajanian, 
    &apos;76; Gerfen et al., &apos;821, whereas cells labeled following 
    superior colliculus injections are located in the medial prefrontal 
    cortex (Neafsy et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Taken together, these studies suggest that it is 
    unlikely that fibers projecting from prefrontal cortex to the 
    superior colliculus were labeled by our nigra injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Corticotectal fibers from the more caudal areas of 
    cortex also would not be labeled by our injections, since they 
    leave the peduncles and travel to the superior colliculus without 
    passing through substantia nigra (Lund, &apos;66).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Two other types of evidence provide further support for 
    the argument that substantia nigra is the source of the terminals 
    we observed in the intermediate grey layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">First, similar distributions of terminals were obtained 
    with both PHA-L and WGA-HRP, and PHA-L, in particular, is less 
    likely to be taken up and transported by fibers of passage (Gerfen 
    and Sawchenko, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Second, with both of these methods, the labeled 
    terminals exhibited a fine structure that is distinct from that 
    observed for corticotectal fibers (Behan, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">The differences between the nigrotectal and 
    corticotectal terminal morphologies are not a reflection of the 
    different methods used in the two studies, since trigeminotectal 
    terminals that resemble closely the corticotectal terminals have 
    been labeled using our PHA-L method (Gregory and Hall, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s251">Distribution of 
    predorsal bundle cells and organization of the superior 
    colliculus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">The present experiments showed that not only the somata 
    (Bickford and Hall, &apos;89), but also the dendrites of the rat 
    predorsal bundle cells are restricted primarily to the intermediate 
    grey layer, as defined by Weiner (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">This laminar distribution of the predorsal bundle cells 
    has significance for our understanding of the organization of the 
    superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Traditionally, the superior colliculus has been divided 
    into superficial and deep zones on the basis of differences in 
    connections and functions (Harting et al., &apos;73; Wurtz and 
    Albano, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">While this dichotomy is still useful for distinguishing 
    between the visuosensory and sensorimotor associations of these two 
    tiers, it may at times obscure what appears to be an equally 
    significant division between the intermediate and deep grey layers 
    of the deep zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">The distribution of predorsal bundle cells in the deep 
    zone provides one basis for this division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Specifically, retrograde transport experiments in a 
    variety of species have demonstrated that almost all of the 
    predorsal bundle cells are located in the intermediate grey layer 
    (Holcombe and Hall, &apos;81a; May and Hall, &apos;84; Lu et al., 
    &apos;85; Bickford and Hall, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Moreover, HRP injections into the decussation of the 
    predorsal bundle, which fill the dendrites as well as the somas of 
    these cells, show that almost their entire receptive surfaces also 
    are confined to this layer (May and Hall, &apos;84; Lu et al., 
    &apos;85; present experiments), with a limited extension of some 
    distal dendrites into the adjacent layers.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">The conclusion that the intermediate grey layer can be 
    distinguished from the deep grey layer by the distribution of 
    predorsal bundle cells also follows from experiments using 
    intracellular injections to examine the morphology and distribution 
    of these cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">For example, in a study of predorsal bundle cells in the 
    cat, all but a few X cells were located in the intermediate grey 
    layer (Moschovakis and Karabelas, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">The exceptional X cells were either in the immediately 
    adjacent part of the deep layer or in a lateral wedge of the deep 
    layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">The lateral wedge of the deep grey layer resembles a 
    similarly located area in the grey squirrel that contains predorsal 
    bundle cells (Holcombe and Hall, %la; May and Hall, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">In studies of the grey squirrel, this wedge was also 
    found to receive inputs that are characteristic of the intermediate 
    grey layer (May and Hall, &apos;84, &apos;86b) and, it could be 
    argued, might most appropriately be considered as forming its 
    ventrolateral tip.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">A similar lateral wedge of the deep grey layer receives 
    nigrotectal projections in the cat (Harting et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">In another study using intracellular methods, Grantyn 
    and Grantyn (&apos;82) found that two-thirds of the predorsal 
    bundle cells they injected in the cat resided in the intermediate 
    grey layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Rhoades et al. (&apos;87) appear to have found a 
    comparable distribution in the hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Similarly, in a study of the monkey, all the injected 
    cells were placed either in the intermediate grey layer or the 
    adjacent part of the optic layer, but not in the deep grey layer 
    (Moschovakis et al., &apos;88a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">These studies all support the argument that the 
    intermediate grey layer is the primary source of predorsal bundle 
    cells, and that this is a fundamental distinction between the 
    intermediate and deep grey layers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">In addition, the present experiments showed that one of 
    the predominant gazerelated inputs to the superior colliculus, the 
    projection from substantia nigra pars reticulata, overlaps 
    extensively with the predorsal bundle cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">The distributions of various other inputs to the deep 
    zone provide further, cross-species support for this distinction, 
    since not only substantia nigra pars reticulata (Graybiel, 
    &apos;78; Beckstead et al., &apos;79; Gerfen et al., &apos;82; May 
    and Hall, &apos;84; Harting et al., &apos;88; Harting and van 
    Lieshout, &apos;91) but also the deep cerebellar nuclei (Roldan and 
    Reinoso-Suarez, &apos;81; Kawamura et al., &apos;82; Sugimoto et 
    al., &apos;82; Uchida et al., &apos;83; May and Hall, &apos;86b; 
    May et al., &apos;go), the frontal eye field (Kiinzle et al., 
    &apos;76; Leichnetz, &apos;81; Huerta et al., &apos;861, the 
    midbrain tegmentum (Edwards, &apos;75; Moschovakis et al., 
    &apos;88b), the spinal trigeminal nucleus (Huerta et al., &apos;81; 
    Killackey and Erzurumlu, &apos;81; Huerta et al., &apos;83; Gregory 
    and Hall, &apos;88), the spinal cord (Antonetty and Webster, 
    &apos;751, the zonaincerta (Ricardo, &apos;81; Kim et al., 
    &apos;89), and the cholinergic cells of the pedunculopontine 
    tegmental nucleus (Beninato and Spencer, &apos;86; Hall et d., 
    &apos;89) project preferentially to the intermediate grey layer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Although many of these inputs have a projection to the 
    deep grey layer as well, it is much sparser and more diffusely 
    organized, without patches or other signs of intralaminar 
    organization.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">All of the inputs that terminate predominantly in the 
    intermediate grey layer are consistent with the prevailing view 
    that the predorsal bundle cells play a role in initiating orienting 
    movements.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">While cells in the deep grey layer may also be premotor 
    in function (Henkel and Edwards, &apos;78; Henkel, &apos;81; Vidal 
    et al., &apos;88; Dean et al., &apos;89) and also give rise to 
    descending-albeit primarily ipsilateral-pathways (Henkel, &apos;81; 
    Holcombe and Hall, &apos;81b; Redgrave et al., &apos;86; Bickford 
    and Hall, &apos;89)) they have their own preferential inputs, 
    including afferents from the supplementary cortical eye field 
    (Heurta and Kaas, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">These differences in efferent and afferent connections 
    seem sufficient to propose that the intermediate and deep grey 
    layers are as different functionally from each other as either is 
    from the more superficial layers.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s275">Evidence for parallel 
    efferent pathways in the predorsal bundle</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Evidence from several studies suggests that multiple 
    efferent pathways might be distinguished in the predorsal bundle 
    using the same general types of criteria that have been used to 
    distinguish parallel pathways in sensory systems.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">For example, in the present experiments, the cells 
    labeled following injections in the cervical spinal cord varied in 
    size.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">A recent study of tectospinal cells in rats and hamsters 
    reported a range of sizes similar to those we measured (Sahibzada 
    et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">In their experiments, the rat tectospinal cell soma 
    areas ranged from 50 to 650 p,m2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Similarly, Weber et al. (&apos;79) found a wide range of 
    tectospinal cell sizes in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">However, in other studies, the majority of cells labeled 
    by spinal cord injections were either large or from medium to large 
    in size (Castiglioni et al., &apos;78; Huerta and Harting, 
    &apos;82; Murray and Coulter, &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">To account for the variations in cell size, the argument 
    has been made that cells truncated by the sectioning process might 
    be erroneously counted as small cells (Huerta and Harting, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">However, even though truncated cells might account for 
    some of the variation observed in the present study, at least two 
    types of data clearly indicate that small as well as large cells 
    contribute to the tectospinal tract in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">First, labeled cells in the 50 km thick sections often 
    were located near the middle of the section, so that their somas 
    and proximal dendrites could be visualized and recognized as 
    complete, Both large and small cells were observed in this way.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Second, and perhaps most convincing, was the observation 
    in the electron micrographs of small labeled tectospinal cells that 
    had other associated distinguishing features, such as infolded 
    nuclear membranes and a reduced density of somatic synaptic 
    contacts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Norita (&apos;80) also has noted the relationship 
    between soma size and density of somatic contacts for 
    tectoreticular cells in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">To summarize, the evidence supports the conclusion that 
    tectospinal cells are distributed over a wide size range, and that 
    size is correlated with other features, such as density of somatic 
    contacts.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Recent studies using intracellular injections of HRP to 
    label the efferent cells of the superior colliculus also provide 
    strong evidence that the different cell types contributing to the 
    predorsal bundle can be distinguished by a combination of features, 
    including soma size.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">At least two of these types, T and X cells, contribute 
    to the predorsal bundle, but can be distinguished by other features 
    such as size, dendritic fields, sublaminar distribution, and 
    collateral projections (Karabelas and Moschovakis, &apos;85; 
    Moschovakis et al., &apos;88a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Furthermore, by recording from and then injecting cells 
    in alert monkeys, Moschovakis et al. (&apos;88b) were able to show 
    that T but not X cells discharge before all saccades in their 
    movement field.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">More indirect evidence suggests that the X cell category 
    may include the visually triggered saccaderelated cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">While these studies support the idea that multiple 
    parallel pathways contribute to the predorsal bundle, none directly 
    addresses the question of the significance of the differences in 
    cell size.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">If the relationship between cell size and recruitment 
    threshold established for lower motor neurons (Henneman and Olson, 
    &apos;65; Henneman et al., &apos;65a,b; Somjen et al., &apos;65) 
    applies to predorsal bundle cells, the smaller predorsal bundle 
    cells may have lower thresholds for activation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">The relationship found in the present study between soma 
    size and the density of somatic synapses might also influence the 
    order of activation of these cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Alternatively, Rhoades et al. (&apos;87) have shown in 
    the hamster that the soma size of predorsal bundle cells is related 
    to both the size of the dendritic field and axon diameter, and 
    therefore must have implications for receptive field organization 
    and conduction velocity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Finally, predorsal bundle cell size might be related to 
    the differences in terminal density within targets of the predorsal 
    bundle (Grantyn and Grantyn, &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s297">Nigrotectal input to 
    predorsal bundle cells</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Physiological studies have shown that the nigrotectal 
    tract provides a tonic, GABAergic, inhibitory influence on the 
    premotor cells of the superior colliculus (Hikosaka and Wurtz, 
    &apos;85a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Shortly before the onset of an orienting movement, the 
    nigrotectal cells are themselves inhibited, allowing the premotor 
    cells of the colliculus to respond with a burst of action 
    potentials and exert their effects on the gaze centers of the 
    brainstem and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Anatomical studies shed light on the morphological basis 
    for this pattern of nigrotectal influence on tectal premotor 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">In all species that have been studied, the terminal 
    field of the nigrotectal tract overlaps extensively with the cells 
    of the predorsal bundle in the intermediate grey layer (May and 
    Hall, &apos;84; Tokuno and Nakamura, &apos;87; Williams and Faull, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">In the rat, the close association between nigrotectal 
    terminals and predorsal bundle cells is further indicated by the 
    finding that the majority of tectospinal cells are located within 
    patches of nigrotectal terminals (Williams and Faull, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">We also observed this association between patches of 
    nigrotectal terminals and predorsal bundle cells, and, with maximal 
    labeling of both terminals and cells, found that nigrotectal 
    terminals were closely apposed to 73% of the tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">When eight tectospinal cells were subsequently examined 
    with the electron microscope, the terminals that appeared in the 
    light microscope to be closely apposed to their somas or dendrites 
    were found to make synaptic contact with the cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">In contrast, in a study of the cat, it was estimated 
    that only 22% of the tectospinal cells are within the patches 
    (Tokuno and Nakamura, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">However, this number may underestimate the percent of 
    tectospinal cells that actually receive nigrotectal input, for 
    while cat predorsal bundle cells are distributed throughout the 
    intermediate grey layer (Kawamura and Hasikawa, &apos;78; Grantyn 
    and Grantyn, &apos;82; Lu et al., &apos;85; Moschovakis and 
    Karabelas, &apos;85; Behan et al., &apos;88)) they have larger 
    dendritic fields than do rat predorsal bundle cells and may receive 
    significant input on their distal dendrites (Behan et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">The experiments using electron microscopy confirm the 
    association between the nigrotectal terminals and predorsal bundle 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">We observed nigrotectal fibers making synaptic contacts 
    with the somas and proximal dendrites of tectospinal cells and 
    similar results have been reported in studies of the rat and cat 
    that used anterograde degeneration as the marker for nigrotectal 
    terminals and retrograde transport of HRP as the label for 
    tectospinal cells (Tokuno and Nakamura, &apos;87; Williams and 
    Faull, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Since retrograde transport from the spinal cord does not 
    fill the entire cell, the evidence is equivocal concerning the 
    existence of inputs to more distal dendrites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Nevertheless, the majority of nigrotectal terminals 
    appear to contact small dendrites and it seems likely that at least 
    some of these dendrites belong to predorsal bundle cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">The finding by Behan et al. (&apos;88) that type I11 
    terminals make up the majority of terminals on the distal dendrites 
    of predorsal bundle cells, as well as on their somas and proximal 
    dendrites, is consistent with this view.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Type I11 terminals usually range from 0.5 to 1.5 km in 
    diameter, contain pleomorphic vesicles, and make symmetrical 
    contacts with dendrites and cell somas (Norita, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">These same features characterize the nigrotectal 
    terminals in the cat (Behan et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Two observations support the evidence based on GABA 
    immunocytochemistry and lectin retrograde transport that the 
    nigrotectal synapses on tectospinal cells use GABA as a 
    neurotransmitter (Ficalora and Mize, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">First, the distribution of nigrotectal terminals 
    overlaps the distribution of GAD-positive terminals on tectospinal 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Second, the ultrastructure of nigrotectal 
    terminals-regardless of whether they were labeled by anterograde 
    transport of WGA-HRP, PHA-L, or tritiated amino acids-is similar to 
    the ultrastructure of the terminals on predorsal bundle cells 
    labeled by the GAD antibodies (present experiments; Vincent et al., 
    &apos;78; Warton et al., &apos;83; Lu et al., &apos;85; Behan et 
    al., &apos;871, that is, in each case the terminals are filled with 
    pleomorphic vesicles, contain many mitochondria, and form synaptic 
    contacts with modest postsynaptic densities.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Taken together, these results provide a morphological 
    basis for the short latency inhibitory effects of substantia nigra 
    stimulation on predorsal bundle cells (Chevalier et al., &apos;84; 
    Moschovakis and Karabelas, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Several other morphological features may be related to 
    the high level of spontaneous activity exhibited by the nigrotectal 
    cells (Hikosaka and Wurtz, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">First, the fibers that give rise to terminal boutons 
    often are densely packed with vesicles.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">The large number of vesicles within both the terminal 
    boutons and the connecting fibers may be related to a high level of 
    neurotransmitter release.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Second, the large number of mitochondria in the 
    nigrotectal terminals also might indicate a high level of 
    neurotransmitter release, especially since GABA-transaminase, an 
    enzyme used in the metabolism of GABA, is localized primarily in 
    mitochondria (Cooper et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Finally, we often observed unlabeled processes of 
    unknown origin surrounding and extending into the nigrotectal 
    boutons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">These processes may be glial in origin and may be 
    involved in the uptake of GABA released at these synapses.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">We suggest this role because the GAD-positive terminals 
    that we examined had similar closely associated processes and 
    because glial cells have been shown to take up tritiated GABA in 
    the cat superior colliculus (Mize et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Even though our results indicate that most tectospinal 
    cells, regardless of their size, receive nigrotectal input, this 
    does not imply that all tedospinal cells receive equal amounts of 
    input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Indeed, we observed large variations in the degree to 
    which the somas and proximal dendrites of individual tectospinal 
    cells were contacted by labeled nigrotectal terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">These variations may have been due simply to vagaries in 
    the uptake and transport of the tracers, or they may indicate that 
    tectospinal cells vary in their connections with substantia 
    nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">The latter alternative is consistent with the results of 
    physiological studies suggesting that not all tectospinal cells are 
    influenced equally by the nigrotectal pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">For example, Chevalier et al. (&apos;84) found that 
    stimulation of substantia nigra could depress the excitability of 
    some tectospinal cells, or completely block the ability of others 
    to generate action potentials, or in some cells even delay the 
    invasion of antidromic potentials evoked from the spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Karabelas and Moschovakis (&apos;85) also found that 
    substantia nigra stimulation elicits a variety of responses from 
    predorsal bundle cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">This range of effects could be due to differences in the 
    density of nigrotectal terminals on tectospinal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Consequently, future investigations should be directed 
    toward determining whether nigral inputs are differentially 
    distributed on predorsal bundle cells of different morphologies, 
    and whether the differences are related to the destinations of 
    their axons.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s333">ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s334">This study was supported by 
    NIH EY-08233.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s335">We thank Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s336">Elizabeth Gregory for 
    technical assistance, Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s337">Celestine Smith for help in 
    preparing the manuscript, and Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s338">Paul J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s339">May for many helpful comments 
    on the text.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s340">Finally, we thank Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s341">Pamela Levine for performing 
    some of the pilot experiments for this study.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s342">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Adams, J.C. (1981) Heavy metal intensification 
    product.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Cytochem. 29t775.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Antonetty, C.M., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Webster (1975) The organisation of the spinotectal 
    projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">An experimental study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s353">163.449466.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Appell, P.P., and projections to M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Behan (1990) Sources of subcortical GABAergic the 
    superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">302,143-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Beckstead, R.M. (1979) An autoradiographic examination 
    of corticocortical and subcortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal-projection (prefrontal) cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neurol. 184t43-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Beckstead, R.M., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Nauta (1979) Efferent connections of the substantia 
    nigra and ventral tegmental area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Brain Res. 175t191-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Behan, M. (1984) An EM-autoradiographic analysis of the 
    projection from cortical areas 17,18 and 19 to the superior 
    colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Neurol. 225:591-604.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Behan, M., C.3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Lin, and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Hall (1987) The nigrotectal projection in the cat: An 
    electron microscope and autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Neuroscience 21529-539.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Behan, M., P.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Appell, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Graper (1988) Ultrastructural study of large efferent 
    neurons in the superior colliculus of the cat after retrograde 
    labeling with horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Neurol. 270t171184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Beninato, M., and R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Spencer (1986) A cholinergic projection to the rat 
    superior colliculus demonstrated by retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase and choline acetyltransferase 
    immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Neurol. 253.525-538.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Bickford, M.E., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Hall (1989) Collateral projections of predorsal bundle 
    cells of the superior colliculus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">283t86-106.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Bunney, B.S., and G.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Aghajanian (1976) The precise localization of nigral 
    derents in the rat as determined by a retrograde tracing 
    technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">I1 7t423435.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Castiglioni, A.J., M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Gallaway and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Coulter (1978) Spinal projections from the midbrain in 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Neurol. 178.329-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Chevalier, G., A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Thierry, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Shibazaki, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Ferger (1981) Evidence for a GABAergic inhibitory 
    nigrotectal pathway in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Lett.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">21:67-10.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Chevalier, G., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Vacher, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Deniau (1984) Inhibitory nigral influence on tectospinal 
    neurons, a possible implication of basal ganglia in orienting 
    behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Brain Res. 53t320-326.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Chevalier, G., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Vacher, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Deniau, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Desban (1985) Disinhibition as a basic process in the 
    expression of striatal functions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">The striatonigral influence on 
    tecto-spinal/tecto-diencephalic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Brain Res. 334.215-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Cooper, J.K., F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Bloom, and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Roth (1982) The Biochemical Basis of 
    Neuropharmacology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">New York: Oxford University Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Dean, P., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Redgrave, and G.W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Westby (1989) Event or emergency?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Two response systems in the mammalian superior 
    colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">TINS 12137147.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Edwards, S.B. (1975) Autoradiographic studies of the 
    projections of the midbrain reticular formation: Descending 
    projections of nucleus cuneiformis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Neurol. 161:341-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Edwards, S.B., C.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Ginsburgh, C.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Henkel, and B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Stein (1979) Sources of subcortical projections to the 
    superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Neurol. 184:309-330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Ficalora, AS., and R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Mize (1989) The neurons of the substantia nigra and zona 
    incerta which project to the cat superior colliculus are GABA 
    immunoreactive: A double-label study using GABA immunocytochemistry 
    and lectin retrograde transport.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Neuroscience 29:567-581.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Gerfen, C.R., W.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Staines, G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Arbuthnott, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Fibiger (1982) Crossed connections of the substantia 
    nigra in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">207283-303.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Grantyn, A,, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Grantyn (1982) Axonal patterns and sites of termination 
    of cat superior colliculus neurons projecting in the 
    tecto-bulbo-spinal tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Brain Res. 46243-256.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Grantyn, A., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Berthoz (1985) Burst activity of identified 
    tecto-reticulospinal neurons in the alert cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Brain Res. 57:417-421.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Graybiel, A.M. (1978) Organization of the nigrotectal 
    connection: experimental tracer study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Brain Res. 143:339-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Gregory, E., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Hall (1988) Characterization of trigeminotectal 
    afferents in the superior colliculus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Abstr. 14:1165.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Hall, W.C., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Fitzpatrick, L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Klatt, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Raczkowski (1989) Cholinergic innervation of the 
    superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Neurol. 287t495-514.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Hardy, S.G.P. (1986) Projections to the midbrain from 
    the medial versus lateral prefrontal cortices of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Lett. 63:159-164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Harting, J.K., W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Hall, I.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Diamond, and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Martin (1973) Anterograde degeneration study of the 
    superior colliculus in Tupaia glis: Evidence for a subdivision 
    between superficial and deep layers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s487">148:361386.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Harting, J.K., M.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Huerta, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Hashikawa, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Weber, and D.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Van Lieshout (1988) Neuroanatomical studies of the 
    nigrotedal projection in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Neurol. 278t615-631.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Harting, J.K. and D.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Van Lieshout (1991) Spatial relationships of axons 
    arising from the substantia nigra, spinal trigeminal nucleus, and 
    pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus within the intermediate grey of 
    the cat superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Neurol. 305:543-558.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Henkel, C.K. (1981) Afferent sources of a lateral 
    midbrain tegmental zone associated with the pinnae in the cat as 
    mapped hy retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Neurol. 203.213-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Henkel, C.K., and S.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Edwards (1978) The superior colliculus control of pinna 
    movements in the cat: Possible anatomical connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Neurol. 182:163-776.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Henneman, E., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Olson (1965) Relations between structure and function in 
    the design of skeletal muscles.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurophysiol. 28:581-598.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Henneman, E., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Somjen, and D.O.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Carpenter (1965a) Excitability and inhibitibility of 
    motoneurons of different sizes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Neurophysiol. 28:599620.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Henneman, E., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Somjen, and D.O.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Carpenter (1965b) Functional significance of cell size 
    in spinal motoneurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Neurophysiol. 28:560-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Hikosaka, O., and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Wurtz (1981) The role of substantia nigra in the 
    initiation of saccadic eye movements.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Fuchs and W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Becker (eds): Progress in Oculomotor Research.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Amsterdam: Elsevier/North Holland, pp. 145-152.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Hikosaka, O., and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Wurtz (1985a) Modification of saccadic eye movements by 
    GABA-related substances.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Effect of muscimol and bicuculline in monkey superior 
    colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Neurophysiol. 53:26&amp;291.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Hikosaka, O., and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Wurtz (1985b) Modification of saccadic eye movements by 
    GABA-related substances. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Effects of muscimol in the monkey substantia nigra pars 
    reticulata.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Neurophysiol. 53292-308.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Holcombe, V., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Hall (1981a) The laminar origin and distribution the 
    crossed tectoreticular pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Neurosci. 1:1103-1112.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Holcombe, V., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Hall (1981b) Laminar origin of ipsilateral tectopontine 
    pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Neuroscience 6.255-260.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Huerta, M.F., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Harting (1982) Tectal control of spinal cord activity: 
    Neuroanatomical demonstration of pathways connecting the superior 
    colliculus with the cervical spinal cord grey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">In H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Kuypers and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Martin (eds): Descending Pathways to the Spinal Cord, 
    Progress in Brain Research, Vol. 57.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 293-328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Huerta, M.F., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Kaas (1990) Supplementary eye field as defined by 
    intracortical microstimulation: Connections in macaques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Neurol. 293:299330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Huerta, M.F., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Frankfurter, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Harting (1981) The trigeminocollicular projection in the 
    cat: Patch-like endings within the intermediate gray.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Brain Res. 211:l-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Huerta, M.F., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Frankfurter, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Harting (1983) Studies of the principal sensory and 
    spinal trigeminal nuclei of the rat Projections to the superior 
    colliculus, inferior olive, and cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">220:147-167.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Huerta, M.F., L.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Krubitzer, and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Kaas (1986) Frontal eye field as defined by 
    intracortical microstimulation in squirrel monkeys, owl monkeys, 
    and macaque monkeys: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Subcortical connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Neurol. 253:415439.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Karabelas, A.B., and A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Moschovakis (1985) Nigral inhibitory termination on 
    efferent neurons of the superior colliculus: An intracellular 
    horseradish peroxidase study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Neurol. 239:309-329.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Kawamura, K., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Hashikawa (1978) Cell bodies of origin of reticular 
    projections from the superior colliculus in the cat: An 
    experimental study with the use of horseradish peroxidase as a 
    tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">182:l-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Kawamura, S., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Hattori, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Higo, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Matsuyama (1982) The cerebellar projections to the 
    superior colliculus and pretectum in the cat: An autoradiographic 
    and horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Neuroscience.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">7:1673-1689.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Keller, E.L. (1979) Colliculoreticular organization in 
    the oculomotor system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">In R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Granit and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Pompeiano (eds): Reflex Control of Posture and Movement, 
    Progress in Brain Research, Vol. 50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 725-734.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Killackey, H.P., and R.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Erzurumlu (1981) Trigeminal projections superior 
    colliculus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Neurol. 201:221-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Kim, U., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Gregory, and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Hall (1989) Connections between a ventral, GABAergic 
    subdivision of zona incerta and the superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Abstr. 15.239.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Kunzle, H., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Akert, and R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Wurtz (1976) Projection of area 8 (frontal eye field) to 
    superior colliculus in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Brain Res. 11 7:487492.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Leichnetz, G.R., R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Spencer, S.G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Hardy, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Astruc (1981) The prefrontal corticotectal projection in 
    the monkey; an anterograde and retrograde horseradish peroxidase 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Neuroscience 6: 1023-1041, S.M., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">-S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Lin, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Behan, N.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Cant, and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Hall (1985) Glutamate decarboxylase immunoreactivity in 
    the intermediate grey layer of the superior colliculus in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Neuroscience 16:123-131.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Lund, R.D. (1966) The occipitotectal pathway of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Anat. 100:51-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">May, P.J., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">Hall (1984) Relationships between the nigrotectal 
    pathway and the cells of origin of the predorsal bundle.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">226:357-376.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">May, P.J., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Hall (1986a) The sources of the Neuroscience 
    19:159-180.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">May, P.J., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Hall (1986b) The cerebellotectal pathway squirrel.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Brain Res. 65200-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">May, P.J., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Hartwich-Young, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Nelson, D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Sparks, and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Porter (1990) Cerebellotectal pathways in the macaque: 
    Implications for collicular generation of saccades.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Neuroscience 36:305-324.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">McLean, I.W., and P.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Nakane (1974) Periodate-lysine-paraformaldehyde 
    fixative: A new fixative for immunoelectron microscopy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Cytochem. 22:1077-1083.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Mize, R.R., R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Spencer, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Sterling (1981) Neurons and glia in cat superior 
    colliculus accumulate [HSI-gamma-aminobutyic acid (GABA).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Neurol. 202385-396.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Moschovakis, A.K., and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Karabelas (1985) Observations on the somatodendritic 
    morphology and axonal trajectory of intracellularly HRPlabeled 
    efferent neurons located in the deeper layers of the superior 
    colliculus of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Neurol. 239376-308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Moschovakis, A.K., A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Karabelas, and S.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Highstein (1988a) Structurefunction relationships in the 
    primate superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Morphological classification of efferent neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Neurophysiol. 60232-262.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Moschovakis, A.K., A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Karabelas, and S.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Highstein (1988b) Structurefunction relationships in the 
    primate superior mlliculus. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Morphological identity of presaccadic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Neurophysiol. 60r263-302.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Munoz, D.P., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Guitton (1985) Tectospinal neurons in the cat have 
    discharges coding gaze position error.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Brain Res. 341:184-188.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Munoz, D.P., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Guitton (1986) Presaccadic burst discharges of 
    tectoreticulo-spinal neurons in the alert head-free and -fixed 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Brain Res. 398:185-190.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Murray, E.A., and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Coulter (1982) Organization of tedospinal in the cat and 
    rat superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Brain Res. 243:201-214.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Neafsey, E.J., K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Hurley-Gius, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Asvanitis (1986) The topographical organization of 
    neurons in the rat medial frontal, insular and olfactory cortex 
    projecting to the solitary nucleus, olfactory bulb, periaqueductal 
    gray and superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Brain Res. 377:261-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Norita, M. (1980) Neurons and synaptic patterns in the 
    deep layers of the superior colliculus of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">A Golgi and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Neurol. 190t29-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Oertel, W.H., D.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Schmechel, M.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Tappaz, and I.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Kopin (1981) Production of a specific antiserum to rat 
    brain glutamic acid decarboxylase by injection of an 
    antigen-antibody complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Neuroscience 6t2689-2700.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Peters, A., S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Palay, and H. de F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Webster (1976) The Fine Structure of the Nervous System: 
    The Neurons and Supporting Cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Philadelphia: W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Saunders Company.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Redgrave, P., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Odekunle, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Dean (1986) Tectal cells of origin of predorsal bundle 
    in rat: Location and segregation from ipsilateral dewending 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Brain Res. 63t279-293.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Rhoades, R.W., R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Mooney, B.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Klein, M.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Jacquin, A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Szczepanik, and N.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Chiaia (1987) The structural and functional 
    characteristics of teetospinal neurons in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Neurol. 255451465.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Ricardo, J.A. (1981) Efferent connections of the 
    subthalamic region in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">The zona incerta.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Brain Res. 214t43-60.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Roldh, M., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Reinoso-Suirez (1981) Cerebellar projections to the 
    superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Neurosci. 1:827-834.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Sahibzada, N., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Yamasaki, and R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Rhoades (1987) The spinal and mmmissural projections 
    from the superior colliculus in rat and hamster arise from distinct 
    neuronal populations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Brain Res. 415242-256.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Segal, R.L., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Beckstead, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Kersey, and S.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Edwards (1983) The prefrontal corticotectal projection 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Brain Res. 51r423432.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Somjen, G., D.O.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Carpenter, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Henneman (1965) Responsesof motoneurons of different 
    sizes to graded stimulation of supraspinal centers of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Neurophysiol. 28r958-965.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Straus, W. (1982) Imidazole increases the sensitivity of 
    the cytochemical reaction for peroxidase with diaminobenzidine at a 
    neutral pH.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Cytochem. 30t491-493.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Sugimoto, T., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Mizuno, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">Uchida (1982) Distribution of cerebellar fiber terminals 
    in the midbrain visuomotor areas: An autoradiographic study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Brain Res. 238:353-370.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Tokuno, H., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Nakamura (1987) Organization of the nigrotectospinal 
    pathway in the cat: A light and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Brain Res. 436:7684.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Uchida, K., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Mizuno, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Sugimoto, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Itoh, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Kudo (1983) Direct projections from the cerebellar 
    nuclei to the superior colliculus in the rabbit: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Neurol. 216319-326.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Vidal, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">-P., P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">May, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">Baker (1988) Synaptic organization of the tectal-facial 
    pathways in the cat: Synaptic potentials following collicular 
    stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Neurophysiol. 6Ot769-797.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Vincent, S.R., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Hattori, and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">McGeer (1978) The nigrotectal projection: A biochemical 
    and ultrastructural characterization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">Brain Res. 151r159-164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Wallace, M.N. (1986) Lattice of high oxidative 
    metabolism in the intermediate grey layer of the rat and hamster 
    superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Lett. 70:320-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Warton, S., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Jones, I.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Ilinsky, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Kultas-Ilinsky (1983) Nigral and cerebellar synaptic 
    terminals in the intermediate and deep layers of the cat superior 
    colliculus revealed by lesioning studies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Neuroscience 10:78% 800.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Weber, J.T., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">Martin, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Behan, M.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Huerta, and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Harting (1979) The precise origin of the tectospinal 
    pathway in three common laboratory animals: A study using the 
    horseradish peroxidase method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Lett. 11:121-127.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Weiner, S.I. (1986) Laminar distribution and patchiness 
    of eytochrome oxidase in mouse superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Neurol. 244t137-148.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Williams, M.N., and R.L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">Faull (1988) The nigrotectal projection and teetospinal 
    neurons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">A light and electron microscopic study demonstrating a 
    monosynaptic nigral input to identified tectospinal neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Neuroscience 25533-562.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Wurtz, R.H., and J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Albano (1980) Visual-motor function of the primate 
    superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Neurosci. 3: 189-226.</S>
  </References>

</File>

