<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Localization of Cholinergic Neurons in the Forebrain and 
  Brainstem That Project to the Suprachiasmatic Nucleus of the 
  Hypothalamus in Rat</Title>

  <Authors>KESHAVAN G. BINA, BENJAMIN RUSAK, AND KAZUE SEMBA</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">In mammals, the suprachiasmatic nucleus is responsible for 
    the generation of most circadian rhythms and their entrainment to 
    environmental cues.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Cholinergic agents can alter circadian rhythm phase, and 
    fibres immunoreactive for choline acetyltransferase, the 
    biosynthetic enzyme for acetylcholine, are present in the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Since there are no cholinergic somata in the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus, these fibres must represent the terminals 
    of cholinergic neurons whose cell bodies are located elsewhere in 
    the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">This study was aimed at locating the cholinergic neurons 
    that project to the suprachiasmatic nucleus by retrograde and 
    anterograde tract-tracing and immunohistochemistry for choline 
    acetyltransferase in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">After injection of fluorogold, a retrograde tracer, into 
    the suprachiasmatic nucleus, retrogradely labelled neurons that 
    were immunopositive for choline acetyltransferase were located 
    throughout the rostrocaudal extent of the cholinergic basal nuclear 
    complex, with highest densities in the substantia innominata and 
    the nucleus basalis magnocellularis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">A few cells were also located in the medial septum and in 
    the vertical and horizontal limbs of the diagonal band of Broca.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">In the brainstem, double-labelled neurons were located in 
    the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus, pedunculopontine tegmental 
    nucleus and the parabigeminal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Injections of the anterograde tracer biocytin in these 
    three brainstem nuclei resulted in fibre labelling in the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus, consistent with the retrograde 
    findings.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">No clearly double-labelled cells were located in the 
    retina.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">These results suggest that the suprachiasmatic nucleus 
    receives cholinergic afferents from both the basal forebrain and 
    mesopontine tegmentum which may mediate cholinergic effects on 
    circadian rhythms. c 1993 Wiley-Liss, Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Circadian rhythms are endogenously generated rhythms with 
    a period of about 24 hours.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Under natural conditions these circadian rhythms are 
    synchronized to environmental cues such as illumination and 
    temperature cycles.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">In mammals, the generation of circadian rhythms in 
    behaviour and physiology and their synchronization to environmental 
    cues are regulated by neural mechanisms centered in the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus (SCN) of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Evidence supporting this role for the SCN comes from a 
    variety of approaches (for reviews see Meijer and Rietveld, 
    &apos;89; Rusak, &apos;89; Hastings et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Brief light pulses administered to animals maintained in 
    continuous darkness are capable of shifting the phase of their 
    behavioural and physiological rhythms in a direction which depends 
    on the time of administration of the pulse.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Light exposure in the early subjective night delays, and 
    in the late subjective night advances, the onset of activity 
    rhythms (DeCoursey, &apos;64; Daan and Pittendrigh, &apos;76; 
    Pittendrigh and Daan, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Such phase-dependent responses can be summarized as a 
    phase response curve, plotting the type of phase shift produced 
    against the circadian phase of application.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">The phase response curve for intraventricularly 
    administered carbachol, a nonspecific cholinergic agonist, has been 
    shown to mimic partially the pattern of sensitivity to the phase 
    shifting effects of light in rats, mice and hamsters (Zatz and 
    Brownstein, &apos;79; Zatz and Herkenham, &apos;81; Earnest and 
    Turek, &apos;83,&apos;85; Meijer et al., &apos;88; Bina and Rusak, 
    &apos;91), suggesting that acetylcholine (ACh) may play a role in 
    the photic entrainment pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Additional evidence for a cholinergic role comes from 
    evidence that nicotinic receptor antagonists block the phase 
    shifting effects of light on pineal serotonin N-acetyltransferase 
    (Zatz and Brownstein, &apos;81) and locomotor activity (Keefe et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Electrophysiological studies have shown that cells in the 
    SCN are responsive to iontophoretically applied ACh, both in vivo 
    and in vitro (Nishino and Koizumi, &apos;77; Kow and Pfaff, 
    &apos;84; Miller et al., &apos;871, implicating the existence of 
    cholinergic receptors within the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">However, evidence against the presence of such receptors 
    exists (for review, see Rusak and Bina, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">In brief, the rat SCN itself is not labelled with either 
    3H-acetylcholine or 3H-nicotine (Segal et al., &apos;78; Clarke et 
    al., &apos;85; van der Zee et al., &apos;911, but a-bungarotoxin 
    binds to sites in a region dorsal and lateral to the SCN (Segal et 
    al., &apos;78; Block and Billiar, &apos;81; Miller et al., 
    &apos;82; Fuchs and Hoppens, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">It is known, however, that a-bungarotoxin binds strongly 
    to nicotinic receptors in the peripheral nervous system (Martin et 
    al., &apos;89) but not to those in the central nervous system 
    (Clarke et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Fibres containing choline acetyltransferase (CUT), the 
    biosynthetic enzyme for ACh, have been localized in the rat SCN 
    (van den Pol and Tsujimoto, &apos;85; Ichikawa and Hirata, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">In the absence of evidence for ChAT in SCN neurons, these 
    fibres can be assumed to derive from sources extrinsic to the 
    SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">However, the location of the neurons which contribute 
    these fibres is not known.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The SCN receives a projection from cells in the basal 
    forebrain (Pickard, &apos;821, a region that is known to contain 
    cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Therefore, this region appears to be a likely source of 
    the cholinergic projection to the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Consistent with this possibility, Fuller et al. 
    (&apos;89) reported in an abstract that neurons in the diagonal 
    band of Broca project to the SCN and also contain 
    acetylcholinesterase (AChE), an enzyme involved in the degradation 
    of ACh.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The present study was carried out in rats to clarify the 
    anatomy of cholinergic input to the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The study involved visualization of fibres and fibre 
    terminals immunopositive for ChAT in the SCN by means of a 
    sensitive immunocytochemical technique (Ojima et al., &apos;88) to 
    confirm the presence of cholinergic fibres in the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Then a retrograde tracer, fluorogold, was injected into 
    the SCN, in combination with immunohistochemistry for CUT, to 
    identify cholinergic neurons in the forebrain and brainstem (major 
    brain areas containing cholinergic projection neurons) as afferent 
    sources of these fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">These projections were further confirmed by injecting an 
    anterograde tracer, biocytin, into the brainstem cholinergic nuclei 
    and visualizing biocytin-labelled fibres and terminals in the 
    SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">A preliminary report of this study has been presented 
    (Bina et al., &apos;90a).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s35">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Three separate sets of experiments were carried out to 
    identify cholinergic cells which project to the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The first study used a sensitive immunocytochemical 
    method to visualize fibres and terminals expressing ChAT 
    immunoreactivity in the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The second study involved retrograde tracing with 
    fluorogold (Fluorochrome, Englewood, CO) as the tracer, injected 
    into the SCN, and evaluation of both forebrain and brainstem 
    cholinergic cell regions as potential sources of the cholinergic 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The third set of studies used biocytin (Sigma Chemical 
    Co., St.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Louis, MO) as an anterograde tracer, which was injected 
    into brainstem cholinergic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Anterograde studies were not performed for projections 
    from the forebrain because, in comparison to cholinergic neurons in 
    the brainstem, forebrain cholinergic neurons are more diffusely 
    distributed, and very large injections spanning, but also 
    restricted to, the entire rostrocaudal extent of the cholinergic 
    basal nuclear complex would have been very difficult to produce.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">In addition, the cholinergic nature of the anterogradely 
    labelled fibres could not be confirmed because although the 
    combination of ChAT immunofluorescence and fluorescence-conjugated 
    avidin for biocytin would be a most suitable method for this 
    purpose, the immunofluorescence of ChAT-positive fibres in the SCN 
    was not sufficiently intense to permit clear identification of 
    double labelling, with the protocol used in the present study (see 
    below).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Two different antibodies to ChAT were used in the present 
    study: a monoclonal antibody (Boehringer Mannheim, Montreal), and a 
    polyclonal antibody raised in rabbit (Chemicon International, 
    Temecula, CA).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The specificity of both antibodies has previously been 
    documented (Eckenstein and Thoenen, &apos;82; Bruce et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">It was also initially confirmed in a double 
    immunofluorescence experiment that the two antibodies label 
    identical cell populations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">In some cases where both antibodies were tried in 
    conjunction with retrograde labelling, the pattern of labelling was 
    the same.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">However, background staining with the two antibodies 
    varied to some extent depending on the tissue under investigation, 
    as well as the protocol used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Thus, for the best results, in the experiment which 
    examined CUT-immunoreactive fibres, the monoclonal antibody was 
    used preferentially, because the protocol used in this experiment, 
    originally developed by Ojima et al. (&apos;881, specifically 
    required the use of this antibody for visualizing fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">In the retrograde labelling study, the polyclonal 
    antibody was usually used to process brain sections because it 
    appeared to provide slightly clearer staining with less background, 
    especially for immunofluorescence.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">For retinal sections, however, the monoclonal antibody 
    was used preferentially because the use of this antibody in our 
    protocol resulted in clearer staining with less background in 
    retinal tissues.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">It should be noted, however, that despite these slight 
    differences, the two antibodies clearly identified the same 
    populations of cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">All control sections which were incubated with the 
    omission of the primary antibodies showed no specific labelling.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Male Sprague Dawley rats weighing 200-250 g, obtained 
    from Charles River Canada (St.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Constant, Quebec), were housed under a 12: 12 light-dark 
    schedule, with free access to food and water.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s55">ChAT-immunoreactive fibre 
    localization in the SCN</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The protocol for perfusion and immunohistochemistry was 
    as described by Ojima et al. (&apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">This protocol was developed specifically for visualizing 
    ChAT-immunoreactive fibres and terminals with the monoclonal 
    antibody against ChAT from Boehringer-Mannheim.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Two rats were deeply anaesthetized by an intraperitoneal 
    (i.p.1 injection of sodium pentobarbital (65 mgikg) and perfused 
    for a few seconds with 0.1 M phosphate buffer (PB; pH 7.4) 
    containing 0.002% calcium chloride followed by an ice cold fixative 
    consisting of 4% paraformaldehyde and 0.2% glutaraldehyde in PB, 
    for 3 minutes and then for a further 10 minutes by 4% 
    paraformaldehyde alone; all perfusions were done at a rate of 10 
    mlimin.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The brain was immediately removed, blocked and postfixed 
    in 4% paraformaldehyde at 4째C for 12 hours.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The brain was transferred to buffered 30% sucrose at 4째C 
    overnight, rapidly frozen with dry ice and cut on a cryostat into 
    40 pm sections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The sections were collected in 0.1 M Tris-buffered saline 
    (TBS; pH 7.3), rinsed in three TBS washes of 20 minutes each and 
    incubated in TBS containing 0.1% Triton X-100 for 20 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The sections were then treated with normal goat serum 
    (1:30) in TBS for 1 hour at room temperature and incubated in a 
    monoclonal antibody against ChAT (1:2.5; Boehringer-Mannheim) with 
    1:30 normal goat serum and 0.1% Triton X-100 at 37째C on a shaker 
    for 2 days.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Subsequently, the sections were rinsed in TBS and 
    incubated for 1 hour in goat anti-rat IgG (1:50) in TBS containing 
    1.8% bovine serum albumin, 1:30 normal goat serum and 0.1% Triton 
    X-100.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">The sections were then rinsed, incubated for 1 hour in 
    rat peroxidase-antiperoxidase complex (1230) in TBS containing 1.8% 
    bovine serum albumin, rinsed again and incubated in 0.06% 
    diaminobenzidine in 0.1 M phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4) for 10 
    minutes and labelling was subsequently visualized with 0.006% 
    hydrogen peroxide.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">The sections were mounted on gelatinized slides, 
    airdried, dehydrated through an ascending alcohol series, 
    coverslipped with Permount and viewed through an Olympus 
    microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Immunoreactive fibres in selected sections were drawn 
    with the aid of a drawing tube attached to the microscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s67">Retrograde tracing</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Injection and perfusion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Animals were anaesthetized with sodium pentobarbital (65 
    mg/kg, i.p.) and positioned in a Kopf stereotaxic holder with the 
    incisor bar set 5 mm above the interaural line.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Unilateral injections of 8% fluorogold (in distilled 
    water) were made into the SCN through a glass microelectrode 
    (outside tip diameter of 25-35 km) positioned at 1.2 mm anterior to 
    bregma and 0.2 mm lateral to the midline and lowered 9.8 mm ventral 
    to the dura.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Fluorogold was delivered iontophoretically with a 
    positive current of 2 FA administered over 10 minutes with a duty 
    cycle of 5 seconds on and 5 seconds off.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">At the end of the injection, the micropipette was kept in 
    place for 5-10 minutes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">After one week survival in their normal lighting cycle, 
    animals were deeply anaesthetized with sodium pentobarbital.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The descending aorta was clamped and the animal perfused 
    intracardially with 60 ml of 0.9% saline followed by 400 ml of ice 
    cold 4% paraformaldehyde made in 0.1 M PB (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Brains were postfixed for 4-5 hours in the same fixative 
    solution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Coronal sections 50 Fm thick were cut from the forebrain 
    and the brainstem on a microslicer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">After confirmation of injection sites, every sixth 
    section was washed in 0.05 M TBS and then processed for 
    immunohistochemistry for ChAT.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Eyeballs with the retina attached were removed after 
    perfusion and cryoprotected in 30% sucrose for 24 hours.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Coronal sections 50 Frn thick were cut perpendicular to 
    the anteroposterior axis of the eyeball on a cryostat and collected 
    directly onto glass slides.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Sections were washed in TBS and processed for 
    immunohistochemistry for CUT.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Forebrain and brainstem sections were incubated for 48 
    hours at 4&quot;C, in a polyclonal antibody raised in rabbit 
    against ChAT (Chemicon), diluted to 1:lOO in antisera diluent (0.3% 
    Triton X-100, 2.0% normal goat serum and 0.01% sodium azide added 
    to 0.05 M TBS).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Subsequent to 3 x 20 minute rinses in TBS, the tissue was 
    incubated in 1:20 dilution of Texas red conjugated goat anti-rabbit 
    IgG (Jackson Immunoresearch, West Grove, PA) in TBS and 1% normal 
    goat serum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Sections were mounted on slides, and dried overnight.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Retinal sections mounted on slides were processed with 
    the monoclonal antibody to ChAT ( l : l O , Boehringer-Mannheim) 
    and a Texas red-conjugated goat anti-rat IgG (Jackson 
    Immunoresearch) as a secondary antibody.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">All sections were coverslipped with either 1:9 
    concentration of ethylene diamine (Sigma) in glycerol or 
    Fluoromount and examined with an Olympus epifluorescence 
    microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">Fluorogold labelling was examined with an ultraviolet 
    filter cube, and Texas red using a green filter cube.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">All retrogradely labelled cells which were also labelled 
    with ChAT were mapped by using standardized section drawings 
    modified from Paxinos and Watson (&apos;861, and selected examples 
    were photographed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s89">Anterograde tracing</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">Biocytin was used as the anterograde tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">This tracer is transported rapidly and allows the 
    placement of discrete injections as well as visualization of 
    Golgi-like terminal morphology.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">It was also originally claimed not to be taken up by 
    fibres of passage (King et al., &apos;89; Izzo, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">After the completion of the present study, however, a 
    paper questioning this claim has been published (Chevalier et al., 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Rats were anaesthetized as described above and placed on 
    a Kopf stereotaxic holder with the incisor bar 3.3 mm below the 
    interaural line.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">Injections of 50 nl of biocytin (5% in 0.05 M Tris 
    buffer, pH 7.6) were made into the pedunculopontine tegmental 
    nucleus (PPT; coordinates: 7.3 mm posterior to bregma, 1.8 mm 
    lateral to the midline and 5.5 mm ventral to the dura), the 
    parabigeminal nucleus (PBg; coordinates: 7.7 mm posterior, 2.9 mm 
    lateral and 6.5 mm ventral to surface of the skull) or the 
    laterodorsal tegmental nucleus (LDT; coordinates: 8.5 mm posterior, 
    0.9 mm lateral and 6.5 mm ventral to dura) through a glass 
    micropipette (tip diameter 30 pm) attached to a 1 p1 Hamilton 
    syringe.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">The injections were made over a period of 10 minutes and 
    the pipette was left in place for a further 5 minutes following the 
    injection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">After survival periods ranging from 12 to 20 hours, the 
    animals were given a lethal dose of pentobarbital and perfused 
    transcardially with an initial rinse of 0.9% physiological saline 
    followed by a mixture of 4% paraformaldehyde and 1% glutaraldehyde 
    in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">Brains were rapidly removed and postfixed overnight in 4% 
    paraformaldehyde.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">Coronal sections of the forebrain 50 pm thick containing 
    the SCN region and the brainstem (to localize the injection site) 
    were cut on a microslicer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">The sections were thoroughly washed in TBS (pH 7.4) and 
    processed for histochemistry to visualize biocytin.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Histochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Free floating sections were incubated in 0.5% hydrogen 
    peroxide for 30 minutes in order to decrease nonspecific 
    labelling.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">Sections were washed in TBS for 30 minutes and 
    subsequently preincubated in 1% Triton X-100 in TBS for 60 minutes 
    followed by incubation in Extravidin-peroxidase conjugate (Sigma) 
    at a concentration of 1:20 for 2 hours.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">The reaction product was visualized by preincubating the 
    tissue in diaminobenzidine (0.5 mgiml) for 5 minutes followed by 
    incubation in a mixture of diaminobenzidine and hydrogen peroxide 
    (0.5 ml /ml of a 30% solution) for about 10 minutes or until the 
    brown reaction product was visible.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">Since dihydro nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide 
    phosphate (NADPH) diaphorase activity has been shown to be a 
    selective marker for cholinergic neurons in the PPT and LDT 
    (Vincent et al., &apos;831, this quick histochemical method was 
    used to process the tissue further to determine whether the 
    biocytin injection site in the brainstem overlapped with 
    cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">NADPH-diaphorase histochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Following biocytin histochemistry, the brainstem 
    sections were processed for NADPH-diaphorase histochemistry 
    (Scherer-Singler et al., &apos;83) to examine the relationship 
    between injection sites and cholinergic cell populations in the 
    brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">The sections were incubated in a mixture of P-NADPH 
    (Sigma; 10 mg/10 ml) and nitroblue tetrazolium (Sigma; 1 mg/10 ml) 
    in Tris buffer (pH 8.0) at 37째C for 5-10 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">This reaction was performed in the dark, since nitroblue 
    tetrazolium is light sensitive.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">In cases where the injection site was acceptable, all 
    sections were mounted on gelatinized slides, air dried, dehydrated 
    in an ascending series of alcohols and coverslipped in Permount.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">The sections were viewed through an Olympus microscope 
    and in selected cases photographed.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s112">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s113">
    <labelingDescription>ChAT-immunoreactive 
    fibres</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    SCN</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114"><labelingDescription>Scattered ChAT-immunoreactive 
    fibres and terminals</labelingDescription> were found throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the entire rostrocaudal extent of the 
    SCN</labelingLocation> (Fig. 1).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">These fibres displayed occasional varicosities.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">Most of <labelingDescription>the fibre 
    labelling</labelingDescription> was localized to 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral aspects of the 
    SCN</labelingLocation>, but <labelingDescription>a few 
    fibres</labelingDescription> were also found in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal SCN</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">In addition, <labelingDescription>CUT-immunoreactive 
    fibres</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    optic chiasm</labelingLocation> ventral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the SCN</neuroanatomicalLandmark> as well 
    as between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the two 
    SCN</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118"><labelingDescription>No CUT-immunoreactive 
    fibres</labelingDescription> were observed in 
    <labelingLocation>anterior hypothalamic and preoptic 
    regions</labelingLocation> surrounding <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    SCN</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">Figure 1B-D shows the location of<labelingDescription> 
    ChAT-immunoreactive fibres</labelingDescription> at three levels 
    (rostral, middle and caudal) of <labelingLocation>the 
    SCN</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s120">ChAT-immunoreactive 
    neurons retrogradely labelled with fluorogold</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>Forebrain</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">Separate animals were used for the studies of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the forebrain, brainstem, and the 
    retina</neuroanatomicalLocation> because these experiments were 
    conducted at different times.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">For the forebrain study, 3<exptLabel>of the 12 rats 
      had <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> injections 
      localized in <injectionLocation>the 
      SCN</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">All three injection sites were mainly unilateral with 
      some diffusion into <injectionSpread>the contralateral 
      SCN</injectionSpread> as well as <injectionSpread>the optic 
      chiasm</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">An example of a 
      <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> injection site is 
      shown in Figure 2A; the retrogradely labelled cholinergic neurons 
      in this case are mapped in Figures 3 and 4.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">Figure 2 shows an example of <labelingDescription>a 
      neuron</labelingDescription> located in <labelingLocation>the 
      substantia innominata region</labelingLocation> of the 
      cholinergic basal nuclear complex that was retrogradely labelled 
      with fluorogold and immunopositive for ChAT.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">ChAT-positive neurons that were retrogradely labelled 
      from the SCN were typically large and multipolar.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128"><labelingDescription>These double-labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were observed bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the entire rostrocaudal extent of the 
      cholinergic basal nuclear complex</labelingLocation>, but there 
      were regional differences in the density of these double-labelled 
      cells (Figs. 3 and 4).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129"><labelingDescription>The largest numbers of 
      double-labelled neurons</labelingDescription> were located in 
      <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata and nucleus basalis 
      magnocellularis of the cholinergic basal nuclear 
      complex</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A-C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130"><labelingDescription>Scattered double-labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were localized in <labelingLocation>
      the medial septum</labelingLocation> as well as <labelingLocation>
      the vertical and horizontal limbs of the diagonal band of 
      Broca</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3B-D, 4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">The double-labelled neurons were intermingled with 
      ChAT-positive neurons without the retrograde marker, as well as 
      singly retrogradely labelled immunonegative neurons in these 
      regions, and no obvious topography of doublelabelled neurons was 
      seen within subregions of the cholinergic basal nuclear 
      complex.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">Within the cholinergic complex, single retrogradely 
      labelled neurons without ChAT immunoreactivity occurred more 
      frequently at rostral than caudal levels, and at caudal levels 
      almost all retrogradely labelled neurons were 
      ChAT-immunoreactive.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133">In addition to the cholinergic basal nuclear complex, 
      consistent with previous reports (Pickard, &apos;821, 
      <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> that were not 
      ChAT-immunoreactive but <labelingDescription>retrogradely 
      labelled with fluorogold</labelingDescription> were found in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septum (Fig. 3A,B), medial preoptic 
      area (Figs. 3D,4A,B), contralatera1 SCN (Fig. 4C), zona incerta 
      (Fig. 4D), and intergeniculate leaflet of the lateral geniculate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Bminstem</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">Two rats used in the brainstem study had their 
      injection sites in <injectionLocation>the 
      SCN</injectionLocation>, but with some diffusion to 
      <injectionSpread>the contralateral SCN</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136">An example is shown in Figure 5; the diffusion into 
      the contralateral side was greater in this case than the case 
      shown in Figure 2A.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137"><labelingDescription>Neurons</labelingDescription> 
      that were <labelingDescription>retrogradely labelled with 
      fluorogold</labelingDescription> and were also ChAT-positive were 
      seen in <labelingLocation>the PPT (Fig. 6A,D), LDT (Fig. 6B,E) 
      and PBg (Fig. 6C,F)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138">Some neurons singly labelled with fluorogold were also 
      present in these three nuclei.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139">No obvious topographic differences were seen between 
      <labelingDescription>double and single retrogradely labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the PPT, 
      LDT or PBg</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140">Figure 7 illustrates the distribution of 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      brainstem</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s141">In addition to double-labelled neurons, consistent 
      with previous findings (Pickard, &apos;821, 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labelled immunonegative 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were found occasionally in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal and median raphe nuclei (Fig. 7B,C), 
      superior colliculus (Fig. 7A,B), dorsal tegmental nucleus (Fig. 
      7E), and parabrachial nucleus (Fig. 7D-F)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142"><labelingDescription>No double-labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>
      any of these nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Retina</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144">In the 3 rats used in the retina study, injection 
      sites were unilateral but included <injectionLocation>the SCN as 
      well as part of the optic chiasm ventral to 
      it</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145">Most of <labelingDescription>the ChAT-immunoreactive 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      retina</labelingLocation> were located in <labelingLocation>the 
      inner nuclear layer</labelingLocation>, most likely corresponding 
      to a subpopulation of amacrine cells.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146"><labelingDescription>Scattered 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ganglion 
      cell layer</labelingLocation> were also 
      <labelingDescription>immunopositive for 
      CUT</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147"><labelingDescription>Many cells</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingDescription>singly labelled with 
      fluorogold</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>
      the ganglion cell layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148">However, although there were a few ambiguous cases, 
      there were no unequivocal cases of retinal cells that were 
      retrogradely labelled with fluorogold and were also 
      immunopositive for CUT.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s149">Anterograde labelling 
    with biocytin</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150"><tracerChemical>Biocytin</tracerChemical> injections 
    directed at <injectionLocation>PPT, PBg, and 
    LDT</injectionLocation> were made in two animals each.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Figure 8A-C shows examples of 
    <tracerChemical>biocytin</tracerChemical> injections placed in 
    <injectionLocation>PPT, PBg, and LDT</injectionLocation>, 
    respectively.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">The location of the injection sites overlapped with 
    NADPH-diaphorase positive (thus cholinergic; Vincent et al., 
    &apos;83) neurons in <labelingLocation>the PPT and 
    LDT</labelingLocation> (not shown).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Cholinergic PBg neurons are not NADPH-diaphorase 
    positive; therefore, anatomical landmarks were used to determine 
    the location of the injection site.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154"><labelingDescription>Scattered 
    anterogradely</labelingDescription> labelled 
    <labelingDescription>fibres and terminals</labelingDescription> 
    were detected in <labelingLocation>the SCN</labelingLocation> after 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>biocytin</tracerChemical> injections 
    into <injectionLocation>PPT, (Fig. 8A, D), LDT (Fig. 8B, E), and 
    PBg (Fig. 8C, F)</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s155">In each 
    case, <labelingDescription>these fibres</labelingDescription> were 
    found throughout <labelingLocation>the entire rostrocaudal extent 
    of the SCN</labelingLocation>, and their density was usually 
    greater than that seen with CUT-immunoreactive fibres (Fig. 
    1).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Following <exptLabel>injections into <injectionLocation>
    PBg and PPT</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, 
    <labelingDescription>fine fibres</labelingDescription> could be 
    seen entering <labelingLocation>the SCN</labelingLocation> through 
    the optic chiasm (Fig. 8E,F).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">In <exptLabel>the case of <injectionLocation>
    PPT</injectionLocation> injections</exptLabel>, 
    <labelingDescription>thicker fibres</labelingDescription> could 
    also be seen coursing through <labelingLocation>the optic 
    chiasm</labelingLocation> at the level of the caudal SCN, and 
    <labelingDescription>a few scattered fibres</labelingDescription> 
    were also observed in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158"><labelingDescription>Extensive fibre 
    labelling</labelingDescription> was also observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the basal forebrain area</labelingLocation> 
    following both <exptLabel><injectionLocation>PPT and 
    LDT</injectionLocation> injections</exptLabel>.</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s159">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">ChAT-immunoreactive fibres were detected in the SCN, 
    suggesting the existence of cholinergic input into the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Cholinergic fibers appeared to enter the SCN from the 
    ventral aspect via the optic chiasm.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">These results are consistent with txevious findings (van 
    den Pol and Tsujimoto, 85; Ichikawa and Hiratay 86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">Ichikawa and Hirata ( 86) Observed very dense C 
    hAT-positive fibres in the ventromedial aspect of the rat SCN with 
    fine mesh-like CUT-positive fibres distributed elsewhere within the 
    SCN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">In the present study, although we observed many fibres 
    in the ventromedial aspects of the SCN, we did not find the dense 
    labelling observed by Ichikawa and Hirata (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">This disparity in the findings may be due to the 
    different sources of antibodies as well as different 
    immunohistochemical techniques used in the two studies.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Neurons retrogradely labelled from the SCN were found in 
    both the basal forebrain and the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">In the basal forebrain, cells labelled with fluorogold 
    and immunopositive for C U T were found in the entire rostrocaudal 
    extent of the cholinergic basal nuclear complex with highest 
    densities occurring in the caudal nuclei, including the nucleus 
    basalis magnocellularis and substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Noncholinergic retrogradely labelled cells were observed 
    in the lateral septum, lateral geniculate nucleus, and zona 
    incerta.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Although no cholinergic cells were found in the lateral 
    septum in the present study, a small cluster of weakly 
    CUT-immunoreactive neurons has been localized in the lateral septum 
    (Kimura et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Retrogradely labelled neurons projecting to the SCN have 
    been reported in hamsters using free horseradish peroxidase as a 
    retrograde tracer (Pickard, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">That study reported retrogradely labelled neurons in 
    lateral septum, medial septum, and the vertical limb of the 
    diagonal band of Broca.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">No labelled cells were found in the horizontal limb of 
    the diagonal band of Broca, magnocellular preoptic area, or any of 
    the caudal nuclei of the cholinergic basal nuclear complex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">In the present study, however, many retrogradely 
    labelled cells were found not only in the medial septum but also 
    throughout the cholinergic basal nuclear complex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The differences between the results of these two studies 
    may be due to the type of tracer used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Fluorogold has been shown to be superior to horseradish 
    peroxidase as a retrograde tracer, and its sensitivity is 
    reportedly comparable to that of wheat germ agglutinin-horseradish 
    peroxidase (Schmued and Fallon, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">It has also been reported that fluorogold is not taken 
    up by undamaged fibres of passage, and that there is little or no 
    transsynaptic labelling, since long survival times do not appear to 
    result in increased cell labelling (Schmued and Fallon, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Another possible explanation for the disparity between 
    the two studies is species differences, since the study by Pickard 
    (&apos;82) was done using Syrian hamsters rather than rats.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Although not identified in the present study, the 
    presence of short cholinergic projections to the SCN arising in an 
    anterior hypothalamic region lateral to the SCN has previously been 
    reported in two abstracts.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Fuller et al. (&apos;89) used AChE histochemistry as a 
    marker for cholinergic cells and horseradish peroxidase as a 
    retrograde tracer, and reported double-labelled cells in the 
    diagonal band and an area lateral to and beyond the boundary of the 
    SCN (referred to as &apos;LASCN,&apos; not to be confused with the 
    lateral SCN) in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Although AChE is not a selective marker for cholinergic 
    neurons (Satoh et al., &apos;831, a similar result was found by 
    Dwyer et al. (&apos;90) in the hamster, by using 
    immunohistochemistry with a polyclonal antibody to ChAT and 
    rhodamine-conjugated latex microspheres as the retrograde 
    tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">The presence of cholinergic neurons in the regions 
    surrounding the SCN is controversial, because although these 
    regions appear to contain ChAT-immunoreactive neurons (Tago et al., 
    &apos;871, no neurons containing mRNA for ChAT are present (Oh et 
    al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">In the present study, no ChAT-labelled neurons were 
    found in the area lateral to the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">This difference between our results and those of Fuller 
    et al. (&apos;89) and Dwyer et al. (&apos;90) may be attributable 
    to species differences or differences in the sensitivity of the 
    antibodies used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">On the other hand, while neurons bearing cholinergic 
    markers may exist lateral to the SCN, we found no evidence of 
    retrograde labelling in this region.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Since our fluorogold tracing identified other 
    projections to the SCN that had been described previously, the 
    sensitivity of the retrograde tracer does not appear to be a 
    problem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">On the basis of these data, therefore, it seems unlikely 
    to us that the rat SCN receives a projection from neurons in this 
    region lateral to the SCN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">In the brainstem, retrogradely labelled cholinergic 
    neurons were localized in three distinct nuclei, namely the PPT, 
    PBg and LDT.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">As previously reported (Tago et al., &apos;89), the PPT 
    and LDT contain strongly ChAT-positive neurons, whereas neurons in 
    the PBg are only weakly ChAT-immunoreactive.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">A recent study using in situ hybridization has reported 
    high levels of mRNA for ChAT in the PPT and LDT, but very low 
    levels in the PBg (Oh et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Previous studies do not report fibre labelling in the 
    SCN following injections of the anterograde tracers wheat germ 
    agglutinin-horseradish peroxidase or Phaseolus 
    uulgaris-leucoagglutinin into the LDT (Satoh and Fibiger, &apos;86; 
    Cornwall et al., &apos;go), whereas following the injection of 
    Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin into the PPT, although not noted 
    by the authors, labelled fibres appear to be present in the SCN 
    (Hallanger and Wainer, &apos;88; their Fig. 3D).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Consistent with the latter observation, retrogradely 
    labelled neurons have been observed in the PPT region following 
    horseradish peroxidase injections into the retrochiasmatic area and 
    caudal part of the SCN (Zaborszky et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">The present retrograde labelling data also suggest that 
    in addition to cholinergic projections from the PPT and LDT 
    regions, there are also projections arising from noncholinergic 
    neurons that are mixed with cholinergic neurons in the same 
    regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">This provides one explanation for the fact that the 
    density of fibres anterogradely labelled with biocytin from the 
    PPT, LDT, or PBg was greater than that of ChAT-immunoreactive 
    fibres in the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">An alternate but not mutually exclusive explanation is 
    that the immunohistochemical procedures used in the present study 
    were not sensitive enough to reveal all cholinergic fibres in the 
    SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">At present, the neurotransmitter content of these 
    noncholinergic projections from the PPT, LDT, and PBg regions is 
    not known.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Retrogradely labelled neurons in the PBg have been 
    visualized in the cat following horseradish peroxidase injections 
    into the optic chiasm with diffusion of the tracer into the SCN 
    (Baleydier and Magnin, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The PBg is known to innervate the contralateral superior 
    colliculus (Mufson et al., &apos;86) through a long loop which 
    ascends along the optic tract, crosses the midline in Gudden&apos;s 
    supraoptic commissure, and returns along the contralateral optic 
    tract (Graybiel, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">It is most likely that some of these fibres reach the 
    SCN at the most rostra1 level of this loop.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">It is, however, also possible that the labelling in the 
    PBg in the present study is, in part, due to leakage of the tracer 
    into the optic tract and its uptake by potential damaged fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">This possibility is suggested by the observation of a 
    few retrogradely labelled cells in the superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Since the superior colliculus projects to the lateral 
    posterior nucleus of the thalamus through the supraoptic 
    commissure, the observation of retrogradely labelled cells in the 
    superior colliculus suggests that there was some leakage of the 
    tracer into the supraoptic commissure.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Therefore some of the PBg neurons labelled by fluorogold 
    may be the neurons projecting to the superior colliculus via the 
    optic tracts.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Anterogradely labelled fibres were observed in the SCN 
    following biocytin injections into PPT, PBg and LDT.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">In view of a recent report of the uptake of this tracer 
    by passing fibres (Chevalier et al., &apos;921, the possibility 
    exists that these labelled fibers in the SCN actually represented 
    fibres which passed through these brainstem regions but arose from 
    neurons whose cell bodies were located further caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">This is particularly a concern for injections in the 
    PPT, which is located amongst various fibre tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Despite this caveat, however, these anterograde 
    labelling results confirm that the retrogradely labelled neurons 
    observed in these brainstem nuclei following fluorogold injections 
    into the SCN were not entirely due to the tracer being taken up by 
    damaged fibres of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">With all three injections, thin biocytin labelled fibres 
    and terminals were observed in the entire rostrocaudal extent of 
    the SCN with the highest density being found in the ventral SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Observation of labelled fibres in the basal forebrain 
    area in the cases of PPT and LDT injections and in the lateral 
    hypothalamus in the case of PPT injections are consistent with 
    previous findings (Satoh and Fibiger, &apos;86; Hallanger and 
    Wainer, &apos;88; Cornwall et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Although it was not technically feasible to confirm the 
    cholinergic nature of fibres anterogradely labelled from the 
    brainstem, the presence of ChATimmunoreactive fibres in the SCN 
    combined with the retrograde and anterograde tracing data provide 
    strong support for the presence of cholinergic projections from the 
    basal forebrain and mesopontine tegmentum to the SCN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">The absence of clearly double-labelled cells in the 
    retina indicates that few, if any, retinal ganglion cells 
    projecting to the SCN are cholinergic.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">This conclusion does not imply that cholinergic effects 
    on rhythms cannot be mediated in part via the retina, since 
    noncholinergic ganglion cells projecting to the SCN could readily 
    be influenced by connections from retinal cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Cholinergic neurons in the cholinergic basal nuclear 
    complex and in the mesopontine tegmentum have been implicated in 
    the regulation of sleep and arousal (Steriade and McCarley, 
    &apos;90; Semba, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">In addition, carbachol has been shown to produce phase 
    shifts in circadian rhythms in rodents.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">These findings and the present results taken together 
    suggest that ACh released from the cholinergic neurons in the basal 
    forebrain and brainstem influence the resetting of the circadian 
    clock.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The basal forebrain area containing cholinergic neurons 
    has been shown to receive retinal terminals in both hamsters and 
    rats (Youngstrom et al., &apos;91; Bina, &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Thus, it is possible that photic input reaching the 
    cholinergic basal nuclear complex activates these cholinergic 
    cells, resulting in the release of ACh in the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">This ACh could then act either directly on pacemaker 
    cells, or indirectly through interneurons that make synaptic 
    connections with pacemaker cells, to alter clock mechanisms, 
    thereby contributing to a phase shift of circadian rhythms.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">The new phase of the clock would be transmitted to the 
    forebrain, brainstem and thalamic nuclei involved in the generation 
    and maintenance of sleep and arousal and to autonomic nuclei, 
    presumably via polysynaptic pathways from the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">This model proposes a feedback loop in which neural 
    mechanisms involved in the regulation of sleep and wakefulness are 
    linked to the area responsible for circadian timing of these 
    processes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">One missing link to this hypothesis is that it is not 
    known whether the retinal fibres entering the basal forebrain 
    terminate on cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">In addition, there are no direct efferent projections 
    from the SCN to the cholinergic basal nuclear complex, to the 
    aminergic (the dorsal raphe and the locus coeruleus) and 
    cholinergic brainstem nuclei involved in sleep and arousal, or to 
    any of the autonomic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Indirect and amplified connections to these nuclei made 
    via the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus, the major 
    target of SCN efferents, do however, remain a possibility (Watts et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">These studies and previously published results provide 
    strong evidence to suggest that cholinergic cells located in 
    several distinct cholinergic nuclei in the basal forebrain and in 
    the PPT, LDT and PBg of the brainstem project to and terminate 
    throughout the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">There are populations of both M1 and M2 muscarinic 
    receptors in the SCN on which ACh released from these terminals may 
    act (Bina et al., &apos;90b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">The cellular components on which these receptors are 
    localized have yet to be identified.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s226">ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s227">The authors thank Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s228">Wolfgang Hartig for help with 
    biocytin tracing techniques and Joan Burns, Janette Nason, Donna 
    Goguen, and Heather Grant for excellent technical assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s229">This work was supported by 
    grants from the US Air Force Office of Scientific Research (901041, 
    MRC of Canada (MA89291 and NSERC of Canada (A0305) to B.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s230">Rusak, and from MRC of Canada 
    (MT113121, Alzheimer Society, and Scottish Rite Charitable 
    Foundation of Canada to K.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s231">Semba.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s232">K.G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s233">Bina was supported by a 
    Dalhousie Killam Graduate Fellowship.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s234">K.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s235">Semba is an MRC scholar.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s236">This study was included as 
    part of a dissertation submitted by K.G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s237">Bina in partial fulfillment 
    of the requirements for a Ph.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s238">D. degree at Dalhousie 
    University.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Baleydier, C., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Magnin (1979) Afferent and efferent connections of the 
    parabigeminal nucleus in cat revealed by retrograde axonal 
    transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Brain Res. 161 :187-198.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Bina, K.G. (1992) Anatomical and behavioural analysis of 
    the role of acetylcholine and nerve growth factor in the mammalian 
    circadian system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Ph.D. dissertation, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova 
    Scotia, Canada.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Bina, K.G., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Rusak (1991) Intracranial nerve growth factor injections 
    phase shift activity rhythms in Syrian hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Abstr. 17:669.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Bina, K.G., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Semba, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Rusak (1990a) Localization of cholinergic and nerve 
    growth factor-receptor neurons projecting to the suprachiasmatic 
    nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Abstr.16:601.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Bina, K.G., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Wilkinson, and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Rusak (1990b) Circadian variation in muscarinic binding 
    sites in the cortex and hypothalamus of the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Biol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Rhythms Abstr. 2:102.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Block, G.A., and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Billiar (1981) Properties and regional distribution of 
    nicotinic cholinergic receptors in the rat hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Brain Res. 212: 152-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Bruce, G., B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Wainer, and L.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Hersh (1985) Immuno-affinity purification of human 
    choline acetyltransferase: Comparison of the brain and placental 
    enzymes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Neurochem. 45:611-620.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Chevalier, G., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Deniau, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Menetrey (1992) Evidence that biocytin is taken up by 
    axons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Lett. 140:197-199.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Clarke, P.B.S., R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Schwartz, S.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Paul, C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Pert, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Pert (1985) Nicotinic binding in rat brain: 
    Autoradiographic comparison of PHI acetylcholine, nicotine, and 
    ~&apos;25111-a-bungarotoxin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Neurosci. 5: 1307-1315.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Cornwall, J., J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Cooper, and O.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Phillipson (1990) Afferent and efferent connections of 
    the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Bull. 25:271-284.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Daan, S., and C.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Pittendrigh (1976) A functional analysis of circadian 
    pacemakers in nocturnal rodents. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">The variability of phase response curves, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Physiol. 106:253-266.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">DeCoursey, P.J. (1964) Function of a light response 
    rhythm in hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Cell.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Physiol. 63:189-196.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Dwyer, M.R., M.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Harrington, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Rahmani (1990) Localization of choline acetyltransferase 
    immunoreactive (CAT-I) cells afferent to the suprachiasmatic nuclei 
    (SCN) in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Abstr. 16:602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Eckenstein, F., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Thoenen (1982) Production of specific antisera and 
    monoclonal antibodies to choline acetyltransferase: 
    Characterization and use for identification of cholinergic 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">EMBO J. 1 :363-368.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Earnest, D.J., and F.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Turek (1983) Role for acetylcholine in mediating effects 
    of light on reproduction.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Science 219:77-79.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Earnest, D.J., and F.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Turek (1985) Neurochemical basis for the photic control 
    of circadian rhythms and seasonal reproductive cycles: Role for 
    acetylcholine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">USA 8242774281.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Fuchs, J.L., and K.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Hoppens (1987) a-bungarotoxin binding in relation to 
    functional organization of the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Brain Res. 407:9-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Fuller, C.A., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Nayduch, and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Murakami (1989) AChE positive neurons that project to 
    the SCN.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Abstr. 151059 Graybiel, A.M. (1978) A satellite of the 
    superior colliculus: The parabigeminal nucleus and its projections 
    to the superficial collicular layers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Brain Res. 145:365-374.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Hallanger, A.E., and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Wainer (1988) Ascending projections from the 
    pedunculopontine and laterodorsal tegmental nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Neuroscience 28: 61 1-623.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Hastings, J.W., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Rusak, and Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Boulos (1991) Circadian rhythms: physiology of 
    biological timing.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">In C.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Prosser (ed.): Neural Integrative Animal Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">New York: Wiley-Liss, pp. 435-546.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Ichikawa, T., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Hirata (1986) Organization of choline 
    acetyltransferasecontaining structures in the forebrain of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Neurosci. 6:281-292.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Izzo, P.N. (1991)A note on the use ofbiocytin in 
    anterograde tracing studies in the central nervous system: 
    Application at both light and electron microscopic level.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Methods 36155-166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Keefe, D.L., D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Earnest, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Nelson, J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Takahashi, and F.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Turek (1987) A cholinergic antagonist, mecamylamine, 
    blocks the phase-shifting effects of light on the circadian rhythm 
    of locomotor activity in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Brain Res. 4031308-312.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Kimura, H., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Tago, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Akiyama, L.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Hersh, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Tooyama, and P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">McGeer (1991) Choline acetyltransferase immunopositive 
    neurons in the lateral septum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Brain Res. 533:165-170.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">King, M.A., P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Louis, B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Hunter, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Walker (1989) Biocytin: A versatile anterograde 
    neuroanatomical tract-tracing alternative.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Brain Res. 497:361-367.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Kow, L., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Pfaff (1984) Suprachiasmatic neurons in tissue slices 
    from ovariectomized rats: Electrophysiological and 
    neuropharmacological characterization and effects of estrogen 
    treatment.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Brain Res. 297:275-286.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Martin, B.R., E.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Onaivi, and T.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Martin (1989) What is the nature of mecamylamine&apos;s 
    antagonism of the central effects of nicotine?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Biochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Pharmacol. 38:339 1-3397.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Meijer, J.H., and W.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Rietveld (1989) The neurophysiology of the 
    suprachiasmatic circadian pacemaker in rodents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Rev. 69:671-707.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Meijer, J.H., E. van der Zee, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Dietz (1988) The effects of intraventricular carbachol 
    injections on the free-running activity rhythm of the hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Biol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Rhythms. 4:333-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Miller, J.D., D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Murakami, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Fuller (1987) The response of suprachiasmatic neurons of 
    the rat hypothalamus to photic and nicotinic stimuli.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Neurosci. 7:978-986.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Miller, M.M., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Silver, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Billiar (1982) Effects of ovariectomy on the binding of 
    [&apos;2s11-a-bungarotoxin (2.2 and 3.3) to the suprachiasmatic 
    nucleus of the hypothalamus: An in vivo autoradiographic 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Brain Res. 24 7:355-364.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Mufson, E.J., T.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Martin, D.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Mash, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Wainer, and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Mesulam (1986) Cholinergic projections from the 
    parahigeminal nucleus (Ch8) to the superior colliculus in the 
    mouse: a combined analysis of horseradish peroxidase transport and 
    choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Brain Res. 370:144-148.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Nishino, H., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Koizumi (1977) Responses of neurons in the 
    suprachiasmatic nuclei of the hypothalamus to putative 
    transmitters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Brain Res. 120:167-172.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">J.D., N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Woolf, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Roghani, R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Edwards, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Butcher (1992) Cholinergic neurons in the rat central 
    nervous system demonstrated by in situ hybridization of choline 
    acetyltransferase mRNA.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Neuroscience 47807-822.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Ojima, H., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Yamasaki, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Kojima, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Akashi (1988) Immunohistochemical conditions for 
    staining choline acetyitransferase-containing terminals in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Stain Technol. 63:137-143.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Second ed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Pickard, G.E. (1982) The afferent connections of the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus of the golden hamster with emphasis on the 
    retinohypothalamic projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Neurol. 21 155-83.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Pittendrigh, C.S., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Daan (1976) A functional analysis of circadian 
    pacemakers in nocturnal rodents IV.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Entrainment: Pacemaker as clock.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Physiol. 106:291-331.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Rusak, B. (1989) The mammalian J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Biol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Rhythms4:121-134.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Rusak, B., and K.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Bina (1990) Neurotransmitters circadian system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Neurosci. 13:387-401.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Satoh, K., D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Armstrong, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Fibiger (1983) A comparison of the distribution of 
    central cholinergic neurons as demonstrated byacetyicholinesterase 
    pharmacohistocheniistry and choline acetyltransferase 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Bull. 11:693-720.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Satoh, K, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Fibiger (1986) Cholinergic neurons of the laterodorsal 
    tegniental nucleus: Efferent and afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Neurol. 253:277-302.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Scherer-Singler, U., S.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Vincent, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Kimura, and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">McGeer (1983) Demonstration of a unique population of 
    neuron with NADPHdiaphorase histochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Methods 9:229-234.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Schmued, L.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Fallon (1986) Fluoro-Gold: A new fluorescent retrograde 
    axonal tracer with numerous unique properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Brain Res. 377: 147-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Segal, M., Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Dudai, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Amsterdam (1978) Distribution of an 
    a-bungarotoxin-binding cholinergic nicotinic rtsceptor in rat 
    brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Brain Res. 148:105-119.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Semba, K. (1991) The cholinergic basal forebrain: A 
    critical role in cortical arousal.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">In T.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Napier, P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Kalivas, and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Hanin (eds.): The Basal Forebrain: Anatomy to 
    Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">New York: Plenum, pp. 197-218.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Steriade, M., and R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">McCarley (1990) Brainstem Control of Wakefulness and 
    Sleep.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">New York: Plenum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Tago, H., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">McGeer, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Bruce, and L.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Hersh (1987) Distribution of choline 
    acetyltransferase-containing neurons of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Brain Res. 415:49-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Tago, H., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">McGeer, E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">McGeer, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Akiyama, and L.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Hersh (1989) Distribution of choline acetyltransferase 
    immunopositive structures in the rat brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Brain Res. 495:271-297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">den Pol, A.N. and K.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Tsujimoto (1985) Neurotransmitters of the hypothalamic 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus: Immunocytochemical analysis of 25 
    antigens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Neuroscience 151049-1086.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">der Zee, E.A., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Streefland, A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Strosberg, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Schroder, and P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Luiten (1991) Colocalization of muscarinic and nicotinic 
    receptors in cholinoceptive neurons of the suprachiasmatic region 
    in young and aged rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Brain Res. 542348-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Vincent, S.R., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Satoh, D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Armstrong, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Fibiger (1983) NADPHdiaphorase: a selective 
    histochemical marker for the cholinergic neurons of the pontine 
    reticular formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Lett. 43:31-36.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Watts, A.G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Swanson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Sanchez-Watts (19871 Efferent projections of the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Studies using anterograde transport of phaseolus 
    vulgaris leucoagglutinin in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Neurol. 255:204-229.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Youngstrom, T.G, M.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Weiss, and A.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Nunez (1991) Retinofugal projections to the 
    hypothalamus, anterior thalamus and basal forebrain in hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Bull. 26:403-411.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Zahorszky, L., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Csuha, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Rosdy, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">MrzeyandM.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Palkovits (1984) Cells of origin of fibres to the 
    retrochiasmatic area: A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Acta Morphol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Hungar. 32251-278.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Zatz, M., and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Brownstein (1979) Intraventricular carbachol mimics the 
    effects of light on the circadian rhythm in the rat pineal 
    gland.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Science 203:358-360.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Zatz, M., and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Brownstein (1981) Injection of alpha-bungarotoxin near 
    the suprachiasmatic nucleus blocks the effects of light on 
    nocturnal pineal enzyme activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Brain Res. 2131438-442.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Zatz, M., and M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Herkenham (19811 Intraventricular the phase-shifting 
    effects of light on the circadian running activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Brain Res. 212:234-238.</S>
  </References>

</File>

