<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Afferent and Efferent Connections of the A5 Noradrenergic Cell 
  Group in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>CHRISTOPHER E. BYRUM AND PATRICE G. GUYENET</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The supraspinal afferent and efferent connections of the 
    A5 noradrenergic cell group were examined in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Very small deposits of HRP-WGA were made in the rostra1 A5 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Catecholamine histofluorescence techniques were used to 
    confirm that the deposits overlapped the A5 column.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Retrogradely labeled cells were present in the 
    perifornical area and paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus, 
    the Kolliker-Fuse nucleus, dorsal parabrachial area, intermediate 
    and caudal portions of the nucleus of the solitary tract, and the 
    ventral medullary reticular formation in the areas of the A1 and B1 
    cell groups.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Anterograde HRP-WGA labeling was found in several areas of 
    the subcortical CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The contribution of A5 neurons to this labeling was 
    confirmed with retrogradely transported fluorescent latex 
    microspheres combined with catecholamine histofluorescence 
    techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The A5 cell group was found to have significant 
    projections to the central nucleus of the amygdala, perifornical 
    area of the hypothalamus, midbrain periaqueductal gray, 
    parabrachial area, and the nucleus of the solitary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Other A5 projections include the paraventricular nucleus 
    of the thalamus, the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, and 
    possibly the zona incerta and lateral and dorsal hypothalamic 
    areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">In addition, A5 neurons may innervate the ventrolateral 
    reticular formation of the medulla.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Virtually all of the areas innervated by A5 noradrenergic 
    neurons are involved in cardiovascular regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">In addition, the A5 area receives afferent input from 
    major cardiovascular regulatory centers of the supraspinal CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Thus the A5 cell group has the potential to exert a 
    significant influence on the cardiovascular regulatory system.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The A5 noradrenergic cell group of the ventrolateral pons 
    appears to play an important but still poorly defined role in 
    autonomic regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The vast majority of these neurons project to the spinal 
    cord and primarily innervate the thoracolumbar intermediolateral 
    cell column (IML) and central autonomic area in the rat (Loewy et 
    al., &apos;79a; Westlund et al., &apos;83; Byrum et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The activity of A5 neurons is powerfully inhibited by 
    increases in arterial pressure, an effect apparently mediated by 
    peripheral receptors (Andrade and Aghajanian, &apos;82; Guyenet, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Moreover, electrical and chemical stimulation of the A5 
    area produces changes in blood pressure and heart rate (Loewy et 
    al., &apos;79b; Close et al., &apos;82; Neil and Loewy, &apos;82a; 
    Stanek et al., &apos;84; Woodruff et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Finally, selective destruction of the A5 noradrenergic 
    cells with 6-hydroxydopamine (6OHDA) alters baroreflex responses 
    (Stornetta et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">The direct projection of A5 noradrenergic neurons to the 
    thoracolumbar IML suggests that this cell group may exert an 
    important influence on spinal sympathetic outflow, and the 
    physiological evidence is consistent with participation of A5 
    neurons in cardiovascular regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Moreover, the A5 cell group may have connections with 
    supraspinal structures involved in cardiovascular regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Anterograde and retrograde tracing studies have 
    demonstrated descending projections from unidentified cells in the 
    A5 area to the nucleus of the solitary tract, dorsal motor nucleus 
    of the vagus nerve, and the ventral medullary reticular formation 
    (Loewy et al., &apos;79a, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The A5 area may also receive input from the NTS and 
    ventral medullary reticular formation (Norgren, &quot;78; Ricardo 
    and Koh, &apos;78; Loewy and Burton, &apos;78; Loewy et al., 
    &apos;81; McKellar and Loewy, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">In addition, the A5 area reportedly has reciprocal 
    connections with the pontine parabrachial area (Sakai et al., 
    &apos;77; Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; Loewy et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The targets of A5 neurons above pontine levels are 
    unknown, although A5 cells project to at least posterior 
    diencephalic levels (Takagi et al., &apos;80; Andrade and 
    Aghajanian, &apos;82; Byrum et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Other afferent input to the A5 area may arise from the 
    paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus and the central nucleus 
    of the amygdaloid complex (Conrad and HaE, &apos;76; Hopkins and 
    Holstege, &quot;78; Hosoya et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">However, most of these suggested connections cannot be 
    conclusively said to involve A5 noradrenergic neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">First. the anteromade and retrograde tracing studies 
    examining projections of A5 area-neurons to supra-spinal structures 
    did not demonstrate involvement of the noradrenergic neurons, which 
    are intermingled with noncatecholamine cells of the parvicellular 
    reticular formation (Loewy et al., &apos;79a; Byrum et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Second, the suggested afferent inputs to the A5 area are 
    based entirely on autoradiographic studies reporting anterograde 
    transport of tracer from various structures to the A5 area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Although this technique unambiguously reveals the 
    distribution of neuronal processes of the labeled cells, in most 
    cases fibers of passage were not distinguished from areas of 
    neuronal termination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">It is therefore unclear which of the demonstrated inputs 
    to this area actually terminate on A5 area neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">It is evident that the afferent and efferent connections 
    of the A5 area must be conclusively determined before realistic 
    hypotheses can be offered regarding the functional role of the A5 
    group.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The present anterograde and retrograde tracing study was 
    undertaken to clarify these connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Our results demonstrate that A5 noradrenergic neurons 
    project widely to many structures involved in cardiovascular 
    regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Furthermore, the A5 area receives afferent input from 
    major cardiovascular regulatory centers of the CNS.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s34">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Male Sprague-Dawley rats (300-400 g) were used in all 
    experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Prior to surgery, the animals were anesthetized with 
    pentobarbital (50-60 mgkg i.p. plus boosters as needed) and 
    received atropine sulfate (0.06-0.15 mgkg i.p.1 as needed to 
    control respiratory tract secretions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s37">HRP-WGA deposits in the 
    A5 area</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The A5 noradrenergic cell group forms a narrow column of 
    cells in the ventrolateral parvicellular reticular formation of 
    caudal pons and rostral medulla (Byrum et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The lateral subdivision of the A5 group is present within 
    the rubrospinal tract, lateral to the superior olivary complex and 
    medial to the trigeminal sensory complex (Fig. 1).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">The much smaller dorsal subdivision is present above the 
    superior olivary complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">A small number of cells representing the caudal pole of 
    the A5 column are present lateral to the rostral pole of the facial 
    motor nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">One series of animals (n = 22) received iontophoretic or 
    pressure injections of HRP-conjugated wheat germ agglutinin 
    (HRP-WGA) in the rostral part of the A5 column.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Because of the very small size of the lateral A5 
    subdivision in cross section (less than 0.3 mm in diameter), the A5 
    column was located electrophysiologically in relation to the facial 
    motor nucleus by a previously described method (Byrum et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The location of the rostral part of the A5 column, 
    containing the densest accumulation of cells, was determined 
    empirically to be 1.5-1.7 mm anterior to the rostral pole of the 
    facial nucleus, 0.1-0.2 mm medial to its lateral edge, and 0.1 mm 
    below its dorsal surface.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">For those animals receiving iontophoretic deposits, a 1% 
    solution of HRP-WGA (Sigma type VI) was prepared in 0.1 M sodium 
    chloride, pH 5.7.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Glass micropipettes with tips broken to 2-3 pm were 
    filled with the solution by vacuum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Impedances of these microelectrodes ranged from 15 to 20 
    Mil in normal saline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The microelectrode was then lowered very slowly (10 
    pdsecond) to the calculated location, and positive current (100 nA) 
    was applied by an iontophoresis unit for 20-30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The microelectrode was left in place with applied current 
    for an equal period of time before it was very slowly withdrawn 
    while a holding current was applied (20 nA negative).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">For those animals receiving pressure injections, glass 
    micropipettes with tips broken to 2-3 pm were filled with the 
    tracer solution by vacuum (1% HRP-WGA in saline).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The micropipette was connected with polyethylene tubing 
    to a pressure injection device (Picospritzer), which was triggered 
    electronically with a stimulation unit to deliver pressure pulses 
    at 10-second intervals (10-20 psi, 10-25-msec duration).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The meniscus height was followed visually with the aid of 
    a dissecting microscope with a reticle.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Deposits of less than 5 nl were made over several 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">After injection the micropipette was left in place for 30 
    minutes and then withdrawn slowly with a small negative pressure 
    applied to the system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">After a recovery period of 2 days, the animals were 
    processed for catecholamine fluorescence and m &apos; reaction 
    product by the sequential technique of Blessing et al. 
    (&apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The animals were anesthetized with pentobarbital and 
    perfused intra-aortally with the Faglu solution (4% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.5% glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer; 
    Furness et aI,, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">After photographing the fluorescent cells of the A5 group 
    (40-pm vibratome sections), the pontine sections were rinsed in 
    ice-cold saline and refrigerated overnight.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The remainder of the brain and the midthoracic spinal 
    cord were stored refrigerated in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) 
    containing 30% sucrose for at least 24 hours before sectioning on a 
    freezing microtome, collecting every third serial section (40 
    pm).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The tissue was processed for HRP reaction product 
    according to the protocol of Mesulam (&apos;78), except that the 
    reaction solutions were continuously filtered to reduce background 
    artifact (Gibson et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Each section was examined under visible light (darkfield) 
    for anterograde and retrograde labeling.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">After photographing areas exhibiting the reaction 
    product, the sections were Nissl stained and then reexamined 
    (brightfield) to determine the distribution of the label in 
    relation to nuclei and other structures.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">In addition, photographs of the area of tracer diffusion 
    were compared with the fluorescence photographs to determine the 
    extent of overlap of the deposit with A5 cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s63">Retrograde tracing of 
    possible A5 projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">A second series of animals (n = 45) received injections 
    of a retrograde tracer in selected areas of the supraspinal CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Rhodamine-labeled fluorescent latex microspheres 
    (0.02-0.2 pm diameter, Tracer Technologies) are taken up by neurons 
    and transported retrogradely (Katz et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Virtually no diffusion of the aqueous microsphere 
    suspension occurs even with very large deposits (200 nl).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The undiluted microsphere suspension was injected with 
    pressure with the aid of glass micropipettes with tips broken to 
    15-25 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">The procedure was similar to that described above, except 
    the 50-200-nl deposits were delivered at a rate of approximately 5 
    nl per minute.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The animals were allowed to recover for 2 days up to 5 
    weeks, with no apparent loss of labeling with the longer survival 
    times.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">The perfusion and tissue-processing procedure was 
    identical to that used in the HRP-WGA cases, with several 
    exceptions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">The concentration of glutaraldehyde in the perfusion 
    solution was reduced to 0.05%.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Higher concentrations of glutaraldehyde resulted in 
    excessive background fluorescence, which partially obscured the 
    microsphere fluorescence.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The mounted sections were coverslipped with the 
    fluorescence mounting medium Krystalon (Harleco), which retarded 
    the loss of catecholamine fluorescence.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The tissue containing the deposit in each case was stored 
    refrigerated in the Faglu solution containing 30% sucrose for at 
    least several days.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">The tissue was then sectioned on a freezing microtome (40 
    pm), collecting every third serial section.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Alternate sections were Nissl-stained to identify the 
    structures overlapped by the deposits.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">The sections were examined under ultraviolet light with 
    an epifluorescence microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">By viewing each section with blue-violet or green 
    excitation filters, the catecholamine or microsphere (rhodamine) 
    fluorescence was alternately visualized, allowing quantitation of 
    singleor double-labeled cells in the A5 group.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">In addition, several animals received iontophoretic 
    deposits of HRP-WGA when necessary to avoid damage to fibers of 
    passage.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">The procedure used during injection and processing is 
    described above.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">The sequential procedure used to quantify retrograde HRP 
    labeling of the A5 area has been described previously (Byrum et 
    al., &apos;84).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="25" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s82">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s83">HRP-WGA deposits in the 
    A5 area</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The lateral subdivision of the 
    A5 column</neuroanatomicalLocation> lies virtually entirely within 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the rubrospinal 
    tract</neuroanatomicalLocation>, as illustrated in Figure 1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">In addition, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the A5 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation> contains other ascending and 
    descending fibers, including many axons interconnecting structures 
    involved in autonomic regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">For this reason, it was important to avoid damage to and 
    thereby labeling of fibers of passage in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the A5 area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87"><exptLabel>Of seven animals with very discrete deposits 
      of <tracerChemical>HRP-WGA</tracerChemical> that overlapped 
      <injectionLocation>the lateral A5 
      subdivision</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, three were rejected 
      because of <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling of 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the red 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">As <tracerChemical>HRP-WGA</tracerChemical> does not 
      appear to be taken up significantly by undamaged fibers (Mantyh 
      and Peschanski, 83), such labeling potentially indicated damage 
      to rubrospinal tract fibers in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the A5 
      area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">Although <connxOrigin>the red nucleus</connxOrigin> 
      projects to <connxTermination>the trigeminal 
      complex</connxTermination> (Edwards, 721, the conservative 
      approach was taken that <labelingLocation>red 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> labeling accompanied damage to other 
      fibers of passage in the area of the deposit.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90">The four cases definitely free from rubrospinal tract 
      damage were systematically examined for anterograde and 
      retrograde labeling.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">The <tracerChemical>HRP-WGA</tracerChemical> deposits 
      (two via iontophoresis, two via pressure) ranged in size from 
      0.75 to 1.5 mm in crosssectional diameter and extended 1-2 mm 
      along the rostrocaudal axis (Fig. 2).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">In each case the dense core of the deposit overlapped a 
      majority of the fluorescent cells in <injectionLocation>the 
      lateral subdivision of the rostral half of the A5 
      column</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">This was determined by comparison of the deposit with 
      photographs of fluorescent cells in the area taken prior to 
      processing the tissue for HRP (Fig. 3).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">In each case the deposit overlapped <injectionSpread>
      the spinal trigeminal tract, the ventral tip of the principal 
      sensory trigeminal nucleus (PrV), and the rostral tip of the 
      spinal trigeminal complex (SpV), as well as a very small area of 
      parvicellular reticular formation (PcRF) and the lateral edge of 
      the superior olivary complex (SOC)</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">The pattern of anterograde and retrograde labeling 
      described below was present in all cases, except as noted.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">It should be noted that anterograde refers to labeling 
      of axons as well as terminals.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">Cell counts in Table 1 represent labeled cells present 
      on every third serial coronal section.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>Neither anterograde nor retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the cerebral cortex</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were not observed rostral to 
      <labelingLocation>the optic chiasm</labelingLocation>, although 
      <labelingDescription>anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
      was present in <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis (BNST) and the preoptic area of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">Caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the optic 
      chiasm</neuroanatomicalLandmark> at the level of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the paraventricular nucleus of the 
      hypothalamus (PVH)</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingDescription>anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
      was present with an ipsilateral predominance in <labelingLocation>
      the lateral hypothalamic area (LH) in and dorsal to the area of 
      the medial forebrain bundle (MFB)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      4A).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">The label extended medially around 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the dorsal and medial surfaces of the 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and extended laterally to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the central nucleus of the amygdala 
      (CNA)</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior part of the lateral parvicellular subdivision of the 
      PVH</labelingLocation>, almost exclusively on the ipsilatera1 
      side.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
       id="s103">At <neuroanatomicalLandmark>anterior 
      tuberal</neuroanatomicalLandmark> levels, predominantly 
      <labelingDescription>ipsilateral anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
      the LH, perifornical area of the hypothalamus (PFH), zona incerta 
      (Zn, and CNA</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
       id="s104">At this level <labelingDescription>anterograde 
      label</labelingDescription> was present bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal hypothalamic area 
      (DHA)</labelingLocation> and extended dorsally along 
      <labelingLocation>the midline of the thalamus</labelingLocation> 
      to <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus of the thalamus 
      (PVT)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
       id="s105"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present with an ipsilateral 
      predominance in <labelingLocation>the ZI centered above the 
      fornix</labelingLocation>, although only a single cell was 
      labeled in case 67, At caudal tuberal levels, 
      <labelingDescription>anterograde label</labelingDescription> was 
      present as at more rostral levels in <labelingLocation>the LH, 
      DHA, ZI, and midline thalamus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4B).</S>
      <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
       id="s106"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>the 
      PFH along with a prominent narrow strip of anterograde label 
      surrounding the fornix</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
       id="s107"><labelingDescription>Retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>ihe 
      ZI</labelingLocation> was present in ail cases, although only a 
      single cell was labeled in case 67, whereas 
      <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> of 
      <labelingLocation>the LH</labelingLocation> was 
      <labelingDescription>weak or absent</labelingDescription> in most 
      cases.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Anterograde and retrograde labeling of 
      <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> was 
      bilateral with an ipsilateral predominance.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">Frequently <labelingDescription>heavy anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the contralateral ventral posterior medial nucleus of the 
      thalamus (VPM)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117"><labelingLocation>The CNA</labelingLocation> was not 
      consistently labeled at these levels.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">In <labelingLocation>the posterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the ipsilateral LH and bilaterally on the medial surface of the 
      now greatly elongated mammillothalamic tract and surrounding the 
      adjacent fornix</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the 
      ZI</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>bilateral with 
      variable strength</labelingDescription> but <labelingLocation>
      this structure</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>not 
      retrogradely labeled</labelingDescription> at this level, and 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> were not 
      consistently present in <labelingLocation>the LH or 
      PFH</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120"><labelingLocation>The thalamus</labelingLocation> was 
      labeled as at more rostral levels, with <labelingDescription>an 
      especially dense area of anterograde label</labelingDescription> 
      on <labelingLocation>the dorsal surface of the contralateral 
      medial lemniscus (ML)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><labelingDescription>Anterograde and retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the ventral periaqueductal gray (PAG) at the level of the 
      posterior commissure</labelingLocation>, primarily on the 
      contralateral side (Fig. 4D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122"><labelingDescription>Only a very few 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in case 67.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">More caudally, <labelingDescription>a particularly 
      striking pattern of anterogradely labeled 
      processes</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the contralateral ventral PAG</labelingLocation>, forming 
      <labelingLocation>a dense band arching over the oculomotor 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124"><labelingDescription>Prominent anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral and dorsal parts of the PAG 
      throughout the mesencephalon</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
      label</labelingDescription> was also present bilaterally with a 
      contralateral predominance in <labelingLocation>the deep layers 
      of the superior colliculus (SC)</labelingLocation> and in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral ML</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">At 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>pontine</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
      levels, <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present near the deposits in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral PcRF and the ventral part of 
      the PrV</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127"><labelingDescription>Anterograde and retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the Kolliker-Fuse nucleus (KFN) and dorsal parabrachial area 
      (DPB)</labelingLocation>, almost exclusively on the ipsilateral 
      side.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>the 
      ipsilateral locus coeruleus (LC) and ventral parabrachial area 
      (VPB)</labelingLocation>, although 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> were generally 
      <labelingDescription>few in number</labelingDescription> in these 
      areas.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129">It should be noted that <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      dorsal and ventral subdivisions of the 
      PBA</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Paxinos and Watson, 82) are also 
      known as <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral and medial 
      subdivisions</neuroanatomicalLocation>, respectively.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130"><labelingDescription>A small number of retrogradely 
      labeled cells</labelingDescription> were present in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral ventrolateral 
      PcRF</labelingLocation> in all cases except 48, including 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral A5 
      area</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">At the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the rostral 
      part of the facial motor nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>the 
      vestibular complex WC)</labelingLocation>, almost exclusively in 
      <labelingLocation>the superior and medial 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>, although <labelingDescription>only a 
      few cells</labelingDescription> were labeled in case 67 (Fig. 
      4G).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">Labeling in <labelingLocation>the 
      VC</labelingLocation> varied between cases from predominantly 
      ipsilateral to predominantly contralateral.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="32" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s133">
      Sections at the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the rostral 
      third of the nucleus of the solitary tract 
      (NTS)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> were not examined.</S>
      <S avgH="32" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s134">This 
      tissue was rendered unusable in each animal by the glue used to 
      mount <neuroanatomicalLocation>the pons</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
      for sectioning on the vibratome.</S>
      <S avgH="32" class="results.body" format="ArialMT" id="s135">At 
      intermediate and caudal levels of <labelingLocation>the 
      NTS</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>both the medial and lateral subdivisions of the 
      NTS, primarily surrounding and ventromedial to the solitary 
      tract</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137">These areas correspond to <labelingLocation>the 
      ventrolateral, intermediate, and medial 
      subnuclei</labelingLocation> of Loewy and Burton ( 78).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the DMNX throughout its 
      extent</labelingLocation>, and in <labelingLocation>the reticular 
      formation immediately adjacent to the ventrolateral 
      NTS</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> also were present at intermediate and 
      caudal levels of <labelingLocation>the NTS</labelingLocation> in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral and medial 
      subnuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140"><labelingDescription>Retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the 
      NTS</labelingLocation> was virtually exclusively ipsilateral 
      except at commissural levels, where <labelingDescription>a small 
      number of contralateral cells</labelingDescription> were 
      labeled.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s141"><labelingDescription>Retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was weak or absent in 
      <labelingLocation>more medial parts of the NTS</labelingLocation> 
      and <labelingDescription>was never observed</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>DMNX</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142">In other areas of <labelingLocation>the caudal 
      medulla</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present on <labelingLocation>
      the dorsal midline, dorsal and dorsolatera1 to the medial 
      longitudinal fasciculus and surrounding the central canal at 
      commissural levels of the NTS</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>
      this area</labelingLocation> in all cases except 48, scattered in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal part of the 
      fasciculus</labelingLocation> and also 
      <labelingLocation>ventromedial to the NTS</labelingLocation> at 
      precommissural levels.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
      label</labelingDescription> was present bilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the inferior olive (10)</labelingLocation> with 
      a contralateral predominance.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145"><labelingDescription>Anterograde and retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>
      the ventral part of the ipsilateral SpV 
      complex</labelingLocation>, with <labelingDescription>a small 
      number of labeled cells</labelingDescription> scattered in the 
      dorsolateral aspect.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146"><labelingDescription>Anterograde and retrograde 
      label</labelingDescription> also was present in <labelingLocation>
      the ventral reticular formation (RF) of the caudal 
      medulla</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      processes</labelingDescription> were distributed 
      <labelingDescription>diffusely</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the area overlying and to some extent 
      overlapping the lateral reticular nucleus 
      (LRt)</labelingLocation>, including the <labelingLocation>area of 
      the nucleus ambiguus (NA)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148">At the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      commissural NTS</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>a 
      prominent strip of label</labelingDescription> extended from 
      <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral RF</labelingLocation> 
      dorsomedially to <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral 
      NTS</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in and especially dorsal 
      to <labelingLocation>the LRt</labelingLocation>, often in close 
      proximity to <labelingLocation>the NA</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150"><labelingDescription>A more medial group of labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> was located just lateral and 
      dorsolateral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      10</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present in <labelingLocation>the 
      raphe obscurus</labelingLocation> in except 48.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s152"><labelingDescription>Anterograde and retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the medullary 
      RF</labelingLocation> was predominantly ipsilateral.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153">A small of the midthoracic spinal cord was also 
      examined.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s154"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
      label</labelingDescription> was present in <labelingLocation>the 
      IML, the dorsal part of the lateral funiculus, and near the 
      central canal</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155">Although the labeling was present primarily on one 
      side of <labelingLocation>the spinal cord</labelingLocation>, it 
      was not determined whether this was ipsilateral or contralateral 
      to the deposit.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156"><labelingDescription>A very few retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were present near <labelingLocation>
      the central canal and medial to the lateral 
      horn</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157"><labelingLocation>The cerebehm</labelingLocation> was 
      not examined in any of the cases.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s158">Retrograde tracing of 
    putative A5 projections</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159">In order to clarify the sources of anterograde 
      labeling, retrogradely transported 
      <exptLabel><tracerChemical>fluorescent 
      microspheres</tracerChemical> were deposited in <injectionLocation
      >selected sites in the supraspinal 
      CNS</injectionLocation></exptLabel> in a series of animals.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">Figure 5 illustrates the location and size of most of 
      the sites.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161">In addition to the cases illustrated, one microsphere 
      deposit overlapped <injectionSpread>the BNST at preoptic 
      levels</injectionSpread> (case 140), and three microsphere 
      deposits were restricted to <injectionLocation>the 
      MFB</injectionLocation> at posterior diencephalic levels 
      (<exptLabel>cases 101, 106, 111</exptLabel>).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">Other microsphere deposits were placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the somatosensory part of the cerebral 
      cortex</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 126</exptLabel>), 
      <injectionLocation>cerebellar cortex</injectionLocation> 
      (<exptLabel>cases 98, 118, 119, 122, 123</exptLabel>), 
      <injectionLocation>septum</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
      1341</exptLabel>, 
      <injectionLocation>caudateputamen</injectionLocation> 
      (<exptLabel>case 1241</exptLabel>, and 
      <injectionLocation>habenula</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
      121</exptLabel>).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">Figure 6 illustrates <labelingDescription>retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>A5 
      noradrenergic neurons at rostra1 and caudal levels of the A5 
      column</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Table 2 indicates the extent of 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> of 
    <labelingLocation>the A5 cell group</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Previous work has determined that each 
    <labelingLocation>unilateral A5 group</labelingLocation> contains 
    approximately 425 noradrenergic cells, with roughly 75% of these 
    present in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    subdivision</labelingLocation> (Byrum et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Of the cases labeling at least 10% of A5 cells (n = 20), 
    the A5 projection was bilateral with an ipsilateral predominance 
    (ipsilateral/contralatera1 mean = 1.3 f 0.06 SEM).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">NO rostral-caudal topography of A5 projections was 
    apparent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">The extent of <labelingLocation>A5</labelingLocation> 
    labeling of the dorsal part of the A5 group was generally slightly 
    less than that of <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    pa&amp;</labelingLocation> (lateral/dorsal mean = 1.3 0.2 SEM 
    ipsilateral, 1.4 + 0.2 SEM contralateral: n = 17).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
     id="s169">Microsphere deposits in several areas resulted in 
    <labelingDescription>heavy retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the A5 cell 
    group</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="26" class="results.body"
     format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT" id="s170">These areas include 
    <injectionLocation>the caudal NTS</injectionLocation> 
    (<exptLabel>cases 130, 135, 1361</exptLabel>, 
    <injectionLocation>PBA</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
    1171</exptLabel>, <injectionLocation>ventral PAG at the level of 
    the oculomotor nucleus</injectionLocation> (case UO), 
    <injectionLocation>lateral PAG</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>case 
    1091</exptLabel>, <injectionLocation>PFH</injectionLocation> (case 
    113), <injectionLocation>CNA</injectionLocation> (case 1121, and 
    <injectionLocation>the LH and ZI</injectionLocation> (cases 108, 
    114).</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
     id="s171">Conversely, iontophoretic deposits of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP-WGA</tracerChemical> centered in 
    <injectionLocation>several areas of medullary 
    RF</injectionLocation> (<exptLabel>cases 90, 92, 96, 
    97</exptLabel>) notably <labelingDescription>did not label any 
    cells</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the A5 
    group</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s186">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s187">Afferent input to the A5 
    area</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Deposits of HRP-WGA in the A5 area retrogradely labeled 
    cells in the PVH, PFH, LH, ZI, PAG, PBA, LC, F&apos;rV, SpV, VC, 
    intermediate and caudal NTS, and caudal ventral medullary RF.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">In addition, labeled cells were present in most cases in 
    the raphe obscurus, dorsal midline of the medulla, and 
    contralateral pontine PcRF.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Significant numbers of retrogradely labeled cells were 
    observed in the intermediate and caudal NTS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">This result confirms reports of anterograde labeling of 
    the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in this portion of the NTS 
    in the rat, cat, and monkey (Loewy and Burton, &apos;78; Ricardo 
    and Koh, &apos;78; Norgren, &apos;78; Beckstead et al., &apos;80; 
    King, &apos;80).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Retrograde labeling of the ventral medullary RF was 
    observed in two areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">One group of cells was located primarily dorsal to the 
    LRt, in the area of the A1 noradrenergic cell group and the caudal 
    part of the C1 adrenergic cell group (Kalia et al., 
    &apos;85a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">This result is consistent with those of two 
    autoradiographic studies in the rat that reported anterograde 
    labeling of the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in the area of 
    the Al/Cl cells (Sawchenko and Swanson, &apos;82; McKellar and 
    Loewy, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The more medial RF cells labeled in the present study 
    are located in the area of the B1 serotoninergic cell group 
    (Steinbusch and Nieuwenhuys, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Loewy et al. (&apos;81) reported anterograde labeling of 
    the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in this region in the 
    rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Retrogradely labeled cells were present in significant 
    numbers in the PBA, primarily in the KFN and DPB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">The VPB was also labeled, but very few cells were 
    present in most cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">This confirms the finding of Saper and Loewy (&apos;80) 
    of anterograde labeling of the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits 
    in the PBA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">In addition, Conrad and Pfaff (&apos;76) found 
    anterograde labeling of the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in 
    the PVH in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">This finding is consistent with the retrograde labeling 
    of the PVH observed in the present study, which was restricted to 
    the posterior part of the lateral parvicellular subdivision.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Retrogradely labeled cells were present in the PFH and 
    LH, although few cells were observed in the LH in most cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Three autoradiographic studies in the rat have reported 
    labeling of ventrolateral pontine PcRF including the lateral A5 
    area with tracer deposits that overlapped both the PFH and LH at 
    tuberal levels (Hosoya and Matsushita, &apos;81; Hosoya et al., 
    &apos;83, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">A fourth study in the rat reported anterograde labeling 
    of the dorsal but not the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in 
    the LH at tuberal levels that did not overlap the PFH (Berk and 
    Finkelstein, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">These results, together with the weak labeling of the LH 
    in the present study, support a projection to the lateral A5 area 
    from the PFH but not the LH.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Retrogradely labeled cells were not observed in the 
    amygdaloid complex in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">However, autoradiographic studies in the rat, cat, and 
    monkey have reported anterograde labeling of the pontine PcRF 
    including the lateral A5 area with tracer deposits in the CNA 
    (Hopkins and Holstege, &apos;78; Hopkins et al., &apos;81; Price, 
    &apos;81; Price and Amaral, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">These studies also indicated that the descending pathway 
    from the CNA passed directly over the SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Although the CNA may innervate A5 area cells not 
    overlapped by the deposits in the present study, it is possible 
    that the reported anterograde labeling of the lateral A5 area 
    represents fibers of passage.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Finally, retrograde labeling of the ZI, ventral PAG, LC, 
    and VC was very weak in case 67, suggesting that these areas do not 
    provide significant input to the lateral A5 area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Merents to the ventrolateral pons from these areas and 
    other areas inconsistently labeled in the present study likely 
    innervate the adjacent pontine PcRF or trigeminal complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">It should be noted that these afferents to the A5 area 
    must be further clarified.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">The A5 area includes noncatecholamine cells in addition 
    to the noradrenergic cells (Loewy et al., &apos;79a; Byrum et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Thus other techniques are necessary to conclusively 
    demonstrate innervation of the noradrenergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Furthermore, as the HRP-WGA deposits in the present 
    study overlapped only a fraction of A5 cells, other A5 afferents 
    may remain unidentified.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s216">Efferents of the A5 
    area</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Interpretation of the pattern of anterograde labeling 
    observed in the present study requires caution for several 
    reasons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">The cells of origin could include noncatecholamine cells 
    in the A5 area and adjacent structures in addition to A5 
    noradrenergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Furthermore, such labeling could represent anterograde 
    labeling of collaterals of axons projecting to the area of the 
    deposit (de Olmos and Heimer, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">In some cases the observed labeling likely represents 
    axons of passage en route to or from their perikarya.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">However, the labeling probably does not arise from 
    damaged axons in the A5 area, since the absence of retrograde 
    labeling of the red nucleus indicates the rubrospinal tract fibers 
    surrounding the A5 cells were undamaged.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">The use of the retrogradely transported fluorescent 
    microspheres combined with catecholamine histofluorescence 
    techniques in the present study resolves some of the ambiguity 
    inherent in the interpretation of the pattern of anterograde 
    HRP-WGA labeling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">In most areas exhibiting anterograde labeling, the 
    contribution of A5 noradrenergic cells is unambiguously 
    established, although this technique does not distinguish between 
    axons of passage and terminal areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s224">Brainstem and spinal 
    cord</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">In the present study, anterograde labeling was 
    distributed diffusely in the ventrolateral medullary RF with an 
    ipsilateral predominance, and bilaterally in the DMNX and the 
    caudal half of the NTS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">These results are consistent with the findings of an 
    autoradiographic study in the rat by Loewy et al. (&apos;79a), 
    which examined the descending projections of cells in the A5 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">The present retrograde tracing results (cases 125, 130, 
    135, 136, 138) demonstrate that A5 area innervation of the NTSDMNX 
    arises from the noradrenergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Furthermore, more than half of the A5 cells on each side 
    of the pons innervate each unilateral NTSLDMNX complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">At least some A5 cells must therefore project 
    bilaterally to the complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">The diffuse anterograde label in the RF of the caudal 
    medulla in the present and Loewy studies may represent areas of 
    termination or axons of passage to the spinal cord or dorsal 
    medulla.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The absence of retrograde labeling of the A5 group with 
    iontophoretic HRP-WGA deposits in the dorsal and ventral medullary 
    RF (cases 90, 92, 96, 97) is consistent with the results of two 
    previous studies in the rat using tracer deposits in the region of 
    the NA (Travers and Norgren, &apos;83; Stuesse and Fish, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Conversely, Andrezik et al. (&apos;81) retrogradely 
    labeled cells in the A5 area in the rat with tracer deposits in the 
    ventrolateral RF, and Sun and Guyenet (&apos;86) labeled up to 73% 
    of A5 noradrenergic cells with C1 area microsphere deposits.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">However, these results must be viewed with caution 
    because of potential damage to fibers of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Additional study is therefore necessary to resolve this 
    point.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">The present anterograde and retrograde tracing results 
    demonstrate that the PBA is heavily innervated by the A5 group.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Anterograde labeling was present in both the KFN and 
    DPB, with a microsphere deposit in this area (case 117) labeling 
    half of the A5 cells bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Projections from cells in the A5 area to the PBA have 
    been demonstrated previously in the rat and cat (Sakai et al., 
    &apos;77; Loewy et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">In addition, the present results demonstrate that a 
    large proportion of A5 noradrenergic cells project to the ventral 
    and lateral mesencephalic PAG (cases 109, 110).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Projections from the A5 cell group to this area have not 
    been reported by others.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Finally, in the spinal cord the anterograde labeling of 
    the thoracic IML, central canal area, and the dorsal part of the 
    lateral funiculus in the present study is consistent with the 
    autoradiographic results of Loewy et al. (&apos;79a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Previous work has demonstrated that virtually the entire 
    A5 group projects to at least thoracic levels (Byrum et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">In other areas of the brainstem, the anterograde 
    labeling of the I0 and the SC arises from cells of the pontine PcRF 
    and trigeminal complex (Baleydier and Mauguiere, &apos;78; Berkley 
    and Hand, &apos;78; Edwards et al., &apos;79; Nagata and Kruger, 
    &apos;79; Courville et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">In addition, the anterograde and retrograde labeling in 
    the caudal portions of the SpV complex represents intrinsic 
    connections with the PrV and rostral SpV (Hockfield and Gobel, 
    &apos;82; Lovick and Wolstencroft, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s244">Forebrain</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">The present anterograde and retrograde tracing results 
    indicate that at least a third of A5 cells project bilaterally to 
    or through the hypothalamus at posterior levels (case 108), with a 
    substantial proportion continuing through the ipsilateral MFB to at 
    least tuberal levels (case 107).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Prior anatomical and electrophysiological studies have 
    demonstrated that A5 noradrenergic cells project through the MFB to 
    at least posterior diencephalic levels (Takagi et al., &apos;81; 
    Andrade and Aghajanian, &apos;82; Byrum et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">However, A5 projections to more rostral areas of the 
    forebrain have not been identified in previous studies.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Within the hypothalamus, the PFH is innervated by at 
    least a fifth of the A5 cell group bilaterally (case 113).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">This area likely represents a terminal area for A5 
    axons, since prominent anterograde HRP-WGA labeling was present in 
    a circumscribed area surrounding the fornix.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Anterogradely labeled processes were also distributed 
    diffusely in the LH and ZI.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">A large number of A5 cells were retrogradely labeled 
    with a microsphere deposit overlapping the ZI and dorsal LH at 
    tuberal levels (case 114), with a smaller proportion labeled with a 
    deposit restricted to the ZI (case 133).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">These results suggest that A5 axons ascend in both of 
    these areas, although it is unclear whether these represent axons 
    of passage or areas of termination.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">In other areas of the diencephalon, anterograde labeling 
    was observed in the DHA and midline thalamus extending to the 
    PVT.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">A single microsphere deposit that overlapped the PVT 
    (case 139) labeled a small proportion of A5 cells.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Notably, noradrenergic innervation of the thalamus of 
    nonLC origin is restricted to the PVT (Lindvall et al., 
    &apos;74).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">The heavy anterograde labeling of the VPM and ML in the 
    present study arises from the PrV (Smith, &apos;73; Fukishima and 
    Kerr, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">This was confirmed with a deposit restricted to the VPM 
    (case 127) that heavily labeled the contralateral PrV but did not 
    label any A5 cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">The present anterograde and retrograde tracing results 
    also demonstrate that approximately a fifth of the A5 cell group 
    innervates the CNA bilaterally (case 112).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Considering the location of this structure, the 
    anterograde labeling observed in this area likely represents a 
    terminal area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">This finding is consistent with reports that the CNA 
    receives a substantial noradrenergic input of non-LC origin (Fallon 
    et al., &apos;78; Moore and Bloom, &apos;79; Lindvall and 
    Bjorklund, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Finally, a microsphere deposit restricted to the BNST 
    labeled a small number of A5 cells bilaterally (case 120).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Microsphere deposits in the cerebral cortex, septum, 
    cerebellar cortex, VPM, habenula, cortical amygdaloid nuclei, and 
    striatum did not label A5 cells (cases 98, 103,118, 119, 121, 
    122,123, 124, 126, 127, 129, 131, 134).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">In summary, the A5 noradrenergic cell group projects 
    widely to structures at many levels of the subcortical CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">It is evident that individual A5 cells must innervate 
    more than one target area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Virtually all A5 cells project to the thoracolumbar 
    spinal cord (Byrum et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">In addition, the NTS complex and PBA each receives 
    afferent input from at least half of the A5 group.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">At least a third of A5 cells innervate the PAG and a 
    similar proportion have projections ascending to diencephalic 
    levels.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Thus each A5 cell must innervate more than one 
    supraspinal structure in addition to the thoracolumbar IML.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">The A5 cell group is therefore similar to the LC in 
    having axons that ramify to innervate multiple structures (Lindvall 
    and Bjorklund, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">The paucity of previous reports of retrograde labeling 
    of the A5 area with tracer deposits in various brainstem and 
    forebrain structures requires comment.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Although it is conceivable that the relatively small A5 
    area was overlooked in previous studies, the most likely 
    explanation lies in the differential sensitivity of the retrograde 
    tracers employed.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Previous retrograde tracing studies of relevance have 
    used free or conjugated HRP virtually exclusively.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">However, false-negative results are known to occur with 
    HRP (Nauta et al., &apos;74), and the present results suggest that 
    the microspheres are a much more sensitive retrograde tracer than 
    HRP-WGA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Moreover, it is possible that the differential 
    sensitivity of the two tracers may be greater with certain cell 
    types, such as those possessing widely ramifying axonal 
    processes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">This differential sensitivity also calls into question 
    the present suggestion that A5 cells do not terminate in the 
    medullary RF.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <References>

    <S avgH="25" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s276">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Andrade, R., and G.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Aghajanian (1982) Single cell activity in the 
    noradrenergic A-5 region: Responses to drugs and peripheral 
    manipulations of blood pressure.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Brain Res. 242:125-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Andrezik, J.A., V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Chan-Palay, and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Palay (1981) The nucleus paragigantocellularis lateralis 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Demonstration of afferents by the retrograde transport 
    of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Embryol. 161.373-390.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Baleydier, C., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Mauguiere (1978) Projections of the ascending 
    somesthetic pathways to the cat superior colliculus visualized by 
    the horseradish peroxidase technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Brain Res. 31r43-50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Beckstead, R.M., J.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Morse, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Norgren (1980) The nucleus of the solitary tract in the 
    monkey: Projections to the thalamus and brain stem nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Cornp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Neurol. 190:259-282.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Finkelstein (1982) Efferent connections of the lateral 
    hypothalamic area of the rat: An autoradiographic investigation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Bull. 8511-526.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Berkley, K.J., and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Hand (1978) Projections to the inferior olive of the 
    cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Comparisons of input from gracile, cuneate and the 
    spinal trigeminal nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Neurol. 180:253-264.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Blessing, W.W., J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Furness, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Costa, and J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Chalmers (1978) Localization of catecholamine 
    fluorescence and retrogradely transported horseradish peroxidase 
    within the same nerve cell.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Lett. 9r311-315.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Byrum, C.E., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Stornetta, and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Guyenet (1984) Electrophysiological properties of 
    spinally-projecting A5 noradrenergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Brain Res. 303:15-29.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Close, J.M., J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Neil, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Loewy (1982) Actions of N-methylaspartate and its 
    antagonist aminophosphonovalerate on the A5 catecholamine cell 
    group in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Brain Res. 249:393-396.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Conrad, L.C.A., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Pfaff (1976) Efferents from medial basal forebrain and 
    hypothalamus in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">An autoradiographic study of the anterior 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Neurol. 169t221-261.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Courville, J., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Faraco-Cantin, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Marcon (1983) Projections from the reticular formation 
    of the medulla, the spinal trigeminal and lateral reticular nuclei 
    to the inferior olive.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Neuroscience 9:129-139.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Olmos, J., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Heimer (1977) Mapping of collateral projections with the 
    HRP-method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Lett. 6t107-114.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Edwards, S.B. (1972) The ascending and descending 
    projections of the red nucleus in the cat An experimental study 
    using an autoradiographic tracing method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Brain Res. 48~2744.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Edwards, S.B., C.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Ginsburgh, C.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Henkel, and B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Stein (1979) Sources of subcortical projections to the 
    superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Cornp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Neurol. 184:309-330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Fallon, J.H., D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Koziell, and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Moore (1978) Catecholamine innervation of the basal 
    forebrain. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Amygdala, suprarhinal cortex and entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Neurol. 180:509-532.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Ferrario, C.M., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Takishita (1983) Baroreceptor reflexes and 
    hypertension.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Genest, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Kuchel, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Hamet, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Cantin (eds): Hypertension.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">New York: McGraw-Hill, pp. 161-170.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Foote, S.L., F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Bloom, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Aston-Jones (1983) The nucleus locus coeruleus: New 
    evidence of anatomical and physiological specificity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Rev. 632344-914.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Fukishima, T., and F.W.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Kerr (1979) Organization of trigeminothalamic tracts and 
    other thalamic afferent systems of the brainstem in the rat: 
    Presence of gelatinosa neurons with thalamic connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Neurol. 183:169-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Furness, J.B., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Costa, and W.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Blessing (1977) Simultaneous fixation and production of 
    catecholamine fluorescence in central nervous tissue by perfusion 
    with aldehydes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">J. 21745-750.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Galosy, R.A., L.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Clarke, M.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Vasko, and I.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Crawford (1981) Neurophysiology and neuropharmacology of 
    cardiovascular regulation and stress.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Biobehav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Rev. 5137-175.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Gibson, A.R., D.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Hansma, J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Houk, and F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Robinson (1984) A sensitive low artifact TMB procedure 
    for the demonstration of WGA-HRP in the CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Brain Res. 298:235-241.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Guyenet, P.G. (1984) Baroreceptor-mediated inhibition of 
    A5 noradrenergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Brain Res. 303r31-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Hilton, S.M. (1982) The defense-arousal system and its 
    relevance for circulatory and respiratory control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Biol. 100:159-174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Hockfield, S., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Gobel (1982) An anatomical demonstration of projections 
    to the medullary dorsal horn (trigeminal nucleus caudalis) from 
    rostra1 trigeminal nuclei and the contralateral caudal medulla.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Brain Res. 252203-211.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Hopkins, D.A., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Holstege (1978) Amygdaloid projections to the 
    mesencephalon, pons, and medulla oblongata in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Brain Res. 321529-547.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Hopkins, D.A., J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">McLean, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Takeuchi (1981) Amygdalotegmental projections: Light and 
    electron microscopic studies utilizing anterograde degeneration and 
    the anterograde and retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase 
    (HRP).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Ben-Ari (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">New York: ElsevierNorth-Holland Biomedical Press, pp. 
    133-147.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Hosoya, Y., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Matsushita (1981) Brainstem projections from the lateral 
    hypothalamic area in the rat, as studied with autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Lett. 24r111-116.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Hosoya, Y., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Matsushita, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Sugiura (1983) A direct hypothalamic projection to the 
    superior salivatory nucleus neurons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">A study using anterograde autoradiographic and 
    retrograde HRP methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Brain Res. 266~329-333.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Hosoya, Y., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Matsushita, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Sugiura (1984) Hypothalamic descending afferents to 
    cells of origin of the greater petrosal nerve in the rat, as 
    revealed by a combination of retrograde HRP and anterograde 
    autoradiographic techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Brain Res. 29Or141-145.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Kalia, M., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Fuxe, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Goldstein (1985a) Rat medulla oblongata. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Dopaminergic, noradrenergic (A1 and A2) and adrenergic 
    neurons, nerve fibers, and presumptive terminal processes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Neurol. 233t308-332.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Kalia, M., K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Fuxe, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Goldstein (1985b) Rat medulla Oblongata.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">III.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Adrenergic (C1 and C2) neurons, nerve fibers and 
    presumptive terminal processes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Neurol. 233r333-349.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Katz, L.C., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Burkhalter, and W.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Dreyer (1984) Fluorescent latex microspheres as a 
    retrograde neuronal marker for in vivo and in vitro studies of 
    visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Nature 310:498-500.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">King, G.W. (1980) Topology of ascending brainstem 
    projections to nucleus parabrachialis in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Neurol. 191:615-638.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Lindvall, O., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Bjorklund (1983) Dopamineand norepinephrine-containing 
    neuron systems: Their anatomy in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">In P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Emson (ed): Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">New York: Raven Press, pp. 229-255.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Lindvall, O., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Bjorklund, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Nobin, and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Stenevi (1974) The adrenergic innervation of the rat 
    thalamus as revealed by the glyoxylic acid fluorescence method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Neurol. 154:317-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Loewy, A.D., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Burton (1978) Nuclei of the solitary tract: Efferent 
    projections to the lower brain stem and spinal cord of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Neurol. 181:421-450.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Loewy, A.D., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">McKellar (1980) The neuroanatomical cardiovascular 
    control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Fed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Proc. 39:2495-2503.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Loewy, A.D., and J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Neil (1981) The role of descending monoaminergic systems 
    in central control of blood pressure.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Fed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Proc. 40:2778-2785.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Loewy, A.D., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">McKellar, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Saper (1979a) Direct projections from the A5 
    catecholamine cell group to the intermediolateral cell column.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Brain Res. 174:309-314.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Loewy, A.D., E.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Gregorie, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">McKellar, and R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Barker (1979b) Electrophysiological evidence that the A5 
    catecholamine cell group is a vasomotor center.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Brain Res. 178r196-200.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Loewy, A.D., J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Wallach, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">McKellar (1981) Efferent connections of the ventral 
    medulla oblongata in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Rev. 3:63-80.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Lovick, T.A., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Wolstencroft (1983) Projections from the brain stem 
    nuclei to the spinal trigeminal nucleus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Neuroscience 9:411-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Mantyh, P.W., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Peschanski (1983) The use of wheat germ 
    agglutininhorseradish peroxidase conjugates for studies of 
    anterograde axonal transport.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Methods 7~117-128.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">McKellar, S., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Loewy (1982) Efferent projections of the A1 
    catecholamine cell group in the rat: An autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Brain Res. 241t11-29.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Mesulam, M.M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for 
    horseradish peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue 
    reaction-product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural 
    derents and efferents. 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Moore, R.Y., and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Bloom (1979) Central catecholamine neuron systems: 
    Anatomy and physiology of the norepinephrine and epinephrine 
    systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Neurosci. 2:113-168.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Nagata, T., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Kruger (1979) Tactile neurons of the superior colliculus 
    of the cat: Input and physiological properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Brain Res. 174r19-37.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Nauta, H.J.W., M.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Pritz, and R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Lasek (1974) Afferents to the rat caudoputamen studied 
    with horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">An evaluation of a retrograde neuroanatomical research 
    method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Brain Res. 67219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Neil, J.J., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Loewy (1982a) Decreases in blood pressure in response to 
    L-glutamate microinjections into the A5 catecholamine cell 
    group.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Brain Res. 241:271-278.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Neil, J.J., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Loewy (198213) The role of spinal cord catecholamines in 
    the cardiovascular response to activation of the A5 catecholamine 
    group.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurosci. 8.722 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Norgren, R. (1978) Projections from the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Neuroscience 3207-218.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Palkovits, M., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Zaborszky (1977) Neuroanatomy of central cardiovascular 
    control.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Nucleus tractus solitarii: Afferent and efferent 
    neuronal connections in relation 47:9-34.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Paxinos, G., and Watson, C. (1982) The Rat Brain 
    nates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">New York Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Price, J.L. (1981) The efferent projections of the 
    amygdaloid complex in the rat, cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Ben-Ari (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">New York Elsevier/North-Holland Biomedical Press, pp. 
    121-132.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Price, J.L., and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Amaral(1981) An autoradiographic study of the 
    projections of the central nucleus of the monkey amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Neurosci. 1:1242-1259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Ricardo, J.A., and E.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Koh (1978) Anatomical evidence of direct projections 
    from the nucleus of the solitary tract to the hypothalamus, 
    amygdala, and other forebrain structures in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Brain Res. 153:l-26.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Sakai, K., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Touret, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Salvert, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Leger, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Jouvet (1977) Afferent projections to the cat locus 
    coeruleus as visualized by the horseradish peroxidase technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Brain Res. 119r21-41.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Saper, C.B., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections of the parabrachial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Brain Res. 197:291-317.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Sawchenko, P.E., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Swanson (1982) The organization of noradrenergic 
    pathways from the brainstem to the paraventricular and supraoptic 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Rev. 4~275-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Smith, R.L. (1973) The ascending fiber projections from 
    the principle sensory trigeminal nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Neurol. 148:423-446.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Specht, L.A., V.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Pickel, T.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Joh, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Reis (1981a) Light-microscopic immunocytochemical 
    localization of tyrosine hydrozylase in prenatal rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Early ontogeny.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Neurol. 199233-253.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Specht, L.A., V.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Pickel, T.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Joh, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Reis (1981b) Light-microscopic immunocytochemical 
    localization of tyrosine hydroxylase in prenatal rat brain, II.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Late ontogeny.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Neurol. 199:255-276.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Spyer, K.M. (1981) Neural organization and control of 
    the baroreceptor reflex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Biochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Pharmacol. 88:23-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Stanek, K.A., J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Neil, W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Sawyer, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Loewy (1984) Changes in regional blood flow and cardiac 
    output after L-glutamate stimulation of A5 cell group.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Physiol. 246:H44-H51.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Steinbusch, H.W.M., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Nieuwenhuys (1983) The raphe nuclei of the rat 
    brainstem: A cytoarchitectonic and immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">In P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Emson (ed): Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">New York Raven Press, pp. 131-207.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Stornetta, R.L., R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">McCarty, and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Guyenet (1984) Baroreceptor reflex modulation by A5 
    noradrenergic (NE) neurons in conscious rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Roc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Neurosci. 10~710 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Stuesse, S.L., and S.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Fish (1984) Projections to the cardioinhibitory region 
    of the nucleus ambiguus of rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Neurol. 229:271-278.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Sun, M-K., and P.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Guyenet (1986) Effect of clonidine and GABA on the 
    discharges of medullo-spinal sympathoexcitatory neurons in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Brain Res. 38rl-17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Takagi, H., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Shioska, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Tohyama, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Senba, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Sakanaka (1980) Ascending components of the medial 
    forebrain bundle from the lower brain stem in the rat, with special 
    reference to raphe and catecholamine cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">A study by the HRP method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Brain Res. 193:315-337.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Travers, J.B., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Norgren (1983) Afferent projections to the oral motor 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Neurol. 220:280-298.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Westlund, K.N., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Bowker, M.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Ziegler, and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Coulter (1983) Noradrenergic projections to the spinal 
    cord of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Brain Res. 263115-31.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Woodruff, M.L., R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Baisden, and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Whittington (1984) Excitation of the pontine A5 
    noradrenergic nucleus decreases blood pressure and heart rate in 
    the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Circulation 7O(Suppl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">IO:II-216 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Woodward, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">J., H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Moises, B.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Waterhouse, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Hoffer, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Freedman (1979) Modulatory actions of norepinephrine in 
    the central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Fed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Proc. 38:2109-2116.</S>
  </References>

</File>

