<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Regional and Laminar Organization of Projections From the 
  Presubiculum and Parasubiculum to the Entorhinal Cortex: An 
  Anterograde Tracing Study in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>MARIA CABALLERO-BLEDA AND MENNO P. WITTER</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The regional and laminar organization of the projections 
    from the presubiculum and the parasubiculum to the entorhinal 
    cortex was analyzed in the rat with the anterograde tracer 
    Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (Pl-IA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The projections from the presubiculum were bilateral and 
    confined to layers I11 and I of the medial entorhinal area 
    (MEA).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Both the ipsiand the contralateral projections showed 
    similar distributions and were almost of equal density.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Projections to layer 111 of the entorhinal cortex arose 
    predominantly from superficial layers of the presubiculum, whereas 
    the fibers that reach layer I of the entorhinal cortex appear to 
    originate preferentially from the deep layers of the 
    presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">These fibers also appeared to innervate weakly layer I1 of 
    MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The parasubiculum distributed projections not only to MEA 
    but also to the lateral entorhinal area (LEA), innervatinglayer I1 
    selectively.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The innervation of LEA was quite dense and extensive.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Very weak projections from the parasubiculum to the 
    contralateral entorhinal cortex were observed in this study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The position of the terminal plexus in the entorhinal 
    cortex was determined by the point of origin along both the 
    dorsoventral and transverse or proximodistal axes of the 
    presubiculum and parasubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Projections from the presubiculum and parasubiculum 
    entered the entorhinal cortex at the level of the injection, or 
    slightly ventral to it, and the main terminal field was always 
    present ventrally to the injection site.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The dorsoventral axis of origin thus corresponded to a 
    similarly oriented axis of termination in the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The distribution in relation to the origin along the 
    transverse axis was more complex, and differences between the 
    presubiculum and parasubiculum were present.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The proximal presubiculum, i.e., the part closest to the 
    subiculum, projected to the most lateral part of MEA and the 
    central part of the presubiculum sent fibers to the most medial 
    part of MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The distal part of the presubiculum, i.e., the part that 
    borders the parasubiculum, projected to the central part of MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Projections from the portion of the parasubiculum 
    directly adjacent to the presubiculum, the so-called proximal 
    parasubiculum, reached medial parts of MEA, and those originating 
    in the central part distributed preferentially to lateral parts of 
    MEA and adjacent medial parts of LEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The distal part of the parasubiculum that borders the 
    entorhinal cortex projected mainly to almost the full mediolateral 
    extent of LEA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">The regional and laminar organizations of the projections 
    from the presubiculum and parasubiculum to the entorhinal cortex 
    suggest that information is selectively conveyed not only to 
    different cell layers but also to restricted dorsoventral and 
    mediolateral parts of the entorhinal cortex. r 199s Wiley-Liss, 
    Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">The entorhinal cortxx occupies a key position in the 
    connections from the cortex to the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Neurons in the superficial layers I1 and 111 of the 
    entorhinal cortex supply the hippocampal formation with fibers that 
    distribute to all of its subfields, i.e., the dentate gyrus, fields 
    CA3ICA2 and CA1 of the Arnmon&apos;s horn, and the subiculum 
    (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Witter et al., &apos;89b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">In both the rat and the monkey there is convincing 
    evidence that cells in layer 11 project almost exclusively to the 
    dentate gyrus and CA3lCA2, whereas cells in layer Ill distribute 
    their axons predominantly to CA1 and the subiculum (Steward and 
    Scoville, &apos;76; Witter and Amaral, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Furthermore, it is clear that most if not all of the 
    cortical inputs to the entorhinal cortex that arise from multimodal 
    association and olfactory cortices are preferentially distributed 
    to the superficial layers 1-111 of the entorhinal cortex (Van 
    Hoesen and Pandya, &apos;75; Van Hoesen et al., &apos;75; Room and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;86; Witter et al., &apos;89a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The terminal distributions in the entorhinal cortex of 
    several of these cortical inputs show a marked laminar 
    specificity.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Inputs from the olfactory cortices, for example, 
    terminate specifically in layer I (Haberly and Price, &apos;78; 
    Turner et al., &apos;78; Kosel et al., &apos;81; Room et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The projections from the parasubiculum show a marked 
    preference for layer I1 and those from the presubiculum and 
    perirhinal cortex selectively distribute in layers I and 111 
    (Shipley, &apos;75; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77; Beckstead, 
    &apos;78; Van Hoesen, &apos;82; Amaral et al., &apos;84; Kohler, 
    &apos;85; Room and Groenewegen, &apos;86; Witter et al., &apos;86, 
    &apos;89b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">The presubiculum and parasubiculum differ with respect to 
    the origins of their major inputs (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Van Groen and Wyss, &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">This suggests that these two cortical areas supply the 
    entorhinal cortex with functionally different information which may 
    then be channeled through the differential projections of layers I1 
    and I11 to different subfields of the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">For this to be true, one must assume specific 
    input-output arrangements to exist in layers I1 and 111 of the 
    entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">It is therefore of interest to study the synaptic 
    relations between terminating fibers from the presubiculum and 
    parasubiculum and their postsynaptic entorhinal targets.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">For this type of analysis detailed knowledge about the 
    topographical organization of these pathways is required.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The most extensive study on the projections from the 
    presubiculum and parasubiculum to the entorhinal cortex in which 
    the sensitive anterograde tracer Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L) was used (Kohler &apos;85) only in part addressed the 
    topographical aspects of these projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Since it has been well established that most of the 
    connections of the hippocampal region are topographically organized 
    along the dorsoventral axis, it is of interest to analyse the 
    organization of&apos;the presubiculum and parasubiculum projections 
    to the entorhinal cortex with respect to this topography.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The parasubiculum of the rat may comprise two 
    cytoarchitectonically different subdivisions, areas 49a and 49b, 
    that are differently located along the mediolateral or transverse 
    axis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Area 49a borders the entorhinal cortex and area 49b 
    borders the presubiculuni (Blackstad, &apos;56; Haug, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Although no such subdivision along the transverse axis of 
    the presubiculum has been described, this should not be taken to 
    imply that no hodological differences along the transverse axis 
    could be present.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">For example, in the hippocampal fields CA1 and subiculum, 
    where there are no cytoarchitectonic subdivisions along the 
    transverse axis, hodological differences along this axis are 
    apparent (Ishizuka et id., &apos;90; Witter and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90, &apos;92; Witter et al., &apos;90; Amaral et al., 
    &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Therefore, it is important to compare the distribution of 
    projections that arise from different populations of cells along 
    the transverse axis of both the parasubiculum and the 
    presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">In the present study, we used PHA-L as tracer, since it 
    allows small, restricted injections to be made that can be reliably 
    delineated.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Emphasis will be placed on the relations between the 
    origin of projections along the dorsoventral and transverse axes of 
    the presubiculum and the parasubiculurn and the location of their 
    terminals in the entorhinal cortex.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s42">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Fourteen female Wistar rats (weight 150-200 g; Harlan 
    Centraal Proefdierbedrijf, Zeist, The Netherlands) were used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">They were deeply anesthetized with 1 mlikg body weight of 
    a mixture of ketamine and xylazine (4:3; 1% solution of Ket, Aesco, 
    Boxtel, The Netherlands, and 2% solution of Rompun, Bayer, 
    Brussels, Belgium) and mounted in a stereotaxic frame.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">A glass micropipette (tip diameter 10-20 pm) filled with 
    Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L, Vector, Burlingame, CA, 
    25 kg/pl in 50 mM Tris-buffered saline, pH 7.4) was placed into the 
    presubiculurn or parasubiculum using coordinates derived from the 
    atlas of Paxinos and Watson (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Iontophoretic injections were made by applying a positive 
    pulsed DC current (7.5 FA; 7 s on/7 s off, for 15 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Injections were positioned along the dorsoventral axis of 
    the presubiculum and parasubiculum and, at each dorsoventral level, 
    injections were aimed at different transverse positions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Four animals received single injections of PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Ten animals also received injections of the retrogradely 
    transported tracer Fast Blue into the fields CAl/subiculum and 
    dentate gyrus/CA3.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">These latter experiments, which will be described in more 
    detail in another report (Caballero Bleda et al., in prep.) were 
    meant to characterize potential postsynaptic targets of 
    presubiculum and parasubiculum fibers in the entorhinal cortex as 
    hippocampal-projecting cells.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">After a survival time of 7-9 days the animals received an 
    overdose of sodium pentobarbital (Nembutal, 60 mgikg body weight; 
    Ceva, Paris, France) and were perfused through the ascending 
    aorta.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The four animals with the single PHA-L injections were 
    perfused with saline (100 ml) followed by 500 ml of a phosphate 
    (100 mM) buffered 4% paraformaldehyde, 0.05% glutaraldehyde 
    solution (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Following postfixation for l h in the same fixative, the 
    brains were stored overnight at 4°C in a solution containing 20% 
    glycerine and 2% dimethyl sulfoxide in 100 mM phosphate buffer (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The brains were cut on a freezing microtome in 40 km 
    thick horizontal sections that were collected in phosphate buffer 
    (100 mM, pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">After rinsing (3 x 10 min) in Tris-buffered saline (50 mM 
    Tris and 0.85% NaCl, pH 7.6) with 0.5% Triton X-100 (TBS-Tx; Triton 
    Trademark of Sigma, St.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Louis, MO), the sections were incubated overnight (4°C) 
    in rabbit anti-PHA-L immunoglobulin (1:2,000; Vector, Burlingame, 
    CA) in TBS-Tx.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The next day, the sections were rinsed (3 x 10 min) in 
    TBS-Tx, and incubated for one hour (room temperature) in swine 
    anti-rabbit immunoglobulin in TBS-Tx (150; Nordic Immunochemicals, 
    Tilburg, The Netherlands).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The sections were subsequently rinsed (3 x 10 min) in 
    TBS-Tx and transferred to rabbit peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) in 
    TBS-Tx (1:800; Nordic Immunochemicals, Tilburg, The Netherlands) 
    for 1 hour at room temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Following washes in TrisiHCl, pH 7.6 (3 x 10 min), the 
    sections were incubated for 20 min (room temp.) in a solution 
    containing 5 mg diamino benzidine (DAB) and 3.3 pI HaOz in 10 ml 
    TrisiHCl, pH 7.6.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">During the incubations, the sections were kept in gentle 
    agitation on a rotator table.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Finally, the sections were rinsed 3 x 10 minutes in 
    TrisiHCl, mounted on glass slides from a 0.2% gelatine solution in 
    TrisiHCl, and subsequently coverslipped.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The animals that received an additional Fast Blue 
    injection were perfused with saline (100 ml) followed by 500 ml of 
    a fixative containing 4% paraformaldehyde, 0.05% glutaraldehyde, 
    and 15%) picric acid in 100 mM phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The brain was removed, postfixed for 1 hour, and cut on a 
    vibratome into 200 Fm thick horizontal slices.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Subsequently, selected retrogradely labeled cells were 
    filled with Lucifer Yellow.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">After this, the slices were stored for 30 minutes in 0.1% 
    glutaraldehyde in 100 mM phosphate buffer, pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The slices were rinsed in phosphate buffer, cryoprotected 
    by infiltration with 20% glycerine and 2% dimethyl sulfoxide in 100 
    mM phosphate buffer, pH 7.4, mounted on a freezing microtome on a 
    flat surface of solidly frozen 30% sucrose in phosphate buffer, and 
    cut into 40 km thick sections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">These sections were incubated according to the protocol 
    described above in order to visualize the transported PHA-L.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">The borders of the presubiculum and parasubiculum were 
    defined according to cytoarchitectonic criteria described by Haug 
    (&apos;76; cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Van Groen and Wyss, &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">The injection sites were reconstructed and mapped onto a 
    three-dimensional reconstruction of the hippocampal/ 
    parahippocampal region with the aid of a computer program (PC3D@@, 
    Jandel Scientific, Corte Madera, CA).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s71">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s72">Nomenclature</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">To describe the sites of injection in t<injectionLocation
    >he presubiculum and the parasubiculum</injectionLocation>, it is 
    necessary to define two axes in these cortical structures (Fig. 
    1A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The dorsoventral or longitudinal axis in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the rat subicular 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> is almost parallel to the normal 
    dorsoventral axis in the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">The transverse axis is oriented perpendicular to the 
    dorsoventral axis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">We employ a proximal (close to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the subiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>) 
    to distal (close to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the entorhinal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLandmark>) terminology to describe positions 
    along the transverse axis (Fig.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">IA).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Within <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    presubiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation>, no further subdivisions are 
    recognized and, therefore, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    postsubiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation> as described by Van Groen 
    and Wyss (&apos;90b) corresponds to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    dorsal part of the present 
    presubiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Since <neuroanatomicalLocation>area 
    29e</neuroanatomicalLocation> as differentiated by Haug (&apos;76) 
    is difficult to distinguish in non-counterstained and in faintly 
    cresylviolet stained sections from the experimental series, this 
    part is not further differentiated.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    parasubiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation> is described as one 
    cortical area although in most sections, except at extreme dorsal 
    and ventral levels, a differentiation between 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>subdivisions a and 
    b</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Haug, &apos;76) can be readily 
    made.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">The border between <neuroanatomicalLocation>areas a and 
    b</neuroanatomicalLocation> is indicated in Figure 1.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">In <neuroanatomicalLocation>the entorhinal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>, we define a dorsoventral axis 
    that corresponds to the caudorostral axis as normally used when 
    coronal sections are analysed.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The mediolateral or transverse axis is positioned 
    perpendicular to the dorsoventral axis and runs from the border 
    with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    parasubiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation> to the border with 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the perirhinal 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">In the present study. <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> is subdivided into 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a lateral (LEA) and medial (MEA) 
    subdivision</neuroanatomicalLocation> according to 
    cytoarchitectonic criteria (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Steward, &apos;76).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s86">Description of 
    anterograde tracing experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">Fourteen cases with iontophoretic injections of&apos; 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the 
    presubiculum (n = 7) and parasubiculum</injectionLocation> (n = 7) 
    were analyzed in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">The position of the injection sites is shown in Figure 
    1B,C.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">The resulting labeling in the entorhinal cortex of six 
    injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    presubiculum</injectionLocation> and three injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the parasubiculum</injectionLocation> will be 
    documented in detail.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>Presuhiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">The most dorsal injection in <injectionLocation>the 
    presubiculum</injectionLocation> (90103; Fig. 1B) was located in 
    its proximal portion, i.e., abutting <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    subiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s92">Four 
    injections involved <injectionLocation>the midportion of the 
    proximodistal extent of the presubiculum</injectionLocation>, at 
    different dorsoventral levels (90552,90473, 91169,90527; Figs. lB, 
    2A).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">The two injections in <injectionLocation>the most distal 
    portion of the presubiculum</injectionLocation>, next to the 
    parasubiculum, were positioned at two different dorsoventral levels 
    (90535, 90532; Figs. lB, 2B).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s94">All injections resulted in 
    <labelingDescription>clearly labeled 
    projections</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> could 
    be seen leaving the injection site, traveling through 
    <labelingLocation>the deep layers of the presubiculum and the 
    parasubiculum</labelingLocation> into <labelingLocation>the deep 
    layers of the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>, where they gave 
    rise to <labelingDescription>a terminal 
    plexus</labelingDescription> that was virtually confined 
    <labelingLocation>to layers I11 and I</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    3A,B).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s96">In <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>, the mediolateral position of 
    <labelingDescription>the terminal plexus</labelingDescription> and 
    the relative densities in <labelingLocation>layers I11 and 
    I</labelingLocation> appeared to be dependent on the location of 
    the injection (see below).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s97">Generally, in the most dorsal 
    section through <labelingLocation>the entorhinal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> that showed <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription>, the labeling was always confined to 
    <labelingLocation>layer 111</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s98">In the 
    cases that showed additional labeling in <labelingLocation>layer I 
    of the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> (see below) this was 
    present only at more ventral levels.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s99">In all 
    cases: we noted <labelingDescription>an almost equally dense 
    contralateral projection</labelingDescription> that showed 
    organizational characteristics similar to those of the ipsilateral 
    projection.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">Proximal injection.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">The injection in <injectionLocation>the proximal part of 
    the presubiculum</injectionLocation> (90103) mainly involved 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the superficial layers (lamina principalis 
    external</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingDescription>only a 
    few cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the layers 
    deep to the lamina dissecans (the lamina principalis 
    interna)</labelingLocation> were labeled (Fig. 4).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s102">A dense 
    plexus of PHA-L fibers and varicosities was seen in layer I11 of a 
    small area laterally in MEA and no fibers reached LEA (Figs. 3A, 
    8A).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103"><labelingDescription>A few fibers</labelingDescription> 
    were observed to extend radially from <labelingLocation>layer III, 
    forming columns through layer I1 into the deep part of layer 
    I</labelingLocation> where they branched and had varicosities 
    (Figs. 3A, 4C, 9A).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s104"><labelingDescription>The 
    labeled plexus</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> first appeared at a level 
    directly ventral to the injection.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s105">The 
    labeling, that was confined to <labelingLocation>
    MEA</labelingLocation>, increased in density at more ventral 
    levels.</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">Note that in this case, in contrast to all other 
    presubiculum injections, the fibers that left the PHA-L labeled 
    cells did not enter the entorhinal cortex directly.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Instead, they first entered the white matter, from where 
    they coursed through the deep entorhinal layers into the 
    superficial layers (Fig. 4A,B).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Central injections.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">Four injections along the dorsoventral axis of 
      <injectionLocation>the central presubiculum</injectionLocation> 
      were available (<exptLabel>cases 90552, 90473, 91169, 
      90527</exptLabel>; Figs. lB, 2A, 5).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">The injections in <exptLabel>animals 90552 and 
      90473</exptLabel> were almost in the same location, and 
      therefore, only the results of the smallest injection 
      (<exptLabel>90473</exptLabel>) will be described.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">The injection in this case mainly involved 
      <injectionLocation>the superficial layers of the 
      presubiculum</injectionLocation>, although it extended slightly 
      into the <injectionSpread>layers deep to the lamina 
      dissecans</injectionSpread> (Fig. 5.1).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">The injection in <exptLabel>case 90527</exptLabel> 
      (Fig. 5.3) showed a similar laminar involvement, whereas the 
      injection in <exptLabel>case 91169</exptLabel> (Figs.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">ZA, 5.2) was confined to <injectionLocation>the 
      superficial layer</injectionLocation>s.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">In all cases, <labelingDescription>no 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was present at levels dorsal to 
      the injection.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Labeling first appeared at the level of the injection 
      site, and extended into more ventral levels.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116"><labelingDescription>The PHA-L labeled terminal 
      plexus</labelingDescription> was located in <labelingLocation>the 
      most medial portion of MEA</labelingLocation> (Figs. 5,8B).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">In the case of the ventral injection 
      (<exptLabel>90527</exptLabel>, Fig. 5.31, 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled fiber 
      plexus</labelingDescription> extended slightly more laterally in 
      <labelingLocation>MEA</labelingLocation> than in the other cases 
      (<exptLabel>90473,91169</exptLabel>; Fig. 5).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">Although all three cases showed 
      <labelingDescription>the densest terminal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layer 
      111</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>some additional 
      labeling of branched varicose fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>layer I</labelingLocation> and of 
      <labelingDescription>a few radial fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>layer I1</labelingLocation> was observed.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">The density of <labelingLocation>layer 
      I</labelingLocation> labeling differed between the three 
      cases.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">Labeling in <labelingLocation>layer 
      I</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>almost 
      absent</labelingDescription> in <exptLabel>case 91169</exptLabel> 
      that had the injection confined to <injectionLocation>the 
      superficial layers of the presubiculum</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121">In case of the injections in <exptLabel>experiments 
      90473 and 90527</exptLabel>, in which the injection showed 
      additional minor involvement of <injectionSpread>the deep 
      layers</injectionSpread>, the density of labeling in 
      <labelingLocation>layer I</labelingLocation> was increased 
      compared to that seen in <exptLabel>case 91169</exptLabel>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">Distal injections.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> in 
    two different dorsoventral levels (<exptLabel>90535, 
    90532</exptLabel>; Figs. lB, 2B, 6) of <injectionLocation>the 
    distal presubiculum</injectionLocation>, i.e., abutting 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    parasubiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, gave rise to similar 
    labeling patterns in <labelingLocation>the entorhinal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> that differed from the patterns described 
    above.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s124">In both cases, the majority 
    of <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> were 
    located in <labelingLocation>the superficial layers of the 
    presubiculum</labelingLocation> (Fig.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s125">ZB), and 
    <labelingDescription>no cells</labelingDescription> were labeled in 
    <labelingLocation>the parasubiculum</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126"><labelingDescription>A very dense plexus of labeled 
    fibers and varicosities</labelingDescription> was present in 
    <labelingLocation>the central part of MEA</labelingLocation>, 
    avoiding <labelingLocation>the most medial and lateral portions of 
    this cortical area</labelingLocation> (Figs. 6, 8 0 .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">At the level of the injection, the density of 
    <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> in the 
    termination area appeared to be low, predominantly being present in 
    <labelingLocation>layer 111</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6.1B,6.2Cj.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">More ventrally, the density of the labeled plexus in 
    <labelingLocation>layer I11</labelingLocation> increased.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><labelingDescription>No labeling</labelingDescription> 
    was present in <labelingLocation>the entorhinal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> at levels dorsal to the injection 
    site.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s130"><labelingLocation>The deep 
    portion of the molecular layer</labelingLocation> also contained 
    <labelingDescription>a large number of labeled fibers with 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> (Figs. 3B, 9A).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131"><labelingDescription>A columnar pattern of radial fibers 
    with varicosities</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layer 
    I1</labelingLocation> was clearly present in these two cases (Fig. 
    6).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>Parasubitulum</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Two injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    parasubiculum</injectionLocation> were confined to 
    <injectionLocation>the proximal half</injectionLocation>, i.e., 
    <injectionLocation>subarea b</injectionLocation>, and involved 
    clearly different dorsoventral levels (<exptLabel>90585; 
    90790</exptLabel>; Figs. lC, 2C).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s134">Two 
    large injections (<exptLabel>91016 and 91 150</exptLabel>; Figs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">lC, 2D) in <injectionLocation>the central 
    portion</injectionLocation> were available for analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">The injection sites of these two cases overlapped almost 
    completely.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s137">In <exptLabel>animal 
    91150</exptLabel>, the longitudinal extent of the injection site 
    covered about <injectionLocation>half the dorsoventral axis of the 
    parasubiculum</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s138">Three 
    injections (<exptLabel>91151, 91177, 90779</exptLabel>) were 
    confined to <injectionLocation>the distal part of the 
    parasubiculum</injectionLocation>, i.e., <injectionLocation>subarea 
    a</injectionLocation> (Figs. lC, 2E).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139">The 
    dorsoventral level of the most dorsal of these injections 
    (<exptLabel>91151</exptLabel>) was similar to that of the proximal 
    injection in <exptLabel>case 90790</exptLabel>, and showed overlap 
    with the ventrally adjacent injection in <exptLabel>case 
    91177</exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">The most ventral injection in 
    <injectionLocation>subarea a</injectionLocation> was made in 
    <exptLabel>case 90779</exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141">All 
    injections resulted in <labelingDescription>a clearly labeled 
    projection</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> left 
    the injection site and traveled laterally into <labelingLocation>
    layers 111 and IV of the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">In none of the cases we observed 
    <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> that coursed 
    through the underlying white matter before entering 
    <labelingLocation>the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    7).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">In all these experiments, <labelingDescription>the 
    terminal plexus</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> was confined to 
    <labelingLocation>layer I1</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3C, 7) 
    although occasionally 
    <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> extended into 
    <labelingLocation>the deep part of the molecular 
    layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9B).</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">As following presubiculum injections, we noted that the 
    mediolateral position of the terminal plexus of 
    <connxTermination>the parasubiculum</connxTermination> projections 
    strongly depended on the site of the injection (see below).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">In contrast to <connxTermination>the 
    presubiculum</connxTermination> projections, 
    <connxTermination>contralateral parasubiculum</connxTermination> 
    projections were very scarce.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">Proximal injections.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Restricted injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
    proximal parasubiculum</injectionLocation> in two cases 
    (<exptLabel>90585; 90790</exptLabel>; Figs. lC, 2C, 7.1B) resulted 
    in almost similar patterns of labeling along the transverse axis of 
    <labelingLocation>the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">Following the more ventral injection 
    (<exptLabel>907901</exptLabel>, placed approximately midway 
    <injectionLocation>the longitudinal axis of the 
    parasubiculum</injectionLocation>, <labelingDescription>a dense 
    plexus of fibers and varicosities</labelingDescription> was 
    present, ctinfined to a small area in <labelingLocation>the most 
    medial portion of layer I1 of MEA</labelingLocation> (Figs. 7.1, 
    8D).</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">This terminal plexus was only present at levels ventral 
    to the injection site.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">The injection site in <exptLabel>case 90585</exptLabel> 
    involved <injectionLocation>a more dorsal part of the 
    parasubiculum</injectionLocation>, resulting in labeling in 
    <labelingLocation>the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> in a 
    more dorsal position (not illustrated).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">However, the mediolateral position of the terminal 
    plexus was similar to that seen in <exptLabel>case 
    90790</exptLabel>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Central injections.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">In two cases, the injections involved <injectionLocation>
    the central portion of the parasubiculum</injectionLocation> and 
    they showed almost complete overlap (<exptLabel>91016; 
    91150</exptLabel>; Figs. lC, 2D, 7.2B).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s155">In 
    <exptLabel>case 91150</exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    terminal fiber plexus</labelingDescription> was located laterally 
    in <labelingLocation>the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>, 
    involving <labelingLocation>the central and lateral portions of 
    layer I1 of MEA and the directly adjacent part of 
    LEA</labelingLocation> (Figs. 7, 8E).</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Like in previous cases, the labeling in <labelingLocation
    >layer I1</labelingLocation> was only present in levels ventral to 
    the level of the injection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">Distal injections.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Three injections confined to <injectionLocation>the 
    distal part of the parasubiculum</injectionLocation>, at different 
    dorsoventral levels were available for analysis (<exptLabel>91151, 
    91177, 90779</exptLabel>; Figs. lC, 2E, 7.31.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s159">In these 
    cases, the labeling in <labelingLocation>layer I1 of the entorhinal 
    cortex</labelingLocation> was not different with respect to the 
    medial-to-lateral position.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s160">Therefore, we will illustrate 
    the results of <exptLabel>case 91151</exptLabel>, since this 
    injection was positioned almost at the same dorsoventral axis as 
    the other two cases.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s161">The distribution of labeling 
    in <labelingLocation>the entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> in 
    <exptLabel>case 91 151</exptLabel> provides additional evidence for 
    the marked preference of the projections from <connxOrigin>the 
    parasubiculum</connxOrigin> for <connxTermination>layer I1 of the 
    entorhinal cortex</connxTermination> (Figs. 2, 3C, 7.3, 8F).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">In sections at the level of the injection site, 
    <labelingDescription>weak labeling</labelingDescription> was 
    present in <labelingLocation>layer I1 of LEA</labelingLocation>, 
    continuing into <labelingLocation>the adjacent most lateral portion 
    of MEA</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7.3B).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s163">Ventral 
    to the injection site, <labelingDescription>a very dense plexus of 
    PHA-L labeled fibers and varicosities</labelingDescription> 
    exclusively appeared in <labelingLocation>layer I1 of 
    LEA</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7.3C,D).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s164">In 
    sections taken through ventral levels of <labelingLocation>the 
    entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation>, at the level where 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>LEA</neuroanatomicalLandmark> takes its 
    largest dimensions, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    plexus</labelingDescription> avoided the typical layer of clustered 
    layer 11 cells and was confined to <labelingLocation>the most 
    superficial part of layer I11</labelingLocation> (layer IIb 
    according to Haug, &apos;76; Fig. 7.3E, 8F).</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s165">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">In the present study the regional and laminar 
    organization of the projections from the presubiculum and the 
    parasubiculum to the entorhinal cortex was analysed in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">Both subicular cortices projected to the superficial 
    layers of the entorhinal cortex, but they differed markedly with 
    respect to their precise terminal distribution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Projections from the presubiculum were confined to MEA 
    and distributed bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">The contralateral projection was almost equal in density 
    and distributed similarly to that found ipsilaterally (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Kohler, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">Projections from the parasubiculum to the contralateral 
    entorhinal area were weak.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">This latter finding is in line with previous reports in 
    which a weak projection from the parasubiculum to the contralateral 
    MEA has been described (Kohler, &apos;85; Van Groen and Wyss, 
    &apos;90a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">The parasubiculum projects not only to MEA but also to 
    LEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The innervation of LEA appeared quite dense and 
    extensive, which stands in contrast with the data of Kiihler 
    (&apos;85) who referred to this projection as weak and not 
    particularly widespread.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Our results corroborate the presence of clear 
    differences in the laminar distribution between the presubiculum 
    and parasubiculum projections (Kohler, &apos;85; Van Groen and 
    Wyss, &apos;90a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Fibers from the parasubiculum selectively terminate in 
    layer 11.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">The projections to the lateral part of LEA excepted, we 
    did not observe termination in either layers I11 or the deeper 
    layers rV-VI.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">In the lateral part of LEA, parasubicular fibers 
    distributed mainly to the most superficial part of layer 111, 
    directly deep to a narrow cell-free zone that separates layer I1 
    from layer 111.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">This portion of layer I11 is characterized by the 
    presence of many medium-sized darkly staining cells, and is 
    considered by some authors to represent a deep part of layer 11, 
    instead of formingpart of layer 111 (Haug, &apos;76; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">In view of the consistent distribution of parasubicular 
    projections to layer 11, the present data support this notion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Projections from the presubiculum preferentially target 
    layer 111 and to a lesser extent layer I.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">In one experiment, in which only the superficial layers 
    of the presubiculum were involved in the injection, we noted only a 
    very weak projection to layer I.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">In other cases, which showed some additional involvement 
    of cells in the layers deep to the lamina dissecans, a moderate 
    projection to layer I was labeled in addition to the layer I11 
    projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">We therefore conclude that the projections to layer I11 
    of the entorhinal cortex arise predominantly from the superficial 
    layers of the presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The presubicular fibers that distribute to layer I of 
    the entorhinal cortex originate most probably from the deep layers 
    of the presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">These fibers traverse layer I1 of the entorhinal cortex 
    on their way to layer I and they always show varicosities in layer 
    11.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">This may imply that fibers from the presubiculum do 
    innervate, be it weakly, cells in layer 11.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Since. in contrast, the parasubiculum appears to 
    selectively innervate layer 11, the presubiculum and parasubiculum 
    may thus differ not only in laminar preference of their respective 
    entorhinal projections, but also in the specificity with which this 
    distinctive laminar distribution is maintained.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Whether such is the case has been subject for further 
    study (Caballero-Bleda et al., in prep.).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">The main finding of the present study is that the 
    position of the terminal field in the entorhinal cortex of fibers 
    from the presubiculum and the parasubiculum is determined by the 
    point of origin along both the proximodistal and the dorsoventral 
    axes of these cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">We observed that, on the one hand, the proximodistal 
    position of the origm determined the mediolateral location of the 
    terminal plexus in the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">On the other hand, the dorsoventral position of the 
    origin appeared to determine the dorsoventral level of entorhinal 
    cortex that contained the main terminal field.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">With respect to this dorsoventral topography, we 
    observed both in the presubiculum and the parasubiculum that 
    projections to the entorhinal cortex never distribute to entorhinal 
    levels dorsal to that of the injection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">This organizational feature may explain why we have not 
    observed any projection to the most dorsal part of the entorhinal 
    cortex in our experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">We infer that we should have injected the most dorsal 
    portions of both subicular cortices in order to label that 
    projection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s196">Organization of 
    presubicular projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Regarding the projections from the presubiculum, our 
    findings appear to he in contrast with the earlier conclusions 
    obtained in the rat (Kohler, &apos;851, the cat (Room and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;86), and the monkey (Amaral et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">In these studies, it was reported that dorsal portions 
    of the presubiculum project to lateral parts of MEA, whereas 
    ventral portions of the presubiculum project to medial parts of 
    MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Rather, we found a relationship between the 
    proximodistal origin of the projection and the mediolateral 
    terminal distribution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">First, we noted that projections that originate from 
    different dorsoventral levels of the presubiculum hut from a 
    similar proximodistal position, distribute to a comparable location 
    along the mediolateral axis of the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The only difference noted between the respective 
    terminal distributions was that the terminal fields in the 
    entorhinal cortex differ with respect to their dorsoventral 
    position.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Consistently, we observed that projections to the 
    entorhinal cortex originating in proximal, central or distal 
    portions of the same dorsoventral level of the presubiculum reach 
    the same dorsoventral level of the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">However, in such cases the terminal distributions are 
    different from each other regarding their mediolateral position.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">An intruiging &quot;irregularity&quot; in the topography 
    of the presubicular projections is that the proximal presubiculum 
    projects to the most lateral part of MEA and the central part of 
    the presubiculum projects to the most medial part of MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Surprisingly, the distal part of the presubiculum 
    projects to the central part of MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Therefore, within the presubiculum a differentiation 
    between proximal and central parts that give rise to 
    topographically organized projections to the most lateral and 
    medial parts of the medial entorhinal cortex respectively, and a 
    distal part that selectively innervates the central zone of the 
    medial entorhinal cortex can be made.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">However, we have not been able to selectively inject the 
    distal part of the ventral presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Therefore, we cannot be sure that this hodologically 
    defined distal part of the presubiculum continues along the full 
    dorsoventral extent of the presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">This might be of interest since from a comparison of 
    Figure 8 of Haug (&apos;76) with our Figure 1, it appears that the 
    area that is involved in all the distally placed injections in the 
    presubiculum coincides with area 29e.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Although this cortical area has quite some 
    chemoarchitectonic as well as hodological aspects in common with 
    the presubiculum, it also has some connectional differences that 
    have lead Haug (&apos;76) to separate it from the presubiculum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s211">Organization of 
    parasubicular projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Although the general organization of the entorhinal 
    afferents from the parasubiculum is comparable to those from the 
    presubiculum, the present data also point to a major difference 
    between the presubiculum and parasubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Projections from the proximal portion of the 
    parasubiculum reach medial parts of MEA, and those originating in 
    the central part distribute preferentially to lateral parts of MEA 
    and the adjacent most medial parts of LEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The distal part of the parasubiculum appears to send its 
    fibers mainly to virtually the full mediolateral extent of LEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Thus, the projections from the parasubiculum to the 
    entorhinal cortex show a topographical organization in which a 
    proximodistal gradient in the parasubiculum is reflected onto a 
    mediolateral gradient in the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">This organization is inverted compared to the 
    organization of the projections from the proximal and middle parts 
    of the presubiculurn (see above).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Based on cytoarchitectonic and chemoarchitectonic 
    criteria the parasubiculum of the rat has been subdivided into two 
    areas (Blackstad, &apos;56; Haug, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Areas a and b, as they are generally described, each 
    represent approximately half of the proximodistal extent of the 
    parasubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Our findings could be taken to support a division of the 
    parasubiculum into two hodologically distinct areas.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">The injections that involve either the proximal or 
    distal extremes of the two subdivisions clearly show a difference 
    with respect to the distribution of entorhinal projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Since the entire proximodistal extent of the 
    parasubiculum distributes fibers to the complete mediolateral 
    extent of the entorhinal cortex, one could assume that each of the 
    two parasubicular divisions project to approximately half of the 
    mediolateral extent of the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Consistent mith this assumption, we observed that 
    injections in the mid-portion of the parasubiculum, involving 
    adjacent portions of both subfields a and b, result in labeling in 
    adjacent parts of both terminal fields in the entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s223">Functional 
    implications</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">The apparent laminar differences between the projections 
    from the presubiculum and the parasubiculum suggest that layers I1 
    and 111 of the entorhinal cortex, giving rise to different 
    components of the perforant pathway, may receive functionally 
    different inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">This will be addressed in more detail in a forthcoming 
    paper (Caballero-Bleda et al., in prep.).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">The specific topography of the projections from both the 
    presubiculum and the parasubiculum to the entorhinal cortex suggest 
    that through each of these pathways information is selectively 
    conveyed to different dorsoventral and mediolateral parts of the 
    entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">There is evidence that the most dorsal part of the 
    presubiculum receives visual input, either directly from primary 
    visual cortex, or by way of a relay through the retrosplenial 
    cortex (Vogt and Miller, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Moreover, the dorsal presubiculum is characterized by 
    the presence of so-called head direction cells (Taube et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Whether comparable differences exist between dorsal and 
    ventral parts of the parasubiculum, and whether different 
    proximodistal parts of both the presubiculum and the parasubiculum 
    transmit functionally different information to restricted cell 
    populations in the entorhinal cortex, needs further 
    investigation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">The possible presence of a selective distribution of 
    information over the mediolateral axis of the entorhinal cortex is 
    of interest in the light of the topographical organization of the 
    origin of the perforant pathway along this entorhinal axis (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Witter et al., &apos;86, &apos;89b).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s232">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s233">This work was supported by 
    grants DGICYT BE90-096 (Stay of Spanish Researchers in Foreign 
    Research Centers), DGYCYT PB87!</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s234">0668-C01 and PB90/0296-C01 
    from the Spanish Ministry of Science and Education, and a Twinning 
    Grant from the European Science Foundation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s235">We thank Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s236">Barbara Jorritsma-Byham for 
    excellent technical assistance and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s237">Dirk de Jong for photographic 
    processing.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s238">The helpful suggestions 
    during the preparation of the manuscript of Drs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s239">H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s240">Groenewegen and F.G 
    Wouterlood are greatly appreciated.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s241">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Amaral, D.G..</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Insausti, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Cowan 11984, The commissural connections of the monkey 
    hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-ItalicMT" id="s249">224:307-336.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Amaral, D.G., C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Dolorfo, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Alvarez-Koyo L1991) Organization of CA1 projections to 
    the suhiculum: a PHA-L analysis in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Hippocampus 1:415-435.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Ueckstead, K.M. 11978) Afferent connections of the 
    entorhinal area in the rat as demonstrated by retrograde 
    cell-labelling with horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Brain Res. 152:249-264.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Blackstad, &apos;T.W 1956) ( Commissural connections of 
    the hippocampal region the rat, with special reference to their 
    mode of termination. d.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Neurol. 105417-537.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Habcrly.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">L.B., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Price (1978) Association and commissural fibrr systems 
    of the olfactory cortcx in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Systems originating In the pirirorm cortex and adjacent 
    art Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Keurol 178r711-740.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Haug, F.M.S. ( 1976) Sulphide silver pattern and 
    cytoarchitectonics of parahippocaiiipal areas in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Special reference to the subdivision of area 
    entorhinalis (area 28) and its demarcation from the pyriform 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Cell Biol. 521-73.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Ishizuka, N., J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Weher, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Amaral(lYY0) Organization of intrahippocampal 
    projections originating from CA3 pyramidal cells in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Neurol. 295r580-623.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Kohler, C:. 11985) Intrinsic projections ot&apos;the 
    retrohippocampal repon in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">&apos;The suhieular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Neurol. 236504-522.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Kusel, K.C., G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Van Hoesen, and J.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">West 11981) Olfactory bulb projections to the 
    parahipocampal area of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Neurol. 198:467-482.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Kretkk, J.E., and J.1,.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Price (19773 Projections from the amygdaloid complex and 
    adjacent olfactow structures to the entorhinal cortex and to the 
    subiculum in the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Neurol. 172723-752.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Paxinos.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates. 
    2nd edition.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Sydney: Academir Press.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Room.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">P.. and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Groenewegen (1986) Connrctions of the parahippocampal 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Cortical afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Ncurol. 251:41545U.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Room.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">P..</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Groenewegen, and A.H.M. 1,ohman (1Y841 Inputs from the 
    olfactory bulb and olfactory cortex to the eritorhinal cortex in 
    the eat I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Anatomical observations.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Brain Rcs. .56:4RX496 Shipley, M.T. 1975, The 
    topographic and laminar organization of presuhirulum&apos;s 
    projection to the ipsiand contralateral entorhinal cortex in the 
    guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Neurol. 160:127-146.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Steward, 0. (1976) Topographic organization of the 
    projections from the entorhiiial area to the hippocampal formation 
    in the rat. d.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Neurol. 167:285-3 14.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Steward.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">O., and S.A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Scnville (1976) Cells of origin of entorhinal cortical 
    fierents to the hippocampus and fascia denlata or the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Ncurol. 169:347 370.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Swanson, I,.W, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Cowan (1977) An autoradiographic study oi&apos;the 
    organization of the efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Comp Neurol. 172:49-84.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Tauhe, cJ.S., R.U.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Muller: and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Ranck (1990) Head-direction cells recorded from the 
    postsuhiculum in freely moving rats.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Neurosci. 10:42@-435.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Turner, B.H., K.C.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Gupta, andM.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Mishkin (1978)&apos;Thelocusand cytoarchitecture of the 
    projection areas of the olfactory bulb in Macaca mulatta.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Kirurul. 177.381-396.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Van Groen, T., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Wyss i199Ua) &apos;The connections of presuhiculum and 
    parasubiculum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Brain Reh. ,518:227-243.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Van Groen.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">&apos;T., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Wyss il9YOh) The postsubicular cortex in the rat: 
    Characterization of the fourth region of subicular cortex and its 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Brain Kes. 529r165-177.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Van Hoesen, G.W. ( 1982) The parahippocampal gyms.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">New observations regarding Its cortical connections in 
    the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">TINS 5rY45-350.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Van Hoescn.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">G.W., and D.N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Pandya (1975) Some runnections of the entorhinal (area 
    281 and perirhinal (area 35) cortices of the rhcsus monkey I.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Trmporal lobe aKerenls.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Brain Rcs. 95:l 24.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Van Hoesen, C.W., D.N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Pandya, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Butters 1975) ( Some connections of cnt.orhina1 (area 
    28) and pcrirhinal (area 3.5) cortices of the rhesus monkey. 11 
    Frontal lobe afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Urain Res. 95:25-38.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Vogt, B.A., and M W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Miller (1983) Cortical connections between rat cingulate 
    cortex and visual, motor. and postsuhicular cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neurol. 2 If?</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">: 192 210.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Witter, M.P.. and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Amaral (1991) Entorhinal cortex of the monkey: V.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">projections to the dentate gyrus, hippocampus, and 
    suhicular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Neurol. 307:437459.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">With, M.P., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Groenewegen il990i The subiculum: cytoarchitectonically 
    n simple structure. hut, hodologica complex In J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">StormMathisen.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">,J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Zinimer, and O.P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Ottersen (ed IJnderstanding the Brain Through the 
    Hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Amsterdam: Elsevier, Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Brain Res. 8.?</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">:4 7-58.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">WiLter, M.P., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Grncnrwrgcn (1992) Organizational principles of 
    hippocampal connections.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">In M.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Trimble and T.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Bolwig (eds): The Temporal Lobes and the Limbic 
    System.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">England: Wrightson Biomedical Publishing LTD. pp. 
    37-60.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Witter, M.P., P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Room, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Groenewegen, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Lohman (19861 Connections of the parahipocampal cortcx 
    in lhe cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">V.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Intrinsic connections; comments on input :output 
    connections with the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Cornp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Neurol. 25278-94.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Witter.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">M.P., U.G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Amaral, and G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Van Hoesen (1989aJ The entorhinaldentate projection in 
    the macaque monkey: topographical organization dong the 
    lonfitudinal axis of the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Neurosci. 9216-228.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Wittcr, MI!</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">, H J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Groencwegen.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">F.H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Lopes Ua Silva, and A.1I.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Lohman (19A9b) Fiinctional organizat,ion of the 
    extrinsic and intrinsic circuitry of thr parahippocampal region.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Neurobiol. 33:161-254 Wit.tcr.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">M.P., R.H Ostendorf. and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Groenewegen (1990j Heterogeneity in the dorsal suhiculum 
    of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Distinct neuronal columns project to different cortical 
    and subcortical t,argels.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Neurosci 2718-725.</S>
  </References>

</File>

