<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Topography of Descending Projections From the Inferior 
  Colliculus to Auditory Brainstem Nuclei in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>ALEJANDRO CAICEDO AND HORST HERBERT</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">We examined the organization of descending projections 
    from the inferior colliculus (IC) to auditory brainstem nuclei and 
    to pontine and reticular nuclei in the rat by employing the 
    anterograde axonal tracer Phuseolus uulguris-leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Small PHA-L injections into cytologically defined 
    subnuclei of the IC revealed that each subnucleus has a unique 
    pattern of efferent projections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The central nucleus of the IC projects in a topographic 
    order to the dorsal nucleus of the lateral lemniscus (DLL), the 
    rostral periolivary nucleus (RPO), the ventral nucleus of the 
    trapezoid body (VNTB), and the dorsal cochlear nucleus (DCN).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">It is assumed that this topography represents a 
    cochleotopic arrangement.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The external cortex of the IC projects to the nucleus 
    sagulum (Sag), the RPO, the VNTB, and the DCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Minor projections were found to pontine and reticular 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Efferent fibers from the dorsal cortex of the IC terminate 
    mainly in the Sag, while other nuclei of the auditory and 
    extra-auditory brainstem receive only minor projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">The intercollicular zone sends a moderate number of fibers 
    to the DLL and very few, if any, to the remaining auditory 
    brainstem nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">In contrast, fairly strong projections from the 
    intercollicular zone to the reticular formation were found.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Auditory processing in the brainstem is performed by 
    several medullary and mesencephalic nuclei that are connected with 
    each other in a complex manner.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Acoustic signals are transmitted from the cochlea to the 
    cochlear nuclei and then relayed through multiple parallel 
    ascending pathways to higher auditory centers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">In turn, most of the higher centers have descending 
    projections to lower auditory nuclei and even to the cochlea (for a 
    recent review, see Huffman and Henson, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Certain cell groups in the brainstem are exclusively 
    concerned with descending pathways, while others, such as the 
    inferior colliculus (IC), serve as relays for ascending, as well as 
    descending, information.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Here we focus on descending projections of the IC to 
    brainstem nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">In the past, several studies of various mammalian species 
    have appeared that have reported projections to auditory and 
    extra-auditory nuclei in the brainstem, including the periolivarv 
    and the cochlear nuclei (e.g., Rasmussen, &apos;64; Moore and 
    coldberg, &apos;66; Noort, &apos;69; Carey and Webster, &apos;71; 
    Borg, &apos;73; Adams and Warr, &apos;76; Kane and Conlee, 
    &apos;79; Andersen et al., &apos;80; Conlee and Kane, &apos;82; 
    Hashikawa, &apos;83; Syka et al., &apos;881, the pontine nuclei 
    (e.g., Aitkin and Boyd, &apos;75; Kawamura, &apos;75; Hashikawa, 
    &apos;83; Schuller et al., &apos;911, and reticular nuclei (e.g., 
    Andrezik et al., &apos;81; Newman, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">However, despite the fairly large number of anatomical 
    studies, only a few investigators have described a differential 
    pattern of the projections from individual subnuclei of the IC to 
    the auditory brainstem.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Studies dealing specifically with descending projections 
    of the IC in the rat are scarce.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Faye-Lund (&apos;86) showed collicular projections to the 
    rostral periolivary nucleus, to the ventral nucleus of the 
    trapezoid body, and to the dorsal cochlear nucleus all originating 
    in the external cortex and in the central nucleus of the IC.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Recently, preliminary reports have suggested that in the 
    rat, the projections from the central nucleus of the IC to the 
    dorsal cochlear nucleus and the ventral nucleus of the trapezoid 
    body are topographically organized (Saldana, &apos;90, &apos;911, 
    and that the collicular fibers may contact neurons of the medial 
    olivocochlear system (Vetter and Saldana, &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In the present investigation we analyzed the descending 
    projections of four individual subnuclei of the IC in the rat, 
    i.e., the central nucleus, the external and dorsal cortices, and 
    the intercollicular zone, by using the anterograde axonal tracer 
    Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">We were particularly interested in whether the anatomical 
    and functional diversity of these IC subnuclei is also reflected in 
    a differential pattern of descending pathways to auditory and 
    extra-auditory brainstem nuclei and whether individual pathways 
    exhibit a topographic order.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">A preliminary report of this study has been previously 
    published (Caicedo and Herbert, &apos;91).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s23">MATERIAL AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The experiments were performed in 36 female SpragueDawley 
    rats weighingZ10-320 g.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The animals were anesthetized with 7% chloral hydrate (40 
    mgi100 g body weight) and fixed in a stereotaxic device.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">They received injections of the anterogradely transported 
    axonal tracer PHA-L (2.5% in 10 mM sodium phosphate buffered 
    saline, pH 8.0) into the different subnuclei of the IC.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The tracer was delivered iontophoretically through 
    beveled glass micropipattes with 25-50 km tip diameters by means of 
    a pulsed positive current of 5 p A with a 50% duty cycle (5 seconds 
    onloff), which was applied for 15 minutes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s28">Tissue preparation</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Six to 16 days after the PHA-L injections, the animals 
    were anesthetized and perfused through the aorta with 0.9% saline, 
    followed by the fixative prepared according to the two-step pH 
    change protocol of Berod et al. (&apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">After perfusion with 200 ml of ice-cold 4% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 h4 sodium acetate buffer ipH 6.51, followed 
    by 300 ml of ice-cold 4% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M borate buffer 
    (pH l l .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">O ) , the brains were removed and postfixed overnight at 
    4°C in the borate buffer fixative containing 56 sucrose.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The brains were then blocked and soaked for 2 days in 0.1 
    M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) containing 30% sucrose, at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Tissue blocks from the lower medulla to the posterior 
    thalamus were cut coronally on a freezing microtome at 40 km and 
    divided into three series.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">One series was further processed by the immunoperoxidasc 
    technique.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The second series was mounted on gelatine-coated slides 
    and stained for Nissl-substance with thionin; the third series was 
    discarded.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s36">Immunoperoxidase 
    staining</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Sections were immunohistochemically processed by the 
    peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) method in order to identify 
    PHA-L-labeled fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">First, the sections were rinsed in several changes of 
    Tris-buffered saline (TBS) and then incubated in a blocking 
    solution containing 10% normal goat serum, 2% bovine serum albumin 
    (BSA), and 0.3%, Triton X-100 in 50 mM TBS, pH 7.6.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">After 1 hour the sections were transferred into the 
    primary antibody solution of rabbit anti-PHA-L (DAKO), diluted 
    1:3,000, in a carrier containing 1% normal goat serum, 1% BSA, and 
    0.3% Triton X-100 in TBS, and then incubated for 48 hours at 
    4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Thereafter, the sections were rinsed for 30 minutes in 
    several changes of TBS, transferred to an unlabeled swine 
    anti-rabbit IgG antiserum (DAKO) diluted 150 in the carrier, and 
    incubated for 1.5 hours at room temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">They were then extensively rinsed in TBS and incubated in 
    a rabbit-PAP complex (DAKO) diluted 1: 150 in the carrier.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">After 1.5 hours at room temperature, the sections were 
    again rinsed in several changes of TBS.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">The final visualization of the anterogradely transported 
    PHA-L was accomplished by processing the sections in TBS, 
    containing 0.05% 3,3-diaminobenzidine and 0.01% HzOz, for 5-15 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The incubation was stopped by transferring the sections 
    into TBS.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">After several rinses in TBS the sections were mounted on 
    gelatine-coated slides, air dried, dehydrated in alcohol, cleared 
    in xylene, and coverslipped with Entellan.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s46">Data analysis</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Of the 36 animals injected, the data of 22 animals, in 
    which the injection sites were clearly confined to a single IC 
    subnucleus, will be presented.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Sections were viewed by using brightfield illumination 
    and Nomarski optics.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The location of the injection sites and the distribution 
    of PHA-L-labeled fibers in the midbrain and medullary brainstem 
    were mapped with a drawing tube.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The PHA-L injection sites in the IC appeared as 
    homogeneous brown spots (Fig. 1) containing intensely labeled 
    dark-brown somata (see Fig. 1C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Gerfen and Sawchenko (&apos;84) assumed that PHA-L is 
    only incorporated into, and axonally transported from?</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">these labeled neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">We thus refer to the population of neurons that is filled 
    by the tracer as the injection site.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Labeled axons were considered to represent terminal 
    labeling when they were intensely arborized, had a curved and 
    irregular course, and exhibited numerous en passant and terminal 
    varicosities.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">In contrast, traversing fibers generally had straight 
    trajectories, larger diameters, and few, if any, axonal 
    varicosities.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The location of labeled fibers within cytoarchitectural 
    boundaries was defined by superimposing projections of the 
    corresponding thionin-stained sections onto the drawings, with bran 
    outlines and blood vessels as reference points.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Occasionally, we also observed retrogradely labeled 
    somata resulting from the PHA-L injections into the IC, which is in 
    accordance with the original report of Gerfen and Sawchenko ( 
    84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The parcellation of the inferior colliculus is based on 
    the studies of Faye-Lund and Osen ( 85) and Herbert et al</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">( 91) and those of the cochlear nucleus and the superior 
    olivary complex are according to Osen et al. ( 84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The parcellation of the lateral lemniscal nuclei and the 
    adjacent areas is based on the cytoarchitecture in Nissl-stained 
    sections of our material and is in accordance with PreuB 91).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s62">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">In order to analyze the descending projections of the 
    inferior colliculus (IC), we placed small injections of the 
    anterograde tracer PHA-L into individual subnuclei of the IC (Fig. 
    1) and mapped the distribution of presumed terminal fibers in the 
    midbrain and brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">We found that each IC subnucleus has a unique pattern of 
    efferent projections, and furthermore, that the projections from 
    the central nucleus of the IC to the auditory brainstem nuclei are 
    topographically organized.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s65">Injections into the 
    central nucleus (ICC)</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">In 8 animals, <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
    injections were confined to <injectionLocation>the 
    ICC</injectionLocation> (e.g., Fig. 1A).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s67">The 
    <labelingDescription>PHA-L-labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    the injection site gave rise to <labelingDescription>a dense band 
    of axonal labeling</labelingDescription>, oriented from 
    ventrolateral to dorsomedial and extending from <labelingLocation>
    the central nucleus to layer 3 of the dorsal cortex of the 
    IC</labelingLocation> (Fig. 1A).</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s68">
    <labelingLocation>Axonal labeling</labelingLocation> was also 
    present in <labelingLocation>layer 3 of the external cortex of the 
    IC</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s69">In <labelingLocation>the 
    contralateral IC</labelingLocation> a corresponding pattern of 
    labeling was found, although <labelingDescription>less 
    dense</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Lateral lemniscal 
    nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">First, we will give a brief description of the 
    parcellation of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lemniscal 
    nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation> and the adjacent areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The dorsal nucleus ofthe lateral 
    lemniscus (DLL)</neuroanatomicalLocation> is clearly demonstrated 
    in thionin-stained coronal sections as an oval nucleus made up of 
    intensely stained, fairly large somata (Fig. 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The somata form dorsoventrally oriented cell columns 
    which are aligned parallelly to the fascicles of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral 
    lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Ventrally, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    DLL</neuroanatomicalLocation> is bordered by a group of lightly 
    stained, small cells whose flattened, fusiform somata are 
    mediolaterally oriented (Fig. 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">We have therefore termed it <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    horizontal cell group of the lateral lemniscus 
    (H)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">This horizontal cell group clearly separates 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the DLL</neuroanatomicalLocation> from the 
    further ventrally located <neuroanatomicalLocation>intermediate 
    nucleus of the lateral leniniscus 
    (ILL)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    ILL</neuroanatomicalLocation> consists of darkly stained, 
    medium-sized neurons whose round to oval somata are also grouped in 
    clusters formed by <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral 
    lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Medially, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nuclei of the 
    lateral lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLocation> are bordered by 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the perilemniscal zone 
    (PI)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The lightly stained, small neurons of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the PI</neuroanatomicalLocation> appear 
    like strings of pearls which are aligned along the dorsoventrally 
    running fascicles of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the lateral 
    lemniscus</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The nucleus saplum 
    (Sag)</neuroanatomicalLocation>, finally, is situatedjust lateral 
    to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the DLL</neuroanatomicalLocation> and 
    can be identified by its lighterstained, medium-sized somata (Fig. 
    2).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Efferent fibers could be traced leaving <connxOrigin>the 
    ICC</connxOrigin> in its ventralmost part and entering 
    <connxTermination>the lateral lemniscus</connxTermination> where 
    they ran ventrally without having a preferential location within 
    the tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">At the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ipsilateral 
    DLL</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, numerous fibers gave off axond 
    collaterals, which then entered <labelingLocation>the 
    DLL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3C,D), thereby forming two 
    medidat.erally oriented bands of <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Highpower light microscopy revealed that 
    <labelingDescription>the terminal fibers</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the DLL</labelingLocation> were 
    <labelingDescription>intensely beaded</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">They were often found closely apposed to horizontally 
    oriented neuronal somata and primary dendrites (Fig. 3A-F), 
    presumably forming synaptic contacts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Occasionally, <labelingDescription>terminal 
    axons</labelingDescription> were located in close proximity to 
    retrogradely labeled neurons (Figs. 3A,F, 4C), indicating a 
    reciprocity of the ICC/DLLconnections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86"><connxTermination>The intermediate nucleus of the lateral 
    lemniscus</connxTermination> received only a sparse projection from 
    <connxOrigin>the ICC</connxOrigin>, while <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral nucleus</labelingLocation>, as well as 
    <labelingLocation>all contralateral nuclei of the lateral 
    lemniscus</labelingLocation>, were <labelingDescription>devoid of 
    fibers</labelingDescription>.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87">A shift of injection sites along the dorsoventral axis 
      of <injectionLocation>the ICC</injectionLocation> resulted in a 
      change in the position of <labelingDescription>the terminal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      DLL</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">After <exptLabel>injections into <injectionLocation>the 
      dorsal part of the ICC</injectionLocation></exptLabel> were made, 
      two horizontally oriented bands of <labelingDescription>axonal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      middle portion of the DLL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5, experiment 
      IC 41).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">Injections placed into <injectionLocation>medial 
      aspects of the ICC</injectionLocation> also resulted in two 
      labeled bands.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90">However, each band had shifted vertically towards the 
      dorsal and ventral periphery (Fig. 5, experiment IC 33).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">Finally, in the case of <injectionLocation>ventral 
      ICC</injectionLocation> injections, the labeling was seen to have 
      reached the dorsal and ventral boundaries of <labelingLocation>
      the DLL</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5, experiment IC 31; see also 
      Fig. 4A,B).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Superior oliuary 
      complex</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">Numerous <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      lemniscus</labelingLocation> could also be seen running further 
      ventrally, then entering <labelingLocation>the rostrd periolivary 
      region (RPO) and the ventral nucleus of the trapezoid body (VNTB; 
      Fig. 6A-C)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">Within <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral RPO and 
      VNTB</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>the 
      fibers</labelingDescription> arborized intensely and formed 
      <labelingDescription>a dense axonal plexus</labelingDescription> 
      which exhibited <labelingDescription>numerous en passant and 
      terminal varicosities</labelingDescription> (Fig. 6D,E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">In <labelingLocation>the VNTB</labelingLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> were 
      often seen closely apposed to large VNTB neurons (Fig. 6D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">In addition, <labelingDescription>very sparse axonal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
      superior paraolivary nucleus and in the dorsal periolivary 
      region</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">Injections into <injectionLocation>dorsal, versus 
      ventral, parts of the ICC</injectionLocation> also resulted in a 
      shift of <labelingDescription>the anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the RPO and 
      the VNTB</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections 
      placed dorsally in <injectionLocation>the ICC</injectionLocation> 
      gave rise to <labelingDescription>terminal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>lateral 
      aspects of the RPO and VNTB</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7, 
      experiment JC 421, while, after injecting <injectionLocation>
      middle parts of the ICC</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>terminal labeling</labelingDescription> 
      occupied <labelingLocation>middle aspects of the RPO and 
      VNTB</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7, experiment IC 33).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Finally, injections into <injectionLocation>the ventral 
      part of the ICC</injectionLocation> resulted in 
      <labelingDescription>terminal labeling</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the most medial aspects of the RPO and 
      VNTB</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3, experiment IC 46; see also Fig. 
      6A-C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">In each experiment <labelingDescription>the axonal 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the RPO and 
      the VNTB</labelingLocation> appeared as a continuous column 
      stretching throughout the entire rostrocaudal extent of the 
      nuclei (e.g., Fig. 7A-D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">Corresponding to the dorsoventral shift of the 
      injection sites in the ICC, this continuous column of labeled 
      fibers moved from lateral to medial in <labelingLocation>the RPO 
      and VNTB</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Cochlear 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> also coursed through 
      <labelingLocation>the trapezoid body</labelingLocation> and 
      through <labelingLocation>the dorsal acoustic 
      stria</labelingLocation>, where they ran bilaterally towards
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal cochlear nuclei 
      (DCN)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Within <labelingLocation>the DCN</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingDescription>the presumed terminal 
      fibers</labelingDescription> branched extensively and exhibited 
      numerous <labelingDescription>en passant and terminal 
      varicosities</labelingDescription> (Figs. 8, 9).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105"><labelingDescription>The fibers</labelingDescription> 
      formed a narrow band oriented perpendicularly to the surface of 
      <labelingLocation>the DCN</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8Cj.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">This band of fibers extended from <labelingLocation>
      the deep layer of the DCN into the fusiform cell 
      layer</labelingLocation> without entering <labelingLocation>the 
      outermost molecular layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9B,Di, and it 
      continued along <labelingLocation>the rostrocaudal extent of the 
      DCN</labelingLocation> (Fig. 10).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107"><labelingDescription>Some labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation>
      the granule cell areas</labelingLocation> which surround the 
      ventral cochlear nucleus (Fig. 10).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108"><labelingDescription>Beaded 
      axons</labelingDescription> were often found in close proximity 
      to neuronal somata in <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      DCN</labelingLocation>, presumably forming synaptic contacts 
      (Figs.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">SA, 9D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">Occasiondly, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were also seen closely apposed to 
      retrogradely labeled somata, indicating reciprocity of the 
      crossed ICCi DCN-connections (Fig.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">SB!.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">Our experiments further revealed that the projection 
      from <connxOrigin>the ICC</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the 
      DCN</connxTermination> is also topographically organized.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">After small <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> 
      injections into <injectionLocation>the dorsal 
      ICC</injectionLocation> we observed <labelingDescription>a narrow 
      band of terminal labeling</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the 
      DCN</labelingLocation>, which was oriented perpendicularly to the 
      surface of the nucleus (Fig. 10, experiment IC 42).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">The labeling within <labelingLocation>the 
      DCN</labelingLocation> shifted dorsomedially when 
      <tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections were placed 
      further ventrally into <injectionLocation>the 
      ICC</injectionLocation> (Fig. 10, experiment TC 33).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">After the tracer was deposited most ventrally in 
      <injectionLocation>the ICC</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>the terminal fibers</labelingDescription> 
      were found in <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial aspect of the 
      DCN</labelingLocation> (Fig. 10, experiment IC 46; see also Fig. 
      9).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">In addition to <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the auditory 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>, presumed <labelingDescription>terminal 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were present ipsilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>nuclei of the reticular 
      formation</labelingLocation>, which are not considered a part of 
      the auditory pathway proper.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117"><neuroanatomicalLocation>These reticular 
      nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation> included <labelingLocation>the 
      pontine nucleus and the lateral paragigantocellular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12).</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s118">Injections into the 
    external cortex (EC)</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">Five animals received 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the 
    EC</injectionLocation></exptLabel> (e.g., Fig. 1D).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s120">These 
    injections resulted in considerable 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
    bilaterally in <labelingLocation>the EC and DC</labelingLocation>, 
    both with an ipsilateral predominance.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s121">In 
    contrast, <labelingLocation>the ICC</labelingLocation> was largely 
    <labelingDescription>devoid of labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s122"><labelingDescription>Efferent 
    axons</labelingDescription> emerging from <labelingLocation>the 
    EC</labelingLocation> ran ventrally into <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral lemniscus</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s123">Along 
    their course, fibers emitted <labelingDescription>varicose axonal 
    branches</labelingDescription> into <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
    sagulum and the horizontal cell group</labelingLocation> (Fig. 11, 
    <exptLabel>experiment IC 26</exptLabel>).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s124">
    <labelingLocation>The core nuclei of the lateral lemniscus, i.e., 
    the dorsal, intermediate, and ventral nuclei</labelingLocation>, 
    were <labelingDescription>largely devoid of 
    fibers</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s125"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
    axons</labelingDescription> also ran further ventrally through 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral lemniscus</labelingLocation>, 
    entering <labelingLocation>the superior olivary 
    complex</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s126">There they formed 
    <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of presumed terminal 
    fibers</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilateral RPO and VNTB</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">In contrast to the efferents from <connxOrigin>the 
    ICC</connxOrigin>, the terminating axons from <connxOrigin>the 
    EC</connxOrigin> did not show a topographical arrangement, but were 
    evenly distributed in <labelingLocation>the RPO and 
    VNTB</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128"><labelingDescription>Individual labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were also present in <labelingLocation>
    the superior paraolivary nucleus</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal and caudal periolivary 
    region</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s129"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were further found bilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>the trapezoid body and in the dorsal acoustic 
    stria</labelingLocation>, running towards both 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>cochlear 
    nuclei</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s130">There 
    the labeled axons arborized and formed <labelingDescription>diffuse 
    patches of presumed terminal fibers</labelingDescription> 
    bilaterally in <labelingLocation>the DCN</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the granule cell layers</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
    12).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131"><labelingDescription>Prominent anterograde axonal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was also present ipsilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>various nuclei of the reticular 
    formation</labelingLocation>. including <labelingLocation>the 
    pontine nucleus, the ventrolateral tegmental nucleus, the 
    gigantocellular reticular nucleus, and the lateral 
    paragigantocellular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s132">Injections into the 
    dorsal cortex (DC)</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">In four animals the 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections were 
    confined to <injectionLocation>the 
    DC</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s134">In these 
    cases, intranuclear labeling was seen bilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>layers 2 and 3 of the DC</labelingLocation>, with 
    an ipsilateral predominance.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s135">In <labelingLocation>the 
    ipsilateral EC</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>patches of 
    anterogradely labeled fibers</labelingDescription> were found in 
    <labelingLocation>layer 2</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">Remarkable was <labelingDescription>the absence of 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    ICC</labelingLocation>, where only <labelingDescription>traversing 
    axons</labelingDescription> could be observed.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137"><labelingDescription>Descending 
    fibers</labelingDescription> leaving the IC entered 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral lemniscus</labelingLocation>, where 
    some of them branched to form <labelingDescription>a prominent 
    plexus of varicose fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation
    >the nucleus sagulum</labelingLocation> (Fig. 11, 
    <exptLabel>experiment IC 45</exptLabel>).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s138">
    <labelingLocation>The core nuclei of the lateral 
    lemniscus</labelingLocation> were largely 
    <labelingDescription>devoid of terminal 
    fibers</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139"><labelingLocation>In the 
    superior olivary complex</labelingLocation> there was only 
    <labelingDescription>sparse labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the RPO and the VNTB</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">Also, in <labelingLocation>the DCN</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>the anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
    was <labelingDescription>very scarce</labelingDescription> compared 
    to the labeling after injections into <injectionLocation>the ICC or 
    the EC</injectionLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141">It should be noted that the 
    efferent projections from <connxOrigin>the DC</connxOrigin> to 
    <connxTermination>lower auditory brainstem 
    nuclei</connxTermination> were far more limited compared to those 
    from <connxOrigin>the ICC and the EC</connxOrigin>, and that the 
    major target area of <connxOrigin>DC</connxOrigin> fibers appears 
    to be <connxTermination>the nucleus sagulum</connxTermination> 
    (Fig. 12).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142">Projections from 
    <connxOrigin>the DC</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the 
    reticular formation</connxTermination> were restricted to 
    <connxTermination>the lateral paragigantocellular 
    nucleus</connxTermination> (Fig. 12).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s143">Injections into the 
    intercollicular zone (IZ)</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">In six animals 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA-L</tracerChemical> injections were 
    placed into <injectionLocation>the 
    IZ</injectionLocation></exptLabel> (corresponding in location to 
    <injectionLocation>the rostra1 portion of the 
    EC</injectionLocation>, as defined by Faye-Lund and Osen, 
    &apos;85).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s145">These injections resulted in 
    <labelingDescription>extensive axonal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral 
    EC</labelingLocation>, extending into its most caudal pole.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">In <labelingLocation>the remaining IC 
    subnuclei</labelingLocation>, only <labelingDescription>sparse 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147"><labelingDescription>Descending 
    axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
    IZ</injectionLocation> could be traced entering <labelingLocation>
    the lateral lemniscus</labelingLocation>, where they branched and 
    formed <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> within the confines of 
    <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral DLL</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148"><labelingDescription>Only few labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    horizontal cell group and the perilemniscal 
    zone</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s149">In <labelingLocation>the 
    remaining nuclei of the lower auditory brainstem</labelingLocation> 
    only <labelingDescription>sparse terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was observed.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s150">A 
    remarkable feature of the projections from <connxOrigin>the 
    IZ</connxOrigin> is the prominent input to 
    <connxTermination>pontine and medullary reticular 
    nuclei</connxTermination>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s151"><labelingDescription>Presumed 
    terminal fibers</labelingDescription> were seen ipsilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral tegmental nucleus and in the 
    lateral paragigantocellular nucleus</labelingLocation>, as well as 
    bilaterally in <labelingLocation>the caudal and oral pontine 
    reticular nuclei and in the gigantocellular reticular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12).</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s152">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">The present study has demonstrated that the subnuclei of 
    the IC have a differential pattern of descending projections 
    (summarized in Fig. 12).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">The collicular projections to lower auditory nuclei 
    originate primarily in the central nucleus and the external cortex, 
    while the dorsal cortex and the intercollicular zone have only 
    modest descending projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">Furthermore, we found that the efferent projections from 
    the central nucleus to the dorsal nucleus of the lateral lemniscus, 
    the rostral periolivary nucleus, the ventral nucleus of the 
    trapezoid body, and the dorsal cochlear nuclei are topographically 
    organized.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Each subnucleus of the IC also projects, more or less 
    prominently, to various extra-auditory nuclei of the pons and the 
    reticular formation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s157">Colliculolemniscal 
    projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Our tracing experiments revealed that the collicular 
    projections to the lateral lemniscus are largely confined to the 
    dorsal nucleus, the sagulum, the horizontal cell group, and the 
    perilemniscal zone.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">The rat&apos;s intermediate and ventral nucleus of the 
    lateral lemniscus receives few, if any, collicular fibers, which is 
    in line with the findings of Faye-Lund (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">Projections to the ventral nucleus have been reported in 
    the monkey and the kangaroo rat (Moore and Goldberg, &apos;66; 
    Carey and Webster, &apos;71).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">However, this contrasting result could be due to species 
    differences or, as assumed by Faye-Lund, actually represents a 
    projection to the rostra1 periolivary nucleus, Projections to the 
    dorsal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">Injections of PHA-L into the central nucleus of the IC 
    yielded two distinct horizontal bands of presumed terminal labeling 
    in the ipsilateral DLL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">We report for the first time that this projection is 
    topographically arranged: neurons located dorsally in the central 
    nucleus (corresponding to a lowfrequency site, Clopton and 
    Winfield, &apos;73) project to the middle portion of the DLL; 
    neurons located ventrally in the central nucleus (corresponding to 
    a high-frequency site) project to the peripheral, i.e., the dorsal 
    and ventral aspect of the DLL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Because of the clear-cut separation of the DLL and the 
    ILL by the horizontal cell group, we can rule out that the ventral 
    band of labeling might actually be located in the dorsal aspect of 
    the ILL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Other studies which reported colliculolemniscal 
    connections in various species also pointed to the DLL as the major 
    target nucleus, but did not demonstrate a topographic order (Moore 
    and Goldberg, &apos;66; Carey and Webster, &apos;71; Borg, 
    &apos;73; Andersen et al., &apos;80; Syka et al., 88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">In addition, the DLL receives a diffuse input from the 
    intercollicular zone, and yet receives hardly any fibers from the 
    external and dorsal cortices of the IC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">The horizontal lamination of labeled collicular axons in 
    the DLL, as reported in the present study, is in agreement with 
    morphological and anatomical descriptions of the DLL in the rat, 
    mouse, and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">In Golgi-stained material, DLI, neurons and terminal 
    fibers within the DLL appear to be oriented horizontally (Kane and 
    Barone, 80; Morest and Oliver, 84; Iwahori, 86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Iwahori ( 86) further reported that axons in the DLL 
    form horizontally oriented pericellular baskets, which closely 
    track the somadendritic shape of DLL neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Similar observations were made of colliculolemniscal 
    axons (present study, see Fig. 3E), as well as of 
    GAl3Aimmunoreactive varicosities, which are aligned horizontally 
    along the soma and dendrites of DLL neurons (Adams and Mugnaini, 
    84; Moore and Moore; 87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">Furthermore, terminal fibers ascending from auditory 
    nuclei of the brainstem are also found in horizontal laminae in the 
    DLL, as are the neurons of the DLL, which project to the IC (Henkel 
    and Spangler, 83; Shneiderman et al., 85; PreuI3, 91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">The lamination in the DLL may provide the morphological 
    substrate for a cochleotopic frequency representation within the 
    DLL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">Recent studies in our laboratory provided first evidence 
    of a tonotopic organization of the rat s DLL.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The frequency representation was demonstrated by a c-fos 
    study after pure-tone acoustic stimulation: high-frequency neurons 
    were found to be located ventrally and dorsally in the DLL, while 
    low-frequency neurons were found centrally in the DLL (see Fig. 1E 
    in Friauf, 92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">These findings are corroborated by results based on 
    injections of two retrograde fluorescent tracers into 
    electrophysiologically characterized sites in the central nucleus 
    of the IC, which showed the same mirror-symmetric arrangement of 
    labeled neurons in the DLL (PreuJ3, 91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">These facts support our assumption that the topography 
    of the colliculolemniscal projection has a cochleotopic 
    organization.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Our data on the tonotopic organization of the rat s DLL 
    are, however, apparently in contrast to physiological (Aitkin et 
    al., 70) and anatomical findings in the cat s DLL (Shneiderman et 
    al., 88), which showed that the high-to-low frequency axis is 
    oriented from ventral to dorsal.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">The DLL is primarily considered to be a relay in the 
    ascending auditory pathway, projecting bilaterally, in a 
    cochleotopic fashion, to the central nucleus of the IC (Shneiderman 
    et al., &apos;88; PreuB, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">As many neurons in the DLL are GABAergic, they may 
    provide an inhibitory input to IC neurons (Adams and Mugnaini, 
    &apos;84; Moore and Moore, &apos;87; Shneiderman et al., 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Taken together, it is possible that the 
    colliculolemniscal projection modulates this presumed inhibitory 
    ascending input, thus forming a short frequency-specific feedback 
    loop.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Projections to the perilemniscal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The present study revealed that the sagulum, the 
    horizontal cell group, and the perilemniscal zone receive efferent 
    collicular fibers from the ipsilateral external and dorsal cortex 
    of the IC only.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">A projection from the external cortex to the sagulum has 
    already been reported in the rat (Faye-Lund; &apos;86) arid also in 
    the monkey (Moore and Goldberg, &apos;66).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">This collicular pathway could mediate information from 
    the auditory cortex to the sagulum, since both the external and 
    dorsal cortex are major recipients of auditory cortical projections 
    (Faye-Lund, &apos;85; Herbert et al., &apos;91 j.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">In the rat and cat, the sagulum projects to the dorsal 
    and external cortex of the IC (PreuB, &apos;91; Henkel and 
    Shneiderman, &apos;88) and thus appears to be reciprocally 
    connected with the respective IC subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The sagulum, which is considered a part of the lateral 
    tegmental system (Morest, &apos;65; Morest and Oliver, &apos;84; 
    Henkel and Shneiderman, &apos;88), is also the origin of a direct 
    projection to the medial and dorsal nucleus of the medial 
    geniculate body (Oliver and Hall, &apos;781, thus providing a 
    parallel ascending projection to the auditory thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Presumably, the collicular projections to the saylum 
    provide an auditory input to this component of the lateral 
    tegmental system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s188">Colliculoolivary 
    projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Our data demonstrate that the ipsilateral rostral 
    periolivary nucleus (RPO) and the ventral nucleus of the trapezoid 
    body (VNTB) are the primary targets of colliculoolivary 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">This is in general agreement with previous findings in 
    mammals (Moore and Goldberg, &apos;66; Noort, &apos;69; Carey and 
    Webster, &apos;71; Borg, &apos;73; Andersen et al., &apos;80; 
    Conlee and Kane, &apos;82; Hashikawa, &apos;83; Syka et al., 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Our results, showing that both the external cortex and 
    the central nucleus of the IC give rise to this projection, extend 
    the findings of Faye-Lund (&apos;86) and support two recent 
    conference notes (Saldafia, &apos;90; Vetter and Saldafia, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">The intercollicular zone and the dorsal cortex of the IC 
    send only a few, if any, fibers to the superior olivary complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Projections to the RPO and the VNTB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">PHA-L injections into the external cortex and the 
    central nucleus of the IC resulted in dense axonal labeling 
    ipsilaterally in ventral aspects of the RPO and VNTB, thereby 
    forming a continuous band which extends from the rostral tip of the 
    RPO to the caudal portion of the VNTB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">This was also observed by Faye-Lund (&apos;861, using 
    anterograde degeneration.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">The colliculofugal terminal fibers in this area appear 
    to overlap the site of origin of the medial olivocochlear bundle 
    (White and Warr, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">In the rat, this system contains cholinergic neurons 
    (White and Warr, &apos;83; Osen et al., &apos;84; Faye-Lund, 
    &apos;86; Vetter et al., &apos;91) which are located exclusively in 
    the RPO and VNTB and innervate the outer hair cells of the 
    contralateral cochlea (Iurato, &apos;74; White and Warr, &apos;83; 
    Aschoff and Ostwald, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Evidence of a termination of collicular fibers on these 
    olivocochlear neurons was provided by a tracing study in which 
    PHA-L-labeled fibers from the IC were found in close apposition to 
    retrogradely labeled neurons of the medial olivocochlear system 
    (Vetter and Saldaiia, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">However, whether these fibers indeed form synaptic 
    contacts requires verification by electron microscopy.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">The anatomical data already indicate that the 
    colliculoolivary pathway may participate in the modulation of 
    cochlear responses.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Functional evidence has been provided by physiological 
    studies in which electrical stimulation of the IC reduced temporary 
    threshold shift after intensive exposure to noise, thus protecting 
    the cochlea from auditory desensitization (Rajan, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Furthermore, electrical stimulation of the IC produces a 
    reduction in the amplitude and an increase in the latency of the 
    auditory whole-nerve response (Dolan and Nutall, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">As these effects are similar to those elicited by 
    electrical stimulation of the crossed olivocochlear system 
    (reviewed in Rajan, &apos;901, it is conceivable that the IC 
    influences the cochlear responses via the medial olivocochlear 
    system, A major finding of our study is that fibers from the 
    central nucleus of the IC terminate in a highly organized fashion 
    within the RPO and VNTB.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Neurons located dorsally in the central nucleus project 
    to the lateral parts of RPO and VNTB, while neurons located 
    ventrally project to the medial parts.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">A topographic organization of this pathway has been 
    recently noted by Saldaiia (&apos;90) as well.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">It appears that the shift of terminal collicular fibers 
    follows the cochleotopic organization of the RPO-VNTB complex, with 
    a low-to-high frequency representation from lateral to medial, as 
    was demonstrated in the rat by means of the c-fos technique 
    (Friauf, &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Neurons of the medial olivocochlear system in the guinea 
    pig exhibit a similar cochleotopic arrangement and apparently 
    project tonotopically to the outer hair cells (Robertson and 
    Gummer, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">In conclusion, the data indicate that the 
    colliculo-olivocochlear pathway, originating in the central 
    nucleus, is entirely cochleotopically organized and thus, may 
    modulate cochlear responses frequency-specifically.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">The external cortex of the IC also provides input to the 
    RPO and VNTB, although in a diffuse manner.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">The fact that the external cortex receives direct 
    auditory cortical (Faye-Lund, &apos;85; Herbert et al., &apos;911, 
    as well as somatosensory input (Aitkin et al., %I), suggests that 
    its colliculoolivary fibers may transmit multimodal information and 
    thus represent a descending pathway which is functionally separate 
    from the pathway originating in the ICC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s211">Projections to the 
    cochlear nuclei</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">We found that the DCN is a major target of collicular 
    projections originating in the external cortex and the central 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">While few collicular fibers were found in the granule 
    cell layers surrounding the ventral cochlear nuclei, the ventral 
    cochlear nuclei proper were completely devoid of fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The existence of a collicular input to the cochlear 
    nuclei was already reported in the past century for cats, rats, 
    rabbits, and humans (Held, 1893).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Since then, various degeneration and tracing studies 
    have confirmed this pathway in different mammalian species 
    (Rasmussen, &apos;64; Noort, &apos;69; Adams and Warr, &apos;76; 
    Kane and Conlee!</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">&apos;79; Lorente de NO, &apos;81; Hashikawa, &apos;83; 
    Faye-Lund, &apos;86; Shore et al., &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">In the cat, the projection from the IC to the DCN was 
    reported to be complementary, i.e., superficial collicular 
    structures project to the outermost layers of the DCN, whereas deep 
    collicular structures (corresponding to the central nucleus) 
    project to the deep layers of the DCN (Conlee and Kane, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">By means of the sensitive axonal tracer PHA-L we could 
    demonstrate that the organization of this pathway in the rat is 
    differently arranged.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s219">Projections to the dorsal cochlear nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s220">Collicular fibers reach the cochlear nucleus via the 
    ventral and the dorsal acoustic stria and terminatp bilaterally at 
    homotopic sites in the deep layers of the DCN.</S>
    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s221">Fibers originating in the central nucleus terminate in a 
    topographic fashion, thereby forming discrete bands which are 
    oriented perpendicular to the surface of the nucleus, a finding 
    that is in line with a Sag Gi LPGi PnC VLTg Pn</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">recent note (Saldana, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">This preferred orientation matches the overall axonal 
    and dendritic arrangement within the DCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">The dendrites of pyramidal and vertical cells and the 
    recurrent axonal collaterals of cartwheel cells are aligned along 
    isofrequency bands, which are created by the type I primary 
    cochlear nerve fibers (Blackstad et al., &apos;84; Berrebi and 
    Mugnaini, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Physiological studies have shown that low frequencies 
    are represented ventrolaterally and high frequencies dorsomedially 
    in the rat&apos;s DCN (Ryan et al., &apos;88; Friauf, &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Thus, the fibers from the central nucleus appear to 
    terminate according to the cochleotopic frequency arrangement in 
    the DCN.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">We are not aware of any study in which the physiological 
    significance of the projections from the central nucleus of the IC 
    to the DCN has been investigated.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Since the DCN provides a prominent, cochleotopically 
    organized input to the contralateral central nucleus of the IC 
    (Beyerl, &apos;78), it is possible that these nuclei are 
    reciprocally connected through frequency-specific channels.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Projections to the granule cell layers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">After PHA-L injections were made into both the central 
    nucleus or the external cortex of the IC, we always found, without 
    any apparent order, terminal labeling in the granule cell layers of 
    the cochlear nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">This is consistent with the fact that axons of granule 
    cells traverse isofrequency layers in the DCN (Mugnaini et al., 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">The granule cells receive multiple afferents, including 
    somatosensory inputs, and project to the molecular layer of the 
    DCN, forming synaptic contacts with interneurons (cartwheel cells) 
    and pyramidal cells (for review, see Osen, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Granule cells thus modulate DCN interneurons, as well as 
    neurons projecting to the central nucleus of the IC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s234">Projections to pontine 
    and mesencephalic reticular nuclei</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">In addition to projections to lower auditory brainstem 
    nuclei, we found that the subnuclei of the IC also contribute 
    differentially to projections into pontine and mesencephalic 
    reticular nuclei (summarized in Fig. 12).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Collicular pathways leading to some of these 
    extra-auditory nuclei have been previously reported (pontine 
    nuclei: Moore and Goldberg, &apos;66; Carey and Webster, &apos;71; 
    Aitkin and Boyd, &apos;75; Kawamura, &apos;75; Mower et al., 
    &apos;79; Andersen et al., &apos;80; Schweizer, &apos;81; 
    Hashikawa, &apos;83; Schuller et al., &apos;91; lateral 
    paragigantocellular nucleus: Andrezik et al., &apos;81; Newman, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">In addition, we found collicular fibers in the 
    gigantocellular reticular nucleus, the ventrolateral tegmental 
    nucleus, and in the caudal pontine reticular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Recently we were able to demonstrate that these same 
    pontine and reticular nuclei also receive a prominent auditory 
    input from the cochlear nuclei (Kandler and Herbert, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">It is conceivable that auditory projections to these 
    extraauditory areas may play a role in longand short-latency 
    audio-motor behaviors or in acoustically elicited autonomic 
    responses (for an extensive discussion on the functional 
    significance of auditory projections to pontine and reticular 
    nuclei we refer to Kandler and Herbert, &apos;91).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s240">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s241">The authors thank Helga 
    Zillus for technical assistance and Gwynn Goldring for correcting 
    the English.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s242">The comments of Drs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s243">Jo Ostwald, Eckhard Friauf, 
    and Annette Klepper on the manuscript were most beneficial and are 
    appreciated.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s244">This study was supported by a 
    PATTY Award to A.C. and the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, SFB 
    307.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s245">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Adams, J.C., and W.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Warr (1976) Origins of axons in the cat&apos;s acoustic 
    stria determined by injections of horseradish peroxidase into 
    severed tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Conip.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Keurol. 170:107-122.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Adams, J.C., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Mugnaini (1984) Dorsal nucleus of the lateral Iemniscus: 
    A nucleus of GABAergic projection neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Bull. 13585590.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Aitkin.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">L.M.!</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">and J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Boyd i 1975) Acoustic input to the lateral pontine 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Hear.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Res. 1:67-77.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Aitkin.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">L.M..</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Anderson, and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Brugge (1970) Tonotopic organization and discharge 
    characteristics of single neurons in nuclei of the lateral 
    lemniscus of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Neurophysiol. .73:421458.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Aitkin, L.M., C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Kenyon. and P.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Philpott (1981) The representation of the auditory and 
    somatosensoiy systems in the external nucleus of the cat inferior 
    colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Neurol. 196:2540.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Andersm, R.A., G.L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Ruth, L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Aitkin, and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Merzenich (1980) The efferent projections of the central 
    nucleus and the pericentral nucleus of the inrerior colliculus in 
    the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Neurol. 194t649-662.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Andrezik, J.A., V.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Chan-Palav, and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Palay (1981) The nucleusparagigantocellularis in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Demnnstratinns of afferents by the retrograde transport 
    of horseradish pernxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Anal.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">(Bed.) 16&apos;1:373390.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Aschar, A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Ostwald (1988) Distribution of cochlear efferents arid 
    olivo-collicular neurons in the brainstem of rat and guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">A double laheling study with fluorescent tracers.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Brain Res. 71:241-251.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Berod, A,, B.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Hartman, and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Pujol (19811 Importance of fixation in 
    irnmunohistochemistry: Use of formaldehyde solutions at variahle pH 
    for the localization of&apos; tyrosine hydroxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">J.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Cytochem. 29:844-850.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Berrebi, A.S.. and E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Mugnaini 11991) Distribution and targets of the 
    cartwheel cell axon in the dorsal cochlear nucleus of the guinea 
    pig.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Anat Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">(Bed.) 183,427454.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Beyerl, B.D. 1 1978) Afferent projections to the central 
    nucleus of the inferior colliculus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Brain Hes. 145:209-223.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Blackstad, T.W., K.K.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Osen, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Mugnaini (1984) Pyramidal neuronb of the dorsal cochlear 
    nucleus: A Golgi and computer reconstruction study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Neuroscience 13:827-854.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Borg, E. (1973) A neuroanatomical study of the brainstem 
    auditory system of the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Part 11.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Descending connections.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Acta Morphnl.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Neer.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Scand. 1 1:49-82.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Caicedo, A., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Herbert (1997) Efferent projections of the inferior 
    colliculus in the rat: An anterograde tracing study using 
    PITA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">In N.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Elsner and H. l&apos;enzlin ieds): 
    Synapse-Transmission-Modulation.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Proceedings of the 19th Gottingen Neurobiology 
    Conference.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">New York: Georg Thieme, pp. 120.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Carey, C.L., and D.R.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Wehster (1971) Ascending and descending prnjcckions of 
    the inferior colliculus in thc kangaroo rat iDipodomys 
    merriaml).</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Brain Uehav.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Evol. 4:401-412.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Clopton, R.M , and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Winfield (1973) &apos;l&apos;onotopic organization 
    inferior colliculus ofthe rat.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Res. 56:355-358.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Coleman, J.R., and W.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Clerici (19871 Sources of projections to subdivisions uf 
    the inferior colliculus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Neurol. 262.315-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Conlrr, d.W.: and E.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Kanc (1982) Descending projections from the inferior 
    colliculus to the dorsal cochlear nucleus in the cat: An 
    autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Neuroscience 1:161-178.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">h , D.F., and A.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Nuttall (1988) Cochlear whole-nerve responses altered by 
    electrical stimulation of the inferior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Abstr. 14:650.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Faye-Lund, H. (1985) The neocortical projection to the 
    inferior colliculus in the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Anat Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">(Berl.) 173:53-70.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Faye-Lund, H. 119861 Projection frurn the inferior 
    colhculus to the superior olivary complex in the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Emhryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">(Berl.) 17535-52.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Faye-Lund, H., and K.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Osen I 19851 Anatomy of the inferior colliculus in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">(Berl.) 171:l -20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Friauf.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">E. (1992) Tonotopic order in the adult and developing 
    auditory system of the rat as shown by c-fos 
    immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Neurosci. 4:798-812.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Sawchenkn (19841 An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons. their s o n s 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseoh idgaris Leucoagglutinin 
    IPHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Hashikawa, T. (19833 The inferior collicnlopnntine 
    neurnns of the cat in rclalion to othcr collicular descending 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Neurol. 2191241-249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Ileld, H. 118931 Die zentrale I 7m-24s.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Henkel, C.K., and K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Spangler (1983) Organization of the efferent projections 
    of the medial superior olivary nucleus in the cat as revealed by 
    HRP and autoradiographic tracing methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Neurol. 227:416428.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">IIenkel.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">C.K., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Shneiderman (19883 Nucleus sagulum: Projections of a 
    lateral tegniental area to the inferior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Nenrol. 271:577-588.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Herbert, H., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Aschoff, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Ostwald (1991) Topography of projections from the 
    auditory cortex to the inferior colliculus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Neurol. 304:1-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Huffman, R.F., and O.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Henson (19901 The descending auditory pathway and 
    acousticonintor systems: Connections with the inferior 
    colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Rev. 15295-323.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Turato, S. (1974) Efferent innervation of the 
    cochlea.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">In W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Keidel and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Neff (eds): Auditory System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Anatomy-Physiology (Ear), Handbook of Sensory 
    Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Berlin: Springer, Vol Vll, pp. 261-282.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Twahori, N. (1986) A Golgi study on the dorsal nucleus 
    of the lemniscus in the mouse.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Res. 3:196-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Kandler, K., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Herbert (1991) Auditory projections from the cochlear 
    nucleus to pontine and mesencephalic reticular nuclei in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Brain Res ,562: 2 30-242 Kanc, E.S., and J.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Conlee (1979) Descending inputs to the caudal cochlear 
    nucleus of the cat: Degeneration and autoradiographic studies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Neurol. 187:759-784.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Kanr, E.S., and 1.31.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Barone (1980) The dorsal nucleus of the lateral 
    lemniscus in thc cat.: Neuronal types and their distributions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Neurol 192)2:797-826.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Kawamura, K. (19751 The pontine projection from the 
    inferior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">An experimental anatomical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Brain Res. 95.309-322.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Tmente dc N6, R. (19811 The Primary Acoustic Nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">New York: Raven Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Moore, R.Y., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Goldberg (1966) Projections of the inferior colliculus 
    in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Ncurol. 14:489-438.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Moore, J.K., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Moore 11987) Glutamic acid decarboxylase-like 
    immunoreactivity in brainstem auditory nuclei of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Ncurol. 260:157-174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Morest, D.K. (1965) The lateral tegmental system of the 
    midbrain and the medial geniculate body: A study with Golgi and Nau 
    ta methods in cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">(Land.) 99:611-634.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Morest, D.K., and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Oliver (1984) The neuronal architecture of the inferior 
    colliculus in the cat: Defining the functional anaton1.y of the 
    auditory midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Neurol. 222209-236.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Mower, G., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Gibson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Glickstein (1979) Tectopontine pathway in the cat: 
    Laminar distrihution of cells of origin and visual properties of 
    target cells in dorsolateral pontine nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Neurophysiol. 42: 1-1 5.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Mugnaini, E., K.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Osen, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">-L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Dahl, V.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Friedrich, and C,.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Korte (1980) Fine structure of granule cells and related 
    interneurons (termed Golgi cells) in the cochlear Neurocytol. 
    9t537-570.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Newman, D.B. (1985) Distinguishing rat brainstem 
    reticulospinal nuclei by their neuronal morphology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Medullary nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Hirnforsch. 26: 187226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Noort, J.V. (1969) The Structure and Connections of the 
    Inferior Colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">An Investigation of the Lower Auditory System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Proefschrift.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Leiden: Van Gorcum and Co., pp. 1-116.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Oliver; D.L., and W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Hall (1978) The medial geniculate body of the tree 
    shrew, Tuppaia glis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Cytoarchitecture and midbrain connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Neurol. 182:423458.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Osen, K.K. (1988) Anatomy of the mammalian cochlear 
    nuclei: A review.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Syka, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Masterton (eds): Auditory Pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Structure and Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">New York and London: Plenum Press: pp. 65-75.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Osen, K.K., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Mugnaini, A.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Dahl, andA.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Christiansen 11984) Histochemical localization of 
    acetylcholinesterase in the cochlear and superior olivary 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">A reappraisal with emphasis on the cochlear granule cell 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Ital.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Biol. 122:169-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Watson (1986) The Kat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Sidney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">PreuR, S. (1991) Elektrophysiologische und 
    neuroanatomische Charakterisierung der Kerne des Lateralen 
    Lemniscus und der umgebenden auditorischen Areale bei der Ratte.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Thesis, Universitat Tubingen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Rajan, R. (1990) Electrical stimulation of the inferior 
    colliculus at low rates protects the cochlea from auditory 
    desensitization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Brain Res. 506:192204.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Rasmussen, G.L. (1964) Anatomic relationships of the 
    ascending and descending auditory systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">In W.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Fields, and Alford B.R. (4s): Neurological Aspects of 
    Auditory and Vestibular Disorders.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Springt5eld: C.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Thomas, pp. 5-19.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Robertson, D., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Gummer (1988) Physiology of cochlear efferents in the 
    mammal, In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Syka, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Masterton (eds): Auditory Pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Structure and Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">London: Plenum Press: pp. 269-278.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Ryan, A.F., Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Furlow, N.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Woolf, and E.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Keithley (1988) The spatial representation of frequency 
    in the rat dorsal cochlear nucleus and inferior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Hear.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Res. 36:181-190.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Saldana, E. (1990) The rat colliculo-olivary projection 
    Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Abstr. 16:716.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Saldada, E. (1991) Descending projection from the 
    inferior colliculus to the cochlear nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">In Merchan M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">(ed): The Mammalian Auditory Nuclei: Organization and 
    Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">NATO Advanced Research Workshop in Honour of Rafael 
    Llorente de NO.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Salamanca.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Schuller, G., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Covey, and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Casseday (1991) Auditory pontine grey: Connections and 
    response properties in the horseshoe bat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Neurosci. 3:648-662.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Schweizer, H. (1981) The connections of the inferior 
    colliculus and the organization of the brainstem auditory system in 
    the greater horseshoe bat (Rhznolophus ferrzmequinun).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurol. 201:25-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Shneiderman, A,, D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Oliver, and C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Henkel (1988) Connections of the dorsal nucleus of the 
    lateral lemniscus: An inhibitory parallel pathway in the ascending 
    auditory system?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Neurol. 276:188-208.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Shore, S.E., R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Helfert, S.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Bledsoe, Jr., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Altschuler, and Godfrey (1991) Descending projections to 
    the dorsal and ventral sions of the cochlear nucleus in guinea 
    pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Hear.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Rcs. 52255-268.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Syka, J., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Robertson, and B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Johnstone (1988) Efferent descending projections from 
    the inferior colliculus in guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Syka, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Masterton ieds): Auditory Pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Structure and Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">London: Plenum Press, pp. 299-303.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Vetter, D.E., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Saldana (1990) Descending input from the central nucleus 
    of the inferior colliculus to the medial olivocochlear system in 
    rat: A combined PHA-L and CT-HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Abstr.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">rat Vetter, D.E., J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Adams, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Mugnaini (1991 1 Chemically distinct olivocochlear 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Synapse 7:2 1-43.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">White, J.S., and W.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Warr (1983) The dual origins of the bundle in the albino 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Neurol. 219:203-214.</S>
    <BR />

  </References>

</File>

