<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Projections of the Ventral Subiculum to the Amygdala, Septum, 
  and Hypothalamus: A PHAL Anterograde Tract-Tracing Study in the 
  Rat</Title>

  <Authors>N.S. CANTERAS AND L.W. SWANSON</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The projections of the ventral subiculum are organized 
    differentially along the dorsoventral (or septotemporal) axis of 
    this cortical field, with more ventral regions playing a 
    particularly important role in hippocampal communication with the 
    amygdala, bed nuclei of the stria terminalis (BST), and rostral 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">In the present study we re-examined the projection of the 
    ventral subiculum to these regions with the Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHAL) method in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The results confirm and extend earlier conclusions based 
    primarily on the autoradiographic method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Projections from the ventral subiculum course either 
    obliquely through the angular bundle to innervate the amygdala and 
    adjacent parts of the temporal lobe, or follow the alveus and 
    fimbria to the precommissural fornix and medial corticohypothalamic 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The major amygdalar terminal field is centered in the 
    posterior basomedial nucleus, while other structures that appear to 
    be innervated include the piriformamygdaloid area, the posterior 
    basolateral, posterior cortical, posterior, central, medial, and 
    intercalated nuclei, and the nucleus of the lateral olfactory 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Projections from the ventral subiculum reach the BST 
    mainly by way of the precommissural fornix, and provide rather 
    dense inputs to the anterodorsal area as well as the transverse and 
    interfascicular nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The medial corticohypothalamic tract is the main route 
    taken by fibers from the ventral subiculum to the hypothalamus, 
    where they innervate the medial preoptic area, shell of the 
    ventromedial nucleus, dorsomedial nucleus, ventral premammillary 
    nucleus, and cell-poor zone around the medial mammillary 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">We also observed a rather dense terminal field just dorsal 
    to the suprachiasmatic nucleus that extends dorsally and caudally 
    to fill the subparaventricular zone along the medial border of the 
    anterior hypothalamic nucleus and ventrolateral border of the 
    paraventricular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The general pattern of outputs to the hypothalamus and 
    septum is strikingly similar for the ventral subiculum and 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus, the endogenous circadian rhythm generator. 
    o 1992 Wiley-Liss, Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The subiculum lies near the end of what is thought to be 
    a largely unidirectional sequence of intracortical association 
    projections that link the various subdivisions of the hippocampal 
    formation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Briefly, the major flow of information through the 
    hippocampal formation takes place through the transversely oriented 
    trisynaptic circuit, which begins with the perforant path 
    projection from the entorhinal area to the dentate gyrus, is 
    relayed to field CA3 of Ammon s horn by the mossy fiber system, and 
    then proceeds to field CAI by way of the Schaffer collateral 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The major intrahippocampal projections of field CAI are 
    to the subiculum and to the entorhinal area (for review, see 
    Swanson et al., 87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">For its part, the subiculum has one of the most massive 
    and divergent efferent projections of any part of the hippocampal 
    formation, providing inputs to many regions of the telencephalon 
    and diencephalon (see Swanson and Cowan, 75, 77; Meibach and 
    Siegel, 77; Krettek and Price, 78a; Groenewegen et al., 87; Kohler, 
    90; Witter and Groenewegen, 90; Witter et al., 90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">It is clear that the projections of the subiculum are 
    differentially organized along the dorsoventral (septotemporal, 
    longitudinal) axis of the subiculum, with more ventral regions 
    playing a more important role in hippocampal communication with the 
    amygdala, bed nuclei of the stria terminalis (BST), and 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Thus, for the hypothalamus, dorsal parts of the subiculum 
    give rise to a massive projection that travels in the 
    postcommissural fornix and tends to end preferentially in the 
    mammillary complex, whereas efferent fibers from more ventral parts 
    course through the medial corticohypothalamic tract and are 
    distributed throughout the entire rostrocaudal extent of the medial 
    zone of the hypothalamus, placing this cortical structure in a 
    unique position to influence a wide range of hypothalamic 
    mechanisms (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, &apos;77; Meibach and 
    Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Kohler, &apos;90; 
    Witter and Groenewegen, &apos;90; Witter et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">In addition, it seems likely that projections from the 
    subiculum to the amygdala and bed nuclei of the stria terminalis 
    arise predominantly if not exclusively from its more ventral 
    regions (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77; Groenewegen et al., &apos;87; 
    Price et al., &apos;87; Witter and Groenewegen, &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Projections from the ventral subiculum to the bed nuclei 
    of the stria terminalis and hypothalamus were originally described 
    with the autoradiographic method in the rat (Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;75, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">However, these findings are limited because it is often 
    difficult if not impossible to distinguish terminal fields from 
    fibers-of-passage with the method, due to the fact that silver 
    grains rather than axons themselves are actually observed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">In addition, the projection from the subiculum to the 
    amygdala has been thoroughly examined with the autoradiographic 
    method in the monkey (Rosene and Van Hoesen, &apos;77; Aggleton, 
    &apos;86), although no detailed study of this projection has been 
    carried out in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In view of these limitations, we have decided to 
    re-examine, in the rat, the projection of the ventral subiculum to 
    the amygdala, septum, and hypothalamus with the PHAL anterograde 
    tracer method, which combines all of the advantages of the 
    autoradiographic method with clearly defined injection sites and 
    Golgi-like staining of labeled axons, so that terminal boutons and 
    varicosities can readily be identified and distinguished (see 
    Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; Wouterlood and Groenegewen, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The results have been interpreted in light of a great 
    deal of new cytoarchitectonic and connectional information that has 
    become available since the original autoradiographic studies, and 
    have also served to clarify differences between regions that lie in 
    the junctional region between the temporal pole of the hippocampal 
    formation and the caudal end of the amygdala (see the accompanying 
    paper by Canteras et al., &apos;92a).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s22">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Eight adult male Sprague-Dawley rats received an 
    injection of Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHAL; Vector 
    Laboratories) into ventral parts of the subiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Each animal was anesthetized with tribromoethanol, and a 
    single iontophoretic injection of a 2.5% solution of PHAL in 0.01 M 
    sodium phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4) was made through a 
    stereotaxically positioned glass micropipette (tip diameter 10 km) 
    by applying a +8 PA current, pulsed at 7-second intervals, and 
    provided by a constant-current source (Midgard Electronics, Model 
    CS3) for a period of 20 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Postinjection survival times for all experiments ranged 
    from 14 to 16 days.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">The animals were perfused and the brains were processed 
    according to procedures described in detail elsewhere (Canteras et 
    al., &apos;92a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Briefly, each animal was deeply anesthetized with 
    tribromoethanol and perfused transcardially with a solution of 4.0% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M sodium borate buffer at pH 9.5; the 
    brains were removed immediately and postfixed overnight in the same 
    fixative containing 10% sucrose.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Four one-in-five series of 30-km-thick frozen sections 
    were cut with a sliding microtome in the frontal plane and 
    collected from the septa1 region rostrally to the middle of the 
    midbrain caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">An additional series of sections was collected through 
    the level of the ventral subiculum, and 
    &quot;quick-stained&apos;&apos; for confirmation of injection site 
    placement (see Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">One complete series of sections was processed for 
    immunohistochemistry with an antiserum directed against PHAL (Dako 
    Laboratories) at a dilution of 1:1,000.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The antigen-antibody complex was localized by using a 
    variation of the avidin-biotin complex system (ABC; Hsu and Raine, 
    &apos;81; Hsu et al., &apos;811, with a commercially available kit 
    (ABC Elite Kit, Vector Laboratories).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The sections were mounted on gelatin-coated slides, and 
    treated with osmium tetroxide to enhance the visibility of the 
    reaction product.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Slides were then dehydrated and coverslipped with DPX.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">An adjacent series was always stained with thionin to 
    serve as a reference series for cytoarchitectonic purposes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Sections were examined with a Leitz Laborlux D microscope 
    with both brightand darkfield illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">The PHAL-labeled cells in the injection sites, as well as 
    the distribution of anterograde labeled fibers were plotted with 
    the aid of a camera lucida onto maps prepared from adjacent 
    Nissl-stained sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">For illustration purposes, the distribution of 
    anterogradely labeled fibers was transferred onto a series of 
    standard drawings of the rat brain (Swanson, &apos;92).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s38">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The parameters used for making the iontophoretic 
    injections described above resulted in discrete injection sites, 
    typically with hundreds of clearly labeled (PHAL-immunoreactive) 
    neurons.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s40"><exptLabel>In five experiments the injection was 
      virtually confined to <injectionLocation>the temporal pole of the 
      subiculum</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s41">The location and approximate extent of each of these 
      injection sites are plotted on an unfolded map of 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the rat hippocampal 
      formation</neuroanatomicalLocation> from Swanson et al. 
      (&apos;78) (Fig. 1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s42">Each of these five experiments labeled a similar 
      pattern of projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s43">Since the injection site in <exptLabel>experiment 
      SUB-16</exptLabel> encompassed <injectionLocation>a relatively 
      broad extent of the ventral subiculum</injectionLocation> (Figs. 
      1, 21, and a correspondingly <labelingDescription>dense pattern 
      of fibers</labelingDescription> was labeled, this experiment was 
      used to illustrate in detail the efferent projections of 
      <connxOrigin>the ventral subiculum</connxOrigin> to 
      <connxTermination>the amygdala, septum, and 
      hypothalamus</connxTermination> (Fig. 3).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s44">Projections to the 
      amygdala</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s45"><labelingDescription>One group of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> courses directly from the injection 
      site to <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> by 
      crossing the angular bundle (Fig. 3P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s46">At caudal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, these fibers establish 
      <labelingDescription>an impressive plexus</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the posterior part of the basomedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>a smaller 
      group of labeled axons</labelingDescription> appears to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the caudalmost parts of the posterior 
      subdivision of the basolateral nucleus, the posterior nucleus, 
      the posterior cortical nucleus, and the piriformamygdaloid 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 31-M; see Canteras et al., 
      &apos;92a for subdivisions of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      amygdala</neuroanatomicalLocation> used here).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s47">It is important to emphasize that <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior part of the basomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> is by 
      far <labelingDescription>the most densely 
      labeled</labelingDescription> region in <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> in any of our experiments.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s48">As <neuroanatomicalLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> leaves <connxOrigin>the 
      amygdala</connxOrigin>, <labelingDescription>a number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course dorsally to supply 
      <labelingDescription>a dense terminal field</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the caudalmost end of the central nucleus 
      and adjacent regions of the caudoputamen</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      31-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s49">It is also interesting to note that <labelingLocation>a 
      very small number of fibers</labelingLocation> in this area leave 
      <connxOrigin>the amygdala</connxOrigin> by way of 
      <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3J,K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s50"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue rostrally through 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation>, providing 
      along the way clear inputs to <labelingLocation>the central 
      nucleus, the medial nucleus, the intercalated nuclei, and the 
      nucleus of the lateral olfactory tract</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s51">Within <labelingLocation>the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the caudalmost pole 
      of the lateral subdivision</labelingLocation> receives 
      <labelingDescription>a particularly dense plexus of 
      fibers</labelingDescription>, and proceeding more rostrally, 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled axons</labelingDescription> 
      preferentially innervate <labelingLocation>the capsular 
      subdivision</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>to a 
      lesser extent</labelingDescription> <labelingLocation>ventral 
      parts of the medial subdivision</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3F-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s52"><labelingLocation>The medial nucleus of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate number of anterogradely labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription>, which are located mainly within 
      <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal and posteroventral 
      subdivisions</labelingLocation>, clearly tending to avoid 
      <labelingLocation>the posterodorsal 
      subdivision</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3F-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s53"><labelingLocation>The intercalated nuclei adjacent to 
      the central and medial nuclei</labelingLocation> also receive 
      <labelingDescription>a moderate number of 
      axons</labelingDescription>, which display <labelingDescription>a 
      highly branched pattern</labelingDescription> and give rise to 
      <labelingDescription>a fairly large number of terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 3F,G).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s54"><labelingDescription>Anterogradely labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      subiculum</labelingLocation> appear to provide only 
      <labelingDescription>a very sparse input</labelingDescription> to 
      the lateral and basolateral nuclei (Fig. 3F-L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s55">Furthermore, only <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>
      the anterior part of the basomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 3E-I), in sharp contrast to <labelingDescription>the dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the posterior 
      part of the nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s56">Throughout the entire extent of the amygdala, 
      <labelingDescription>a small number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> take a lateral course to 
      <labelingLocation>the piriform area</labelingLocation> and 
      especially to <labelingLocation>the dorsal endopiriform 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> just deep to it (Fig. 3D-M).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s57">In addition, <labelingDescription>some labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> also appear to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the claustrum</labelingLocation> as well as in 
      <labelingLocation>deep layers of the agranular insular and 
      perirhinal areas</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s58">At rostral levels of the amygdala, 
      <labelingDescription>a sparse contingent of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> enters <labelingLocation>the 
      substantia innominata</labelingLocation> and courses toward 
      <labelingLocation>caudal parts of the BST</labelingLocation>; in 
      addition, <labelingDescription>a very few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were observed surrounding 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal border of the supraoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> on their way toward <labelingLocation>
      the preoptic region</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3E-F).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s59">In none of our experiments with 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections in 
      <injectionLocation>the ventral subiculum</injectionLocation> were 
      <labelingDescription>any labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      observed in <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s60">Projections through the 
      fimbria</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s61">The second major group of labeled axons that leaves 
      <connxOrigin>the ventral subiculum</connxOrigin> courses through 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the alveus and 
      fimbria</neuroanatomicalLocation>, and on reaching 
      <connxTermination>the septum</connxTermination> divides into two 
      components, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the precommissural 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation> and <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      medial corticohypothalamic tract</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s62"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Precommissural 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s63">As <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      fimbria</neuroanatomicalLocation> approaches 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the caudal end of the septal 
      region</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>these 
      axons</labelingDescription> fan out to run through (and give rise 
      to <labelingDescription>many terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> within) <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral lateral septal nucleus and adjacent parts of the 
      intermediate lateral septal and septofimbrial 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig.3A-D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s65">The rostral continuation of the pathway will be briefly 
      described below.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s66">Here it is appropriate to point out that many of these 
      fibers course in a more ventral direction to innervate 
      <labelingLocation>the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis 
      (BST)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B-D), although 
      <labelingDescription>a very small number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> may reach <labelingLocation>this 
      complex</labelingLocation> by way of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      stria terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> and/or 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ansa 
      peduncularis</neuroanatomicalLocation> (see above).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s67">In addition, <labelingDescription>several labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      precommissural fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation> also take a 
      ventral course just rostral <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and appear to enter 
      <connxTermination>the preoptic region</connxTermination> (Fig. 
      3B), as discussed below.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s68">In the <labelingLocation>anterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> (for subdivisions see Ju and Swanson, 
      &apos;891, <labelingDescription>the majority of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> end within <labelingLocation>the 
      anterodorsal area adjacent to the ventral part of the lateral 
      septal nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s69"><labelingDescription>Only a few 
      axons</labelingDescription> continue laterally toward 
      <labelingLocation>the anterolateral area</labelingLocation>, 
      which contained <labelingDescription>only scattered fibers and 
      terminal boutons</labelingDescription> i Fig. 3B-D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s70"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> also reach <labelingLocation>the 
      anteroventral area of the BST</labelingLocation>, either by 
      taking a ventromedial course rostral to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 3B), or by running 
      ventrolaterally through <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal 
      area</labelingLocation>, immediately caudal to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 3D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s71">Within <labelingLocation>the anteroventral 
      area</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appear to end primarily in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial, dorsolateral, magnocellular, 
      and ventral nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3C,D); interestingly, 
      they tend to avoid <labelingLocation>the parastrial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, which has been regarded as part of 
      the preoptic region (Simerly et al., &apos;84; Ju and Swanson, 
      &apos;89) and lies immediately ventral to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial aspect of this part of the 
      BST</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 3B-D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s72">At more caudal levels, <labelingDescription>a moderate 
      number of labeled axons</labelingDescription> take a ventral 
      route toward <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, where they give rise to 
      <labelingDescription>dense terminal fields</labelingDescription> 
      within <labelingLocation>the interfascicular and transverse 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>, but almost <labelingDescription>no 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the principal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3E, 4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s73">It is important to point out that it is not possible in 
      our material to be certain whether scattered fibers from 
      <connxOrigin>the BST</connxOrigin> continue on to end in various 
      parts of <connxTermination>the preoptic 
      region</connxTermination>, as their orientation would suggest, or 
      whether they are confined to <connxTermination>the 
      BST</connxTermination>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s74">Finally, <labelingDescription>a small number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      contralateral BST</labelingLocation>, particularly in regions 
      that are the most densely innervated ipsilaterally, including 
      <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal area, and the interfascicular 
      and transverse nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s75">These fibers reach the contralateral side of the brain 
      by crossing through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral 
      hippocampal commissure</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 3E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s76">The rostrally directed group of precommissural fibers 
      continues on to the rostral pole of <labelingLocation>the septal 
      region</labelingLocation> in <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral 
      corner of the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s77"><labelingDescription>Many of these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course ventrally to innervate 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, and 
      <labelingDescription>to a much lesser 
      extent</labelingDescription> <labelingLocation>the fundus of the 
      striatum and olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3A), 
      while rostral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the septal 
      regon</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (not examined here; see Swanson 
      and Cowan, &apos;79; Swanson, &apos;81; Jay and Witter, 
      &apos;91), other 
      <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> innervate parts 
      of <labelingLocation>the cellular layer of the anterior olfactory 
      nucleus, as well as the prelimbic, infralimbic, and medial 
      orbital areas of the cortex</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s78"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Medial corticoh.ypypothalanzic 
      tract</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79">These fibers diverge from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation> in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      anterodorsomedial tip of the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>, between 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the paraventricular nuclei of the 
      thalamus and hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Figs. 3E, 
      4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80"><labelingDescription>No labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the postcommissural fornix</labelingLocation> 
      in any of our experiments with 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections confined to 
      <injectionLocation>the ventralmost part of the 
      subiculum</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The medial corticohypothalamic 
      tract</neuroanatomicalLocation>, whose only known source of 
      fibers is <connxOrigin>the ventral subiculum</connxOrigin>, in 
      fact gwes rise to two branches, one to <connxTermination>the 
      thalamus</connxTermination> and the other to 
      <connxTermination>the hypothalamus</connxTermination> (Swanson et 
      al., &apos;87).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> to <connxTermination>the 
      thalamus</connxTermination> from <connxOrigin>the ventral tip of 
      the subiculum</connxOrigin> end throughout <labelingLocation>the 
      length of the paraventricular nucleus and nucleus 
      reuniens</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>a few 
      axons</labelingDescription> also appear to innervate 
      <labelingLocation>the parataenial nucleus and the lateral 
      habenula</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3E-M).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s83">The much larger hypothalamic branch of this tract 
      predominantly innervates <labelingLocation>cell groups of the 
      medial zone</labelingLocation>, contributing relatively 
      <labelingDescription>few axons</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the periventricular and lateral 
      zones</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s84">At rostral levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      preoptic region</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> are 
      distributed mainly within <labelingLocation>undifferentiated 
      parts of the medial preoptic area</labelingLocation> and to a 
      lesser extent in <labelingLocation>the anteroventral preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>; <labelingDescription>very few 
      axons</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the 
      anteroventral periventricular and the median preoptic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85">Proceeding caudally, one finds a somewhat more 
      <labelingDescription>dense plexus of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
      undifferentiated parts of the medial preoptic 
      area</labelingLocation>, as well as in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral subdivision of the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3D,E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86"><labelingLocation>This nucleus</labelingLocation> also 
      contains <labelingLocation>a moderate number of labeled axons in 
      ventral and caudal regions of the medial 
      subdivision</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingLocation>the 
      central subdivision</labelingLocation> is 
      <labelingDescription>virtually free of anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 3D,E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> from 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral subiculum</labelingLocation> tend 
      to avoid <labelingLocation>the parastrial and anterodorsal 
      preoptic nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B-D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">As noted above, <labelingDescription>a moderate 
      contingent of fibers</labelingDescription> from 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the precommissural 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation> also appears to project to 
      <connxTermination>the preoptic region</connxTermination>, and the 
      extent to which fibers in each of the preoptic cell groups 
      travel, through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial 
      corticohypothalamic tract and/or the precommissural 
      fornix</neuroanatomicalLocation> could not be determined.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89"><labelingLocation>In the anterior hypothalamic 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>anterogradely 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      ventral subiculum</connxOrigin> generate <labelingDescription>a 
      dense terminal field</labelingDescription> just dorsal to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the suprachiasmatic 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Figs. 3E, 4B) that extends 
      dorsally and caudally to fill <labelingLocation>the 
      subparaventricular zone</labelingLocation> (of Watts et al., 87) 
      along the medial border of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      hypothalamic nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and the 
      ventrolateral border of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      paraventricular nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Figs. 3F,G, 
      4C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90"><labelingLocation>The paraventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> itself (see Swanson and Simmons, 89 
      for subdivisions) is traversed by small fascicles of 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial corticohypothalamic 
      tract</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Fig. 4C), which are also obvious 
      within <labelingLocation>the anterior periventricular and 
      suprachiasmatic nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">However, both the <labelingLocation>Paraventricular 
      nucleus and the other periventricular nuclei</labelingLocation> 
      appear to contain only <labelingDescription>a few fibers bearing 
      terminal boutons</labelingDescription> (Figs. 3E-H, 4B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">Caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the suprachiasmatic 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingLocation>the 
      retrochiasmatic area</labelingLocation> receives 
      <labelingDescription>a moderately dense 
      projection</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the ventral 
      subiculum</connxOrigin>, and <labelingDescription>a sparse 
      contingent of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> was also 
      observed coursing more laterally through and to <labelingLocation>
      the anterior hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3F).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93"><labelingDescription>The dense plexus of labeled axons 
      and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
      the subparaventricular zone</labelingLocation> continues caudally 
      toward <neuroanatomicalLocation>the tuberal 
      region</neuroanatomicalLocation> to surround mainly 
      <labelingLocation>dorsal and medial aspects of the ventromedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3G-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of these 
      axons</labelingDescription> cross through <labelingLocation>
      lateral parts of the arcuate nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3H,I), although <labelingDescription>few of 
      them</labelingDescription> actually give rise 
      <labelingDescription>to terminal boutons</labelingDescription> 
      within <labelingLocation>the nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      itself.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">At the tuberal level, <labelingDescription>a number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course dorsally to provide 
      <labelingDescription>a moderately dense terminal 
      plexus</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 31-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96"><labelingDescription>A smaller number of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> at this level also run near 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral and ventral borders of the 
      ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation>, as well as through 
      rostral parts of <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral subdivision 
      of this nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3H-J).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">In addition to innervating <labelingLocation>the 
      cell-sparse shell around the ventromedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>some 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the ventral 
      subiculum</connxOrigin> also appear to end in <labelingLocation>
      caudal parts of both the central and the ventrolateral 
      subdivisions of this nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3J,K, 
      4D).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <labelingLocation>the medial 
      corticohypothalamic tract</labelingLocation> continue on to 
      <labelingLocation>the mammillary region</labelingLocation>, where 
      they provide <labelingDescription>moderately dense 
      inputs</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the posterior 
      periventricular nucleus, the ventral premammillary nucleus, 
      ventral regions of the posterior nucleus, and the fiber capsule 
      around the outside of the medial mammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 360).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">In fact, the results of our experiments indicate that 
      <injectionLocation>the ventral subiculum</injectionLocation> 
      innervates <labelingLocation>the posterior periventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>more 
      densely</labelingDescription> than any other structure in 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the periventricular 
      zone</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">In addition, we also observed at this level 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      that appear to end in <labelingLocation>both the dorsal and 
      ventral parts of the tuberomammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 3L,M).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">The caudalmost projection of <connxOrigin>the ventral 
      subiculum</connxOrigin> appears to consist of 
      <labelingDescription>a few axons</labelingDescription> coursing 
      through <labelingLocation>the posterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> that continue on to end in 
      <labelingLocation>rostralmost parts of the periaqueductal gray, 
      and the medial subdivision of the supramammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3N,O).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">Although the output of <connxOrigin>the ventral 
      subiculum</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the 
      hypothalamus</connxTermination> is largely ipsilateral, 
      <labelingDescription>a small number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were reliably found on 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral side of the 
      brain</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">In general, the contralateral projections are directed 
      to areas that contained the densest plexus of fibers 
      ipsilaterally.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Most of the labeled fibers cross the midline in 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral hippocampal commissure, the 
      supraoptic commissures</neuroanatomicalLocation>, and in regions 
      dorsal to the third ventricle, either through 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nucleus 
      reuniens</neuroanatomicalLocation>, or more posteriorly, through 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the supramammillary 
      decussation</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">The results of the present study confirm and extend what 
    was previously known about projections from the ventral subiculum 
    to the amygdala, septum, and hypothalamus, and are based on the 
    PHAL method, whose now well-known advantages were referred to in 
    the Introduction.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Furthermore, they appear to be reliable to the extent 
    that they were confirmed in all five experiments with injections 
    centered in the ventral subiculum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Nevertheless, there are two major sources of confusion 
    that render difficult the comparison of our results with the 
    earlier literature: nomenclature and the geometry of the 
    hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">In a general way, it has been appreciated at least since 
    the time of Lorente de NO (&apos;34) that there are clear 
    differences in the cytoarchitecture of the subiculum along both the 
    septotemporal and proximodistal (or mediolateral; transverse) axes, 
    and it has since been shown that these differences are reflected in 
    the connections of various regions of this cortical field (Swanson 
    and Cowan, &apos;75, &apos;77; Swanson et al., &apos;87; Witter and 
    Groenewegen, &apos;90; Witter et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">However, problems have arisen because different authors 
    have defined in different ways the borders of the subiculum, with 
    hippocampal field CAI on one side (proximally) and with the 
    presubiculum on the other (distally); and because the relative 
    positions of lesions or injection sites are difficult to appreciate 
    in relation to the two cardinal axes, in sections cut in any of the 
    standard planes of section, due to the highly folded nature of the 
    hippocampal formation (see Swanson et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">lherefore, it is important to point out that we have 
    followed Blackstad&apos;s (&apos;56) definition of the borders of 
    the subiculum, as have most workers since that time.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">There appears to be little remaining confusion about the 
    distal border of the subiculum with the presubiculum (whose layer 
    I1 is so distinct).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">It is the proximal border, with hippocampal field CAI, 
    that is so problematic, especially ventrally where distinctions 
    between the two cortical areas become progressively less clear as 
    the temporal pole (and amygdala) is approached.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">Nevertheless, we have chosen to maintain the two 
    criteria for the boundary that are relatively clear dorsally: the 
    disappearance of the stratum oriens associated with field CAI at 
    the proximal border of the subiculum, and the disappearance of the 
    dense superficial layer of field CAI pyramidal cells at the 
    proximal border of the subiculum (see Fig. 2 in Lorente de NO, 
    &apos;34; and Fig. 2 in Blackstad, &apos;56).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">The &quot;prosubiculum&quot; as originally defined by 
    the Vogts (&apos;19), Rose (&apos;261, and Lorente de NO (&apos;34) 
    clearly falls within the subiculum as defined by Blackstad 
    (&apos;56).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">The second major problem associated with interpreting 
    our results-the complex geometry of each hippocampal field-has been 
    addressed by plotting the location of injection sites on an 
    unfolded map of the hippocampal formation (Swanson et al., 
    &apos;781, which allows topographical relationships to be 
    appreciated much more clearly than in sections through the 
    structure (see Fig. l), and by producing injection sites that were 
    small enough to avoid spurious labeling of cell bodies in adjacent 
    cortical (or amygdalar) areas that would label pathways not arising 
    in the subiculum as defined here.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">With these caveats in mind, we can now discuss the 
    relationship of our findings to the earlier literature, as well as 
    their functional implications (Fig. 5 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">Input to the temporal lobe</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">Projections from the subiculum to the amygdala have been 
    described in the rat (Ottersen, &apos;82; Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;87), cat (Russchen, &apos;821, and monkey (Rosene and Van 
    Hoesen, &apos;77; Aggleton, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">In all three species, neurons located more ventrally 
    appear to generate this projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">Our results indicate that efferent fibers from the 
    ventral subiculum reach the amygdala by crossing obliquely through 
    the angular bundle.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">These axons appear to innervate most densely caudal 
    regions of the amygdala, where they provide a massive input to the 
    posterior part of the basomedial nucleus, and a less dense input to 
    nearby regions, including the caudal pole of the posterior part of 
    the basolateral nucleus, the posterior nucleus, the posterior 
    cortical nucleus, and the piriform-amygdaloid area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">The present study is the first to document a projection 
    to the posterior basomedial nucleus, by far the densest target of 
    ventral subicular outputs within the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">Using fluorogold as a retrograde tracer, we were able to 
    confirm this projection, which also appears to contain fibers that 
    may arise in adjacent, ventral parts of field CA1 (N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">Canteras and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">A projection from the ventral subiculum to the posterior 
    cortical nucleus has also been reported by Ottersen (&apos;821, in 
    the rat, using horseradish peroxidase (HRP) as a retrograde tracer; 
    according to this author ventral parts of field CA1 project more 
    densely to this nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">A smaller number of efferent fibers from the ventral 
    subiculum continue rostrally though the amygdala, providing inputs 
    mainly to the central nucleus, the medial nucleus, the adjacent 
    intercalated nuclei, and the nucleus of the lateral olfactory 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">In the central nucleus, a relatively dense terminal 
    field was observed in the caudalmost pole of the lateral 
    subdivision, whereas at more rostra1 levels labeled axons were 
    preferentially located in the capsular subdivision.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">In the medial nucleus, the projection was mainly 
    directed to the anterodorsal and the posteroventral 
    subdivisions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">In agreement with the present results, Ottersen 
    (&apos;82) reported a few retrogradely labeled cells in the ventral 
    subiculum following injections of HRP into the medial nucleus or 
    the central nucleus of the rat amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">While a projection from the ventral subiculum to the 
    nucleus of the lateral olfactory tract has not been specifically 
    described in the past, Groenewegen et al. (&apos;87) did illustrate 
    without comment anterogradely labeled fibers in this nucleus after 
    injections of PHAL into the ventral subiculum of the rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">In all of the experiments analyzed in the present study, 
    the basolateral and lateral nuclei of the amygdala received only a 
    few labeled fibers, except for the caudal pole of the posterior 
    basolateral nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">In his studies on the connections of the amygdala in the 
    rat, Ottersen (&apos;82) reported only a few retrogradely labeled 
    neurons in the ventral subiculum after injections of HRP into the 
    basolateral or lateral nuclei, although the temporal third of field 
    CA1 in these experiments did contain a larger number of labeled 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">A projection from the temporal third of field CAI to the 
    basolateral nucleus has also been reported recently in the rat with 
    the PHAL method (Van Groen and Wyss, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">In contrast to what has just been discussed for the rat, 
    there is as yet no evidence in the monkey (Rosene and Van Hoesen, 
    &apos;77; Aggleton, &apos;86) or cat (Russchen, &apos;82) for a 
    direct projection from field CA1 to the amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">Another component of the hippocampal formation, the 
    lateral entorhinal area, also provides a dense input to the 
    amygdala that is especially directed to the lateral and basolateral 
    nuclei (Wyss, &apos;81; Swanson and Kohler, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">In view of what has been discussed thus far, projections 
    from the hippocampal formation to the amygdala appear to have a 
    certain topographic organization in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">Thus, the lateral and basolateral nuclei receive inputs 
    mainly from the lateral entorhinal area and/or temporal regions of 
    field CA1, whereas the ventral subiculum projects especially 
    densely to the posterior part of the basomedial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">The latter also receives a very dense projection from 
    the lateral nucleus of the amygdala (Krettek and Price, &apos;78b), 
    and is thus in a position to integrate cortical information known 
    to converge upon the lateral nucleus (see Ottersen, &apos;82; Price 
    et al., &apos;87) with information processed in the hippocampal 
    formation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">It should also be pointed out that the posterior 
    basomedial nucleus shares several targets in common with the 
    ventral subiculum, including the nucleus accumbens, the bed nuclei 
    of the stria terminalis, the ventromedial nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus, and the ventral premammillary nucleus (Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">In view of evidence presented here that the posterior 
    basomedial nucleus is an important relay for information generated 
    in the hippocampal formation, a detailed analysis of the 
    projections of this nucleus with the PHAL method would clearly be 
    useful.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">Before we compare results on the projections of the 
    ventral subiculum to the amygdala in the rat with what has been 
    reported for the cat (Russchen, &apos;82) and monkey (Rosene and 
    Van Hoesen, &apos;77; Aggleton, &apos;86), it is necessary to point 
    out that correlations of this type should be viewed with some 
    caution until homologies between various amygdalar cell groups are 
    clarified more fully in different species.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Be that as it may, in the cat, Russchen (&apos;82) found 
    retrogradely labeled neurons in the ventral subiculum after tracer 
    injections in the central nucleus, in the posterolateral part of 
    the posterior cortical nucleus, or in the latter combined with the 
    basomedial nucleus, in agreement with our PHAL studies in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Furthermore, Russchen (&apos;82) found no evidence of 
    retrograde labeling in the ventral subiculum following tracer 
    injections in the lateral or basolateral nuclei of the amygdala, 
    which is also in essential agreement with our results.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">Autoradiographic studies in the monkey (Rosene and Van 
    Hoesen, &apos;77; Aggleton, &apos;86) indicate that the ventral 
    subiculum projects most densely to medial and caudal regions of the 
    parvicellular part of the basal nucleus, which has been said to 
    correspond to what we call here in the rat the posterior 
    basolateral nucleus (see Price et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">The autoradiographic evidence also indicates that the 
    ventral subiculum in the monkey projects less densely to the 
    central and medial nuclei of the amygdala, as well as to the 
    periamygdaloid cortex, which corresponds to the piriformamygdaloid 
    area plus the lateral part of the posterior cortical nucleus in the 
    subdivision scheme we have adopted here for the rat (compare Price 
    et al., &apos;87 with Canteras et al., &apos;92a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Based on our results, the projection of the ventral 
    subiculum upon the amygdala is very similar in the monkey and rat 
    if we regard (as seems plausible to us) medial areas of the 
    parvicellular basal nucleus in the monkey as homologous to the 
    posterior basomedial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">However, Price et al. (&apos;87) suggested that the 
    posterior basomedial nucleus of the present account corresponds to 
    the accessory basal nucleus in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">The present connectional information suggests that 
    further work is needed to evaluate this homology.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">For the sake of completeness, it should be mentioned 
    that we confirmed the well-known topographic input from the 
    subiculum to the entorhinal area (for review see Swanson et al., 
    &apos;87), as well as the recently described (Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;87; Witter et al., &apos;88) input to the dorsal endopiriform 
    nucleus; in addition, labeled fibers that appear to be related in a 
    general way to these projections were observed in the cellular 
    layers of adjacent olfactory cortical regions, including the 
    piriform area, and area TR, as well as in the claustrum, and deep 
    layers of the agranular insular and perirhinal areas (see also Fig. 
    3 in Groenewegen et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s152">Input to the septum</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Projections from the hippocampal formation to the bed 
    nuclei of the stria terminalis appear to arise almost exclusively 
    from neurons in more ventral parts of the subiculum (Swanson et 
    al., &apos;871, and reach the BST mainly by way of the 
    precommissural component of the fornix.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">The projection from the ventral subiculum to the BST 
    described here is similar to our earlier observations in the rat 
    (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77) using the autoradiographic method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">However, the PHAL study here provides a more thorough 
    analysis in terms of inputs to the various subdivisions of the BST 
    recently described by Ju and Swanson (&apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">In the anterior division of the BST, anterogradely 
    labeled fibers and terminal boutons from the ventral subiculum were 
    distributed preferentially to the anterodorsal area, and to a 
    lesser extent the anteroventral area, whereas the anterolateral 
    area contained only a few PHAL-immunoreactive axons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">In the posterior division of the BST, the 
    interfascicular and the transverse nuclei receive a dense plexus of 
    fibers, which tend to avoid the adjoining principal nucleus, where 
    only a very few anterogradely labeled fibers were observed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">In addition, the contralateral BST contained a few 
    labeled fibers that were particularly obvious in regions that 
    appear to be more densely innervated on the ipsilateral side of the 
    brain.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">The BST receives massive inputs from the ventral 
    subiculum and from many parts of the amygdala (see Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;78a; Canteras et al., &apos;92a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">From this point of view, the ventral subiculum is more 
    like adjacent parts of the amygdala than the rest of the 
    hippocampal formation, especially when its projections to the 
    hypothalamus are also taken into account (Swanson et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">However, it is important to note that the posterior 
    nucleus of the amygdala, which lies directly adjacent to the 
    ventral subiculum, gives rise to a distinct pattern of projections 
    to the BST and hypothalamus (see Canteras et al., &apos;92a), as 
    discussed below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">Thus, the ventral subiculum projects massively to the 
    transverse and interfascicular nuclei in the posterior division 
    (like the posterior cortical nucleus, and several parts of the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala), whereas the posterior nucleus of 
    the amygdala projects massively to the principal nucleus of the 
    posterior division of the BST (like the posterodorsal part of the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">It is thus interesting to note that specific populations 
    of cells in the BST (such as the transverse and interfascicular 
    nuclei) may be directly influenced by information processed within 
    both the amygdala and the trisynaptic circuit of the hippocampal 
    formation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">As suggested by previous autoradiographic studies, the 
    projections from the BST include a very widespread input to the 
    hypothalamus, as well as inputs to the nucleus accumbens, to 
    several parts of the thalamus, and to widespread parts of the 
    brainstem (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;79; Holstege et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">However, to provide reliable clues about the possible 
    functional significance of the direct projection from the 
    hippocampal formation to specific parts of the BST, it will be 
    necessary to characterize the specific patterns of outputs from 
    these particular cell groups in the BST.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">As illustrated in Figure 3, fibers from the 
    precommissural fornix also continue rostrally to and through 
    ventral and intermediate parts of the lateral septal nucleus as 
    well as to the nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">This projection, along with its continuation to the 
    anterior olfactory nucleus and the medial prefrontal region is well 
    known (see Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77; Swanson, &apos;81; 
    Groenewegen et al., &apos;87; Jay and Witter, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s168">Input to the 
    hypothalamus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Massive projections from the ventral subiculum to the 
    hypothalamus have been reported with both anterograde (Swanson and 
    Cowan, &apos;75, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek 
    and Price, &apos;78a; Kohler, &apos;90; Witter and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90) and retrograde tracing techniques (Berk and Finkelstein, 
    &apos;81; Zaborsky, &apos;82; Ono et al., &apos;85; Simerly and 
    Swanson, &apos;86; Fahrbach et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Efferent fibers from the ventral subiculum reach the 
    hypothalamus primarily by way of the medial corticohypothalamic 
    tract, and to a much lesser extent through the precommissural 
    component of the fornix and the ansa peduncularis (after passing 
    through the amygdala).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">In a study of subicular projections to the hypothalamus 
    with the PHAL, method, Kohler (&apos;90) reported labeled axons in 
    the postcommissural fornix as it passes through the lateral 
    hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">However, no labeled fibers coursing through the 
    postcommissural fornix were observed in any of our experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">This discrepancy would easily be explained if his 
    injection sites spread to involve somewhat more dorsal parts of 
    this cortical field, which are known to project to the hypothalamus 
    by way of the postcommissural fornix (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, 
    &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Witter and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90; Witter et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">This interpretation is strengthened by the fact that 
    labeled fibers in the postcommissural fornix have not been reported 
    in previous autoradiographic studies of the ventralmost parts of 
    the subiculum (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, 
    &apos;77; Krettek and Price, &apos;78a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">We have confirmed an extensive, largely ipsilateral 
    projection from the ventral subiculum to the entire rostrocaudal 
    extent of the hypothalamus that appears to be mainly directed to 
    regions lying in the medial zone (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, 
    &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">In the preoptic region, undifferentiated parts of the 
    medial preoptic area, as well as the lateral subdivision of the 
    medial preoptic nucleus, receive a dense input, whereas a smaller 
    number of labeled fibers end in the anteroventral periventricular 
    nucleus and in the medial subdivision of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">As suggested by the results of previous retrograde 
    tracer studies (Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Simerly and 
    Swanson, &apos;86), neurons in the temporal pole that project to 
    the medial zone of the preoptic region lie chiefly in the medial 
    and posterior nuclei of the amygdala, as well as in ventral parts 
    of the subiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">However, in contrast to what was just described for the 
    subiculum, the posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus and the 
    posterior nucleus of the amygdala appear to project much more 
    heavily to the anteroventral periventricular nucleus, as well as to 
    the medial subdivision of the medial preoptic nucleus (Simerly et 
    al., &apos;89; Canteras et al., &apos;92a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">This is important because each cell group in the medial 
    preoptic region gives rise to a distinct pattern of projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Thus, the medial subdivision of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus and the anteroventral periventricular nucleus project 
    heavily to all of the parvicellular neurosecretory regions of the 
    periventricular zone of the hypothalamus, whereas the 
    undifferentiated regions of the medial preoptic area and the 
    lateral subdivision of the medial preoptic nucleus give rise to 
    massive projections to the septal region and the brainstem (Simerly 
    and Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">In the anterior hypothalamic region, the ventral 
    subiculum provides a very dense plexus of fibers and terminal 
    boutons to a narrow vertical region that lies between the anterior 
    hypothalamic nucleus and the periventricular zone, a region that we 
    had earlier referred to as the subparaventricular zone (Watts et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Very few terminal boutons were found within the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus itself.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">As previously reported in the autoradiographic studies 
    (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, 
    &apos;77; Krettek and Price, &apos;78a), at the tuberal level of 
    the hypothalamus, the ventral subiculum provides a dense terminal 
    field to the cell-sparse &quot;shell&quot; surrounding the 
    ventromedial nucleus, particularly in regions where this nucleus 
    adjoins the dorsomedial nucleus and the periventricular zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">In addition, we found that a number of these fibers also 
    end within the cellular &quot;core&quot; of caudal regions of the 
    central and ventrolateral subdivisions of this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">We also found at tuberal levels a moderate projection to 
    all parts of the dorsomedial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">This cell group may represent an important interface 
    between the ventral subiculum and parvicellular neurons that 
    secrete hormones into the hypophyseal portal system, since it 
    provides a massive projection to neurosecretory regions of the 
    paraventricular nucleus, the anterior periventricular nucleus, and 
    the arcuate nucleus, which are known to contain most of the 
    neurosecretory cells directly involved in neuroendocrine control 
    mechanisms (see Swanson, &apos;871, and according to our 
    observations appear to receive only a sparse direct innervation 
    from the ventral subiculum itself.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">This implies that the ventral subiculum has little if 
    any direct influence on the perikarya of neurosecretory 
    motoneurons, although clearly, their dendrites may extend into the 
    terminal fields described.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Immediately caudal to the tuberal region we also found a 
    moderately dense projection to the posterior periventricular 
    nucleus, the ventral premammillary nucleus, and ventral parts of 
    the posterior hypothalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">The projection to the ventral premammillary nucleus has 
    been reported previously with the autoradiographic method (Swanson 
    and Cowan, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;78a), and we have shown recently that this nucleus in 
    turn provides massive inputs to the periventricular subdivision of 
    the paraventricular nucleus, all parts of the periventricular 
    nucleus, and the arcuate nucleus (Canteras et al., &apos;92b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Therefore, it may represent another gateway for the 
    ventral subiculum to influence neurosecretory motoneurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">In complete agreement with previous autoradiographic 
    studies (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, ,771, we 
    also observed at the level of the mammillary complex that the 
    ventral subiculum gives rise to a dense plexus of fibers in the 
    cell-free region surrounding the medial mammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">On the other hand, the cellular &quot;core&quot; of this 
    nucleus, which appears to receive very few labeled fibers in the 
    experiments analyzed here, clearly is the major hypothalamic target 
    of neurons in the dorsal subiculum (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, 
    &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Witter and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90; Witter et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Since the cell-free zone contains the distal dendrites 
    of medial mammillary neurons (see Ramon y Cajal, &apos;111, the 
    evidence suggests that the dorsal subiculum innervates the cell 
    bodies of medial mammillary neurons whereas the ventral subiculum 
    innervates distal parts of their dendrites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Hypothalamic regions that receive direct inputs from the 
    ventral subiculum are thought to play an important role in the 
    initiation of motivated or goal-oriented behavior and in the 
    regulation of endocrine responses (see Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The importance of these observations is further 
    strengthened by the fact that this hippocampal field appears to 
    relay information from widespread cortical areas (see 
    Introduction), and is therefore in a position to modulate important 
    anticipatory adjustments to endocrine and behavioral responses 
    integrated at the level of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">One example of the possible involvement of the ventral 
    subiculum in anticipatory adjustments of hormone levels was 
    reported by Fischette et al. ( 801, who disrupted the diurnal 
    rhythm of plasma adrenal glucocorticoid levels after lesions that 
    selectively interrupt the medial corticohypothalamic tract, which 
    arises almost exclusively from the ventral subiculum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The diurnal rhythm of plasma glucocorticoids is also 
    regulated by the suprachiasmatic nucleus, the endogenous circadian 
    rhythm generator (for references see Watts et al., 87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">One of the most interesting features to emerge from the 
    present study is that the pattern of projections from the ventral 
    subiculum to the septum and hypothalamus overlaps almost precisely 
    with the efferent projections of the suprachiasmatic nucleus (Watts 
    et al., 87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Thus, it is tempting to suggest that basal forebrain 
    circuits controlling behavioral state and neuroendocrine responses 
    receive convergent inputs from the suprachiasmatic nucleus and the 
    ventral subiculum, the former concerned with providing a circadian 
    bias, and the latter with anticipatory biases related to the 
    previous experience of the animal.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">In conclusion, the present observations expand in a 
    number of ways what has been reported previously about the 
    projections of the ventral subiculum to the amygdala, septum, and 
    hypothalamus, providing further insights into possible hippocampal 
    influences on endocrine and behavioral responses.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">However, it is important to emphasize that our 
    experimental observations are limited to the outputs of the 
    temporal end (ventralmost pole) of the subiculum; thus, further 
    work is required to provide a more complete picture of the 
    projections of the cortical field examined in the present work.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s202">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s203">We thank Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s204">David Warren for document 
    preparation, and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s205">Kris Trulock for photographic 
    assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s206">This work was supported in 
    part by CNPq Fellowship 200969/ 90-0, FAPESP Fellowship 88/1289-0 
    to N.S.C., and NINDS 2ROlNS16686 to L.W.S.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s207">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Aggleton, J.P. (1986) A description of the 
    amygdalo-hippocampal interconnections in the macaque monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Brain Res. 64t515-526.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Finkelstein (1981) Afferent projections to the preoptic 
    area and hypothalamic regions in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Neuroscience 6:16011624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Blackstad, T.W. (1956) Commissural connections of the 
    hippocampal region in the rat, with special reference to their mode 
    of termination.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Neurol. 105:417-438.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">Swanson (1992a) The projections of the posterior nucleus 
    of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">Neurol. 324: 143-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Swanson (1992b) The projections of the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Neurol. 324:195-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Fahrbach, S.E., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Morrell, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Pfaff (1989) Studies of ventromedial hypothalamic 
    afferents in the rat using three methods of HRP application.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Brain Res. 77:221-233.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Fischette, C.T., B.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Komisaruk, H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Edinger, H.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Feder, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Siegel (1980) Differential fornix ablations and the 
    circadian rhythmicity of adrenal corticosteroid secretion.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Brain Res. 195373-387.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Groenewegen, H.J., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Vermeulen-Van der Zee, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Te Kortschot, and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Witter (1987) Organization of the projections from the 
    subiculum to the ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">A study using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Neuroscience 23: 103-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Holstege, G., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Meiners, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Tan (1985) Projections of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis to the mesencephalon, pons, and medulla oblongata in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Brain Res. 58:379-391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Hsu, S.M., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Raine (1981) Protein A, avidin and biotin in 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Cytochem. 29:1349-1353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Hsu, S.M., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Raine, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Fanger (1981) The use of avidin-biotinperoxidase complex 
    (ABC) in immunoperoxidase techniques: A comparison between ABC and 
    unlabeled antibody (PAP) procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Cytochem. 29:577-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Jay, T.M., and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Witter (1991) Distribution of hippocampal CA1 and 
    subicular efferents in the prefrontal cortex of the rat studied by 
    means of anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    vulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Neurol. 313:574-586.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">G., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Swanson (1989) Studies on the cellular architecture of 
    the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis in the rat: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Neurol. 280:587-602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Kohler, C. (1990) Subicular projections to the 
    hypothalamus and brainstem: Some novel aspects revealed in the rat 
    by the anterograde Phaseolus uulgaris leukoagglutinin (PHA-L) 
    tracing method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Brain Res. 83:59-69.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Price (1978a) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Neurol. 178.225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Price (1978b) A description of the amygdaloid complex in 
    the rat and cat with observations on intra-amygdaloid axonal 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">I78:255-280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Lorente de NO, R. (1934) Studies on the structure of the 
    cerebral cortex. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Continuation of the study of the Ammonic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Psychol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Neurol. 46t113-177.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Siegel (1977) Efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Brain Res. 124:197-224.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Ono, T., P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Luiten, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Nishijo, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Fukuda, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Nishino Topographic organization of projections from the 
    amygdala hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Res. 2:221-239.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Ottersen, O.P. (1982) Connections of the amygdala of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">IV Corticoamygdaloid and intraamygdaloid connections as 
    studied with axonal transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurol. 205:3048.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Price, J.L., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Russchen, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Amaral (1987) The limbic region. 11: The amygdaloid 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 279-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Ramon y Cajal, S. (1911) Histologie du Systeme Nerveux 
    de I Homme et des Vertebres.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Paris: A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Maloine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Rose, M. (1926) Der Allocortex bei Tier und Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">(Lpz.) 34:l-111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Rosene, D.L., and G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Van Hoesen (1977) Hippocampal efferents reach widespread 
    areas of cerebral cortex and amygdala in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Science 198:3 15-3 17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Russchen, F.T. (1982) Amygdalopetal projections in the 
    cat: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Cortical afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">A study with retrograde and anterograde tracing 
    techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Neurol. 206r159-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Swanson (1986) The organization of neural inputs to the 
    medial preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Neurol. 246:312-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Swanson (1988) Projections of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus: A Phaseolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Neurol. 270:209-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Simerly, R.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Swanson, and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Gorski (1984) Demonstration of a sexual dimorphism in 
    the distribution of serotonin-imrnunoreactive fibers in the medial 
    preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Neurol. 225: 15 1-166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Simerly, R.B., B.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Young, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Capozza, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Swanson (1989) Estrogen differentially regulates 
    neuropeptide gene expression in a sexually dimorphic olfactory 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">U.S.A. 86:47664770.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Swanson, L.W. (1981) A direct projection from Ammon s 
    horn to prefrontal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Brain Res. 21 7:150-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Swanson, L.W. (1987) The hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 
    Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 1-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Swanson, L.W. (1992) Brain Maps: Structure of the Rat 
    Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Amsterdam: Elsevier, in press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Cowan (1975) Hippocampo-hypothalamic connections: Origin 
    in subicular cortex not Ammon s horn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Science 189t303304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Cowan (1977) An autoradiographic study of the 
    organization of the efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Neurol. 172t49-84.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Cowan (1979) The connections of the septal region in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Neurol. 186t621-656.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Swanson, L.W., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Kohler (1986) Anatomical evidence for direct projections 
    from the enthorhinal area to the entire cortical mantle in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Neurosci. 6;3010-3023.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Swanson, L.W., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Simmons (1989) Differential steroid hormone and neural 
    influences on peptide mRNA levels in CRH cells of the 
    paraventricular nucleus: A hybridization histochemical study in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Neurol. 285t413-435.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Swanson, L.W., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Wyss, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Cowan (1978) An autoradiographic study of the 
    organization of intrahippocampal association pathways in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Neurol. 181t681-716.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Swanson, L.W., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Kohler, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Bjorklund (1987) The limbic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">I: The septohippocampal system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 125-277.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Van Groen, T., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Wyss (1990) Extrinsic projections from area CA1 of the 
    rat hippocampus: Olfactory, cortical, subcortical, and bilateral 
    hippocampal formation projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Neurol. 302t515-528.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Vogt, C., and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Vogt (1919) Allgemeine Ergebnisse unserer 
    Hirnforschung.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Vierte Mitteilung: Die physiologische Bedeutung der 
    architektonischen Rindenfelderung auf Grund neuer 
    Rindenreizungen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Psychol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">(Lpz.) 25.279462.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Watts, A.G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Swanson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Sanchez-Watts (1987) Efferent projections of the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Studies using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris leucoagglutinin in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Neurol. 258t204-229.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Witter, M.P., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Groenewegen (1990) The subiculum: Cytoarchitectonically 
    a simple structure, but hodologically complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">83t47-58.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Witter, M.P., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Room, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Groenewegen, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Lohman (1988) Reciprocal connections of the insular and 
    piriform claustrum with limbic cortex: An anatomical study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Neuroscience 24t519-539.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Witter, M.P., R.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Ostendorf, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Groenewegen (1990) Heterogeneity in the dorsal subiculum 
    of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Distinct neuronal zones project to different cortical 
    and subcortical targets.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Eur.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Neurosci. 2:71&amp;725.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Wouterlood, F.G., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Groenewegen (1985) Neuroanatomical tracing by use of 
    Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) electron microscopy of 
    PHA-L filled neuronal somata, dendrites, axons, and axon 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Brain Res. 326t188-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Wyss, J.M. (1981) An autoradiographic study of the 
    efferent connections of the entorhinal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Neurol. 199t495-512.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Zaborszky, L. (1982) Afferent connections of the medial 
    basal hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Cell Biol. 69:l-107.</S>
  </References>

</File>

