<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Projections of the Ventral Premammillary Nucleus</Title>

  <Authors>N.S. CANTERAS, R.B. SIMERLY, AND L.W. SWANSON</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The projections of the ventral premammillary nucleus (PMv) 
    have been examined with the Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHAL) method in adult male rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The results indicate that the nucleus gives rise to two 
    major ascending pathways and a smaller descending pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">One large ascending pathway terminates densely in most 
    regions of the periventricular zone of the hypothalamus, with the 
    notable exception of the suprachiasmatic, suprachiasmatic preoptic, 
    and median preoptic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">This pathway is in a position to influence directly many 
    cell groups known to regulate anterior pituitary function.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The second large pathway ascends through the medial zone 
    of the hypothalamus and densely innervates the ventrolateral part 
    of the ventromedial nucleus and adjacent basal parts of the lateral 
    hypothalamic area, medial preoptic nucleus, principal nucleus of 
    the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis, ventral lateral septal 
    nucleus, posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus of the amygdala, 
    posterior nucleus, and immediately adjacent regions of the 
    posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">It is already known that these regions are major 
    components of the sexually dimorphic circuit, and, interestingly, 
    that they provide the major neural inputs to the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The smaller descending projection from the PMv seems to 
    innervate preferentially the posterior hypothalamic nucleus, 
    although a small number of fibers appear to end in the 
    tuberomammillary nucleus, supramammillary nucleus, specific regions 
    of the medial mammillary nucleus, interfascicular nucleus, 
    interpeduncular nucleus, periaqueductal gray, dorsal nucleus of the 
    raphe, laterodorsal tegmental nucleus, Barrington&apos;s nucleus, 
    and locus coeruleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Relatively sparse terminal fields associated with 
    ascending fibers were also observed in the dorsomedial nucleus of 
    the hypothalamus; in the nucleus reuniens, parataenial nucleus, 
    paraventricular nucleus of the thalamus, and mediodorsal nucleus; 
    in the central nucleus of the amygdala, anterodorsal part of the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala, posterior part of the basomedial 
    nucleus of the amygdala; and in the ventral subiculum and adjacent 
    parts of hippocampal field CAI, and the infralimbic and prelimbic 
    areas of the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Taken as a whole, the evidence suggests that the PMv 
    receives two major inputs-one from the sexually dimorphic circuit, 
    and the other from the blood in the form of gonadal steroid 
    hormones-and gives rise to two major outputs: one (perhaps 
    feed-forward) to the neuroendocrine (periventricular) zone of the 
    hypothalamus, and the other (perhaps feed-back) to the sexually 
    dimorphic circuit. o 19% wiey-Lis, Inc.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s10">motivated behavior</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The ventral premammillary nucleus (PMv) was first 
    recognized by Gurdjian (&apos;27) in the rat as a distinct, compact 
    group of neurons in the medial zone of the hypothalamus, surrounded 
    by the ventromedial, dorsal premammillary, and medial mammillary 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Previous anatomical observations indicate that the PMv is 
    strongly influenced by areas related to the sexually dimorphic 
    circuit, and as a corollary of this appears to be dominated by 
    sensory inputs relayed from the accessory olfactory bulb by way of 
    the medial and posterior cortical nuclei of the amygdala, as well 
    as by the principal (encapsulated) nucleus of the bed nuclei of the 
    stria terminalis (Krettek and Price, &apos;78; Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;79; Post and Mai, &apos;80; Kevetter and Winnans, &apos;81; 
    Luiten et al., &apos;85; Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88; Canteras et 
    al., &apos;92; N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">In addition to these neuronal inputs, the PMv may be 
    influenced directly by fluctuating levels of gonadal steroid 
    hormones, since it contains a very high density of neurons that 
    concentrate circulating gonadal steroids (Pfaff and Keiner, 
    &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;75a,b; Stumpf et al., &apos;75), 
    and express high levels of mRNA encoding the androgen receptor, and 
    moderate levels of mRNA encoding the estrogen receptor (Simerly et 
    al., &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Previous functional studies indicate that the PMv may be 
    involved in the expression of aggressive behavior (van den Berg et 
    al., &apos;831, thermoregulation (Shiraishi and Mager, 
    &apos;80a,b), and gonadotropin secretion (Beltramino and Taleisnik, 
    &apos;84, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">However, just how these and perhaps other responses may 
    be mediated remains largely unknown, partly because the anatomical 
    relationships of the nucleus have yet to be critically analyzed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Thus, a comprehensive description of the organization of 
    the projections of the PMv should at least facilitate a general 
    understanding of its role in these mechanisms, as well as provide 
    insights into other possible roles played by this structure.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Some information regarding the projections of the PMv can 
    be gleaned from the earlier work of Saper et al. (&apos;76) and 
    Krieger et al. (&apos;791, who reported the results of 
    autoradiographic experiments with 3H-amino acid injections at the 
    level of the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">However, these observations are rather limited because 
    the injection sites always involved surrounding areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">On the other hand, labeled neurons within the PMv have 
    been reported after injections of retrograde tracers in the septum 
    (Luiten et al., &apos;82; Staiger and Nurnberger, &apos;891, 
    amygdala Weening, &apos;78; Ottersen, &apos;80; Russchen, &apos;82; 
    Luiten et al., &apos;85; Volz et al., &apos;901, thalamus 
    (Herkenham, &apos;78; Cornwall and Phillipson, &apos;88; Chen and 
    Su, &apos;go), hypothalamus (Shiosaka et al., &apos;80; Kita and 
    Oomura, &apos;82; Sawchenko and Swanson, &apos;83; Chiba and 
    Murata, &apos;85; Simerly and Swanson, &apos;86; Fahrbach et al., 
    &apos;891, and brainstem (Contestabile and Flumerfelt, &apos;81; 
    Morrell et al., &apos;81; Satoh and Fibiger, &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">In the present report we describe the results of a series 
    of pathway-tracing experiments in which the anterogradely 
    transported lectin, Phaseolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHAL), was 
    injected into the PMv, and the distribution of labeled axons 
    throughout the forebrain and brainstem was determined.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">As is now well known, this method has a number of 
    advantages.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">It is very sensitive, does not appear to label 
    fibers-of-passage, and has very clear injection sites since the 
    dendrites and somata of neurons that give rise to labeled 
    projections are filled.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">In addition, projections are labeled with the clarity of 
    a Golgi impregnation, thus allowing the identification of terminal 
    boutons and varicosities along axons as well as at their ends (see 
    Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; Wouterlood and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;85; Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The results of the present report are compared with our 
    observations on the projections of the nearby ventromedial and 
    dorsal premammillary nuclei (Canteras and Swanson, &apos;92b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">A preliminary account of this work has been presented 
    elsewhere (Canteras et al., &apos;90).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s29">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Ten adult male Sprague-Dawley rats (275-340 g) received 
    an injection of PHAL (Vector Laboratories) into the region of the 
    ventral premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Each animal was anesthetized with tribromoethanol (0.25 
    g/kg b.w., dissolved in 9O:lO saline/ethanol, v/v), and a single 
    iontophoretic injection of a 2.5% solution of PHAL in 0.01 M sodium 
    phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4) was made through a 
    stereotaxically positioned glass micropipette (tip diameter 10 pm) 
    by applying a +4 pA current pulsed at 7-second intervals, provided 
    by a constant-current source (Midgard Electronics, model CS3), for 
    a period of 15 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Postinjection survival times for all experiments ranged 
    from 14 to 16 days.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The animals were perfused and the brains were processed 
    according to procedures described in detail elsewhere (Canteras et 
    al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Briefly, each animal was deeply anesthetized with 
    tribromoethanol and perfused transcardially with a solution of 4.0% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M sodium borate buffer at pH 9.5; the 
    brains were removed immediately and postfixed overnight in the same 
    fixative containing 10% sucrose.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Three series of 30-pm-thick frozen sections were cut in 
    the frontal plane on a sliding microtome and collected at the 
    following frequencies: one-in-ten through the olfactory bulbs and 
    forebrain rostral to the vascular organ of the lamina terminalis, 
    one-in-four through the hypothalamus and rostral half of the 
    midbrain, and one-in-ten through the caudal midbrain and 
    hindbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Additional sections were collected through levels 
    containing the PMv and &quot;quickstained&quot; for confirmation of 
    the injection site location (see Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">One complete series of sections was processed for 
    immunohistochemistry with an antiserum directed against PHAL (Dako 
    Laboratories) at a dilution of 1: 1,000.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The antigen-antibody complex was localized by using a 
    variation of the avidin-biotin complex system (ABC; Hsu and Raine, 
    &apos;81; Hsu et al., &apos;811, with a commercially available kit 
    (ABC Elite Kit, Vector Laboratories).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The sections were mounted on gelatin-coated slides, and 
    treated with osmium tetroxide to enhance visibility of the reaction 
    product.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Slides were then dehydrated and coverslipped with DPX.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">An adjacent series was always stained with thionin to 
    serve as a reference series for cytoarchitectonic purposes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Sections were examined with a Leitz Laborlux D microscope 
    with both brightand darkfield illumination.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">PHALlabeled cells in the injection sites, as well as the 
    distribution of the anterogradely labeled fibers, were plotted with 
    the aid of a camera lucida on maps prepared from the adjacent 
    Nissl-stained sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">For the purposes of illustration, the distribution of 
    anterogradely labeled fibers was transposed onto a series of 
    standard drawings of the rat brain (Swanson, &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Finally, it should be noted that we generated six 
    experiments with an iontophoretic deposit of the retrograde tracer 
    fluorogold (Schmued and Fallon, &apos;86) centered in the PMv, 
    using procedures described in detail elsewhere (Canteras et al., 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">These experiments were carried out to determine possible 
    sources of afferents to the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">However, since the results almost entirely confirmed 
    information in the literature, we have chosen not to describe these 
    results, although they are occasionally referred to in the 
    Discussion, where they help to clarify an issue or add a seemingly 
    minor detail.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s48">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The parameters used for iontophoretic injections 
    described above resulted in very discrete injection sites, usually 
    with hundreds of neurons that were clearly labeled with PHAL.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s50">As shown in Figure 1, <exptLabel>five experiments 
      labeled neurons that were fairly confined to <injectionLocation>
      the PMv</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s51">Although a few neurons outside the limits of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PMv</neuroanatomicalLandmark> were 
      labeled in each case, in all of these experiments a very similar 
      pattern of anterogradely labeled fibers was observed.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s52"><exptLabel>Experiment PMv-8</exptLabel> (Figs. 2 and 3) 
      was chosen as a prototype to illustrate our results, since the 
      injection here labeled the most extensive population of cells in 
      <injectionLocation>the PMv</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s53"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      PMv</injectionLocation> may be divided into an ascending group 
      that innervates targets rostral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      diencephalon and telencephalon</neuroanatomicalLocation>, and a 
      much smaller descending group that ends in <connxTermination>the 
      brainstem central gray</connxTermination>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s54">Ascending projections</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s55">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s56">The greater part of <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> that arise from injection sites in 
      <injectionLocation>the PMv</injectionLocation> course rostrally 
      through <labelingLocation>the periventricular and medial zones of 
      the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, while a smaller group of 
      <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> was also 
      observed coursing through <labelingLocation>the medial forebrain 
      bundle</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s57">From the injection site in <exptLabel>experiment 
      PMv-8</exptLabel> (Fig. 3K,L), <labelingDescription>a rather 
      large number of fibers</labelingDescription> course medially and 
      then rostrally to ascend within <labelingLocation>the 
      periventricular zone of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s58"><labelingDescription>The density of fibers and terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>this 
      zone</labelingLocation> indicates that the PMv supplies 
      relatively strong inputs to <labelingLocation>all parts of the 
      periventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, 
      as well as <labelingLocation>the related arcuate and 
      paraventricular nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s59">Within <labelingLocation>the arcuate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, we observed <labelingDescription>a 
      terminal field that was particularly dense 
      laterally</labelingDescription> (Figs. 3 H 4 , 4E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s60">It is important to note that, in spite of massive 
      inputs to nearby areas, <labelingLocation>the median 
      eminence</labelingLocation> was <labelingDescription>virtually 
      free of anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> (Figs. 3H4, 
      4E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s61">Within <labelingLocation>the paraventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>labeled fibers 
      and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> were 
      <labelingDescription>particularly numerous</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the periventricular and anterior 
      parvicellular parts</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingLocation>
      the rest of the parvicellular division</labelingLocation>, as 
      well as <labelingLocation>the anterior part of the magnocellular 
      division</labelingLocation>, appears to receive 
      <labelingDescription>a sparser innervation</labelingDescription> 
      (Figs. 3F-I, 4D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s62"><labelingDescription>Only an occasional labeled 
      fiber</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior part of the magnocellular division</labelingLocation> 
      or in <labelingLocation>the supraoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (see Swanson and Simmons, &apos;89, for subdivision of 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the paraventricular 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation>).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s63">Rostrally, at the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      preoptic region</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the PMv</injectionLocation> coursing through 
      <labelingLocation>the periventricular zone</labelingLocation> 
      provide <labelingDescription>a remarkably dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      anteroventral periventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 
      3C,D, 4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s64">Some of <labelingDescription>these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue farther rostrally to end in 
      <labelingLocation>a region just lateral to the vascular organ of 
      the lamina terminalis</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s65">Thus, <injectionLocation>the PMv</injectionLocation> 
      projects densely to <labelingLocation>most regions within the 
      periventricular zone of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>; 
      curious~y, the Only in this &apos;One that do not Seem to receive 
      a significant input are <labelingLocation>the suprachiasmatic, 
      suprachiasmatic preoptic, and median preoptic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3C-G).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s66">Another <labelingDescription>massive contingent of 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> ascends from the injection 
      site through <labelingLocation>the medial zone of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s67">Just rostral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      PMv</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, these fibers give rise to 
      <labelingDescription>an exceedingly dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> that fills <labelingLocation>the 
      ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus and ventrally 
      adjacent parts of the basal lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 35).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s68"><labelingLocation>The dorsomedial and central parts of 
      ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation> were virtually 
      <labelingDescription>free of anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription>, although <labelingLocation>the 
      cell-poor zone surrounding dorsal aspects of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> appears to receive 
      <labelingDescription>a moderate number of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 3H-J).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s69">At this level, <labelingDescription>some labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue dorsally to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      particularly medially near the periventricular zone (Fig. 35).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s70">Toward the rostral end of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      tuberal region</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, most of the fibers 
      coursing through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial 
      zone</neuroanatomicalLocation> tend to display 
      <labelingDescription>few branches and terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription>, appearing more like 
      <labelingDescription>fibers-of-passage</labelingDescription> 
      (Fig. 3H,I).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s71">These axons continue rostrally through <labelingLocation
      >the anterior hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3G-I), 
      where they also give rise to <labelingDescription>few terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription>, to reach <labelingLocation>the 
      medial preoptic area</labelingLocation>, which (in contrast) is 
      filled by <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of highly branched 
      axons</labelingDescription> displaying <labelingDescription>an 
      overwhelming number of terminal boutons</labelingDescription> 
      (Fig. 3E,F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s72">Within this area, <labelingLocation>the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>a 
      particularly dense input</labelingDescription> that is somewhat 
      <labelingDescription>more dense</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial as compared to the lateral 
      part</labelingLocation> and is <labelingDescription>very 
      sparse</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the central 
      part</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3E,F, 4B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s73"><labelingLocation>The anterodorsal and anteroventral 
      preoptic nuclei</labelingLocation>, as well as <labelingLocation>
      the parastrial nucleus</labelingLocation>, appear to receive only 
      <labelingDescription>a very sparse input</labelingDescription> 
      from the PMv (Fig. 3C-E).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s74"><labelingDescription>A small group of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> courses dorsally and then laterally to ascend 
      through <labelingLocation>the dorsal half of the medial forebrain 
      bundle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3F-L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s75">As they travel through <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      hypothalamic area</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>very 
      few terminal boutons</labelingDescription> can be seen on these 
      axons.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s76">At the level of <labelingLocation>the anterior 
      hypothalamic area</labelingLocation>, some of these fibers turn 
      medially, dorsal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the descending 
      column of the fornix</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and provide 
      <labelingDescription>a relatively sparse 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>rostral parts of 
      the zona incerta and ventral parts of the nucleus 
      reuniens</labelingLocation>, in <labelingLocation>a region dorsal 
      to the paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3G,H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s77">At the rostral end of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      lateral hypothalamic area</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, the 
      remaining fibers in this pathway enter <labelingLocation>caudal 
      regions of the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis and the 
      substantia innominata</labelingLocation>, joining a larger group 
      of fibers from <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin> that leaves 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial preoptic 
      area</neuroanatomicalLocation> at this level (Fig. 3F), as 
      described below.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s78">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Thalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> that ascend through 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation> take a dorsal course to 
      provide <labelingDescription>inputs</labelingDescription> to 
      <connxTermination>several parts of the 
      thalamus</connxTermination>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80"><labelingLocation>The paraventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate plexus of fibers</labelingDescription> that also appears 
      to extend somewhat to adjacent parts of <labelingLocation>the 
      paratenial nucleus and the medial part of the mediodorsal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3F-L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81">In addition, we observed <labelingDescription>sparse 
      anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> throughout the length 
      of <labelingLocation>the nucleus reuniens</labelingLocation>; 
      <labelingDescription>these fibers</labelingDescription> were 
      especially common in <labelingLocation>ventral regions of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3G-J).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Septum</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s83"><labelingDescription>A group of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> that ascends through <labelingLocation>the 
      medial zone</labelingLocation>, and perhaps, to a much lesser 
      extent, through <labelingLocation>the periventricular zone of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> appears to provide 
      <labelingDescription>massive inputs</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis (BST), 
      the lateral septal nucleus, and certain parts of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s84">At 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>preoptic</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
      levels these axons leave <labelingLocation>the medial zone of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, taking either a dorsolateral 
      route toward <labelingLocation>caudal regions of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3E,F) or a dorsal route rostral to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 30.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85"><labelingLocation>Parts of the posterior division of 
      the BST</labelingLocation> (see Ju and Swanson, &apos;89 for 
      subdivision of the BST) are filled with <labelingDescription>a 
      dense plexus of fibers</labelingDescription>, and at this level 
      some <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      enter <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> 
      or, to a much lesser extent, <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata (ansa peduncularis)</labelingLocation> to gain access 
      to <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3E,F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86">Within <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> running through 
      <labelingDescription>the interfascicular and transverse 
      nuclei</labelingDescription> display <labelingDescription>many 
      fewer ramifications and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> as 
      compared to axons lying more medially within <labelingLocation>
      the principal nucleus</labelingLocation>, where 
      <labelingDescription>a rather dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> was observed, particularly around the 
      periphery of the nucleus (Figs. 3E,F, 4C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87">Within <labelingLocation>the anterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> are widely distributed throughout 
      <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal and anteroventral 
      areas</labelingLocation>, while obviously tending to avoid 
      <labelingLocation>the anterolateral area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3C-E).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88"><labelingDescription>Many fibers</labelingDescription> 
      from <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin> also end in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      where they form <labelingLocation>a particularly dense terminal 
      field</labelingLocation> in <labelingLocation>the caudal 
      two-thirds of the ventral part and adjacent regions of the 
      intermediate part</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B-D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">At more rostral levels, 
      <labelingDescription>considerably fewer labeled axons and 
      terminal boutons</labelingDescription> were found, and these were 
      located primarily within <labelingLocation>the intermediate part 
      of the nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3B).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Prefrontal 
      cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue rostrally from 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      and appear to end in <labelingLocation>the infralimbic and 
      prelimbic areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3A).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">These axons, which display <labelingDescription>a few 
      varicosities and terminal boutons</labelingDescription>, do not 
      form a strikingly laminar input to these regions of 
      <labelingLocation>the medial prefrontal 
      cortex</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were not observed in 
      <labelingLocation>other nearby parts of the cortical 
      mantle</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>Amygdala</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94"><connxTermination>This part of the 
      telencephalon</connxTermination> receives <labelingDescription>a 
      very dense input</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from the injection site reach 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> primarily by 
      way of <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis</labelingLocation>, 
      although <labelingDescription>a few axons</labelingDescription> 
      also appear to run through <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      hypothalamic area and the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> in <labelingLocation>the ansa 
      peduncularis</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96"><labelingLocation>The medial part, and ventral regions 
      of the capsular part, of the central nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      as well as <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal part of the medial 
      nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation>, appear to receive 
      <labelingDescription>moderate inputs</labelingDescription> from 
      <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin>, which at these levels also 
      seems to provide <labelingDescription>a much sparser 
      input</labelingDescription> to adjacent regions such as 
      <labelingLocation>the intercalated nuclei and the anterior part 
      of the basomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3G-I).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">At caudal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (for parcellation see Canteras 
      et al., &apos;921, <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin> gives rise 
      to <labelingDescription>very dense 
      projections</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus</labelingLocation>, to 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior nucleus</labelingLocation>, and 
      to <labelingLocation>adjacent regions of the posterior cortical 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3J-M).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> form <labelingDescription>a particularly dense 
      terminal field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>deeper 
      parts of the posterodorsal part of the medial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 35).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Specifically, <labelingDescription>these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appear to innervate selectively a 
      distinct rod-shaped cell aggregate in <labelingLocation>deeper 
      parts of the nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">As pointed out elsewhere, <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> represents by far the main source of afferent 
      fibers to the <connxTermination>posterior 
      nucleus</connxTermination> (Canteras et al., &apos;921, which, in 
      all of the experiments analyzed in the present study, is filled 
      with <labelingDescription>a remarkably dense plexus of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> that spreads to include 
      <labelingLocation>adjacent deep parts and medialmost regions of 
      the molecular layer of the posterior cortical 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 3K-M, 4F).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">At these levels of the amygdala we also observed 
      <labelingDescription>a smaller number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> that appear to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior part of the basomedial nucleus 
      and the posterior part of the basolateral 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3J-M).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Hippoearnpal 
      formation</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">At the caudal pole of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate number of labeled axons</labelingDescription> take a 
      medial course to end in <labelingLocation>the ventral tip of the 
      subiculum and adjacent parts of hippocampal field 
      CAI</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3L-N).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> could also be followed to 
      <labelingLocation>area TK</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105">(Fig. 3M,N), <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the 
      medial entorhinal area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3N, area 
      28M&apos; of Haug, &apos;761, and <labelingLocation>ventral 
      regions of the lateral entorhinal area</labelingLocation> (not 
      illustrated).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s106">Descending 
      projections</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">The descending projections of <connxOrigin>the 
      PMv</connxOrigin> are considerably less extensive than the 
      ascending projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">From the injection site, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> travel dorsally to enter 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">The majority of these fibers course dorsally, just 
      rostra1 to <labelingLocation>the dorsal premammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>; only <labelingDescription>a few axons 
      with very sparse terminal boutons</labelingDescription> pass 
      through <labelingLocation>this nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      3K,L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> give rise to <labelingDescription>a 
      rather dense terminal field</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>ventral parts of the posterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3K,L), and 
      <labelingDescription>at least some of them</labelingDescription> 
      continue on caudally either toward <labelingLocation>the 
      mammillary complex</labelingLocation> or into <labelingLocation>
      the periaqueductal gray</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">In <labelingLocation>the mammillary 
      complex</labelingLocation>, <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin> 
      provides <labelingDescription>a sparse 
      projection</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the medial 
      and lateral parts of the supramammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> and to <labelingLocation>the cell-poor 
      zone that surrounds the medial mammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3M,N).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112"><labelingDescription>A very few of these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue on to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the interfascicular and interpeduncular 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> and perhaps <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3N,O).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">In addition, at caudal levels of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PMv</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingLocation>a sparse number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingLocation> were also observed projecting to 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the tuberomammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3L).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the midbrain 
      periventricular system</labelingLocation> appear to provide 
      <labelingDescription>inputs</labelingDescription> primarily to 
      <labelingLocation>ventrolateral parts of the periaqueductal 
      gray</labelingLocation> (Fig. 30,P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">In addition, <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> also appear to innervate 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal nucleus of the raphe and the 
      laterodorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 30,P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">At still more caudal levels, <labelingDescription>the 
      periventricular fibers</labelingDescription> course chiefly 
      through <labelingLocation>lateral parts of the pontine central 
      gray</labelingLocation>, near the ependymal wall of the fourth 
      ventricle (Fig. 3Q-S).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117"><labelingDescription>A very few of these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> arch laterally to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the parabrachial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3Q,R).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">Although <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed 
      <labelingDescription>only rarely</labelingDescription> within 
      <labelingLocation>the nuclear borders of the locus 
      coeruleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3S), <labelingDescription>some 
      labeled fibers and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> were 
      observed <labelingLocation>immediately rostral to 
      it</labelingLocation>; these fibers appear to innervate 
      <labelingLocation>the so-called Barrington&apos;s 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 3R), which is the most caudal 
      structure to receive significant projections from 
      <connxOrigin>the PMv</connxOrigin>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s119">Crossed projections</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">In general, the contralateral projection is a mirror 
      image of the ipsilateral projection, but much less dense.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121">In <labelingLocation>the forebrain</labelingLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> appear 
      to cross the midline through <labelingLocation>the supraoptic 
      commissures and the supramammillary 
      decussation</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">It is important to point out here that the latter 
      fibers, in addition to other contralateral targets, provide 
      <labelingLocation>a moderate projection</labelingLocation> to 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral PMv</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">Curiously, the density of contralateral labeled fibers 
    is relatively greater in <labelingLocation>the midbrain and 
    pons</labelingLocation> than in <labelingLocation>the 
    forebrain</labelingLocation>.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s124">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">The major conclusion that can be drawn from the 
    experiments reported here is that the PMv supplies a dense input to 
    the medial and periventricular zones of the hypothalamus, to the 
    septal region, and to the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">In view of the advantages of the PHAL method referred to 
    in the Introduction, and the fact that there is little disagreement 
    as to the location and boundaries of the PMv, our description of 
    its projections would appear to be rather reliable.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">Nevertheless, our results are limited in a number of 
    ways, since, for example, they do not address the issue of whether 
    the projections of the PMv arise from a homogeneous population of 
    cells or whether they arise from multiple cell types, and they do 
    not address the issue of neurotransmitter specificity.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s128">Projections of the 
    PMv</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">Because the projections of the PMv itself have never 
    been examined with anterograde tracing methods, our discussion of 
    the literature must rely primarily on earlier retrograde tracer 
    studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">Our results indicate that the great majority of fibers 
    from the PMv take a rostral course, through both the 
    periventricular and medial zones of the hypothalamus, whereas much 
    smaller groups of axons ascend through the medial forebrain bundle, 
    or descend through caudal parts of the hypothalamus and central 
    gray.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">The medialmost projections from the PMv ascend through 
    the periventricular zone of the hypothalamus, which is densely 
    innervated throughout, except for the suprachiasmatic, 
    suprachiasmatic preoptic, and median preoptic nuclei, where 
    virtually no labeled fibers were observed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">Inputs to the paraventricular nucleus from the PMv have 
    been identified previously with retrograde tracers (Sawchenko and 
    Swanson, &apos;831, and Luiten et al. (&apos;87) reported such a 
    projection with the PHAL, method, although the terminal field they 
    described differs substantially from our observations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">They illustrate (their Fig. 12; Luiten et al., &apos;87) 
    a moderate terminal field centered in the medial parvicellular part 
    of the paraventricular nucleus after an injection site that appears 
    to involve the rostral tip of the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">All of our experiments that involved the PMv, including 
    the region illustrated for their injection site, labeled a massive 
    terminal field in the periventricular zone of the paraventricular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">The reason for this discrepancy is not apparent.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">Fibers from the PMv that ascend through the medial zone 
    of the hypothalamus give rise to a particularly dense projection to 
    the ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus and surrounding 
    parts of the basal lateral hypothalamic area, as well as to the 
    medial preoptic nucleus, as suggested by earlier retrograde tracer 
    studies (Kita and Oomura, &apos;82; Chiba and Murata, &apos;85; 
    Simerly and Swanson, &apos;86; Fahrbach et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">A somewhat weaker projection was found to the 
    dorsomedial nucleus, and to the cell-poor region surrounding the 
    dorsomedial subdivision of the ventromedial nucleus; the PMv does 
    not appear to provide a substantial input to the cellular 
    &quot;core&quot; regions of the dorsomedial and central parts of 
    the ventromedial nucleus, or to cell groups in the anterior 
    hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">A projection from the PMv to the dorsomedial nucleus was 
    reported by Kita and Oomura (&apos;82) using retrograde tracer 
    methods.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">Previous retrograde and anterograde studies suggested 
    that a projection from the PMv travels through the medial forebrain 
    bundle (Shiosaka et al., &apos;80; Veening et al., &apos;821, and 
    here we were able to confirm that a small number of such fibers 
    course through the dorsal half of the medial forebrain bundle, 
    where they give rise to very few terminal boutons and have the 
    appearance of fibers-of-passage.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">These axons seem to provide a sparse input to rostral 
    parts of the zona incerta and the ventral part of the nucleus 
    reuniens, while at more rostral levels the remaining fibers enter 
    the posterior subdivision of the BST and the substantia 
    innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">The nucleus reuniens also seems to receive an input from 
    fibers ascending from the injection site through the medial and 
    periventricular zones of the hypothalamus, fibers that also provide 
    a rather substantial input to the paraventricular nucleus of the 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">Evidence for a projection from the PMv to these thalamic 
    nuclei was also reported in earlier retrograde tracer studies 
    (Herkenham, &apos;78; Cornwall and Phillipson, &apos;88; Chen and A 
    large group of fibers from the PMv ascending mainly through the 
    medial zone of the hypothalamus ultimately ends in the BST, lateral 
    septal nucleus, and amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">Within the BST, axons from the PMv give rise to a 
    particularly dense terminal field in the principal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Weller and Smith (&apos;82) reported the presence of 
    retrogradely labeled cells in the premammillary region after 
    injections of horseradish peroxidase (HRP) in the BST, although 
    they did not state that these cells were within the PMv itself.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Inputs to the lateral septal nucleus were also suggested 
    in previous retrograde tracer studies (Luiten et al., &apos;82; 
    Staiger and Nurnberger, &apos;891, and have been confirmed more 
    directly here; we observed a particularly dense projection to the 
    caudal two-thirds of the ventral part, and adjacent regions of the 
    intermediate part, of this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">A few axons from the PMv continue through the rostral 
    pole of the lateral septal nucleus to end in the infralimbic and 
    prelimbic areas of the medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">The majority of fibers from the PMv that project to the 
    amygdala travel through the stria terminalis, whereas only a few 
    course through the ansa peduncularis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Within the amygdala, these fibers provide a massive 
    input to the posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus, to the 
    posterior nucleus, and to immediately adjacent regions of the 
    posterior cortical nucleus, as well as a sparser input to other 
    parts of the amygdala, including the medial and capsular parts of 
    the central nucleus, and the anterodorsal part of the medial 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">Tracer injections centered in (but not necessarily 
    restricted to) each of the above-mentioned parts of the amygdala 
    retrogradely label cells in the vicinity of the PMv (Veening, 
    &apos;78; Ottersen, &apos;80; Russchen, &apos;82; Luiten et al., 
    &apos;85; Volz et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">Furthermore, recent observations using fluorogold as a 
    retrograde tracer indicate that the PMv is by far the main source 
    of projections to the posterior nucleus of the amygdala (Canteras 
    et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Finally, ascending fibers from the PMv also end in 
    limited parts of the cortex adjacent to the amygdala, particularly 
    in the ventral tip of the subiculum and adjacent parts of 
    hippocampal field CAI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Descending projections from the PMv give rise to a 
    substantial input to ventral regions of the posterior hypothalamic 
    nucleus and a few axons continue on to the mammillary complex and 
    to the midbrain periventricular system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Within the mammillary complex, the PMv appears to 
    innervate the supramammillary nucleus and the cell-poor zone 
    surrounding the medial mammillary nucleus, with a very few fibers 
    continuing even farther to end in the interfascicular and 
    interpeduncular nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">A sparse projection from the PMv to the interpeduncular 
    nucleus was suggested by Contestabile and Flumerfelt (&apos;81) 
    using HRP as a retrograde tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">The fibers coursing through the midbrain periventricular 
    system form a distinct terminal field in ventrolateral regions of 
    the periaqueductal gray.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">At this level, a somewhat weaker input was also found to 
    the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus and the dorsal nucleus of the 
    raphe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">In agreement with our observations, injections of 
    retrograde tracers in the periaqueductal gray (Morrell et al., 
    &apos;811, and in the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus (Satoh and 
    Fibiger, &apos;861, labeled only a few cells within the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">At pontine levels, we observed a small number of fibers 
    coursing caudally, near the wall of the fourth ventricle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">These axons provide a distinctive innervation to a 
    region just rostral to the locus coeruleus that is thought to 
    correspond to Barrington&apos;s nucleus, as discussed further 
    below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">Finally, occasional PHAL-labeled fibers were observed 
    within the boundaries of the locus coeruleus, which appears to be 
    the caudalmost target of efferents from the PMv.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">It may be of interest at this point to summarize what 
    little is known about possible neurotransmitters utilized by the 
    pathways just described.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">Previous immunohistochemical studies have provided some 
    information about neuropeptides that may be synthesized by neurons 
    of the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">Thus, it has been shown that at least some PMv neurons 
    may express met-enkephalin (Wamsley et al., &apos;80; Abe et al., 
    &apos;871, substance P (Tsuruo et al., &apos;84; Akesson and 
    Micevych, &apos;881, atrial natriuretic peptide (Jacobowitz et al., 
    &apos;85; Standaert et al., &apos;86; Bidmon et al., &apos;go), and 
    galanin (Skofitsch and Jacobowitz, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Clearly, a great deal remains to be learned about 
    neurotransmission in the terminal fields established by the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">In addition to these peptides, other neurotransmitters 
    are likely to be utilized by neurons located within the PMv, 
    although further studies are needed to clarify this issue.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s166">Comparison between 
    projections of the PMv and adjacent nuclei in the medial 
    hypothalamus As mentioned in the Introduction, the PMv lies in 
    the</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">medial zone of the hypothalamus, just caudal to the 
    ventromedial nucleus, and at more caudal levels it lies just 
    ventral to the dorsal premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">There are two major reasons for comparing what we now 
    know about the projections from these three regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">First, since all of our PHAL injection sites labeled at 
    least a few neurons outside the limits of the PMv, it is important 
    to consider the pattern of efferents from adjacent cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Second, it is clearly important to determine whether the 
    PMv plays a unique role in circuits associated with the caudal 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">The following comparisons are based on the work of Saper 
    et al. (&apos;76), Krieger et al. (&apos;791, and our own 
    unpublished observations (with the PHAL method) for the 
    ventromedial nucleus, and our paper on the dorsal premammillary 
    nucleus (Canteras and Swanson, &apos;92b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">To begin with, in contrast to the PMv, the ventromedial 
    nucleus provides a massive input to the anterior hypothalamic 
    nucleus, but a much less dense projection to nuclei within the 
    periventricular zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">In addition, we have observed in our PHAL experiments 
    that the projection from the ventromedial nucleus to the preoptic 
    region, which arises chiefly from cell bodies in the ventrolateral 
    subdivision (see Simerly and Swanson, &apos;86), is mainly directed 
    toward the lateral subdivision of the medial preoptic nucleus, in 
    contrast to the medial part of this nucleus, which receives a very 
    small input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">It will be recalled that the PMv projects densely to 
    both the medial and lateral parts of the medial preoptic nucleus, 
    with slightly more fibers in the medial part.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Similarly, the PMv provides a strong input to the 
    anteroventral periventricular nucleus, whereas only a few labeled 
    fibers are found in this structure following injections of PHAL 
    centered in the ventromedial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">Like the PMv, a group of fibers from the ventromedial 
    nucleus gives rise to a dense terminal field in the BST that tends 
    to avoid the principal nucleus, unlike inputs from the PMv that end 
    heavily within the principal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Furthermore, cells in the ventromedial nucleus project 
    less densely to the septum, where inputs tend to be more uniformly 
    distributed in the ventral and intermediate parts of the lateral 
    septal nucleus, than is the case for inputs from the PMv.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">There are remarkable differences between the projections 
    of the ventromedial nucleus and the PMv to the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Thus, fibers arising in the ventromedial nucleus project 
    to the amygdala by way of the ansa peduncularis and end primarily 
    in the central nucleus and in the lateral nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">In contrast, most projections from the PMv to the 
    amygdala course through the stria terminalis and end primarily in 
    the posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus and in the posterior 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Finally, the descending projections from the 
    ventromedial nucleus to the brainstem appear to be more extensive 
    than those from the PMv and give rise to particularly dense inputs 
    to the central gray and the peripenduncular nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Our recent findings on the projections of the dorsal 
    premammillary nucleus (PMd) using the PHAL, method clearly indicate 
    that the overall pattern of efferents arising from this nucleus is 
    quite distinct from that of the PMv and the ventromedial nucleus 
    (Canteras and Swanson, &apos;92b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Thus, the PMd gives rise to a characteristic projection 
    to the ventral part of the anteromedial nucleus of the thalamus, as 
    well as dense projections to the anterior hypothalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">In contrast to the PMv, only a few axons from the PMd 
    innervate the periventricular zone of the hypothalamus, the medial 
    preoptic area, the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis, the septum, 
    and the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Finally, the PMd innervates rather densely a 
    characteristic dorsolatera1 zone of the periaqueductal gray.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s186">Inputs to the PMv</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Since we have characterized the distribution of 
    projections from the PMv, and compared the pattern of projections 
    from this nucleus with those arising from surrounding regions in 
    the medial zone of the hypothalamus, it is now appropriate to 
    review what is known about the afferent control of the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">As mentioned in the Introduction, the PMv is thought to 
    receive dense inputs from the medial nucleus of the amygdala 
    (especially its posterodorsal part), the posterior nucleus and 
    adjacent deep regions of the posterior cortical nucleus of the 
    amygdala, the principal nucleus of the BST, and the medial preoptic 
    nucleus (particularly from the central part and adjacent regions of 
    the medial part) (Krettek and Price, &apos;78; Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;79; Post and Mai, &apos;80; Kevetter and Winnans, &apos;81; 
    Luiten et al., &apos;85; Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88; Canteras et 
    al., &apos;92; N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Swanson, unpublished observations; see Materials and 
    Methods).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Perhaps the most obvious features common to all of the 
    sources of afferents to the PMv just listed is that they are in a 
    position to relay information from the vomeronasal organ (for 
    references see Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Other classes of sensory information may well reach the 
    PMv by way of the ventral subiculum and ventral part of the lateral 
    septal nucleus (see Swanson et al., &apos;871, where we found 
    labeled cells after fluorogold deposits in the region of the PMv, 
    although only the projection from the ventral subiculum has been 
    reported with anterograde tracing methods (Swanson and Cowan, 
    &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78; Canteras and Swanson, &apos;92a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">The PMv may also receive relatively sparse inputs from 
    the infralimbic area (Brittain, &apos;88; Hurley et al., &apos;91), 
    the posterior part of the basomedial nucleus of the amygdala 
    (Krettek and Price, &apos;78), and the ventromedial nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus (N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Finally, our fluorogold experiments revealed at least a 
    few labeled cells in other areas of the forebrain and brainstem for 
    which anterograde tracing data are not available, including area 
    TR, the arcuate nucleus of the hypothalamus, the periaqueductal 
    gray, the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus, the dorsal nucleus of the 
    raphe, the nucleus incertus, and the locus coeruleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Recently, it has been suggested (Perez-Clause11 et al., 
    &apos;89) that the massive projection from posterior nucleus of the 
    amygdala to the PMv contains high levels of zinc, which are 
    presumably associated with pools of excitatory amino acid 
    neurotransmitters (Frederickson and Danscher, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">In addition, the PMv receives a substantial number of 
    fibers that cross-react with antisera to met-enkephalin (Abe et 
    al., &apos;87), atrial natriuretic peptide (Standaert et al., 
    &apos;861, and neuropeptide Y (DeQuidt et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The distribution of neuropeptide Y-immunoreactive axons 
    is commonly rather similar to that of fibers stained with antisera 
    to tyrosine hydroxylase and dopamine-P-hydroxylase (see Sawchenko 
    et al., &apos;85; Simerly et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">This does not seem to be the case in the region of the 
    PMv, however, where very few axons containing these 
    catecholamine-synthesizing enzymes have been identified (Swanson 
    and Hartman, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">The PMv also appears to receive sparse serotonergic and 
    cholinergic inputs (Steinbusch, &apos;81; Rao et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Further studies that combine retrograde tracing with 
    immunohistochemistry are needed to determine the location of cell 
    bodies that give rise to each of these neurochemically defined 
    inputs to the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">For the sake of completeness, it should be noted that 
    high concentrations of NK3 receptors, which apparently bind 
    specifically neurokinin B (NKB), have been reported in the PMv 
    (Mussap and Burcher, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">However, a precise &quot;matching&quot; of NK3 binding 
    sites to NKB-immunoreactive terminals, as well as the location of 
    cell bodies that synthesize this peptide, is not possible at this 
    time due to the absence of specific NKB antibodies (see Mussap and 
    Burcher, &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">In addition to these neural inputs, the PMv may be 
    influenced directly by fluctuating levels of gonadal steroid 
    hormones, since it contains a very high density of neurons that 
    concentrate estrogen, progesterone, and testosterone (Pfaff and 
    Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;75a,b; Stumpf et al., 
    &apos;751, and mRNAs encoding the androgen and estrogen receptors 
    are expressed at relatively high levels in the PMv (Simerly et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">In general, there appears to be a considerable degree of 
    overlap between the cells that concentrate each of these gonadal 
    steroids, although the extent to which individual neurons express 
    more than one steroid hormone receptor is unclear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Michael et al. (&apos;89) have suggested that, in male 
    macaques, most of the testosterone that is taken up by neurons in 
    the PMv is not converted to estradiol, whereas in the rat, only a 
    small population of neurons within the PMv does not seem to 
    aromatize androgen to estrogen (Sheridan, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Considering the evidence that these hormones may 
    regulate cellular levels of neuropeptides (for references see 
    Simerly et al., &apos;901, it will be of interest to characterize 
    the neurotransmitterspecificity of the PMv neurons that expresses 
    androgen andlor estrogen receptors, and to determine whether 
    gonadal steroids influence their rate of synthesis.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">It is also important to point out that the strongest 
    projections from the PMv end in nuclei that also contain high 
    densities of gonadal steroid-concentrating neurons (PfafF and 
    Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;75a,b; Stumpf et al., 
    &apos;751, express mRNAs encoding the androgen and/or estrogen 
    receptors (Simerly et al., &apos;901, and display structural sexual 
    dimorphisms (see for references see Simerly and Swanson, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Furthermore, almost all these regions innervate densely 
    the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">These remarkable hodological relationships between the 
    PMv and the sexually dimorphic cell groups suggests that the PMv 
    plays an important role in the function of this neuronal 
    network.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">In addition, it has been shown that the PMv itself may 
    be sexually dimorphic with respect to the number of 
    tachykinin-immunoreactive cells, which are more numerous in males 
    (Akesson and Micevych, &apos;91).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">We have not in the present study examined the 
    projections of the PMv in female animals.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">However, the results of previous anatomical studies in 
    the medial preoptic nucleus and elsewhere suggests that the 
    sexually dimorphic circuit is qualitatively similar in both sexes, 
    while presenting quantitative differences within particular 
    terminal fields (see Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s217">Functional 
    implications</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">At the most basic level, the PMv appears to integrate 
    neuronal influences from other forebrain regions, particularly 
    those related to the sexually dimorphic circuit, receiving but 
    sparse direct inputs from other centers in the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Remarkably, with the exception of the ventral subiculum 
    and adjacent parts of hippocampal field CAI (and the central part 
    of the medial preoptic nucleus), the main sources of projections to 
    the PMv in turn receive a massive input from the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">In addition, the PMv provides massive unidirectional 
    projections to most parts of the periventricular zone of the 
    hypothalamus, which is known to be the major central regulator of 
    anterior pituitary function.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">In short, the PMv establishes massive bidirectional 
    connections with the sexually dimorphic circuit, and projects 
    massively to the neuroendocrine zone of the hypothalamus, in 
    addition to expressing high levels of gonadal steroid hormone 
    receptors (see Fig. 5).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Electrolytic lesions in the region of the PMv reportedly 
    induce a premature onset of the proestrous surge of luteinizing 
    hormone (LH), while electrochemical stimulation applied to the 
    nucleus at noon on the day of proestrus prevented ovulation and the 
    preovulatory surge of LH (Beltramino and Taleisnik, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">The PMv has also been implicated in the regulation of LH 
    secretion by pheromonal stimuli (Beltramino and Taleisnik, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Our results indicate that the PMv may not provide a 
    substantial direct input to neurons that express 
    gonadotropin-releasing hormone (Barry, &apos;79; King et al., 
    &apos;821, although it may indirectly influence the secretion of LH 
    or follicle-stimulating hormone by way of its massive inputs to the 
    anteroventral periventricular nucleus of the preoptic region and 
    the arcuate nucleus, which are thought to be involved in the 
    regulation of these hormones (Wiegand and Terasawa, &apos;82; Kalra 
    and Kalra, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Our results also suggest that the PMv may influence the 
    secretion of prolactin and growth hormone as well, through its 
    dense projections to the arcuate nucleus, where the majority of 
    neurosecretory cells containing dopamine (see Bjorklund and 
    Lindvall, &apos;84) and growth hormone-releasing hormone (Sawchenko 
    and Swanson, &apos;90) are found.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Furthermore, the PMv projects massively to the 
    periventricular region (the anterior periventricular nucleus) that 
    contains the majority of neurosecretory somatostatin cells (see 
    Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Other parvicellular neurosecretory regions of the 
    periventricular zone of the hypothalamus appear to be considerably 
    less densely innervated and very few axons from the PMv are 
    associated with magnocellular neurosecretory neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Marked hypothermic responses have been reported after 
    the injection of low concentrations of 2-deoxy-d-glucose (2-DG) 
    into the region of the PMv, and it has been suggested that this 
    effect is related in some way to vagal stimulation and subsequent 
    lowering of peripheral heat production (Shiraishi and Mager, 
    &apos;80a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">The PMv does not appear to provide direct inputs to 
    preganglionic autonomic neurons, but does project to cell groups 
    that are known to project in turn to both sympathetic and 
    parasympathetic preganglionic cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Thus, the PMv provides direct inputs to the posterior 
    hypothalamic nucleus and the retrochiasmatic area, as well as to 
    the tuberal zone of the hypothalamus, all of which contain at least 
    a few neurons that project to the dorsal vagal complex and/or the 
    spinal cord, presumably to the intermediolateral cell column; 
    however, it is not clear where in the spinal cord most of these 
    hypothalamic neurons end, and the density of cells that project to 
    lower autonomic centers in these hypothalamic regions is quite low 
    (see Swanson, &apos;87, for review).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The dorsal parvicellular part of the paraventricular 
    nucleus, which projects preferentially to preganglionic sympathetic 
    neurons in the spinal cord, as well as the ventral medial 
    parvicellular part of the nucleus, which projects more or less 
    equally to the dorsal vagal complex and to the spinal cord (see 
    Swanson and Sawchenko, &apos;831, also receives a sparse projection 
    from the PMv.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">In addition, the PMv sends rather substantial 
    projections to lateral regions of the BST and also less dense 
    inputs to the medial part of the central nucleus of the amygdala, 
    both of which are known to provide direct, massive inputs to the 
    dorsal vagal complex (Sofroniew, &apos;83; Holstege et al., 
    &apos;85; see Price et al., &apos;87 for reviews).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">A final way that the PMv may influence parasympathetic 
    outflow is via a direct projection to Barrington&apos;s nucleus, 
    which provides a direct input to the region of sacral 
    parasympathetic preganglionic neurons (Loewy et al., &apos;791, and 
    appears to correspond to the &quot;micturition reflex center&quot; 
    in the dorsolateral pontine tegmentum that was described by 
    Barrington (see Satoh et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">It is important to point out here that, apart from all 
    of these regions that may provide direct inputs to autonomic cell 
    groups, the PMv gives rise to a very dense projection to the medial 
    preoptic nucleus, which is thought to provide an important 
    influence on a variety of responses that involve the autonomic 
    nervous system (see Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88 for review).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">It has also been suggested that the PMv plays a role in 
    central mechanisms that underlie aggressive behavior, in view of 
    the fact that small bilateral electrolytic lesions in the region of 
    this nucleus led to marked increases in attack behavior (van den 
    Berg et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Perhaps this result should not be surprising in view of 
    strong bidirectional connections between the PMv and several 
    regions thought to be involved in the control of antagonistic 
    behavior, including the medial nucleus of the amygdala, the bed 
    nuclei of the stria terminalis, the lateral septa1 nucleus, and the 
    medial preoptic nucleus (see Luiten et al., &apos;85; Swanson, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Considering the possible involvement of the PMv in the 
    expression of aggressive behavior, it is important to recall that 
    thresholds for the activation of this type of behavior are 
    modulated by circulating levels of gonadal steroid hormones (see 
    Floody and Pfaff, &apos;74).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Finally, the anatomical results presented here strongly 
    imply that the PMv is involved in at least some aspects of 
    reproductive physiology and behavior, although clearly, further 
    work is needed to explore this possibility.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s239">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s240">We thank Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s241">David Warren for document 
    preparation, and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s242">Kris Trulock for photographic 
    assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s243">This work was supported in 
    part by CNPq Fellowship 2009691 90-0, FAF&apos;ESP Fellowship 
    88/1289-0 to N.S.C., and NINDS 2ROlNS16686 to L.W.S.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s244">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Abe, J., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Okamura, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Makino, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Yanaihara, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Ibata (1987) Immunocytochemical distribution of 
    [Metlenkephalin-Arg-Gly-Leu immunoreactivity in the rat 
    diencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Bull. 19:735-741.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Akesson, T.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Micevych (1988) Estrogen concentration by substance 
    P-immunoreactive neurons in the medial basal hypothalamus of the 
    female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Res. 19:412419.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Akesson, T.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Micevych (1991) Tachykinin immunoreactive cells in the 
    rat ventral premammillary nucleus: Sex differences, castration 
    effects, and gonadal steroid binding.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Abstr. 17:418.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Barry, J. (1979) Immunohistochemistry of luteinizing 
    hormone-releasing hormone-producing neurons of the vertebrates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Int.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Cytol. 60t179220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Beltramino, C., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Taleisnik (1984) Inhibitory influence of the nuclei of 
    the posterior hypothalamus on the pro-oestrus surge of LH.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Acta Endocrinol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">(Copenh.) 105:433440.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Beltramino, C., and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Taleisnik (1985) Ventral premammillary nuclei mediate 
    pheromonal-induced LH release stimuli in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Neuroendocrinology 41:119-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Bidmon, H.J., W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Stumpf, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Kawamata, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Shirasu, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Gutkowska,andM.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Sar (1990) Colocalization of atrial natriuretic factor 
    (ANF) and estradiol in hypothalamic neurons by combined 
    autoradiography-immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Histochemistry 94:505-508.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Bjorklund, A,, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Lindvall (1984) Dopamine-containing systems in the 
    CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Bjorklund and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    2, Classical Transmitters in the CNS, Part I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 55-122.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Brittain, D.A. (1988) The Efferent Connections of the 
    Infralimbic Cortex in the Rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Doctoral dissertation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">University of California, San Diego.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Canteras, N.S., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Swanson (1992a) Projections of the ventral subiculum to 
    the amygdala, septum, and hypothalamus: A PHAL anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Neurol. 324:180194.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Canteras, N.S., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Swanson (1992b) The dorsal premammillary nucleus: A 
    novel component of the mammillary nuclei. in preparation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Swanson (1990) The efferent connections of the ventral 
    premamrnillary nucleus: A Phaseolus uulguris leucoagglutinin 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Abstr.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">16~576.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Swanson (1992) The projections of the posterior nucleus 
    of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Neurol. 324: 143-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Chen, S., and H.3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Su (1990) Afferent connections of the thalamic 
    paraventricular and parataenial nuclei in the rat-a retrograde 
    tracing study with iontophoretic application of Fluoro-Gold.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Brain Res. 522:l-6.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Chiba, T., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Murata (1985) Afferent and efferent connections of the 
    medial preoptic area in the rat: A WGA-HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Bull.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">14:261-272.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Contestabile, A,, and B.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Flumerfelt (1981) Afferent connections of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus and the topographic organization of the 
    habenulo-interpeduncular pathway: An HRP study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">196:253-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Cornwall, J., and O.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Phillipson (1988) Afferent projections to the dorsal 
    thalamus of the rat as shown by retrograde lectin transport. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">The midline nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Bull. 21:147-161.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Quidt, M.E., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Kiyama, and P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Emson (1990) Pancreatic polypeptide, neuropeptide Y and 
    peptide YY in central neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 9, 
    Neuropeptides in the CNS, Part 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 287-357.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Fahrbach, S.E., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Morrell, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Pfaff (1989) Studies of ventromedial hypothalamic 
    afferents in the rat using three methods of HRP application.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Brain Res. 77:221-233.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Floody, D.R., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Pfaff (1974) Steroid hormones and aggressive behavior: 
    Approaches to the study of hormone-sensitive brain mechanisms for 
    behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Assoc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Nervous Mental Dis. 52149-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Frederickson, C.J., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Danscher (1990) Zinc-containing neurons in hippocampus 
    and related CNS structures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Brain Res. 83:71-84.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phuseolus uulguris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Gurdjian, E.S. (1927) The diencephalon of the albino 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">brain of the rat, No. 2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Neurol. 4311-114.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Haug, F.M.S. (1976) Sulphide silver pattern and 
    cytoarchitectonics of parahippocampal areas in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Special reference to the subdivision of area 
    entorhinalis (area 28) and its demarcation from the pyriform 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Cell Biol. 521-73.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Herkenham, M. (1978) The connections of the nucleus 
    reuniens thalami: Evidence for a direct thalamo-hippocampal pathway 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Neurol. 177:589-610.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Holstege, G., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Meiners, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Tan (1985) Projections of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis to the mesencephalon, pons, and medulla oblongata in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Brain Res. 58:379-391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Hsu, S.M., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Raine (1981) Protein A, avidin and biotin in 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Cytochem. 29: 1349-1353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Hsu, S.M., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Raine, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Fanger (1981) The use of avidin-biotinperoxidase complex 
    (ABC) in immunoperoxidase techniques: A comparison between ABC and 
    unlabeled antibody (PAP) procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Cytochem. 29:577-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Hurley, K.M., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Herbert, M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Moga, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Saper (1991) Efferent the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">projections of the infralimbic cortex of 308:249-276.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Jacobowitz, D.M., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Skofitsch, H.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Keiser, R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Eskay, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Zamir (1985) Evidence for the existence of atrial 
    natriuretic factor-containing neurons in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Neuroendocrinology 4Ot92-94.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">G., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Swanson (1989) Studies on the cellular architecture of 
    the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis in the rat: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Neurol. 280t587-602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Kalra, S.P., and P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Kalra (1983) Neural regulation of luteinizing hormone 
    secretion in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Endocrinol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Rev. 4:311-351.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Kevetter, G.A., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Winans (1981) Connections of the corticomedial amygdala 
    in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Efferents of the vomeronasal amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Neurol. 197t81-98.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">King, J.C., S.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Tobet, F.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Snavely, and A.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Arimura (1982) LHRH immunopositive cells and their 
    projections to the median eminence and organum vasculosum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Neurol. 209:287-300.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Kita, H., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Oomura (1982) An HRP study of the afferent connections 
    to rat medial hypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Bull. 8:53-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Price (1978) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">I78:225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Krieger, M.S., L.C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Conrad, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Pfaff (1979) An autoradiographic study of the efferent 
    connections of the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Neurol. 183t785-816.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Loewy, A.D., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Saper, and R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Baker (1979) Descendingprojections the pontine 
    micturition center.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Brain Res. 172533-538.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Luiten, P.G.M., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Kuipers, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Schuitmaker (1982) Organization of diencephalic and 
    brainstem afferent projections to the lateral septum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Lett. 30:211-216.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Luiten, P.G.M., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Koolhaas, S. de Boer, and S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Koopmans (1985) The corticomedial amygdala in the 
    central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Organization of agonistic behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Brain Res. 332283-297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Luiten, P.G.M., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Ter Horst, and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Steffens (19871 The hypothalamus, intrinsic connections 
    and outflow pathways to the endocrine system in relation to the 
    control of feeding and metabolism.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Neurobiol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">28:l-54.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Siege1 (1977) Efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Brain Res. 124t197-224.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Michael, R.P., H.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Rees, and R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Bonsall(1989) Sites in the male primate brain at which 
    testosterone acts as an androgen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Brain Res. 50211-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Morrell, J.I., L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Greenberger, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Pfaff (1981) Hypothalamic, other diencephalic, and 
    telencephalic neurons that project to the dorsal midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Neurol. 201t589-620.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Mussap, C.J., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Burcher (1990) [12511-Bolton-Hunter Scyliorhinin 11: A 
    novel, selective radioligand for the tachykinin NK3 receptor in rat 
    brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Peptides 11:827-836.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Ottersen, O.P. (1980) Afferent connections of the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat and cat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Afferents from the hypothalamus and the basal 
    telencephdon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Neurol. 194:267-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Perez-Clausell, J., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Frederickson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Danscher (1989) Amygdaloid efferents through the stria 
    terminalis in the rat gives origin to zinccontaining boutons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Neurol. 290:201-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Pfaff, D.W., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Keiner (1973) Atlas of estradiol-concentrating cells in 
    the central nervous system of the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">I51t121-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Post, S., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Mai (1980) Contribution to the amygdaloid projection 
    field in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">A quantitative autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Hirnforsch. 21: 199225.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Price, J.L., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Russchen, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Amaral (1987) The limbic region. 11: The amygdaloid 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 279-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Rao, Z.R., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Yamano, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Wanaka, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Tatehata, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Shiosaka, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Tohyama (1987) Distribution of cholinergic neurons and 
    fibers in the hypothalamus of the rat using choline 
    acetyltransferase as a marker.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Neuroscience 20t923-934.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Russchen, F.T. (1982) Amygdalopetal projections in the 
    cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Subcortical afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">A study with retrograde tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Neurol. 207t157-176.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Swanson, W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Cowan (1976) The efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Neurol. 169t409442.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Sar, M., and W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Stumpf (1975a) Distribution of androgen-concentrating 
    neurons in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">In W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Grant (eds): Anatomical Neuroendocrinology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Basel: Karger, pp. 120-133.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Sar, M., and W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Stumpf (197513) Cellular localization of progestin and 
    estrogen in guinea pig hypothalamus by autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">In W.E.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Grant Karger, pp. 142-155.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Satoh, K., and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Fibiger (1986) Cholinergic neurons of the laterodorsal 
    tegmental nucleus: Efferent and afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">253t277-302.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Satoh, K., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Shimizu, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Tohyama, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Maeda (1978) Localization of the micturition reflex 
    center at the dorsolateral pontine tegmentum of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Lett. 8:27-33.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Sawchenko, P.E., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Swanson (1983) The organization of forebrain afferents 
    to the paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Neurol. 218:121-144.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Sawchenko, P.E., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Swanson (1990) Growth hormone releasing hormone.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 9, 
    Neuropeptides in the CNS, Part 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 131-163.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Sawchenko, P.E., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Swanson, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Grzanna, P.R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Howe, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Polak, and S.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Bloom (1985) Co-localization of neuropeptide 
    Y-immunoreactivity in brainstem catecholaminergic neurons that 
    project to the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Neurol. 241t138-153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Schmued, L.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Fallon (1986) Fluoro-Gold: A new fluorescent retrograde 
    axonal tracer with numerous unique properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">377:147-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Sheridan, P.J. (1979) The nucleus interstitialis striae 
    terminalis and the nucleus amygdaloideus medialis: Prime targets 
    for androgen in the rat forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Endocrinology 104:130-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Shiosaka, S., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Tohyama, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Takagi, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Takahashi, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Saitoh, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Sakumoto, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Nakagawa, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Shimizu (1980) Ascending and descending components of 
    the medial forebrain bundle in the rat as demonstrated by the 
    horseradish peroxidase-blue reaction.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Forebrain and upper brain stem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Brain Res. 39t377-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Shiraishi, T., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Mager (1980a) Hypothermia following injection of 
    2-deoxy-D-glucose into selected hypothalamic sites.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Physiol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s592">239:R265-R269.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Shiraishi, T., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Mager (1980b) 2-Deoxy-D-glucose-induced hypothermia: 
    Thermoregulatory pathways in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Physiol. 239tR270R276.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Swanson (1986) The organization of neural inputs to the 
    medial preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Neurol. 246:312-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Swanson (1988) Projections of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus: A Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Neurol. 270:209-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Simerly, R.B., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Gorski, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Swanson (1986) Neurotransmitter specificity of cells and 
    fibers in the medial preoptic nucleus: An immunohistochemical study 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Neurol. 246:343-363.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Simerly, R.B., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Chang, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Muramatsu, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Swanson (1990) Distribution of androgen and estrogen 
    receptor mRNA-containing cells in the rat brain: An in situ 
    hybridization study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Neurol. 294t7E-95.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Skofitsch, G., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Jacobowitz (1985) Immunohistochemical mapping of 
    galanin-like neurons in the rat central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Peptides 6t509546.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Sofroniew, M.V. (1983) Direct reciprocal connections 
    between the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and dorsomedial 
    medulla oblongata: Evidence from immunohistochemical detection of 
    tracer proteins.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Neurol. 213:399-405.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Staiger, J.F., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">Nurnberger (1989) Pattern of afferents septum in the 
    guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Cell Tissue Res. 275t471-490.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Standaert, D.G., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Needleman, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Saper (1986) Organization of atriopeptin-like 
    immunoreactive neurons in the central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Neurol. 253:315-341.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Steinbusch, H.W.M. (1981) Distribution of serotonin 
    immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Cell bodies and terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Neuroscience 4t557-618.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Stumpf, W.E., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Sar, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Keefer (1975) Atlas of estrogen target cells in rat 
    brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">In W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Grant (edsj: Anatomical Neuroendocrinology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Basel: Karger, pp. 104-119.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Swanson, L.W. (1992) Brain maps: Structure Elsevier, in 
    press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Swanson, L.W. (1987) The hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 1-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Swanson, L.W., and B.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Hartman (1975) The central adrenergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">An Immunofluorescence study of the location of cell 
    bodies and their efferent connections in the rat utilizing 
    dopamine-P-hydroxylase as a marker.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Neurol. 163:467-506.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Cowan (1977) An autoradiographic organization of the 
    efferent connections of the hippocampal formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Neurol. 17249-84.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Cowan (1979) The connections of the septa1 region in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Neurol. 186:621-656.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Swanson, L.W., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Sawchenko (1983) Hypothalamic integration: Organization 
    of the paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Annu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Neurosci. 6,275-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Swanson, L.W., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Simmons (1989) Differential steroid hormone and neural 
    influences on peptide mRNA levels in CRH cells of the 
    paraventricular nucleus: A hybridization histochemical study in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Neurol. 285t413-435.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Swanson, L.W., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Kohler, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Bjorklund (1987) The limbic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">I: The septohippocampal system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 125-277.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Tsuruo, Y., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Hisano, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Okamura, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Tsukamoto, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Daikoku (1984) Hypothalamic substance P-containing 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Sex-dependent topographical differences and 
    ultrastructural transformations associated with stages of the 
    estrous cycle.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Brain Res. 305331-341.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Van den Berg, M.J., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Ter Horst, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Koolhaas (1983) The nucleus premammillaris ventralis 
    (PMV) and aggressive behavior in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Aggress.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Behav. 9t41-47.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Veening, J.G. (1978) Subcortical afferents to the 
    amygdaloid complex in the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Lett. 8t197-202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Veening, J.G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Swanson, W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Cowan, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Nieuwenhuys, and L.M.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Geeraedts (1982) The medial forebrain bundle of the rat. 
    11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">An autoradiographic study of the topography of the major 
    descending and ascending components.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Neurol. 206t82-108.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Volz, H.P., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Rehbein, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Triepel, M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Knuepfer, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Stumpf, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Stock (1990) Merent connections of the nucleus centralis 
    amygdalae.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">A horseradish peroxidase study and literature survey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Embryol. 18lt177-194.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Wamsley, J.K., W.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Young 111, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Kuhar (1980) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    enkephalin in rat forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Brain Res. 190:153-174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Weller, K.L., and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Smith (1982) Afferent connections to the bed nucleus of 
    the stria terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Brain Res. 232:255-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Wiegand, S.J., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Terasawa (1982) Discrete lesions reveal functional 
    heterogeneity of suprachiasmatic structures in regulation of 
    gonadotropin secretion in the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Neuroendocrinology 34t395-404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Wouterlood, F.G., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Groenewegen (1985) Neuroanatomical tracing by use of 
    Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) electron microscopy of 
    PHA-L filled neuronal somata, dendrites, axons, and axon 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Brain Res. 326:188-191.</S>
  </References>

</File>

