<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Organization of Projections From the Medial Nucleus of the 
  Amygdala: A PHAL Study in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>N.S. CANTERAS, R.B. SIMERLY, AND L.W. SWANSON</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The organization of axonal projections from the four 
    recognized parts of the medial amygdalar nucleus (MEA) were 
    characterized with the Phaesolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHAL) 
    method in male rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The results indicate that the MEA consists of two major 
    divisions, ventral and dorsal, and that the former may also consist 
    of rostra1 and caudal regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">As a whole, the MEA generates centrifugal projections to 
    several parts of the accessory and main olfactory sensory pathways, 
    and projections to a) several parts of the intrahippocampal circuit 
    (ventrally); b) the ventral striatum, ventral pallidum, and bed 
    nuclei of the stria terminalis (BST) in the basal telencephaon; c) 
    many parts of the hypothalamus; d) midline and medial parts of the 
    thalamus; and e) the periaqueductal gray, ventral tegmental area, 
    and midbrain raphe.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The dorsal division of the MEA (the posterodorsal part) is 
    characterized by projections to the principal nucleus of the BST, 
    and to the anteroventral periventricular, medial, and central parts 
    of the medial preoptic, and ventral premammillary hypothalamic 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">These hypothalamic nuclei project heavily to 
    neuroendocrine and autonomic-related parts of the hypothalamic 
    periventricular zone.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The ventral division of the MEA (the anterodorsal, 
    anteroventral, and posteroventral parts) is characterized by dense 
    projections to the transverse and interfascicular nuclei of the 
    BST, and to the lateral part of the medial preoptic, anterior 
    hypothalamic, and ventromedial hypothalamic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">However, dorsal regions of the ventral division provide 
    rather dense inputs to the medial preoptic region and capsule of 
    the ventromedial nucleus, whereas ventral regions of the ventral 
    division preferentially innervate the anterior hypothalamic, 
    dorsomedial, and ventral parts of the ventromedial nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Functional evidence suggests that circuits associated with 
    dorsal regions of the ventral division may deal with reproductive 
    behavior, whereas circuits associated with ventral regions of the 
    ventral division may deal preferentially with agonistic behavior. 
    61996 WiIey-Liss, Inc.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The medial nucleus of the amygdala (MEA) is influenced 
    directly by gonadal steroid hormones (Pfaff and Keiner, 1973; Sar 
    and Stumpf, 1975; Simerly et al., 19901, and integrates 
    chemosensory stimuli relayed by the vomeronasal and main olfactory 
    pathways, as well as by genital somatosensory inputs (Scalia and 
    Winans, 1975; Krettek and Price, 1978b; Lehman and Winans, 1982; 
    Canteras et al., 1992a; Rowe and Erskine, 1993).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Thus, it is not surprising that the MEA plays an 
    important role in both male and female rodent copulatory behavior 
    (Harris and Sachs, 1975; Lehman et al., 1980; Pfaus et al., 1993; 
    Rajendren and Moss, 19931, and apparently in the neuroendocrine 
    events that accompany copulation, such as prolactin and luteinizing 
    hormone surges (Rajendren and Moss, 1993; Rowe and Erskine, 1993; 
    Pfeiffer and Johnston, 1994).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">A large body of evidence also suggests that the MEA is 
    involved in social learning processes that modulate agonistic 
    behavior (Luiten et al., 1985; Vochteloo and Koolhaas, 19871, as 
    well as in neural circuits mediating the regulation of 
    aldosterone-induced salt appetite (Schulkin et al., 19891, body 
    weight control (Tubbiola et al., 1989; Levin, 19911, 
    thermoregulation (Frederico et al., 19959, and the neuroendocrine 
    control of growth hormone (Kato et al., 1986) and corticosterone 
    (Dunn and Whitener, 1986; Feldman et al., 1990) secretion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Current understanding of axonal projections from the MEA 
    that presumably mediate these functions is based mainly on 
    anterograde axonal tracer studies that did not examine possible 
    differential outputs from the various subdivisions of the nucleus 
    (Krettek and Price, 1978a,b; Kevetter and Winans, 1981; Luiten et 
    al., 1985; Caffe et al., 1987).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The MEA is a complex structure that has been divided on 
    cytoarchitectonic grounds (de Olmos et al., 1985) into seemingly 
    clear anteroventral (MEAav), anterodorsal (MEAad), posteroventral 
    (MEApv), and posterodorsal (MEApd) parts.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">It is now clear that the several parts of the MEA display 
    unique patterns of gonadal steroid receptor expression.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">For example, while androgen receptor mRNA is expressed 
    abundantly throughout the MEA, estrogen receptor mRNA is expressed 
    mainly in the MEApd (Simerly et al., 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Furthermore, neuropeptide synthesis is not uniform 
    throughout the MEA; neurons expressing cholecystokinin, substance 
    P, and angiotensin also tend to be localized almost entirely to 
    specific areas of the MEApd (Simerly and Swanson, 1987; Simerly et 
    al., 1989; Lind and Ganten, 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">This chemoarchitectonic evidence lends support to the 
    possibility that different parts of the MEAmay give rise to 
    somewhat different projections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Recently, Gomez and Newman (1992) examined projections 
    from the hamster MEA with the Phaseolus uuZgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHAL) anterograde tracer method and reported different patterns of 
    labeled axons from anterior and posterior injections in the 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">They showed that projections from the MEAav and MEAad 
    considered together are distinct from those arising in the MEApd, 
    although projections from the MEApv were not examined.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In the present study we have conducted, in the rat, a 
    more comprehensive examination of MEA projections with the PHAL 
    method, which is known to yield small injection sites that can be 
    defined precisely on the basis of labeled perikarya.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">It is also a very sensitive anterograde tracttracing 
    method that allows visualization of labeled axons, including 
    terminal boutons and boutons-of-passage, with the clarity of Golgi 
    impregnations (Gerfen and Sawchenko, 1984).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Thus, it has been possible to obtain an accurate profile 
    of specific outputs from the anterodorsal, posteroventral, and 
    posterodorsal parts of the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Because the anteroventral part is so tiny, PHAL deposits 
    confined entirely within its borders were not obtained, although it 
    was still possible to distinguish some of its characteristic 
    projections.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s24">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Twenty adult male Sprague-Dawley rats (240-310 g) 
    received a single injection of PHAL (Vector Laboratories, 
    Burlingame, CA) into the region of the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Each animal was anesthetized with tribromoethanol (0.25 
    gikg b.w., dissolved in 9O:lO saline:ethanol, viv), and a single 
    iontophoretic injection of a 2.5% solution of PHAL in 0.1 M sodium 
    phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4) was made through a 
    stereotaxically positioned glass micropipette (tip diameter 10 pm) 
    by applying a +5 pA current pulsed at 7 second intervals provided 
    by a constant-current source (Midgard Electronics, model CS3), for 
    a period of 15 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Postinjection survival times for all experiments ranged 
    from 15 to 18 days.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">The animals were perfused and the brains were processed 
    according to procedures described in detail elsewhere (Canteras et 
    al., 1992a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Briefly, each animal was deeply anesthetized with 
    tribromoethanol and perfused transcardially with a solution of 4.0% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M sodium borate buffer at pH 9.5; the 
    brains were removed immediately and postfixed overnight in the same 
    fixative containing 10% sucrose.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Three series of 30 Fm thick frozen frontal sections were 
    cut on a sliding microtome and collected at the following 
    frequencies: one-in-ten through the olfactory bulbs and forebrain 
    rostral to the vascular organ of the lamina terminalis, one-in-four 
    through the hypothalamus and rostral half of the midbrain, and 
    one-in-ten through the caudal midbrain and hindbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Additional sections were collected through the injection 
    site and quick-stained as described in detail elsewhere (see 
    Simerly and Swanson, 1988) to verify the location and size of the 
    PHAL deposit.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">One complete series of sections was processed for 
    immunohistochemistry with an antiserum directed against PHAL (Dako 
    Laboratories; 1:1,000 dilution).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The antigen-antibody complex was localized with a variant 
    of the avidinbiotin complex system (ABC; Hsu et al., 19811, using a 
    commercially available kit (ABC Elite kit, Vector Laboratories, 
    Burlingame, CA).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The sections were mounted on gelatin-coated slides and 
    treated with osmium tetroxide to enhance visibility of the reaction 
    product.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Slides were then dehydrated and coverslipped with DPX.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">An adjacent series was always stained with thionin to 
    serve as a reference series for cytoarchitectonic purposes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Sections were examined with a Leitz Laborlux D microscope 
    (brightand dark-field illumination).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">PHAL-labeled cells in the injection sites, and the 
    distribution of anterogradely labeled fibers, were plotted with the 
    aid of a camera lucida on maps prepared from adjacent Nissl-stained 
    sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">For illustration, the distribution of anterogradely 
    labeled fibers was transferred onto a series of standard rat brain 
    drawings (Swanson, 1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">In transposing our results onto standard drawings, as a 
    first step we tried to match as closely as possible the actual 
    section to be represented with the corresponding section (or 
    sections) in the atlas (Swanson, 1992), based on a careful 
    observation of cytoarchitectonic features.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">To achieve the most accurate representation, once the 
    correct standard section was chosen for a given pathway or terminal 
    field, in addition to the maps prepared with the aid of a camera 
    lucida, constant observation of the actual material was 
    accomplished with a Leitz Laborlux D microscope while plotting the 
    distribution of anterogradely labeled fibers onto the standard 
    drawing, nucleus by nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Unless otherwise indicated, parcellation of the rat brain 
    follows Swanson (1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Descriptions of axonal morphology at the light 
    microscopic level are those commonly used in conjunction with 
    Golgi-impregnated material, and are discussed in Risold et al. 
    (1994).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">In brief, it is highly probable that terminal boutons and 
    boutons-of-passage (together referred to as terminals) form 
    synapses, whereas the significance of varicosities along axons is 
    much less clear and must be established at the ultrastructural 
    level.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s45">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s46">Parcellation</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Before describing the experimental results it is 
    important to discuss our interpretation of the MEA parcellation 
    advanced by De Olmos et al. (1985).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Based on cytoarchitecture they subdivided the nucleus 
    into four parts: anterodorsal, anteroventral, posterodorsal, and 
    posteroventral (Figs. 1, 2).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Briefly, the entire MEA displays a molecular layer 
    dominated by inputs from various parts of the accessory and main 
    olfactory systems reviewed below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The MEAad is the largest component, extending throughout 
    the rostral two thirds of the amygdala, and merging rostrally with 
    the anterior amygdaloid area and caudally with the MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">It contains a heterogeneous population of small to 
    mediumsized neurons (Figs. 1A,B, 2A,B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Ventral to the rostral half of the MEAad, a small, 
    wellldefined, cell-dense region that corresponds to MEAav may be 
    observed in Nissl preparations (Figs. lA, 2A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">The MEApv lies ventrally in the caudal third of the MEA 
    and is also a clearly outlined region; it contains a relatively 
    homogeneous population of mediumsized neurons (Figs. lC,D, 
    2C,D).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Finally, the MEApd (Figs. 1C,D, 2C,D) is shaped roughly 
    like an elongated triangle with a ventral base.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">It lies dorsally in the caudal third of the MEA and 
    presents a characteristic cytoarchitectonic organization: 
    cell-dense regions lie superficially and deep, separated by a 
    relatively cell-sparse intermediate region (labeled a, c, and b, 
    respectively, in Swanson, 1992).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s56">Injection sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">The following description of projections is based on 20 
    PHAL injections where labeled neurons were confined almost entirely 
    to the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Of these, five injections were almost entirely limited to 
    the MEAad, three to the MEApv, and three to the MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The appearance and location of PHAL-labeled cells for 
    representative injections localized primarily to these three parts 
    of the nucleus are shown in Figure 3B,B , 3C,C , and 3D,D .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">In addition, as illustrated in Figure 3A,A , one 
    injection was centered in the MEAav, with a significant number of 
    labeled cells in the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">The remaining eight experiments with PHAL injections 
    confined to the MEA were centered in the anterodorsal part, but 
    also included a number of PHAL-labeled neurons in the posterodorsal 
    (four experiments), posteroventral (one experiment), or 
    anteroventral (three experiments) parts of the nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s62">Projections from the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Regardless of the precise location of PHAL injection 
    sites in the MEA, labeled axons followed the same basic routes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">A detailed account of these pathways will be given in the 
    description of MEAad outputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">What little could be gleaned about the projections of the 
    MEAav is described with those of the MEAad because all injections 
    centered in the former spread to include a significant extent of 
    the latter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s66">Projections from the 
    MEAad</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s67"><exptLabel>All five experiments with a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection site confined 
      almost entirely to <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labeled a very similar 
      pattern of axons.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s68">Experiment MEA number 2 was chosen as a prototype to 
      illustrate (Figs. 3B,B , 4) because the injection labeled the 
      most extensive population of MEAad neurons.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s69">Zntraamygdalar terminal fields.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s70"><labelingDescription>A remarkable plexus of 
      anterogradely labeled axons</labelingDescription> was found to 
      extend through much of <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-Q).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s71">However, before describing these intraamygdalar 
      pathways, it is important to note that in all experiments with a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection restricted to 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingLocation>many labeled boutons</labelingLocation> were 
      observed throughout <labelingDescription>all parts of the 
      MEA</labelingDescription> itself, although 
      <labelingDescription>the density was clearly 
      less</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      MEApd</labelingLocation>(Fig. 4J-0).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s72">Within the amygdala, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> provides 
      <labelingDescription>especially dense 
      inputs</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the anterior 
      amygdaloid area, bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, 
      central nucleus, anterior and posterior parts of the basomedial 
      nucleus, anterior cortical nucleus, and deep layers of the 
      piriform-amygdaloid area</labelingLocation>, whereas 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior cortical nucleus, posterior 
      nucleus, and lateral nucleus</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>somewhat less anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 41-Q).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s73">In the central nucleus, axons from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> were 
      <labelingDescription>most dense</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the capsular part</labelingLocation> 
      (especially caudally), were <labelingDescription>moderately 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
      part</labelingLocation>, and clearly <labelingModifier>tend to 
      avoid</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      part</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4J-N).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s74">Curiously, unlike adjacent amygdalar regions, 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior and posterior parts of the 
      basolateral nucleus</labelingLocation> receive only 
      <labelingDescription>a very sparse input</labelingDescription> 
      from <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> (Fig. 
      4J-P).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s75">Local cortical projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s76"><labelingDescription>One group of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> that <labelingModifier>courses 
      through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> extends both laterally toward 
      <labelingLocation>the piriform area and endopiriform 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-P) and caudally toward 
      <labelingLocation>the postpiriform transition area (area TR) and 
      hippocampal formation</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4Q-S).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s77"><labelingLocation>The piriform area and endopiriform 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> contain <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate number of anterogradely labeled fibers that give rise to 
      boutons</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s78"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> are found throughout most of 
      <labelingLocation>the piriform area</labelingLocation>, but are 
      <labelingDescription>especially prominent</labelingDescription> 
      caudally and medially, and in layer 3 (Fig. 4C-P).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79"><labelingDescription>Some fibers</labelingDescription> 
      continue toward <labelingLocation>the agranular insular area and 
      claustrum</labelingLocation>, which receive 
      <labelingDescription>a relatively sparse 
      input</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4D-M).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80"><labelingDescription>A small number of 
      axons</labelingDescription> coursing through 
      <labelingLocation>the piriform area</labelingLocation> also 
      <labelingModifier>extend rostrally through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral olfactory tract</labelingLocation> 
      to end in <labelingLocation>the accessory olfactory bulb mitral 
      cell layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A-E).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81">In the hippocampal formation, <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral entorhinal area (all layers)</labelingLocation> receives 
      <labelingDescription>a substantial 
      projection</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation>, while <labelingDescription>a smaller 
      number of labeled axons</labelingDescription> were also observed 
      throughout <labelingLocation>the ventral subiculum and adjacent 
      ventral parts of field CA1</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4Q-S); 
      <labelingDescription>an even smaller number of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were found reliably in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial entorhinal area and 
      parasubiculum</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4R-S).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82">Finally, another <labelingDescription>group of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> extends rostral to the amygdala, where 
      they appear <labelingModifier>to innervate</labelingModifier> 
      primarily <labelingLocation>the fundus of the striatum and layer 
      3 of the olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4E-I).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s83">The stria terminalis and ansa peduncularis.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s84"><labelingDescription>The vast majority of MEAad 
      axons</labelingDescription> that leave the amygdala enter 
      <labelingLocation>the ansa peduncularis or stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> before 
      <labelingModifier>innervating</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>a number of telencephalic and diencephalic 
      sites</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85"><labelingDescription>An especially large number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course through <labelingLocation>the 
      ansa peduncularis (in the so-called ventral amygdalofugal 
      pathway)</labelingLocation>, where they form two distinct bundles 
      coursing a) through <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> or b) directly to and through 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86">At caudal levels of the BST, most fibers 
      <labelingModifier>coursing through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata</labelingLocation> 
      appear to merge with axons coursing through the stria 
      terminalis.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87">Together, they 
      <labelingModifier>innervate</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>caudal regions of the BST</labelingLocation>, 
      and some of them probably continue ventrally toward 
      <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, as 
      described below (Fig. 41).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> are usually poorly branched, 
      although they display <labelingDescription>a significant number 
      of boutons</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">At caudal levels they are concentrated ventromedially, 
      but as they approach <labelingLocation>the BST</labelingLocation> 
      they fill <labelingLocation>much of the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-K).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90">Rostral to this level, <labelingDescription>some fibers 
      with boutons</labelingDescription> continue through 
      <labelingLocation>rostral parts of t.he substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4D-H).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">Septa1 projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> 
      initially provide <labelingDescription>a dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the septal 
      region</labelingLocation>, including <labelingLocation>the 
      BST</labelingLocation> (see above).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">In <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the transverse and 
      interfascicular nuclei</labelingLocation> are filled with 
      <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of 
      fibers</labelingDescription>, whereas <labelingDescription>the 
      principal nucleus</labelingDescription> receives 
      <labelingDescription>a rather sparse input</labelingDescription> 
      (Fig. 41).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">In <labelingLocation>the anterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> supplies <labelingDescription>dense 
      inputs</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      anterodorsal and anteroventral areas</labelingLocation>, whereas 
      only <labelingLocation>caudal zones of the anterolateral 
      area</labelingLocation> appear to receive <labelingDescription>a 
      significant number of fibers and boutons</labelingDescription> 
      (Fig. 4F-H).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingDescription>the stria terminalis</labelingDescription> 
      also provide <labelingDescription>a rather dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the intermediate 
      and ventral parts of the lateral septal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, as well as <labelingDescription>very 
      sparse projections</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsal part of the lateral, septofimbrial, and medial septal 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4D-H).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">From the septal region, <labelingDescription>a few 
      labeled axons</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>extend into 
      and innervate</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>caudalmost 
      parts of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4D-E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97"><labelingDescription>Axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> in 
      <labelingLocation>the ansa peduncularis</labelingLocation> also 
      extend rostrally through <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> (mentioned above) and ventral to 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the diagonal 
      band</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4E-H), and then merge at the level 
      of the nucleus accumbens with 
      <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingModifier>coursing through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the septal region</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      4D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> running ventral to 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the diagonal 
      band</labelingLocation>generate <labelingDescription>many 
      boutons</labelingDescription> near <labelingLocation>the 
      ventromedial surface of the brain (just superficial to neuronal 
      cell bodies in the nucleus of the diagonal 
      band</labelingLocation>; Fig. 4E-H) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Prefrontal cortex and accessory olfactory bulb.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">Rostral to the nucleus accumbens, 
      <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>innervate</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the medial prefrontal cortex, taenia tecta, 
      anterior olfactory nucleus, and accessory olfactory bulb mitral 
      cell layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A-C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">Specifically, <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      prelimbic and infralimbic areas of the prefrontal 
      region</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4 0 , and 
      <labelingDescription>some fibers</labelingDescription> extend 
      rostrally through <labelingLocation>the anterior olfactory 
      nucleus and taenia tecta</labelingLocation>, where they generate 
      <labelingDescription>a relatively small number of 
      boutons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 4B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">Some or all of these fibers continue on to provide 
      <labelingDescription>a relatively dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the accessory 
      olfactory bulb mitral cell layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">As mentioned above, <labelingDescription>a few 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> also reach <labelingLocation>the 
      accessory olfactory bulb mitral cell layer</labelingLocation> by 
      <labelingModifier>coursing directly through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral olfactory 
      tract</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Hypothalamic projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105"><labelingDescription>Axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>innervate</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>a number of hypothalamic 
      sites</labelingLocation>, particularly in the medial zone, 
      although it was not possible to determine with certainty the 
      relative contributions of fibers in the stria terminalis and ansa 
      peduncularis to particular terminal fields because of the way 
      these two pathways converge at the level of the septal region 
      (see above).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">At preoptic levels, <labelingLocation>undifferentiated 
      parts of the medial preoptic area and the lateral part of the 
      medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> contain 
      <labelingDescription>a remarkable number of labeled fibers and 
      boutons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 4H,I).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">In contrast, <labelingDescription>many fewer labeled 
      axons and boutons</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>more rostral parts of the medial preoptic 
      area</labelingLocation>, and these fibers clearly 
      <labelingModifier>tend to avoid</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the anteroventral periventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4G).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108"><labelingLocation>The lateral preoptic 
      area</labelingLocation> contains only <labelingDescription>sparse 
      labeled axons</labelingDescription> with the morphological 
      features of 
      <labelingDescription>fibers-of-passage</labelingDescription> (few 
      if any boutons, and only occasional varicosities; Fig. 4G,H).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">At <labelingLocation>anterior hypothalamic 
      levels</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>most labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> also distribute within 
      <labelingLocation>the medial zone</labelingLocation>, where they 
      form <labelingDescription>particularly dense terminal 
      fields</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>dorsal zones of 
      the central part of the anterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, in <labelingLocation>adjacent regions 
      surrounding the paraventricular nucleus (including the 
      subparaventricular zone)</labelingLocation>, and in 
      <labelingLocation>the retrochiasmatic area</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 4J-L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">In sharp contrast, <labelingLocation>the 
      periventricular zone</labelingLocation> at this level contains 
      <labelingDescription>only a few anterogradely labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription>, which appear to be 
      <labelingDescription>more numerous</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior parvicellular part of the 
      paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4J-L).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">At tuberal levels, 
      <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> form 
      <labelingDescription>a dense terminal field</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the capsule of the ventromedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, whereas the nucleus itself contains 
      <labelingDescription>relatively fewer labeled axons and 
      boutons</labelingDescription> (see Figs. 4L-0, 7B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">However, in experiments with 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection sites labeling a 
      substantial population of neurons in <injectionSpread>the 
      anteroventral part of the MEA</injectionSpread>, 
      <labelingDescription>a very dense plexus of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> was seen within <labelingLocation>the 
      ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation> itself (particularly in 
      <labelingLocation>the central and dorsomedial 
      parts</labelingLocation>; see Fig. 7A).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">In contrast, <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>few 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEAad</injectionLocation> (Fig. 4N,O).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114"><injectionLocation>The MEAad</injectionLocation> also 
      provides <labelingDescription>substantial 
      inputs</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>a region (the 
      tuberal nucleus</labelingLocation>; see Canteras et al., 
      &apos;94) immediately lateral to ventral parts of the 
      ventromedial nucleus (Fig. 4M-0), and to <labelingLocation>a 
      region of the lateral hypothalamic area immediately adjacent to 
      the cerebral peduncle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 40,P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Finally, <labelingDescription>labeled fibers and 
      boutons</labelingDescription> at the tuberal level were also 
      found reliably in <labelingLocation>the intermediate 
      periventricular nucleus and lateral regions of the arcuate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4L-0).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116"><labelingDescription>Axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEAad</injectionLocation> continue on to 
      the rnarnmillary level, where they provide 
      <labelingDescription>dense inputs</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior periventricular nucleus, ventral 
      premammillary nucleus, and ventral regions of the posterior 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>; and <labelingDescription>more sparse 
      inputs</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the fiber 
      capsule around superficial parts of the medial mammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4P-R), and 
      <labelingLocation>both parts of the supramammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4Q).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">Thalamic projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118"><labelingDescription>Some labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> leave <labelingLocation>dorsal parts 
      of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> to enter 
      <labelingLocation>the thalamus</labelingLocation>, whereas a few 
      others leave the stria terminalis to enter the thalamus via the 
      stria medullaris.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">In <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      thalamus</labelingLocation>, 
      <injectionLocation>MEAad</injectionLocation> inputs, which are 
      <labelingDescription>sparse</labelingDescription>, appear 
      confined mostly to <labelingLocation>rostral parts of the zona 
      incerta</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4L-N).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">In contrast, <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>a 
      particularly dense plexus of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>ventral regions of the nucleus 
      reuniens</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>a 
      substantial projection</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus and medial part of 
      the mediodorsal nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-PI.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><labelingDescription>Very sparse anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was also observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the parataenial nucleus, lateral habenula, and 
      subparafascicular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 41-P).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">Brainstem projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123"><labelingDescription>A few axons</labelingDescription> 
      coursing through <labelingLocation>the posterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> extend caudally into 
      <labelingLocation>periependymal regions of the periaqueductal 
      gray</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4Q-S), provide 
      <labelingDescription>a sparse input</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      and continue as far caudal as <labelingLocation>the pontine 
      central gray</labelingLocation> (not illustrated).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124"><labelingDescription>A few axons</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingModifier>coursing through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> extend caudally into 
      <labelingLocation>the midbrain</labelingLocation>, where they 
      provide <labelingDescription>a sparse input</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental 
      area</labelingLocation>, and <labelingLocation>the 
      interfascicular, rostral linear, and central linear raphe 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4R-S).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">Contralateral projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">It is important to note that projections from the 
      MEAad are mostly ipsilateral, although <labelingLocation>a very 
      small number of axons</labelingLocation> <labelingModifier>cross 
      the midline</labelingModifier> in the anterior commissure, 
      supraoptic commissures, and supramammillary decussation.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127"><labelingDescription>Occasional labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed on 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral side</labelingLocation> only 
      in those regions with a very dense ipsilateral projection, 
      including <labelingLocation>the accessory olfactory bulb mitral 
      cell layer, lateral septal nucleus, BST, medial preoptic area, 
      ventromedial nucleus, ventral premammillary nucleus, and nucleus 
      reuniens</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128"><labelingDescription>Virtually no anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s129">Projections from the 
    MEApv</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130">In three experiments <exptLabel>the 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit was virtually 
      confined to <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, and each displayed a 
      similar pattern of anterograde labeling.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">Experiment MEApv number 2 was chosen as a prototype to 
      illustrate our results (Figs. 3C,C , 5).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">Zntraamygdar terminal fields.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133">The MEApv projects extensively within the amygdala, 
      with a pattern resembling in may ways that described for the 
      MEAad. 1) <labelingDescription>Axons and 
      terminals</labelingDescription> were found throughout 
      <labelingLocation>the rest of the MEA</labelingLocation>, 
      although they are considerably <labelingDescription>more 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the MEAad and 
      MEAav</labelingLocation> than in <labelingLocation>the 
      MEApd</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5G-L). 2) 
      <labelingDescription>Many labeled terminals</labelingDescription> 
      were observed in <labelingLocation>the anterior amygdaloid area, 
      bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, anterior and 
      posterior parts of the basomedial nucleus, piriformamygdaloid 
      area, anterior and posterior cortical nuclei, and posterior 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5F-N). 3) As with the MEAad, the 
      MEApv provides <labelingDescription>a moderate 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      amygdaloid nucleus</labelingLocation>, where 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> tended 
      to be concentrated ventrally (Fig. 5K-M), and 4), in contrast to 
      the MEAad, the MEApv 
      <labelingModifier>innervates</labelingModifier> mainly ventral 
      regions of <labelingLocation>the capsular central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and <labelingLocation>the medial 
      central nucleus</labelingLocation> contains only 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      terminals</labelingDescription> (Fig. 5G-K).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134">Local cortical projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">As with the MEAad, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from the MEApv 
      <labelingModifier>course through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> to 
      <labelingLocation>the piriform area and endopiriform 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B-M), and to 
      <labelingLocation>the postpiriform transition area (area TR) and 
      hippocampal formation</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5N-P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136"><labelingDescription>Some axons</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the piriform area</labelingLocation> extend 
      to <labelingLocation>the agranular insular area and 
      claustrum</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B-J).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137">As with the MEAad, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> contributes 
      <labelingDescription>moderate inputs</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral entorhinal area</labelingLocation>, 
      and <labelingDescription>very sparse inputs</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the ventral subiculum, adjacent ventral 
      parts of field CA1, parasubiculum, and medial entorhinal 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5N-P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138">In contrast to the MEAad, however, only 
      <labelingDescription>a few axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApv</injectionLocation> extend rostral 
      to the amygdala into <labelingLocation>the striatal fundus and 
      olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B-F).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139">The stria terminalis and ansa peduncularis.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140">Most descending axons of neurons in the MEApv follow 
      the stria terminalis and ansa peduncularis (Fig. 5F-L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s141">However, as compared to the MEAad, 
      <labelingDescription>many fewer axons</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingModifier>course through</labelingModifier> the ventral 
      route, where their course through and to the 
      <labelingLocation>substantia innominata</labelingLocation> is 
      essentially the same as that described for the MEAad (Fig. 
      5F-I).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142"><labelingDescription>Axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApv</injectionLocation> in these two 
      pathways <labelingModifier>innervate</labelingModifier> basically 
      <labelingLocation>the same general regions of the telencephalon 
      and diencephalon</labelingLocation> as axons from the MEAad, 
      although typically they generate a topographically distinct 
      terminal field within a particular region.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143">Septalprojections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144"><injectionLocation>The MEApv</injectionLocation> 
      provides <labelingDescription>a dense 
      projection</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior division of the BST</labelingLocation>, where (as with 
      the MEAad) <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>tend to 
      avoid</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the principal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and instead provide 
      <labelingDescription>a strikingly dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      interfascicular and transverse nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      5F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145">On the other hand, projections to 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> differ somewhat for the MEAad and MEApv, 
      with the latter providing <labelingDescription>a dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      anterodorsal</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a sparse 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      anteroventral</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>a very 
      sparse input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      anterolateral areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5C-El.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146">Furthermore, the MEApv provides only 
      <labelingDescription>a sparse input</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the intermediate and ventral parts of the 
      lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5B-E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147">Finally, <labelingDescription>some 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> were observed extending rostral to the 
      septal region, and they appear <labelingModifier>to 
      end</labelingModifier> in <labelingLocation>the infralimbic and 
      prelimbic areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5A).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148">Importantly, and in contrast to the MEAad, 
      <labelingDescription>no labeled axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApv</injectionLocation> could be 
      followed to <labelingLocation>any part of the olfactory 
      bulb</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149">Hypothalamic projections.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150">The pattern of hypothalamic projections observed in 
      experiments with PHAL deposits restricted to the MEApv was 
      distinct in many ways from that described for the MEAad.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151">At the preoptic level, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation>, like the MEAad, provides 
      <labelingDescription>a rather dense input</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the caudal pole of the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5F), whereas at more rostral 
      levels, the MEApv (unlike the MEAad) provides 
      <labelingDescription>relatively few axons and 
      terminals</labelingDescription> throughout 
      <labelingLocation>undifferentiated parts of the medial preoptic 
      area</labelingLocation> and <labelingLocation>the lateral and 
      medial parts of the medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 5C-E).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s152">At the anterior hypothalamic leuel, 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApv</injectionLocation> provides 
      <labelingDescription>a denser projection</labelingDescription> 
      than the MEAad to <labelingLocation>the medial 
      zone</labelingLocation>, where <labelingDescription>many labeled 
      terminals</labelingDescription>were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      region surrounding the suprachiasmatic nucleus; retrochiasmatic 
      area; rostral pole, central, and posterior parts of the anterior 
      hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation>; and 
      <labelingLocation>regions near the periventricular 
      zone</labelingLocation>, including the (Fig. 5F-I).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153">At the tuberal level, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> provides <labelingDescription>an 
      impressive plexus of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the capsule of the ventromedial nucleus, and to 
      the dorsomedial and central parts of the nucleus 
      itself</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s154">This projection tends <labelingModifier>to 
      avoid</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the ventrolatera1 part 
      of the ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation>, whereas 
      <labelingLocation>the adjacent tuberal nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      receives <labelingDescription>a substantial 
      input</labelingDescription> (see Figs. 51-L, 7C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155">Interestingly, <labelingDescription>the dense plexus 
      of fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the capsule 
      of the ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation> invades 
      <labelingLocation>the periventricular zone</labelingLocation> and 
      appears to provide <labelingDescription>a very dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the intermediate 
      periventricular nucleus</labelingLocation>, although only 
      <labelingDescription>a few axons</labelingDescription> extend 
      ventrally into <labelingLocation>the arcuate 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 51-L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> also <labelingModifier>appear to 
      end</labelingModifier> in <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5K-L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157">In addition, unlike the MEAad, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> projects <labelingDescription>only 
      sparsely</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the region of 
      the lateral hypothalamic area adjacent to the cerebral 
      peduncle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5L-M).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">At the mammillary level, just caudal to the 
      ventromedial nucleus, <labelingDescription>a relatively dense 
      plexus of fibers</labelingDescription> is found in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral premammillary nucleus and ventral 
      regions of the posterior nucleus</labelingLocation>, whereas only 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled axons</labelingDescription> 
      are observed in <labelingLocation>the posterior periventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5M).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159"><labelingDescription>A small number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> also appear <labelingModifier>to 
      innervate</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
      supramammillary nucleus and fiber capsule around the medial 
      mammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5N,O).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">Thalamic projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161">As with the MEAad, <labelingDescription>some 
      fibers</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>coursing 
      through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> extend dorsally into 
      <labelingLocation>thalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">In <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>only occasional 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>rostral parts of the zona 
      incerta</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5I-K), whereas in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal thalamus</labelingLocation>, 
      <labelingLocation>a rostroventral zone of the nucleus 
      reuniens</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate input</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation>, although it is 
      <labelingDescription>far less dense</labelingDescription> than 
      that described for the MEAad (Fig. 5G,H).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">In contrast to the MEAad, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> provides only <labelingDescription>a 
      few axons</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation>, and 
      <labelingDescription>no anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
      mediodorsal nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5F-M).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s164">Brainstem projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s165"><labelingDescription>A small group of 
      fibers</labelingDescription>extends from <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation> into 
      <labelingLocation>the periaqueductal gray</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 5N,O).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s166">At least <labelingDescription>a few such 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed throughout 
      <labelingLocation>its rostrocaudal extent</labelingLocation>, as 
      well as in <labelingLocation>the dorsal nucleus of the 
      raphe</labelingLocation> (not illustrated).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s167">In contrast to the MEAad, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> provides <labelingDescription>only an 
      occasional fiber</labelingDescription> <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral tegmental area, and the nearby interfascicular, rostral 
      linear, and central linear nuclei of the raphe</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 50.P).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s168">Contralateral projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s169">As with the MEAad, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApv</injectionLocation> projects 
      <labelingDescription>lightly</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral side</labelingLocation>, 
      basically to <labelingLocation>those regions with a very dense 
      ipsilateral projection</labelingLocation>, including 
      <labelingLocation>the BST, anterior hypothalamic nucleus, 
      ventromedial nucleus, ventral premammillary nucleus, and 
      posterior hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170">These fibers also cross the midline through the 
      anterior commissure, supraoptic commissures, and supramammillary 
      decussation.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s171">However, they <labelingModifier>do not appear to 
      innervate</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> to any significant extent.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s172">Projections from the 
    MEApd</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">Three experiments contained <exptLabel>a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit that was confined 
      to <injectionLocation>the MEApd</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      and each displayed a similar pattern of anterogradely labeled 
      fibers; experiment MEApd number 3 was chosen as a prototype for 
      illustration (Figs. 3D,D&apos; and 6).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174">Zntraamygdalar terminal fields.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175">From the injection site, 
      <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> extend throughout other parts of the 
      MEA (Fig. 6H-L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s176">Elsewhere in the amygdala, there is 
      <labelingDescription>a dense projection</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior cortical 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> that 
      <labelingModifier>ends</labelingModifier> primarily in 
      <labelingLocation>the molecular layer of the medial part, and 
      layers 1 and 2 in caudal regions of the lateral 
      part</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6L-N), and <labelingDescription>a 
      moderate projection</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      6GM).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s177">Unlike other parts of the MEA, <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApd</injectionLocation> sends <labelingDescription>very few 
      axons</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the anterior 
      amygdaloid area, bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, 
      anterior and posterior basomedial nucleus, deep layers of the 
      posterior cortical nucleus, and piriform-amygdaloid 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6F-N).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s178"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of fibers with 
      boutons</labelingDescription> were observed ventromedially in 
      <labelingLocation>the capsular central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and only <labelingDescription>a few 
      labeled axons</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s179">Local cortical projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s180">As with other parts of the MEA, <injectionLocation>the 
      ME-4pd</injectionLocation> sends <labelingDescription>a group of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> through <labelingDescription>the 
      amygdala</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      postpiriform transition area and hippocampal 
      formation</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6N-P), although 
      <labelingDescription>few labeled axons</labelingDescription> 
      could be traced to <labelingLocation>the piriform area and 
      endopiriform nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6F-M).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s181">The distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      hippocampal formation</labelingLocation> is similar to that 
      described for other parts of the MEA: they are distributed mainly 
      within <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the entorhinal 
      area</labelingLocation>, although <labelingDescription>a few 
      labeled terminals</labelingDescription> were also found in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial part of the entorhinal area, ventral 
      subiculum, and adjacent ventral parts of field 
      CA1</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6N-P).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s182">The stria terminalis and ansa peduncularis.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s183"><labelingLocation>The stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> represents by far 
      <labelingDescription>the major pathway</labelingDescription> 
      followed by descending projections from the MEApd.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s184"><labelingDescription>A few axons</labelingDescription> 
      leave <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> via the 
      ansa peduncularis, and their course through (and to) 
      <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata</labelingLocation> is 
      similar to that for other parts of the MEA.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s185"><labelingDescription>Axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApd</injectionLocation> in 
      <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> appear 
      to end in <labelingLocation>a number of telencephalic and 
      diencephalic sites</labelingLocation>, including 
      <labelingLocation>the septal region, infralimbic area of the 
      prefrontal cortex, and several hypothalamic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>, although their distribution pattern is 
      quite distinct from that outlined for other parts of the MEA.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s186">Septa1 and prefrontal inputs.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s187">In <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a very dense plexus 
      of terminals</labelingDescription> was observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the principal nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      rather than <labelingLocation>the interfascicular and transverse 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>, which appear to receive 
      <labelingDescription>very few axons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
      6F).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s188">In <labelingLocation>the anterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal 
      area</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>a 
      relatively large number of terminals</labelingDescription>, 
      whereas only <labelingDescription>a few 
      axons</labelingDescription> were observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the anteroventral and anterolateral 
      areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6C-E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s189"><labelingDescription>Few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>MEApd</injectionLocation> injections reach 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      where they generate <labelingDescription>a small number of 
      terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      and intermediate parts</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6B-E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s190">In addition, <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> extend rostrally toward 
      <labelingDescription>the prefrontal region</labelingDescription>, 
      where they end in <labelingLocation>the infralimbic 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6A), the most rostra1 target of the 
      MEApd.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s191">Hypothalamic projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s192">At the preoptic level, 
      <labelingLocation>axons</labelingLocation> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApd</injectionLocation> generate 
      <labelingDescription>a strikingly dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      anteroventral periventricular and medial preoptic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6C-F).</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s193">This is an important feature because 
      <labelingLocation>the anteroventral periventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> receives <labelingDescription>very 
      sparse inputs</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>other 
      parts of the MEA</injectionLocation>.</S></TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s194">Furthermore, projections from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApd</injectionLocation> to <labelingLocation>the medial and 
      central parts of the medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      are clearly <labelingDescription>more dense</labelingDescription> 
      than in <labelingLocation>the lateral part</labelingLocation> 
      (<labelingModifier>except for</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the caudal pole of the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>) (Fig. 6E), whereas the opposite was 
      seen in all the experiments with injection sites that did not 
      involve the MEApd.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s195">At the anterior hypothalamic level, 
      <labelingDescription>many labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      extend caudally from the preoptic level through 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s196">Most of <labelingDescription>these 
      axons</labelingDescription> present <labelingDescription>widely 
      spaced varicosities and very few boutons</labelingDescription>, 
      thus resembling 
      <labelingDescription>fibers-of-passage</labelingDescription> 
      (Fig. 6G-I).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s197">At the tuberal level, 
      <labelingDescription>PHAL-containing axons</labelingDescription> 
      arriving by way of <labelingLocation>the anterior hypothalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> are found mainly in the capsule 
      surrounding <labelingLocation>the central and ventrolateral parts 
      of the ventromedial nucleus and immediately adjacent regions of 
      the tuberal nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 6J-L, 7D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s198">Curiously, <labelingDescription>these labeled axons 
      are also very poorly branched and appear to generate relatively 
      few boutons</labelingDescription> (Figs. 6J-L, 7D).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s199">Some axons at this level extend into 
      <labelingLocation>the periventricular zone</labelingLocation>, 
      where they appear <labelingModifier>to 
      innervate</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingDescription>lightly</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingLocation>the intermediate periventricular and arcuate 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 61-L).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s200">At the mammillary level, just caudal to the 
      ventromedial nucleus, <labelingLocation>fibers</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>descending through</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the medial zone</labelingLocation> form 
      <labelingDescription>a massive terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      premammillary nucleus and adjacent ventral regions of the 
      posterior nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6M).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s201"><labelingDescription>Some labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> extend caudally into 
      <labelingLocation>the mammillary body</labelingLocation>, where 
      they end in <labelingLocation>the fiber capsule around caudal 
      regions of the medial mammillary nucleus</labelingLocation>, and 
      in <labelingLocation>the supramammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6N,O).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s202"><labelingDescription>Very few 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApd</injectionLocation> extend into <labelingLocation>the 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6F-M) and 
      <labelingLocation>periaqueductal gray</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      6N-PI.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s203">Contralateral projections.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s204">As with other parts of the MEA, only 
      <labelingDescription>a few axons</labelingDescription> from 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApd</injectionLocation> could be traced 
      to<labelingLocation> the contralateral side of the 
      brain</labelingLocation> through the three pathways described 
      above.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s205">Contralateral fibers are distributed to basically 
      those parts of the septum and hypothalamus with a dense 
      ipsilateral terminal field.</S>
    </TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s206">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">The present results confirm and extend earlier views 
    about how the very complex axonal projections from the MEA are 
    organized, and thus hopefully provide a relatively accurate 
    description of pathways and terminal fields arising in 
    anterodorsal, posteroventral, and posterodorsal parts of the 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">At least certain characteristic projections from the 
    anteroventral part of the nucleus were also elucidated, although 
    its very small volume prevented definitive analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Overall, our results provide hodological support for the 
    cytoarchitectonic parcellation of the MEA proposed by De Olmos et 
    al. (1985).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s210">Projections from the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">In all experiments with a PHAL deposit confined to the 
    MEA, labeled axons followed the same basic pathways (Fig. 8), 
    regardless of differences observed in the distribution pattern of 
    specific terminal fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">The output of the MEA is mostly ipsilateral, with a few 
    axons crossing the midline through the anterior commissure, 
    supraoptic commissures, and supramammillary decussation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Axons from the MEA initially generate dense terminal 
    fields in several parts of the amygdala, and some fibers extend 
    laterally to the piriform area and associated endopiriform nucleus, 
    caudally to the postpiriform transition area and hippocampal 
    formation, or rostrally to the striatal fundus, olfactory tubercle, 
    and accessory olfactory bulb.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Most extraamygdalar axons from the MEA join the ansa 
    peduncularis (ventral amygdalofugal component) or stria terminalis 
    to end in a number of telencephalic and diencephalic sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The MEAad, and to a lesser extent the MEApv, contribute 
    an many fibers to the ansa peduncularis, whereas only a few axons 
    arising in the MEApd, a cell group that ascends with the stria 
    terminalis along the medial edge of the tip of the temporal horn of 
    the lateral ventricle (see plate 30 in Swanson, 19921, join this 
    pathway to and through the substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">As in the hamster (Gomez and Newman, 19921, our results 
    indicate that MEA outputs tend to course through medial regions of 
    the stria terminalis, with axons from the MEAad and MEApv tending 
    to lie ventral to those from the MEApd.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Intraamygdalar and olfactory projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">We confirm that the MEA establishes massive 
    intraamygdalar connections, and suggest that each part of the 
    nucleus generates a distinct pattern of terminal fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Our results also confirm dense intrinsic connections 
    within the MEA itself (Nishizuka and Arai, 1983; Gomez and Newman, 
    1992); and indicate specifically that the MEAad, MEApv, and 
    possibly MEAav, are heavily interconnected, unlike the MEApd, which 
    establishes much lighter interconnections with the rest of the 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">This is one of many indications that the MEA consists 
    essentially of ventral and dorsal divisions, with the MEAad, av, 
    and pv included in the former, and the MEApd constituting the 
    latter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">This view of two primary divisions is strengthened by 
    evidence that projection patterns from the MEAad and MEApv to other 
    parts of the amygdala are similar but differ markedly from that 
    observed for the MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">The MEAad and MEApv generate substantial intraamygdalar 
    terminal fields in structures related particularly to the 
    vomeronasal system (medial posterior cortical nucleus, posterior 
    nucleus, and bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract); the 
    main olfactory bulb (anterior amygdaloid area, anterior cortical 
    nucleus, piriform-amygdaloid area, and lateral posterior cortical 
    nucleusj; and the basolateral complex (basomedial and lateral 
    nuclei).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">In contrast, substantial projections from the MEApd are 
    restricted to the posteromedial cortical and posterior nuclei 
    (accessory system) and the posterolateral cortical nucleus (main 
    system), and only a light input to the basomedial nucleus is 
    found.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">One difference is that medial and capsular parts of the 
    central nucleus clearly receive larger inputs from the MEAad than 
    from the MEApv.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">The MEApd projects lightly to these parts of the central 
    nucleus, and no part of the MEA sends more than a few axons to the 
    lateral central nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Projections from the MEA to the posterior cortical, 
    basomedial, and anterior cortical nuclei were inferred from 
    autoradiographic studies (Krettek and Price, 1978b), although local 
    connections are difficult to establish autoradiographically.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">The intraamygdalar MEA projections identified here are, 
    with two exceptions, similar to those described with PHAL in the 
    hamster (Gomez and Newman, 1992).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">However, they reported a projection to layers 2 and 3 of 
    the nucleus of the lateral olfactory tract, which was notably free 
    of anterograde labeling here.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Furthermore, they did not describe a projection from the 
    MEA to the lateral nucleus of the amygdala, although it had been 
    suggested in the rat by Ottersen ( 1982) using horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">These discrepancies may reflect species differences.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The MEA receives a massive input from the accessory 
    olfactory bulb, and possibly a very restricted input from the main 
    olfactory bulb to the rostral tip of the MEAad (Scalia and Winans, 
    1975; Lehman and Winans, 1982).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">However, main olfactory information reaches most of the 
    nucleus via intraamygdalar projections from the anterior cortical 
    nucleus (Ottersen, 1982; G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Petrovich and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Swanson, unpublished observations with PHAL), lateral 
    posterior cortical nucleus (Canteras et al., 1992a), and 
    piriformamygdaloid area (Ottersen, 19821, and possibly from the 
    endopiriform nucleus (Krettek and Price, 1978b) and piriform area 
    (Luskin and Price, 1983).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Thus, the MEA as a whole may be viewed as an important 
    site for the integration of olfactory information from the 
    accessory system with that from the main system, and for sending 
    this information to other parts of the amygdala, some of which also 
    process information from the main and/or accessory olfactory 
    bulbs.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">The MEA also projects back to a number of extraamygdalar 
    parts of the olfactory system and is thus in an even stronger 
    position to modulate the central flow of olfactory information.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">The MEA projects directly to the accessory olfactory 
    bulb i:De Olmos et al., 19781, and we have demonstrated 
    specifically that the MEAad innervates its projection cell 
    layer.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">The medial posterior cortical nucleus (which receives an 
    input from most or all parts of the MEA) also generates a robust 
    projection back to the accessory olfactory bulb, although it 
    appears to be directed mainly to the granular layer (Canteras et 
    al., 1992a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Thus, the MEA and medial posterior cortical nucleus, 
    which both receive inputs from the accessory olfactory bulb, 
    project back to different cell types in the accessory olfactory 
    bulb, and presumably influence differentially the central flow of 
    vomeronasal information.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Gomez and Newman (1992) described a major projection 
    from the hamster MEA to the anterior olfactory nucleus, whereas our 
    material suggests that this projection is sparse in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">Our results also confirm evidence (Caffe et al., 1987; 
    Gomez and Newman, 1992) for MEA projections to the endopiriform 
    nucleus and cortical areas receiving direct inputs from the main 
    olfactory bulb (olfactory tubercle; piriform, piriform-amygdaloid, 
    postpiriform transition, lateral entorhinal areas).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">All of these cortical areas, and the endopiriform 
    nucleus, receive substantial inputs from the MEAad and MEApv, but 
    sparse inputs from the MEApd, in the rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Hippocampal inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Aside from the lateral entorhinal area input just 
    mentioned, the MEA projects to other parts of the hippocampal 
    formation, including the medial entorhinal area, parasubiculum, and 
    especially ventral subiculumi ventral field CA1.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">MEA inputs to the ventral subiculumi field CA1 was 
    described by Caffe et al. (19871, who suggested that it may contain 
    vasopressin.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The entorhinal area constitutes the starting point of 
    the hippocampal trisynaptic circuit, and field CA1 and the 
    subiculum are on the output side of this circuit, which is thought 
    to play an important role in short-term episodic memory (see 
    Swanson et al., 1987).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Projections to the septum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">A projection from the MEA to the BST is known (Krettek 
    and Price, 1978a; De Olmos et al., 1985; Price et al., 19871, and 
    our results on projections from the MEA to the BST and substantia 
    innominata largely confirm those of Gomez and Newman (1992) in the 
    hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">It appears that the MEA participates in two relatively 
    distinct circuits.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Our results indicate that the MEAad and MEApv provide 
    similar BST projections, which differ markedly from those of the 
    MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">In the posterior BST, the MEAad and MEApv generate dense 
    terminal fields in the interfascicular and transverse nuclei, 
    whereas the MEApd projects densely to the principal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">In the anterior division, all parts of the MEA generate 
    a dense terminal field in the anterodorsal area, whereas only the 
    MEAad innervates significantly the anteroventral area and caudal 
    anterolateral area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">The principal nucleus of the BST also receives a dense 
    input from the posterior amygdalar nucleus, and both cell groups 
    innervate densely the MEApd, and hypothalamic regions innervated by 
    the MEApd (Simerly et al., 1989; Canteras et al., 1992a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Thus, the MEApd, posterior nucleus of the amygdala, and 
    principal nucleus of the BST constitute an interconnected group of 
    basal telencephalic nuclei innervating essentially the same 
    constellation of hypothalamic nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">In contrast, the MEAad and MEApv are massively 
    interconnected, and both densely innervate the interfascicular and 
    transverse nuclei of the BST.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">In agreement with retrograde tracer results (Grove, 
    1988a), our observations indicate that the MEAad, and to a lesser 
    extent the MEApv and MEApd, provide a dense input to neurons in the 
    substantia innominata along the course of the ventral amygdalofugal 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Caudal parts of the ventral substantia innominata, and 
    parts of the BST observed here to receive dense inputs from the 
    MEAad and MEApv, may project to the MEA (Swanson and Cowan, 1979; 
    Grove, 1988a,b), although the distribution of such fibers in the 
    MEA is unclear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Thus, current evidence indicates that the MEAad and 
    MEApv (and possibly the MEAav), along with parts of the BST densely 
    innervated by these parts of the MEA (interfascicular and 
    transverse nuclei) and certain regions of the caudal substantia 
    innominata, are highly interrelated, forming part of a circuit 
    distinct from that associated with the MEApd.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Because the MEAad projects heavily to the central 
    nucleus of the amygdala, it is interesting that the MEAad also 
    projects to caudal regions of the anterolateral part of the BST, 
    which also receives a dense input from the central nucleus (Krettek 
    and Price, 1978a; Sun et al., 1991).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">We confirmed (Caffe et al., 1987; Gomez and Newman, 
    1992) a projection from the MEA to the lateral septal nucleus, 
    although it is markedly sparser than that to the BST.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">This projection is distributed mainly to the 
    intermediate and ventral parts of the lateral septal nucleus, and 
    appears to arise mainly within the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Some of these fibers may be vasopressinergic (Caffe et 
    al., 1987).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Inputs to the ventral striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Rostral to the septum, the striatal fundus and olfactory 
    tubercle polymorphic layer receive substantial inputs from the 
    MEAad, and it also projects lightly to the caudal shell of the 
    nucleus accumbens (Zahm and Brog, 1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Projections from the rostral MEA to the striatal fundus 
    and olfactory tubercle have been seen in the hamster by Gomez and 
    Newman (1992), who reported a dense projection to the shell of the 
    nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">A sparse projection in the rat is supported by a few 
    retrogradely labeled cells in the rat MEA after fluorogold 
    injections in the shell region (Brog et al., 1993).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">In addition to a direct projection to the ventral 
    striatum, information processed in the MEA may be conveyed to the 
    striatum indirectly via a projection to the basomedial nucleus of 
    the amygdala, which provides a major input to the striatum (Kelley 
    et al., 1982; Brog et al., 1993).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Projections to the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Different parts of the MEA provide distinct inputs to 
    the hypothalamus, confirming and extending work in the hamster 
    (Gomez and Newman, 1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Overall, the MEA generates dense inputs to the entire 
    extent of the hypothalamic medial zone.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">A projection from the MEA to medial parts of thepreoptic 
    region is well established (Keveter and Winans, 1981; Berk and 
    Finkelstein, 1981; Simerly and Swanson, 1986; Caffe et al., 1987; 
    Maragos et al., 1989; Simerly et al., 1989; Gomez and Newman, 
    1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Our results indicate that the caudal pole of the medial 
    preoptic nucleus (mainly the caudal end of the lateral part of the 
    nucleus) receives a dense input from all parts of the MEA, although 
    more rostrally, different parts of the MEA generate distinct 
    projections within this general area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">In the rostral 2/3 of the preoptic region the MEAad 
    projects very densely to undifferentiated zones of the medial 
    preoptic area and the lateral medial preoptic nucleus, in contrast 
    to the MEApd, which innervates densely the central and medial parts 
    of the medial preoptic nucleus, and the anteroventral 
    periventricular nucleus; remarkably, fibers arising in other parts 
    of the MEA clearly avoid the latter.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">A differential pattern of inputs to medial parts of the 
    hamster preoptic region from anterior and posterodorsal parts of 
    the MEA was reported by Gomez and Newman (1992), although their 
    cytoarchitectonic parcellation of the preoptic region differs from 
    ours.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">We also observed that the MEApv, which was not 
    investigated specifically by Gomez and Newman (1992), projects 
    densely to the caudal pole of the medial preoptic nucleus, but 
    unlike other parts of the MEA supplies many fewer axons to rostral 
    levels of the medial preoptic region.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">At the anterior hypothalamic level, the MEApv supplies 
    dense inputs to the rostral pole, central, and posterior parts of 
    the anterior hypothalamic nucleus, retrochiasmatic area, 
    perisuprachiasmatic region, and subparaventricular zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">A similar but sparser projection to the anterior 
    hypothalamic level was also observed from the MEAad, in contrast to 
    the MEApd, which supplied a modest number of terminals to this 
    hypothalamic level.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">The projection from the MEA to the anterior hypothalamic 
    level has not been examined with retrograde axonal tracers, 
    although similar results were reported by Gomez and Newman 
    (1992).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">At tuberal levels, it is clear that the MEA projects 
    topographically to the ventromedial and adjacent tuberal nuclei 
    (Krettek and Price, 1978a; Post and Mai, 1980; Berk and 
    Finkelstein, 1981; Kevetter and Winans, 1981; Kita and Oomura, 
    1982; Zaborszky, 1982; Luiten et al., 1983; Ono et al., 1985; 
    Luiten et al., 1985; Caffe et al., 1987; Fahrbach et al., 1989; 
    Simerly et al., 1989; Gomez and Newman, 1992).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Earlier work in the rat (Krettek and Price, 1978a; Post 
    and Mai, 1980) suggested that the MEA projects preferentially to 
    the cellular core of the ventromedial nucleus, although injection 
    sites in these studies did not label specific parts of the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Gomez and Newman (1992) later emphasized that anterior 
    regions of the hamster MEA, including the MEAav and MEAad, 
    innervate preferentially the core of the ventromedial nucleus, 
    whereas the MEApd innervates primarily the surrounding capsule.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Our results indicate that the rat MEAad projects more 
    densely to the capsule than to the core, and the MEAav provides 
    especially dense inputs to the core of the nucleus (especially 
    ventrally and dorsomedially).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">The MEApv projects massively to both core and capsule, 
    although MEApv fibers clearly tend to avoid the ventrolateral part 
    of the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">In contrast to all the other parts of the MEA, the MEApd 
    projects only sparsely to the VMH, where labeled axons were 
    observed mainly in capsular regions associated with the 
    ventrolateral and central parts of the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">A similar pattern of inputs from the MEApd to the 
    ventromedial nucleus was reported in the hamster (see Fig. 10B in 
    Gomez and Newman, 1992).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">As in other PHAL work (Caffe et al., 1987; Gomez and 
    Newman, 19921, we observed sparse to moderate inputs from the whole 
    MEA to the dorsomedial nucleus and periventricular zone, where 
    labeled terminals were found in the intermediate periventricular 
    and arcuate nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">All parts of the MEA project densely to the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus and adjacent ventral regions of the posterior 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">A robust projection to the posterior periventricular 
    nucleus was also seen at this level, especially with PHAL 
    injections in the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">A projection to the ventral premammillary nucleus has 
    been reported (Krettek and Price, 1978a; Post and Mai, 1980; 
    Kevetter and Winans, 1981; Luiten et al., 1985; Caffe et al., 1987; 
    Gomez and Newman, 1992), and our work indicates that the MEApd 
    supplies the most fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">This is confirmed by retrograde tracing experiments 
    where more retrogradely labeled cells are seen in the MEApd than 
    other parts of the MEA after fluorogold deposits in the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus (N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Our results also indicate that caudal to the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus, labeled axons from the MEA innervate the 
    cell-sparse capsule around the medial mammillary nucleus 
    (containing distal dendrites of medial mammillary neurons; Cajal, 
    19091911) and the supramammillary nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">In summary, one of the most interesting features of 
    projections from the MEA to the hypothalamus is the striking 
    difference between those arising in the MEApd and those arising in 
    other parts of the nucleus: the former supplies dense inputs to the 
    anteroventral periventricular nucleus, central and medial parts of 
    the medial preoptic nucleus, and ventral premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Singificantly, both the principal nucleus of the BST and 
    posterior nucleus of the amygdala, which together with the MEApd 
    form part of a highly interconnected circuit in the basal 
    telencephalon (above), generate very similar hypothalamic 
    innervation patterns (Simerly et al., 1989; Canteras et al., 
    1992a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">The hypothalamic sites (anteroventral periventricular 
    nucleus, central and medial parts of the medial preoptic nucleus, 
    and ventral premammillary nucleus) associated with this set of 
    basal telencephalic nuclei are also highly interconnected and are 
    characterized by dense inputs to components of the hypothalamic 
    periventricular zone including parvicellular parts of the 
    paraventricular nucleus, intermediate periventricular nucleus, and 
    arcuate nucleus (Simerly and Swanson, 1988; Canteras et al., 
    1992b), which contain cells that express hypothalamic releasing 
    hormones and project to the median eminence neurohemal zone (see 
    Swanson, 1987).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">The MEApd, posterior nucleus of the amygdala, and 
    principal nucleus of the BST also receive strong feedback 
    projections from their affiliated hypothalamic targets, especially 
    the ventral premammillary nucleus and central medial preoptic 
    nucleus (Simerly and Swanson, 1988; Canteras et al., 1992b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">This hodological evidence reinforces the view of a 
    distinct circuit within the basal telencephalon that includes the 
    MEApd, posterior nucleus of the amygdala, and principal nucleus of 
    the BST, that is extended to include certain hypothalamic nuclei 
    (especially the anteroventral periventricular, medial preoptic, and 
    ventral premammillary nuclei), and that plays a significant role in 
    controlling the output of the neuroendocrine system.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Furthermore, the ventral premammillary nucleus also 
    receives a less dense input from other parts of the MEA and may 
    thus represent an interface between the two differentiated 
    subsystems associated with the MEA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Along with a projection to the ventral premammillary 
    nucleus, the MEAad projects densely to other hypothalamic medial 
    zone regions including the undifferentiated medial preoptic area, 
    lateral medial preoptic nucleus, anterior hypothalamic nucleus, 
    capsule of the ventromedial nucleus, and tuberal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">The MEApv also projects to medial zone nuclei at 
    preoptic, anterior, and tuberal levels, although the overall 
    pattern of terminal fields is distinct from that from the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Most obviously, the MEApv projects much less to the 
    medial preoptic region and projects significantly to the anterior 
    hypothalamic nucleus, and dorsomedial and ventrolateral 
    ventromedial nucleus (and its capsule).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Previous hodological work suggests that hypothalamic 
    medial zone structures receiving dense inputs from the MEAad and 
    MEApv are involved in two partly segregated intrahypothalamic 
    circuits.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">One includes the undifferentiated part of the medial 
    preoptic area and lateral medial preoptic nucleus, along with the 
    ventrolateral part of the the ventromedial nucleus and tuberal 
    nucleus, and the other includes the anterior hypothalamic nucleus 
    and dorsomedial and central parts of the ventromedial nucleus 
    (Simerly and Swanson, 1988; Canteras et al., 1994; Risold et al., 
    1994).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Interestingly, the MEAad heavily innervates the former 
    circuit, whereas the MEApv innervates preferentially the latter.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">The specific functional roles played by these two medial 
    hypothalamic circuits are still unclear, although considerable 
    evidence suggests that the former helps mediate reproductive 
    behavior, whereas the latter circuit appears essential for the 
    expression of defensive/ aggressive behavior (see Lehman et al., 
    1980; Simerly and Swanson, 1988; Canteras et al., 1994; Risold et 
    al., 1994).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Apart from the ventral premammillary nucleus, all of the 
    hypothalamic medial zone targets of the MEAad and MEApv send a 
    massive, topographically organized projection to the periaqueductal 
    gray, which is known to play a pivotal role in the expression of 
    several motivated behaviors (see Simerly and Swanson, 1988; Rizvi 
    et al., 1992; Canteras et al., 1994; Risold et al., 1994).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">The evidence thus indicates that the MEApd is associated 
    with parts of the hypothalamus involved most directly with 
    neuroendocrine regulation, whereas the MEAad, MEApv, and perhaps 
    MEAav, project to hypothalamic medial zone regions involved in 
    mediating reproductive and defensive behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Thus, it may be convenient to divide provisionally the 
    MEA into two broad divisions, ventral and dorsal.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">The dorsal division includes the MEApd, and its major 
    descending projections to the hypothalamus end in the anteroventral 
    periventricular nucleus, medial and central parts of the medial 
    preoptic nucleus, and ventral premammillary nucleus, which play a 
    major role in neuroendocrine regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">The ventral division of the MEA includes the MEAad, 
    MEAav, and MEApv, and its major projections to the hypothalamus end 
    in medial zone nuclei related primarily to modulating reproductive 
    and defensive behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">It is possible that the ventral division is further 
    divided into parts that related more to reproductive (MEAad) or 
    aggressive (MEAav and MEApv) behavior (the MEAav innervates 
    dorsomedial and ventral parts of the ventromedial nucleus, like the 
    MEApv).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">The ventromedial nucleus receives a massive input from 
    the ventral component of the MEA, and projects massively to the 
    same parts of the BST (especially transverse and fascicular nuclei) 
    and substantia innominata that receive inputs from the ventral 
    component (Grove, 1988a; Canteras et al., 1994).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Whereas the ventromedial nucleus does not project 
    substantially to the MEA, its amygdalar projections resemble those 
    described here for the MEAad and MEApv (Canteras et al., 1994).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Thus, the ventromedial nucleus may provide feedback 
    information to the basal telencephalic nuclei associated with the 
    ventral component of the MEA, just as the ventral premammillary 
    nucleus may provide feedback information to basal telencephalic 
    nuclei associated with the dorsal component (see above).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Confirming Gomez and Newman (1992) in the hamster, a 
    projection was observed from the MEAad to a caudal region of the 
    lateral hypothalamic area adjacent to the cerebral peduncle.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">This region receives olfactory information from several 
    terminal fields of the lateral olfactory tract (Price et al., 
    19911, and an input from the central nucleus of the amygdala 
    (Krettek and Price, 1978a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Projections to the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Significant projections to the thalamus, mainly directed 
    toward the midline nuclei, were found after injections centered in 
    the MEAad and MEApv, in contrast to the MEApd, which projects 
    lightly to the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">After MEAad injections, we observed a strikingly dense 
    plexus of labeled fibers in rostroventral parts of the nucleus 
    reuniens, a substantial projection to the paraventricular and 
    medial part of the mediodorsal nuclei, and a sparse input to the 
    parataenial nucleus, lateral habenula, and subparafascicular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">The pattern of thalamic inputs from the MEApv is 
    reminiscent of that just described from the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">The MEApv also provides a significant, but far less 
    dense, projection to the rostroventral nucleus reuniens, and a very 
    sparse input to the paraventricular nucleus, although it does not 
    appear to innervate the mediodorsal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Projections from the MEA to the nucleus reuniens, 
    paraventricular nucleus, and medial mediodorsal nucleus have been 
    labeled in retrograde tracer experiments (Siege1 et al., 1977; 
    Herkenham, 1978; McDonald, 1987; Chen and Su, 19901, and a similar 
    pattern of thalamic projections from rostral parts of the MEA was 
    reported in the hamster (Gomez and Newman, 1992).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">As discussed, the MEA projects directly to several areas 
    of the hippocampal formation, and another potentially significant 
    way for the MEA to access the hippocampal formation is by way of 
    inputs from the nucleus reuniens (Herkenham, 1978; Wyss et al., 
    1979; Swanson et al., 1987; Su and Bentivoglio, 1990; Wouterlood et 
    al., 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Similar labeling patterns in the nucleus reuniens arise 
    in the anterior and ventromedial hypothalamic nuclei (Canteras et 
    al., 1994; Risold et al., 19941, which constitute major 
    hypothalamic recipients of projections from the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Other midline thalamic nuclei receiving inputs from the 
    MEA, especially the paraventricular nucleus, confirm important 
    indirect links between the MEA and nucleus accumbens (Su and 
    Bentivoglio, 1990; Berendse and Groenewegen, 19901, even if direct 
    projections from the MEA to this part of the ventral striatum are 
    limited.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Finally, inputs to the medial mediodorsal nucleus may 
    provide an indirect route for MEA information to reach the 
    prefrontal cortex (Groenewegen, 1988).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Projections to the bruinstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">The MEA provides limited inputs to the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Our work revealed a small group of axons from the MEA 
    that courses through (and to) the posterior hypothalamic nucleus 
    into periependymal regions of the periaqueductal gray; some of 
    these fibers, especially from the MEAad and MEApv, provide a sparse 
    input to the dorsal raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Projections from the MEA to the periaqueductal gray and 
    dorsal raphe nucleus have been reported (Caffe et al., 1987).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">After PHAL injections in the MEAad we also found that 
    some axons coursing through the lateral hypothalamic area extend 
    caudally into the midbrain, where they provide a sparse input to 
    the ventral tegmental area, and to the interfascicular, rostral 
    linear, and central linear raphe nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s334">Possible 
    neurotransmitters</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Several neuropeptides are expressed by MEA neurons: 
    cholecystokinin (Roberts et al., 1982; Simerly and Swanson, 1987; 
    Micevych et al., 1988; Simerly et al., 19891, substance P (Roberts 
    et al., 1982; Simerly et al., 19891, vasopressin (Caffe and Van 
    Leeuwen, 1983; Urban et al., 1990), corticotropin releasing hormone 
    (Swanson et al., 1983; Sakanaka et al., 19861, angiotensin (Lind 
    and Ganten, 1990), somatostatin (Roberts et al., 1982; McDonald, 
    19891, and neuropeptide Y (McDonald, 1989); and some differences 
    between the hamster and rat have been reported.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Many MEA neurons in the hamster but not rat express 
    tyrosine hydroxylase (Asmus et al., 1992) and prodynorphin (Neal et 
    al., 1989).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Importantly, cholecystokinin, substance P, and 
    angiotensin are expressed almost entirely within the MEApd (Simerly 
    and Swanson, 1987, Simerly et al., 1989, Lind and Ganten, 19901, 
    whereas neurons expressing corticotropin releasing hormone are 
    mainly distributed throughout other parts of the nucleus (Swanson, 
    et al., 1983; Sakanaka et al., 1986).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">In contrast, neurons expressing somatostatin and 
    neuropeptide Y apparently display little preferential distribution 
    within the nucleus (McDonald, 1989), and vasopressin is localized 
    primarily to the MEAad (Urban et al., 1990).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">MEA neurons expressing cholecystokinin, substance P, and 
    somatostatin project to the hypothalamus, and those expressing 
    somatostatin probably innervate the BST as well (McDonald, 1987; 
    Simerly et al., 1989).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Vasopressinergic neurons in the MEA project to the 
    lateral septa1 nucleus and ventral hippocampus (Caffe et al., 
    1987).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Most of the peptides just listed also are expressed in 
    parts of the BST that receive massive inputs from the MEA (Woodhams 
    et al., 1983; Ju et al., 1989).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">In particular, the principal nucleus of the BST and the 
    MEApd, which share massive bidirectional connections, contain many 
    neurons expressing cholecystokinin (Ju et al., 1989; Simerly et 
    al., 1989).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Many neurons throughout the MEA express glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase (GAD) mRNA (Okamura et al., 1990) and almost 
    certainly contribute to the dense GABAergic innervation of the BST 
    (see Sun and Cassell, 1993).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">It has also been suggested that certain fibers arising 
    in the MEA contain high levels of zinc (Perez-Claussell et al., 
    1989), which may be associated with pools of excitatory amino acid 
    neurotransmitters (Frederickson and Danscher, 1990).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s345">Neural inputs to the 
    MEA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">The MEA receives its major neuronal input from the 
    accessory olfactory bulb and is thus dominated by pheromonal inputs 
    from the vomeronasal organ (above).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Three other regions are also innervated directly by the 
    accessory olfactory bulb (Scalia and Winans, 1975), and each 
    projects to the MEA as well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">These regions include the bed nucleus of the accessory 
    olfactory tract (Ottersen, 19821, posteromedial cortical nucleus 
    (Ottersen, 1982; Canteras et al., 1992a), and BST (Swanson and 
    Cowan, 1979; Ottersen, 1980).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">It was noted above that several areas receiving direct 
    input from the main olfactory bulb project to the MEA (anterior and 
    posterolateral cortical nucleus, piriformamygdaloid area, and 
    perhaps piriform area andlor the associated endopiriform 
    nucleus).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Except for the accessory bulb, there is limited 
    information about the possible topographic distribution of these 
    olfactory-related inputs to the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">However, most appear to be widely distributed, except 
    for the anterior and posterolateral cortical nucleus, which project 
    much more strongly to the MEAad, and the main olfactory bulb, which 
    at most innervates the rostral tip of the MEAad.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Considered together, the evidence suggests that the MEA 
    receives inputs from both the accessory (direct) and main 
    (indirect) olfactory bulbs, and sends centrifugal projections back 
    to many regions along these two interrelated sensory systems.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">The MEAad and MEApv also receive inputs from the ventral 
    subiculum (Ottersen, 1982; Canteras and Swanson, 19921, and project 
    to the ventral subiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">These bidirectional projections interrelate the ventral 
    division of the MEA with the intrahippocampal circuit (see Swanson 
    et al., 1987) and could thus play a role in learning and memory 
    associated with behaviors mediated in part by the MEA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Many subcortical regions project to the MEA, and with 
    several important exceptions, all of them receive inputs from the 
    MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">In or adjacent to the telencephalon, the substantia 
    innominata projects to the MEA (Ottersen, 1980; Grove, 1988b1, as 
    do the closely associated magnocellular preoptic nucleus (Swanson, 
    1976; Ottersen, 1980) and lateral preoptic area (Swanson, 1976; 
    Ottersen, 1980; Simerly and Swanson, 19881.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">These projections appear to be relatively weak.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Furthermore, parts of the BST receiving inputs from the 
    MEA send fibers back to the MEA (Swanson and Cowan, 1979; Ottersen, 
    1980), although the topography and strength of BST-MEA projections 
    are unclear.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Except for the anteroventral periventricular nucleus 
    (Simerly and Swanson, 19881, parts of the hypothalamus receiving 
    inputs from the MEA also project to the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">This includes a projection from the central medial 
    preoptic nucleus to the MEApd (see Ottersen, 1980; Simerly and 
    Swanson, 19881, a light projection from the anterior nucleus 
    (primarily the central part) to all parts of the MEA (Conrad and 
    Pfaff, 1976; Risold, et al., 19941, a light projection from all 
    parts of the ventromedial nucleus to all parts of the MEA (Conrad 
    and Pfaff, 1976; Saper et al., 1976; Krieger et al., 1979; Canteras 
    et al., 19941, a light projection from the tuberal nucleus to all 
    parts of the MEA (Ottersen, 1980; Canteras et al., 19941, a dense 
    projection from the ventral premammillary nucleus to the MEApd 
    (Canteras et al., 1992a), a projection from the arcuate and 
    posterior periventricular nuclei to the MEApd (Krieger et al., 
    1979; Ottersen, 19801, and a projection from the posterior nucleus 
    (Ottersen, 1980).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Two thalamic regions innervate the MEA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">First, the MEAad in particular projects to the 
    paraventricular and parataenial nuclei and nucleus reuniens, and 
    all three send a light project,ion to most of the MEA Weening, 
    1978; Ottersen and Ben-Ari, 1979; Ohtake and Yamada, 1989).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">And second, a very heterogeneous region surrounding the 
    ventral nucleus of the medial geniculate body, including the 
    parvicellular subparafascicular nucleus, peripeduncular nucleus, 
    medial nucleus of the medial geniculate body, suprageniculate 
    nucleus, and posterior complex contains retrogradely labeled 
    neurons after HRP injections in the MEA (Ottersen and Ben-Ari, 
    19791, and projections from this general region have been confirmed 
    anterogradely (Jones et al., 1976; LeDoux et al., 1990a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">This general region is not innervated by the MEA and may 
    relay auditory, tactile, nociceptive, and/or thermal information to 
    the MEA (see Bordi and LeDoux, 1994; Dado et al., 1994), including 
    sensory information related to sexual behavior (see L6pez and 
    Carrer, 1985).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Brainstem inputs to the MEA are limited.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Medial regions of the lateral parabrachial nucleus 
    project to the MEA (Saper and Loewy, 1980; Ottersen, 1981; Bernard 
    et al., 1993), a pathway that, along with one from the region 
    around the medial geniculate body, may relay sensory information 
    from the spinal cord to the MEA (including from the genital region; 
    Rowe and Erskine, 1993).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">In addition, the parabrachial nucleus probably relays 
    information from the vagus and/or glossopharyngeal nerves to the 
    MEA (Herbert and Saper, 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Sparse inputs to the MEA also arise in the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus and superior central nucleus (Azmitia and Segal, 1978; 
    Ottersen, 19811, and in the locus ceruleus (Jones and Moore, 
    1977).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Broadly speaking, the MEA receives massive inputs from 
    the olfactory system, and modest inputs from parts of the basal 
    telencephalic nuclei that receive inputs from the amygdala, from 
    parts of the hypothalamus involved in modulating the neuroendocrine 
    system as well as sexual and agonistic behaviors, and from parts of 
    the thalamus and dorsal pons that relay somatic and visceral 
    information from the spinal cord and from the 9th and 10th cranial 
    nerves.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Seemingly light projections also arise in the midline 
    thalamus, and in certain aminergic brainstem cell groups, including 
    the midbrain raphe and locus ceruleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s371">Hormonal regulation of 
    MEA circuitry: sexual dimorphism</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">The MEA contains a substantial population of neurons 
    concentrating estrogen and/or testosterone (Pfaff and Keiner, 1973; 
    Sar and Stumpf, 19751, and mRNAs encoding the androgen and estrogen 
    receptors are expressed at relatively high levels (Simerly et al., 
    1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Neurons throughout the nucleus express abundant androgen 
    receptor mRNA, whereas estrogen receptor mRNA is abundant in the 
    MEApd, and weakly expressed elsewhere in the nucleus (Simerly et 
    al., 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">As in most other parts of the CNS that express estrogen 
    receptor, the MEA displays clear structural and biochemical sexual 
    dimorphisms induced by gonadal steroid hormones during a perinatal 
    critical period (Segovia and Guillamon, 1993).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">The MEA is some 20% larger in males, although sex 
    differences in volume are maximal in the MEApd, which may be about 
    twice as large in males (Hines eta]., 1992).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Gonadal steroids influence the expression of peptides, 
    including cholecystokinin (Simerly and Swanson, 1987; Micevych et 
    al., 1988, Oro et al., 1988; Simerly et al., 19891, vasopressin (De 
    Vries et al., 1985; De Vries and Al Shamma, 1990; Urban et al., 
    19911, and somatostatin (Baldino et al., 19881, in MEA 
    perikarya.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">In male and female rats, gonadal steroids increase 
    levels of cholecystokinin peptide and mRNA, and this effect occurs 
    within physiological limits because cholecystokinin levels vary 
    systematically during the estrous cycle (Simerly et al., 1987; Oro 
    et al., 1988).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Furthermore, at least some neurons in the MEApd that 
    project to the medial preoptic nucleus coexpress cholecystokinin 
    and substance P, and estrogen influences levels of 
    preprocholecystokinin mRNA but not preprotachykinin (which encodes 
    substance P) mRNA in these neurons (Simerly et al., 1989).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">This evidence suggests that the ratio of cholecystokinin 
    and substance P within individual neurons of the MEApd that project 
    to the hypothalamus varies systematically during the estrous cycle, 
    and that such biochemical switching may play a role in altering the 
    flow of information through sexually dimorphic circuitry.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Several MEA targets also contain many gonadal 
    steroidconcentrating neurons (Pfaff and Keiner, 1973; Sar and 
    Stumpf, 19751, express mRNAs encoding the androgen and/or estrogen 
    receptors (Simerly et al., 19901, and display structural and/or 
    biochemical sex differences (see Simerly and Swanson, 1988; 
    Canteras et al., 1992b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">In rodents, these regions are dominated by inputs from 
    the vomeronasal organ, are highly interconnected, and have been 
    referred to as the sexually dimorphic circuit (see Simerly et al., 
    1989).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Targets of MEA projections that are clearly part of this 
    sexually dimorphic circuit include the accessory olfactory bulb; 
    principal nucleus of the BST and ventral lateral septa1 nucleus; 
    and medial preoptic, anteroventral periventricular, ventromedial, 
    and ventral premammillary nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">As with the MEApd, the principal nucleus of the BST 
    contains more cholecystokinin and substance P cell bodies in males 
    (Micevych et al., 1988; Simerly et a]., 1989); it is about twice as 
    large in males (Hines et a]., 1992); and gonadal steroids influence 
    cholecystokinin but not substance P levels (Simerly et al., 
    1989).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">The MEApd and principal nucleus of the BST contain 
    neurons where testosterone is not converted to estrogen, implying 
    that these cell groups are important for direct influences of 
    androgen on the rat brain (Sheridan, 1979).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">The medial preoptic nucleus also receives a massive 
    input from the MEA, and levels of cholecystokinin are increased in 
    this sexually dimorphic nucleus by gonadal steroids (see Oro et 
    al., 1988).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">We have not examined MEA projections in female rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Previous anatomical studies in the medial preoptic 
    nucleus and elsewhere suggest that the sexually dimorphic circuit 
    is qualitatively similar in both sexes, while presenting 
    quantitative differences in particular cell groupsiterminal fields 
    (Simerly and Swanson, 1988).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s388">The extended amygdala</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Many attempts have been made over the years to clarify 
    fundamental organizing principles of the basal telencephaIon, that 
    is, the noncortical basal nuclei or ganglia as a whole.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">The extended amygdala concept has proven useful recently 
    in focusing attention on one aspect of this problem (deOlmos et 
    al., 1985; Heimer et al., 1985; Alheid and Heimer, 1988; Alheid et 
    al., 1995).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">According to this view, a continuous region with caudal 
    and rostral poles, and separate dorsal and ventral bands of neurons 
    connecting them, forms a recognizable structural system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">The caudal pole of the extended amygdala includes the 
    medial and central nuclei of the amygdala, the rostral pole 
    includes medial and lateral regions of the BST, the dorsal bridge 
    includes scattered neurons along the stria terminalis (the stria1 
    extension of the BST), and the ventral bridge includes scattered 
    neurons in approximately the caudal (sublenticular) half of the 
    substantia innominata along parts of the ansa peduncularis 
    containing axons from the medial and central amydgalar nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">There are two other important features of this 
    concept.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">First, it has been suggested that in lower vertebrates 
    (and perhaps early in mammalian development) the central and medial 
    amygdalar nuclei are connected with the BST through a continuous 
    longitudinal association bundle, which is split in mammals into 
    dorsal and ventral components by passage of the internal capsule as 
    it expands along with the cortical mantle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">And second, it has been suggested that the extended 
    amygdala can be divided into two parts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">One is a continuous band of similar neurons in the 
    medial amygalar nucleus, ventromedial regions of the sublenticular 
    substantia innominata, and medial regions of the BST (the medial 
    amygdaloid group ), whereas the other is an adjacent, continuous 
    band of neurons in the central amygdalar nucleus, dorsolateral 
    regions of the sublenticular substantia innominata, and lateral 
    regions of the BST (the central amygdaloid group ).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Several lines of evidence favor this hypothesis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">First, Johnston (1923) described a phylogenetically 
    ancient and conserved bed of the stria terminalis, which develops 
    in the ventral striatal (ventricular) ridge and forms a continuous 
    group of scattered neurons along the stria terminalis from the 
    central and medial amygdalar nuclei caudally, to the BST, nucleus 
    accumbens, and anterior olfactory nucleus rostrally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">In addition to the stria terminalis, he described a 
    ventral fiber system associated with the amygdala that he viewed as 
    a rostral extension of the amygdalo-piriform association bundle 
    coursing through Meynert s (1872) ansa peduncularis (Johnston s 
    deep gray of the diagonal band, and our caudal substantia 
    innominata) to the basal forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Second, it has been claimed that the medial and central 
    amygdaloid groups are each characterized by a similar cell type.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Third, the medial and central amygdaloid groups are 
    interconnected.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Fourth, it has been suggested that the afferent and 
    efferent connections of each group may be rather uniform.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">This is especially clear for the central amygdaloid 
    group, all three parts of which project to certain 
    autonomic-related parts of the brainstem, and receive inputs from 
    them.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">And fourth, the two amygdaloid groups may be 
    characterized by certain histochemical features.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">For example, the cupric silver impregnation method is 
    said to delimit the central amygdaloid group.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">There are, however, several problems with the extended 
    amygdala concept as now understood.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">First, the substantia innominata in the modern sense 
    (e.g., Nauta and Haymaker, 1969; Jones et al., 1976; Swanson, 1992) 
    has been divided into a rostral, subcommissural, part referred to 
    as the ventral pallidum (Heimer and Wilson, 1975; Heimer, 1978), 
    and a caudal, sublenticular, part referred to as the sublenticular 
    part of the extended amygdala (deOlmos et al., 1985; Alheid and 
    Heimer, 1988).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">This division was based on two observations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Initially, Heimer and Wilson (1975) made the important 
    point that the ventral striatum (the nucleus accumbens and 
    olfactory tubercle) projects to the ventral pallidum, rostroventral 
    to the traditional globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">This result was based on the silver degeneration method, 
    which showed that lesions of the ventral striatum produced 
    degenerating terminals primarily in subcommissural regions of the 
    substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Then, deOlmos et al. (1985) suggested that cells 
    accompanying the ventral amygdalofugal pathway are located caudal 
    to the ventral pallidum, in sublenticular parts of the substantia 
    innominata, which they referred to as part of the extended 
    amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">However, more sensitive tracing methods 
    (autoradiography: Swanson and Cowan, 1975; Mogenson et al., 1983; 
    PHAL: Heimer et al., 1991) have shown that the nucleus accumbens 
    projects topographically to virtually all of the substantia 
    innominata, not just its rostral half.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Similarly, the present results demonstrate that the 
    medial amygdalar nucleus projects not just to the sublenticular 
    half of the substantia innominata, but all the way to its rostral 
    tip; and the same is true for the central amygdaloid nucleus (G.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Petrovich and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Thus, a two-part division of the substantia innominata 
    based on major inputs (from ventral striatum and amygdala) is 
    unjustified, and this is compounded by a lack of evidence for a 
    division based on cytoarchitectonic criteria.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">And while immunohistochemical and other staining 
    gradients in the substantia innominata have been described (see 
    Alheid et al., 1995), none have been used to demonstrate a clear 
    distinction between rostral and caudal divisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">It is also curious that the rostroventral extension of 
    the substantia innominata (the part not actually adjacent to the 
    globus pallidus) has been referred to as the ventral pallidum, 
    whereas the part of the substantia innominata immediately ventral 
    to the globus pallidus has been referred to as a part of the 
    extended amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">A second problem relates to dividing the sublenticular 
    extended amygdala into central (dorsolateral) and medial 
    (ventromedial) parts based on similarities of cell types in 
    associated parts of the amygdala and BST, and on their location 
    around fibers connecting the associated parts.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Thus, while it has been stated that cell types 
    throughout the medial or central amygdalar groups are similar, 
    there are as yet no formal descriptions of these neurons in the 
    substantia innominata, so that uniform cell types within a group 
    have not been established.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">More importantly, the course of axons from the central 
    and medial amygdalar nuclei overlap considerably in the substantia 
    innominata on their way to the BST; they do not define two separate 
    zones within the substantia innominata (present results and 
    unpublished observations by G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Petrovich and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Swanson for the central nucleus).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">At the very caudal end of the substantia innominata, 
    axons from the central nucleus clearly lie dorsolateral to those 
    from the medial nucleus (see Fig. 3, level I), but as these fibers 
    approach the BST (e.g., Fig. 3, levels F, G), they overlap 
    considerably in the substantia innominata, and considerable overlap 
    is also apparent in the rostra1 half of the substantia 
    innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Thus, there are no clear differences between medial and 
    central parts of the extended amygdala in the substantia 
    innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Furthermore, essentially nothing is known about the 
    morphology and connections of neurons throughout most of the stria1 
    extension of the BST along the course of the stria terminalis 
    itself, the dorsal limb of the extended amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">One criterion for distinguishing the central group of 
    the extended amygdala has been the existence of bidirectional 
    pathways with brainstem autonomic regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Thus, a more or less continuous band of retrograde 
    labeling is observed in the central nucleus, sublenticular 
    substantia innominata, and lateral regions of the BST after 
    retrograde tracer injections in the dorsal vagal complex (e.g., 
    Schwaber et al., 1982; Schwanzel-Fukuda et al., 1984; Grove, 1988b) 
    and parabrachial nucleus (Moga et al., 1990).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">However, this labeling is not restricted to dorsolateral 
    parts of the sublenticular substantia innominata (it spreads 
    ventrally, and is in fact more dense ventrally; Grove, 1988b and 
    Fig. 6C therein; Moga et al., 1990), and it spreads medially to 
    involve much of the lateral hypothalamic area and even 
    paraventricular hypothalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Thus, such labeling is not specific for the extended 
    amygdala, unless the term is expanded to include the hypothalamus 
    (and periaqueductal gray more caudally).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">A third problem with the extended amygdala concept is 
    that all parts of the amygdala, except the lateral nucleus, project 
    to the BST (e.g., Krettek and Price, 1978a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">The current view, limiting the extended amygdala to the 
    central and medial nuclei, appears based largely on Johnston s 
    (1923) view that these two nuclei are phylogenetically the oldest 
    parts of the amygdala, and thus associated with the primordial bed 
    of the stria terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">This seems an unnecessarily limiting restriction.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">When other amygdalar projections to the substantia 
    innominata are added to those from the central and medial nuclei, 
    the already incomplete separation of this region into central and 
    medial parts becomes even more blurred, e.g., inputs from the 
    posterior cortical and posterior nuclei are similar, although not 
    identical, to those from the medial nucleus (Canteras et al., 
    1992a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Fourth, the view that the dorsal and ventral arms of the 
    extended amygdala are initially part of a single fiber system (with 
    its bed nucleus) that is later split by the developing internal 
    capsule is provocative but unsupported by available embryological 
    evidence.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Johnston (1923) referred to three distinct olfactory 
    pathways associated with the amygdala (lateral olfactory tract, 
    stria terminalis, and longitudinal association bundle), and during 
    early forebrain vesicle development the stria terminalis extends 
    dorsally along the sulcus terminalis (caudal edge of the 
    telencephalic epithelial lamina), while the ansa peduncularis 
    presumably grows rostroventrally through the pallidal (ventral 
    striatal) ridge (Alvarez-Bollado et al., 1995).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Even the presumed early embryological continuity between 
    the amygala, neurons along the stria terminalis, and the BST, 
    remains to be demonstrated.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Finally, the extended amygdala concept itself might be 
    examined.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">The three distinct parts of the extended amygdala 
    (amygdala, substantia innominata, and BST) are no doubt 
    interconnected, but it is clear that these pathways are part of 
    much larger circuits involving many other parts of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">However, the same logic suggests the existence of an 
    extended hippocampus (with the septal region forming a bed nucleus 
    for the fornix), or even an extended cerebral cortex (with the 
    basal ganglia forming a bed nucleus for the internal capsule).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">A fundamental problem with extending the amygdala, or 
    any other part of the brain, is determining how far to carry the 
    extension in a meaningful way.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">A parsimonious interpretation of the evidence can be 
    based on the fundamental insight that the striatum and pallidum may 
    be divided without clear boundaries into dorsal and ventral regions 
    (Heimer and Wilson, 19751, and that the ventral striatum (nucleus 
    accumbens, striatal fundus, and olfactory tubercle) projects 
    topographically to the whole substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">In this view, the substantia innominata as a whole and 
    the ventral pallidum are synonomous, and different regions of the 
    ventral pallidum may be dominated by topographically organized 
    nonstriatal inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">In contrast, the BST is an important way station along 
    descending pathways from the amygdala, as the adjacent lateral 
    septal nucleus is an important way station along descending 
    pathways from the hippocampal formation, and the striatum is an 
    important way station along descending projections from 
    isocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Stria terminalis, fornix, and internal capsule all 
    contain descending fibers innervating noncortical parts of the 
    cerebral hemispheres.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s446">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s447">This work was supported in 
    part by CNPq Fellowship 200969190-0 and FAPESP Fellowship 8811289-0 
    to N.S.C.; and National Institutes of Health grants NS16686 
    (L.W.S.)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s448">and NS26723 (R.B.S.).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s449">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Alheid, G.F., J.S. de Olmos, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Beltramino (1995) Amygdala and extended amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Paxinos (ed.): The Rat Nervous System, 2nd.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Ed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">San Diego: Academic Press, pp. 495-578.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Alheid, G.F., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Heimer (1988) New perspectives in basal forebrain 
    organization of special relevance for neuropsychiatric disorders: 
    The striatopallidal, amygdaloid, and corticopetal components of 
    substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Neuroscience 27: 1-39.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Alvarez-Bollado, G., M.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Rosenfeld, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Swanson (1995) A model of forebrain regionalization 
    based on spatiotemporal patterns of POU-I11 homeobox gene 
    expression, birthdates, and morphological features.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Neurol. 355t237-295.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Asmus, S.E., A.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Kincaid, and S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Newman (1992) A species-specific population of tyrosine 
    hydroxylase-immunoreactive neurons in the medial amygdaloid nucleus 
    of the Syrian hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Brain Res. 575199207.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Azmitia, E.C., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Segal (1978) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    differential ascending projections of the dorsal and median raphe 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Neural. 179,641-668.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Baldino Jr., F., S.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">McElligott, T.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">O Kane, and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Gazes (1988) Hormonal regulation of somatostatin 
    messenger RNA.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Synapse 2317-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Groenewegen (1990) Organization ofthalamostriatal 
    projections in the rat, with special emphasis on the ventral 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Neural. 299t187-228.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Finkelstein (1981) Afferent projections to the preoptic 
    area and hypothalamic regions in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Neuroscience 6:16011624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Bernard, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">-F., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Alden, and J:M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Besson (1993) The organization of the efferent 
    projections from the pontine parabrachial area to the amygdaloid 
    complex: A Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) study in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Neural. 329t201-229.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Bordi, F., and J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">LeDoux (1994) Response properties of single units in 
    areas of rat auditory thalamus that project to the amygdala. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Cells receiving convergent auditory and somatosensory 
    inputs and cells antidromically activated by amygdala 
    stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Brain Res. 98.275-286.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Brog, J.S., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Salyapongse, A.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Deutch, and D.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Zahm (1993) The patterns of afferent innervation of the 
    core and shell in the accumbens part of the rat ventral striatum: 
    immunohistochemical detection of retrogradely transported 
    Fluoro-Gold.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Neural. 338255-278.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Caffe, A.R., and F.W. van Leeuwen (1983) 
    Vasopressin-immunoreactive cells in the dorsomedial hypothalamic 
    region, medial amygdaloid nucleus and locus ceruleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Cell Tiss.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Res. 233:23-33.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Caffe, A.R., F.W. van Leeuwen, and P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Luiten (1987) Vasopressin cells in the medial amygdala 
    of the rat project to the lateral septum and ventral 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurol. 261.237-252.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Cajal, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Ramon y (1909-191 1) Histologie du systeme nerveux de l 
    homme et des Vertebres.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Paris: Maloine, 2 vols.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Canteras, N.S., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Swanson (1992) Projections of the ventral subiculum to 
    the amygdala, septum, and hypothalamus: A PHAL anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Neurol. 324.180-194.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Swanson (1992a) Connections of the posterior nucleus of 
    the amygdala. 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Neurol. 324t143-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Swanson (199213) Projections of the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Neurol. 324t195-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Swanson (1994) Organization projections from the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus: PHAL study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Neurol. 348t41-79.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Chen, S., and H.3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Su (1990) Merent connections of the thalamic 
    paraventricular and parataenial nuclei in the rat: A retrograde 
    tracing study with iontophoretic application of Fluoro-Gold.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Brain Res. 522:1-6.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Conrad, L.C.A., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Pfaff (1976) Efferent projections from medial basal 
    forebrain and hypothalamus in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">An autoradiographic study of the anterior 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Neurol. 169:221-262.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Dado, R.J., J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Katter, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Giesler (1994) Spinothalamic and spinobypothalamic tract 
    neurons in the cervical enlargements of rats. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Responses to innocuous and noxious mechanical and 
    thermal stimuli.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Neurophysiol. 71:981-1002.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Olmos, J., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Hardy, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Heimer (1978) The afferent connections of the main and 
    accessory olfactory bulb formations in the rat: An experimental 
    HRP-study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Neurol. 181.213-244.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Olmos, J.S., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Beltramino (1985) Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System, Vol. 1, Forebrain 
    and Midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">New York: Academic Press, pp. 223-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Vries, G.J., and H.A. a1 Shamma (1990) Sex differences 
    in hormonal responses of vasopressin pathways in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Neurobiol. 213386-693.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Vries, G.J., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Buijs, F.W. van Leeuwen, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Caffe, and D.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Swaab (1985) The vasopressinergic innervation of the 
    brain in normal and castrated rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Neurol. 233236-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Dunn, J.D., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Whitener (1986) Plasma corticosterone responses to 
    electrical stimulation of the amygdaloid complex: Cytoarchitectural 
    specificity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Neuroendocrinology 4221 1-2 17.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Edwards, D.A., F.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Nahai, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Wright (1993) Pathways linking the olfactory bulbs with 
    the medial preoptic anterior hypothalamus are important for 
    intermale aggression in mice.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Behav. 53.611-615.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Fahrbach, S.E., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Morrell, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Pfaff (1989) Studies of ventromedial hypothalamic 
    afferents in the rat using three methods of HRP application.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Brain Res. 77.221-223.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Feldman, S., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Conforti, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Saphier (1990) The preoptic area and bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis are involved in effects of the amygdala on 
    adrenocortical secretion.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Neuroscience 37t775-779.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Frederickson, C.J., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Danscher (1990) Zinc-containing neurons hippocampus and 
    related CNS structures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Brain Res. 83t71-84.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Frederico, P., W.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Veale, and Q.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Pittman (1992) Vasopressin-induced antipyresis in the 
    medial amygdaloid nucleus of conscious rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Physiol. 262:R901-R908.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Sawchenko (19841 An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-Ll.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Gomez, D.M., and S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Newman (1992) Differential projections of the anterior 
    and posterior regions of the medial amygdaloid nucleus in the 
    Syrian hamster. .J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Neurol. 317t195-218.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Groenewegen, H.J. (19881 Organization of the afferent 
    connections of the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus in the rat, related 
    to the mediodorsalprefrontal topography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Neuroscience 24:379%43 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Grove, E.A. (1988a) Neural associations of the 
    substantia innominata rat: Afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Neurol. 277t315-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Grove, E.A. (1988bl Efferent connections of the 
    substantia the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Neurol. 277:347-364.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Harris, V.S., and B.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Sachs (1975) Copulatory behaviour following amygdaloid 
    lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Brain Res. 86:514-518.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Heimer, L., D.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Zahm, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Churchill, P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Kalivas, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Wohltmann (1991) Specificity in the projection patterns 
    of accumbal core and shell in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Neuroscience 41:89-125.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">Heimer, L. ( 19781 The olfactory cortex and the ventral 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">In: K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Livingstone, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Hornykiewicz (eds): Limbic Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 95-188.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Heimer, L., and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Wilson (19751 The subcortical projections of allocortex: 
    Similarities in the neural associations of the hippocampus, the 
    pyriform cortex and the neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">In: M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Santini (ed): Golgi Centennial Symposium Proceedings.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">New York: Raven Press, pp. 177-193.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Heimer, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Zaborsky (1985) The basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Paxinos (edl: The Rat Nervous System, Vol. 1, Forebrain 
    and Midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">New York: Academic Press, pp. 37-74.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Herbert, H., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Saper (19901 Cholecystokinin-, galanin-, and 
    corticotropin-releasing factor-like immunoreactive projections from 
    the nucleus of the solitary tract to the parabrachial nucleus in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Neurol. 293:58 1-598.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Herkenham, M. (1978) The connections of the nucleus 
    reuniens thalami: evidence for a direct thalamo-hippocampal pathway 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Neurol. 177:589-610.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Hines, M., L.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Allen, and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Gorski (1992) Sex differences in subregions of the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala and the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Brain Res. 579:321-326.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Hsu, S.M., I,.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Raine, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Fanger (1981) The use of avidin-biotinperoxidase complex 
    (ABC) in immunoperoxidase techniques: A comparison between ABC and 
    unlabeled antibody (PAP) procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Cytochem. 29:577-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Johnston, J.B. (1923) Further contributions to the study 
    of the evolution of the forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Neurol. 35:337-481.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Jones, B.J., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Moore (1977) Ascending projections of the locus ceruleus 
    in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Brain Res. 127t23-53.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Jones, E.G., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Burton, C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Saper, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Swanson (1976) Midbrain, diencephalic and cortical 
    relationships of the basal nucleus of Meynert and associated 
    structures in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Neurol. 167:385-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Swanson, and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Simerly (1989) Studies on the cellular architecture of 
    the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Chemoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Neurol. 280:603-621.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Kato, M., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Kakegawa, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Suzuki (1986) Electrical stimulation of several limbic 
    areas suppressed the growth hormone (GH) release induced by human 
    pancreatic GH-releasing factor in pentobarbitalanesthetized 
    rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Endocrinology 118:955-960.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Kelley, A.E., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Nauta (1982) The amygdalostriatal projection in the rat: 
    An anatomical study by anterograde and retrograde tracing 
    methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Neuroscience 7:615-630.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Kevetter, G.A., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Winans (1981) Connections of the corticomedial amygdala 
    in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Efferents of the vomeronasal amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Neural. 197:81-98.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Kita, H., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Oomura (19821 An HRP study of the afferent connections 
    to rat medial hypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Bull. 8:53-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Price (1978a) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">I78t225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Krettek, J.E , and J L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Price (1978bl complex in the rat and cat with 
    observations connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Neurol. 178:255-280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Krieger, M.S., L.C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Conrad, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Pfaff (1979) An autoradiographic study of the efferent 
    connections of the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Neurol. 183:785-816.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">LeDoux, J.E., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Farb, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Ruggero (1990a) Topographic organization of neurons in 
    the acoustic thalamus that project to the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Neurosci., 10: 1043-1054.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">LeDoux, J.E., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Cicchetti, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Xagoraris, and L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Romanski (1990bl The lateral amygdaloid nucleus: Sensory 
    interface of the amygdala in fear conditioning.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Neurosci. 10:1062-1069.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Lehman, M.N., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Winans (1982) Vomeronasal and olfactory pathways to the 
    amygdala controlling male hamster sexual behavior: Autoradiographic 
    and behavioral analyses.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Brain Res. 240:27-41.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Lehman, M.N., S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Winans, and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Powers (1980) Medial nucleus of the amygdala mediates 
    chemosensory control of male hamster sexual behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Science 2IOt557-559.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Levin, B.E. (19911 Defective cerebral glucose 
    utilization obese rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Physiol. 261:R787-R792.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Lind, R.W., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">Ganten (1990) Angiotensin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Kuhar (eds.): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Val. 9, 
    Neuropeptides in the CNS, Part 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 165-286.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Lopez, H.S., and H.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Carrer (1985) Further studies on 
    peripeduncularhypothalamic pathways involved in sexual behavior in 
    the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Neurol. 88:241-252.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Luiten, P.G.M., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Koolhaas, S. de Boer, and S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Koopmans (19851 The corticomedial amygdala in the 
    central nervous system: Organization of agonistic behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Brain Res. 332283-297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Luiten, P.G.M., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Ono, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">Nishijo, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Fukuda (19831 Differential input from the amygdaloid 
    body to the ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Lett. 35.253-258.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Luskin, M.B., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Price (1983) The topographic organization of 
    associational fibers of the olfactory system in the rat including 
    centrifugal fibers to the olfactory bulb.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Neurol. 216:264-291.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Maragos, W.F., S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Newman, M.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Lehman, and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Powers ( 19891 Neurons of origin and fiber trajectory of 
    amygdalofugal projections to the medial preoptic area in the Syrian 
    hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Neurol. 280:5971.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">McDonald, A.J. (1987) Somatostatinergic projections from 
    the amygdala to the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and medial 
    preoptic-hypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Lett. 75:271-277.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">McDonald, A.J. (19891 Coexistence of somatostatin with 
    neuropeptide Y, but not with cholecystokinin or vasoactive 
    intestinal peptide, in neurons of the rat amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Brain Res. 500:3745.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Meynert, T. (1872) The brain of mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">In Strecker, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">(ed): A Manual of Histology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">New York, Wm.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Wood &amp;amp;amp; Co., pp. 650-766.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Micevych, P., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">Akesson, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Elde (1988) Distribution ofcholecystokininimmunoreactive 
    cell bodies in the male and female rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Neurol. 269:381-391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Moga, M.M., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Herbert, K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Hurley, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">Yasui, T.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Gray, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Saper (1990) Organization of cortical, basal forebrain, 
    and hypothalamic afferents to the parabrachial nucleus in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Neurol. 2953524-661.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Mogenson, G.J., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Swanson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Wu (19831 Neural projections from nucleus accumbens to 
    globus pallidus, substantia innominata, and lateral 
    preoptic-lateral hypothalamic area: An anatomical and 
    electrophysiological investigation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Neurosci. 3:189-202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Nauta, W.J.H., and W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">Haymaker (19691 Hypothalamic nuclei and fiber 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">In: W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Haymaker, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">Anderson, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Nauta (edsl: The hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Springfield: Charles C Thomas, pp. 136-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">Neal Jr., C.R., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Swann, and S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Newman (1989) The colocalization of substance P and 
    prodynorphin immunoreactivity in neurons of the medial preoptic 
    area, bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala of the Syrian hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Brain Res. 496:l-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Nishizuka, M., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Arai (1983) Intrinsic connections in the medial amygdala 
    as revealed by complete deafferentation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Lett. 35547-25 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Ohtake, T., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Yamada (19891 Efferent connections of the nucleus 
    reuniens and the rhomboid nucleus in the rat: An anterograde PHA-L 
    tracing study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Res. 6:556-568.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Okamura, H., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Abitbol, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">-F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">Julien, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Dumas, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Berod, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Geffard, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">Kitahama.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Bobillier, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">Mallet, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Wiklund (19901 Neurons containing glutamate 
    decarboxylase in rat hypothalamus demonstrated by in situ 
    hybridization, with special emphasis on cell groups in medial 
    preoptic area, anterior hypothalamic area and dorsomedial 
    hypothalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Neuroscience 393375-699.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Ono, T., P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">Luiten, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Nishijo, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Fukuda, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Nishino Topographic organization of projections from the 
    amygdala hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Res. 2.221-239.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">Oro, A.E., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Swanson (1988) Estrous cycle variations in levels of 
    cholecystokinin immunoreactivity within cells of three 
    interconnected sexually dimorphic forebrain nuclei: Evidence for a 
    regulatoly role for estrogen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Neuroendocrinology 47225-235.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Ottersen, O.P. (1982) Connections of the amygdalaof the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">IV.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Corticoamygdaloid and intraamydaloid connections as 
    studied with axonal transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">Neurol. 205t30-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Ottersen, O.P. (1980) Afferent connections of the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat and cat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Afferents from the hypothalamus and the basal 
    telencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Neurol. 194.267-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">Ottersen, O.P. (1981) Afferent connections to the 
    amygdaloid complex ofthe rat with some observations in the cat. 
    111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Afferents from the lower brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Neurol. 202:335-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Ottersen, O.P., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Ben-Ari (1979) Afferent connections to the amygdaloid 
    complex of the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Projections from the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Neurol. 187:401424.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Perez-Claussell, J., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Frederickson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Danscher (1989) Amygdaloid efferents through the stria 
    terminalis in the rat gives origin to zinccontaining boutons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Neurol. 290:ZOl-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Pfaff, D.W., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Keiner (1973) Atlas of estradiol-concentrating cells in 
    the central nervous system of the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Neurol. 151t121-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Pfaus, J.G., S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Kleopoulos, C.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Mobbs, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Gibbs, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Pfaff (1993) Sexual stimulation activates c-fos within 
    estrogen-concentrating regions of the female rat forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Brain Res. 624.253-267.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Pfeiffer, C.A., and R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Johnston (1994) Hormonal and behavioral responses of 
    male hamsters to females and female odors: Roles of olfaction, the 
    vomeronasal system, and sexual experience.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Behav. 55t129-138.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Post, S., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Mai (1980) Contribution to the amygdaloid projection 
    field in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">A quantitative autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">Hirnforsch. 21t199225.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Price, J.L., B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Slotnick, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">-F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Revial (1991) Olfactory projections to the 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Neur. 306,447461.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">Price, J.L., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Russchen, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Amaral (1987) The limbic region. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">The amygdaloid complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 279-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">Rajendren, G., and R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Moss (1993) The role of the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala in the mating-induced enhancement of lordosis in female 
    rats: The interaction with luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone 
    neuronal system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">Brain Res. 61 7:81-86.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">Risold, P.Y., N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">Canteras, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Swanson (1994) Organization projections from the 
    anterior hypothalamic nucleus: A PHAL study the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">Neurol. 348t140.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Roberts, G.W., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Woodhams, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Polak, and T.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">Crow (1982) Distribution of neuropeptides in the limbic 
    system of the rat: The amygdaloid complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Neuroscience 7r99-131.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">Rowe, D.W., and M.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">Erskine (1993) c-Fos proto-oncogene activity induced by 
    mating in the preoptic area, hypothalamus and amygdala in the 
    female rat: Role of afferent input via the pelvic nerve.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">Brain Res. 621: 25-34.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">Sakanaka, M., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">Shibasaki, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">Lederis (1986) Distribution and efferent projections of 
    corticotropin-releasing factor-like immunoreactivity in the rat 
    amygdaloid complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">Brain Res. 382.213-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">Saper, C.B., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections of the parabrachial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Brain Res. 197:291-317.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Cowan (1976) The efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">Neurol. 169:409442.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Sar, M., and W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Stumpf (1975) Distribution of androgen-concentrating 
    neurons in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">In W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Grant (eds): Anatomical Neuroendocrinology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Basel: Karger, pp. 120-133.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">Scalia, F., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Winans (1975) The differential projections of the 
    olfactory bulb and accessoly olfactory bulb in mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Neurol. 161:31-56.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Schulkin, J., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">Marini, and A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">Epstein (1989) A role for the medial region of the 
    amygdala in mineralocorticoid-induced salt hunger.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Neurosci. 103:178-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">Schwaber, J.S., B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">Kapp, G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Higgins, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">Rapp (1982) Amygdaloid and basal forebrain direct 
    connections with the nucleus of the solitaly tract and the dorsal 
    motor nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">Neurosci. 21424-1439.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">Schwanzel-Fukuda, M., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Morrell, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">Pfaff (1984) Localization of forebrain neurons which 
    project directly to the medulla and spinal cord of the rat by 
    retrograde tracing with wheat germ agglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Neurol. 226:l-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">Segovia, S., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">Guillamon (1993) Sexual dimorphism in the vomeronasal 
    pathway and sex differences in reproductive behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Rev. 18t51-74.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Sheridan, P.J. (1979) The nucleus interstitialis striae 
    terminalis and the nucleus amygdaloideus medialis: Prime targets 
    for androgen in the rat forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">Endocrinology 104: 130-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">Siegel, A., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">Fukushima, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">Meibach, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Burke, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">Edinger, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">Weiner (1977) The origin of the afferent supply to the 
    mediodorsal thalamic nucleus: Enhancement of HRP transport by 
    selective lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">Brain Res. 135t11-23.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Swanson (1986) The organization of neural inputs to the 
    medial preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">Neurol. 246,312-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">Swanson (1987) Castration reversibly alters the level of 
    cholecystokinin immunoreactivity within cells of three 
    interconnected sexually dimorphic forebrain nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">U.S.A. 84.2087-2091.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Swanson (1988) Projections of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus: a Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">Neurol. 270:209-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">Simerly, R.B., B.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">Young, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Capozza, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">Swanson (1989) Estrogen differentially regulates 
    neuropeptide gene expression in a sexually dimorphic olfactory 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">U.S.A. 86,47664770.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Simerly, R.B., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">Chang, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">Muramatsu, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">Swanson (1990) Distribution of androgen and estrogen 
    receptor mRNA-containing cells in the rat brain: An in situ 
    hybridization study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">Neurol. 294t76-95.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">H.S., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Bentivoglio (1990) Thalamic midline cell populations 
    projecting to the nucleus accumbens, amygdala, and hippocampus in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">Neurol. 297:582-593.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Sun, N., and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">Cassell (1993) Intrinsic GABAergic neurons central 
    extended amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Neurol. 330t381-404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Sun, N., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">Roberts, and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Cassell(1991) Rat central amygdaloid nucleus 
    projections to the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">Bull. 27:651-662.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">Swanson, L.W. (1976) An autoradiographic study of the 
    efferent connections of the preoptic region in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Neurol. 167.227-256.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">Swanson, L.W. (1987) The hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 1-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Swanson, L.W. (1992) Brain Maps: Structure of the Rat 
    Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">Amsterdam: Elsevier.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Cowan (1979) The connections of the septa1 region in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">Neurol. 186:621-656.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Cowan (1975) A note on the connections development of 
    the nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">Brain Res. 92324-330.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">Swanson, L.W., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Kohler, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">Bjorklund (1987) The limbic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">The septohippocampal system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">Swanson feds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1064">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 125-277.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1065">Swanson, L.W., P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1066">Sawchenko, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1067">Rivier, and W.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1068">Vale (1983) Organization of ovine 
    corticotropin-releasing factor immunoreactive cells and fibers in 
    the rat brain: An immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1069">Neuroendocrinology 36t165-186.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1070">Tubbiola, M.L., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1071">Nock, and E.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1072">Bittman (1989) Photoperiodic changes in opiate binding 
    and their functional implications in golden hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1073">Brain Res. 503t91-99.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1074">Urban, J.H., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1075">Miller, and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1076">Dorsa (1991) Dexamethasone-induced suppression of 
    vasopressin gene expression in the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis and medial amygdala is mediated by changes in 
    testosterone.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1077">Endocrinology 129:109-116.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1078">Urban, J.H., M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1079">Miller, C.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1080">Drake, and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1081">Dorsa (1990) Detection of vasopressin mRNA in cells of 
    the medial amygdala but not the locus ceruleus by in situ 
    hybridization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1082">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1083">Chem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1084">Neuroanat. 3277-283.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1085">Veening, J.G. (1978) Subcortical afferents of the 
    amygdaloid complex in the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1086">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1087">Lett. 8:196-202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1088">Vochteloo, J.D., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1089">Koolhaas (1987) Medial amygdala lesions in male rats 
    reduce aggressive behavior: Interference with experience.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1090">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1091">Behav. 41:99-102.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1092">Woodhams, P.L., G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1093">Roberts, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1094">Pol&amp;amp;amp;amp;, and T.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1095">Crow (1983) Distribution of neuropeptides in the limbic 
    system of the rat: The bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, septum 
    and preoptic area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1096">Neuroscience 8:677-703.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1097">Wouterlood, F.G., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1098">Saldana, and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1099">Witter (1990) Projection from the nucleus reuniens 
    thalami to the hippocampal region: Light and electron microscopic 
    tracing study in the rat with the anterograde tracer Phaseo/us 
    uulguris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1100">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1101">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1102">Neurol. 296: 179-203.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1103">Wyss, J.M., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1104">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1105">Cowan (1979) A study of subcortical afferents to the 
    hippocampal formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1106">Neuroscience 4:463Zaborszky, L. (1982) Afferent 
    connections of the medial basal hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1107">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1108">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1109">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1110">Cell Biol. 69t1-107.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1111">Zahm, D.S., and J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1112">Brog (1992) Commentary: On the significance of the 
    core-shell boundary in the rat nucleus accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1113">Neuroscience 50:751767.</S>
  </References>

</File>

