<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<File>

  <Title>Connections of the Posterior Nucleus of the Amygdala</Title>

  <Authors>N.S. CANTERAS, R.B. SIMERLY, AND L.W. SWANSON</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The connections of a relatively homogeneous band of 
    neurons in the caudal amygdala have been examined with anterograde 
    and retrograde axonal tracing methods in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">This region, called here the posterior nucleus of the 
    amygdala (PA), corresponds in part to an area that has been 
    referred to as the cortico-amygdaloid transition area, posterior 
    part of the medial nucleus of the amygdala, amygdalo-hippocampal 
    transition area, and posteromedial basal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Experiments with fluorogold and phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHAL) indicate that the major neuronal input to 
    the PA arises in the ventral premammillary nucleus, and that 
    substantial projections also arise in olfactory-related areas such 
    as the medial nucleus of the amygdala, bed nucleus of the accessory 
    olfactory tract, and posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala, as 
    well as in the ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of hippocampal 
    field CAI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Other seemingly minor inputs, including cholinergic fibers 
    from the substantia innominata, dopaminergic fibers from the 
    ventral tegmental area, and serotoninergic fibers from the dorsal 
    nucleus of the raphe, were also identified.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The efferent projections of the PA as determined with the 
    PHAL method appear to follow five major routes: 1) a relatively 
    small group of laterally directed fibers innervates the dorsal 
    endopiriform nucleus, and a few of these fibers reach cortical area 
    TR and the lateral entorhinal area; 2) another small group of 
    fibers courses medially to innervate the ventral subiculum and 
    adjacent parts of field CAI; 3) many fibers course ventrally to 
    innervate the outer molecular layer of the medial part of the 
    posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala; 4) a moderate group of 
    fibers courses rostrally to innervate primarily the posterodorsal 
    part of the medial nucleus of the amygdala, although some fibers 
    continue on to end less densely in rostral parts of the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala before leaving the amygdala through the 
    ansa peduncularis; and 5) the major output of the PA courses 
    through the stria terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">One branch of this pathway massively innervates the 
    principal nucleus of the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis before 
    entering the medial hypothalamus, where it ends massively in the 
    anteroventral periventricular and medial preoptic nuclei, 
    ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus and adjacent parts 
    of the basal lateral hypothalamic area, and ventral premammillary 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The other branch sends fibers to the ventral lateral 
    septal nucleus, nucleus accumbens, olfactory tubercle, and 
    infralimbic area of the prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Projections from control injections of PHAL in distinct 
    parts of the adjacent posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala 
    were also described since they differ significantly from those 
    arising in the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The possible functional significance of the PA was 
    discussed in terms of its connections and the fact that neurons 
    here express high levels of nuclear receptors for gonadal and 
    adrenal steroid (particularly mineralmrticoid) hormones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Potential roles in the expression of behaviors related to 
    salt appetite, reproduction, and aggression are particularly 
    obvious.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">B 1% Wiley-Liss, Inc.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s12">sexually dimorphic circuit</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">While it is widely recognized that the amygdala and 
    hippocampus lie adjacent to one another in ventromedial parts Of 
    the temporal lobe, the region surrounding the junction between them 
    has never been subjected to detailed architectonic O r connectional 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Broadly speaking, this junctional region lies on either 
    side of the angular bundle, and consists of the so-called temporal 
    (or ventral) pole of the hippocampal formation on the one hand, and 
    the caudal pole of the amygdala on the other.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Crosby and Humphrey ( 44) were apparently the first to 
    call particular attention to a relatively small band of neurons 
    just deep to the angular bundle in the caudalmost part of the 
    amygdala of the shrew, and named it the corticoamygdaloid 
    transition area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Several years later, Brodal( 47) pointed in the rat to a 
    similar area, which he regarded as the posterior part of the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">More than 20 years later, Yu ( 69) introduced the term 
    amygdalohippocampal transition area for what appears to be 
    essentially the same structure in the rat, and Scalia and Winans ( 
    75) subsequently proposed yet another interpretation, referring to 
    this general region in the rat, rabbit, and opossum as the 
    posteromedial basal (or B3 ) nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">The fact that the same general area has been regarded in 
    the recent literature as a transitional area, as a part of the 
    medial nucleus, or as a part of the basal nucleus, reflects a lack 
    of knowledge about the fundamental relationship of this area to the 
    rest of the amygdala, and in fact to the rest of the temporal lobe 
    as a whole.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">While the term amygdalohippocampal transition area is 
    perhaps the most widely used at the moment, there seems general 
    agreement that is not necessarily appropriate (e.g., Krettek and 
    Price, 78b; DeOlmos et al., 85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">To shed new light on this problem, we have examined the 
    afferent and efferent connections, as well as the cellular 
    architecture, of this region in some detail (present report), and 
    have compared these results with a reexamination of the output of 
    the ventral subiculum, the most extensive component of adjacent 
    parts of the ventral hippocampal formation (Canteras and Swanson, 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">In addition, since the limits between this zone and the 
    surrounding posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala (COAp) are 
    little understood, in the present study we also reexamine the 
    cytoarchitectonic organization of the COAp and provide a brief 
    account of the outputs of this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">For reasons that will become apparent, we suggest that 
    the region under consideration may be regarded as a distinct 
    component of the deep amygdalar nuclei, and as such propose that 
    the name posterior nucleus of the amygdala (PA) is perhaps more 
    appropriate.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">A preliminary account of this work has been presented 
    elsewhere (Canteras et al., &apos;89).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s24">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Adult male albino rats (275-330 g body weight) 
    Sprague-Dawley strain were used in all experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s26">Cytoarchitecture</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The cytoarchitecture of the PA and of surrounding parts 
    of the temporal region was examined in an adjacent series of 
    thionin-stained frozen sections prepared for each pathway tracing 
    experiment (see below), as well as in a celloidinembedded brain 
    from which 40-km-thick serial frontal sections had been cut, and 
    stained with thionin (Ju and Swanson, &apos;89; Swanson, 
    &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s28">Retrograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Animals were anesthetized with tribromoethanol (0.25 gikg 
    body weight, dissolved in 90: 10 salineiethanol, viv), and 
    unilateral iontophoretic deposits of a 2% solution of fluorogold 
    (Fluorochrome, Inc.; see Schmued and Fallon, &apos;86) in 0.9% 
    saline were placed stereotaxically into the region of the PA (five 
    rats), the medial nucleus of the amygdala (one rat), or ventral 
    parts of the hippocampal formation (one rat).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Deposits were made over 15 minutes through a glass 
    micropipette (tip diameter 25 pm), using a constant-current device 
    (Midgard Electronics, model CS3) set to deliver +5 )*A, with 
    7-second pulse and interpulse durations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">After a survival time of 1 week, the animals were 
    anesthetized deeply with tribromoethanol and perfused 
    transcardially with 100 ml of 0.15 M NaC1, followed immediately by 
    400 ml of 4.0% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The brains were then removed and allowed to postfix 
    overnight in the perfusate with 10% sucrose added.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Three series of 30-km-thick sections were cut on a 
    sliding microtome in the frontal plane and collected at the 
    following frequencies: one-in-ten through the olfactory bulbs and 
    forebrain rostral to the vascular organ of the lamina terminalis; 
    one-in-four through the hypothalamus and rostra1 half of the 
    midbrain; and one-in-ten through the caudal midbrain and 
    hindbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">In one series the sections were mounted onto 
    gelatin-coated slides, and coverslipped with a buffered glycerol 
    mountant (pH 8.5; Hartman, 73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">These slides were kept frozen in the dark at -20°C until 
    observation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">An adjacent series was always stained with thionin to 
    serve as a cytoarchitectonic reference series for the distribution 
    of retrograde labeling.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">A Leitz Dialux 20 microscope equipped with 
    epifluorescence was used for observation and photography of 
    fluorescent material, and the fluorogold was visualized with Leitz 
    filter system A (which provides wide-band W excitation 
    wavelengths).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">For illustration purposes, the location of labeled cells 
    was transferred onto a series of standard drawings of the rat brain 
    (adapted from Swanson, 92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s39">Anterograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Ten animals received an injection of Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHAL; Vector Laboratories) into the region of the 
    PA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Each animal was anesthetized with tribromoethanol, and a 
    single iontophoretic injection of a 2.5% solution of PHAL in 0.1 M 
    sodium phosphate-buffered saline (pH 7.4) (Gerfen and Sawchenko, 
    84) was made over a 15-20 minute period through a stereotaxically 
    positioned glass micropipette (tip diameter 10 km) by applying a +5 
    FA current, pulsed at 7-second intervals, that was provided by a 
    constant-current source (Midgard Electronics, model CS3).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">In addition, six animals received a PHAL deposit in the 
    posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala, and several control 
    injections were also made into various areas that contained 
    retrogradely labeled cells in the animals that had received 
    fluorogold deposits in the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">After a survival period of 14-18 days, the animals were 
    anesthetized deeply with tribromoethanol, and perfused 
    transcardially with 400 ml of ice-cold 4.0% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 
    M sodium borate buffer at pH 9.5; following a brief saline rinse, 
    the brains were removed and postfixed overnight at 4°C in the same 
    fixative containing 10% sucrose.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">The brains were then frozen, and serial sections were 
    collected in the same way as described for the retrograde tracing 
    experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Additional sections were collected through the injection 
    site and quick-stained as described in detail elsewhere (see 
    Simerly and Swanson, 88) to verify the location and size of the 
    PHAL. deposit.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">One complete series of sections was processed for 
    immunohistochemistry with an anti-PHAL serum raised in rabbits 
    (Dako Laboratories), at a dilution of 1:1,000.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">For this series, the primary antiserum was localized by 
    using a variation of the avidinbiotin complex system (ABC; Hsu and 
    Raine, 81; Hsu et al., 81) described in detail by Gerfen and 
    Sawchenko ( 84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">In brief, the sections were incubated for 45 minutes at 
    room temperature in a solution of biotinylated goat anti-rabbit IgG 
    (Vector Labs), and then were placed in the mixed avidin-biotin-HRP 
    complex solution for the same period of time.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The Vectastain Elite ABC Kit was used and the working 
    solution of avidin-biotin-HRP complex was prepared by adding 90 p1 
    of reagent A + 90 111 of reagent B to 10 ml of 0.02 M potassium 
    phosphate-buffered saline at pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The sections were recycled through the biotinylated 
    antibody and the avidin-biotin-HRP complex, and then processed for 
    peroxidase histochemistry by using a 0.05% solution of 
    diaminobenzidine (Polysciences, Inc.).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The sections were mounted on gelatin-coated slides, and 
    the reaction product was intensified by placing the slides in a 
    0.005% aqueous solution of osmium tetroxide for 30 minutes followed 
    by 15 minutes in a 0.05% aqueous solution of thiocarbohydrazide (EM 
    Sciences), and then placed in the osmium solution for an additional 
    30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Slides were then dehydrated and coverslipped with DPX.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">An adjacent series was always stained with thionin to 
    serve as a reference series.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Sections were examined with a Leitz Laborlux D 
    microscope, and PHAL-labeled cells in the injection sites as well 
    as the distribution of anterogradely labeled axons were plotted 
    with the aid of a camera lucida on maps prepared from the adjacent 
    Nissl-stained series.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">For illustration purposes, and to facilitate comparison 
    between different experiments, the distribution pattern of 
    anterogradely labeled fibers in each experiment was transposed onto 
    a series of standard drawings of the rat brain (see above).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s56">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s57">Cytoarchitectonic 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Before describing the results of our experimental work it 
    is necessary to consider in some detail the scheme we have adopted 
    for subdividing the caudal amygdala in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The brief historical summary in the Introduction 
    indicated that the boundaries of what is referred to here as the PA 
    have not been defined precisely or consistently by earlier workers, 
    and the same general problem (including differences in 
    nomenclature) necessarily applies to surrounding areas as well.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">The following account is based on cytoarchitectonic as 
    well as connectional criteria, and our reasons for adopting it are 
    outlined more fully in the Discussion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Unfortunately, no useful chemoarchitectonic guides for 
    defining the boundaries of the PA and adjacent regions have emerged 
    from the literature or from our own unpublished observations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The cellular architecture and our subdivision of the 
    caudal amygdala are illustrated in Figures 1 and 2, 
    respectively.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Posterior nucleus of the 
    amygdala (PA)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    first appears at caudal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus of the amygdala 
    (MEApd)</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Figs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">IA, 2A) as a distinct, thin, plate-like group of cells 
    contiguous with deeper parts of <neuroanatomicalLocation>layer 111 
    of the posterolateral part of the posterior cortical nucleus of the 
    amygdala (COApl)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">It extends posteriorly throughout most of the length of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the COAp</neuroanatomicalLocation>, 
    curving along with the pyramidal layer of <neuroanatomicalLocation>
    the overlying ventral subiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Figs. 
    lD, 2D).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">It is separated from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    MEApd</neuroanatomicalLocation> by a band of fibers related to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>intraamygdalar parts of the stria 
    terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> that continues to shield the 
    nucleus dorsally and caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    can be distinguished easily from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    pyramidal layer of the ventral subiculum</neuroanatomicalLocation>, 
    although limits between <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> and <neuroanatomicalLocation>deeper 
    parts of the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> are not nearly as 
    obvious.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Careful examination of the cellular organization of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> reveals 
    that the region is quite homogeneous, consisting mainly of large, 
    multipolar, deeply stained neurons that are arranged in very 
    tightly packed clusters.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Taking into account this cytoarchitectonic feature, the 
    border between <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> and <neuroanatomicalLocation>deeper 
    parts of the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> can be traced rather 
    accurately since neurons within the latter are more loosely 
    arranged, and are stained slightly less intensely.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">This account of the boundaries of <neuroanatomicalLocation
    >the PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> is supported by the results of 
    PHAL experiments described below.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    corresponds approximately to what has been described as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the amygdalo-hippocampal transition 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>, although as delineated by most 
    authors, the latter also includes at least part of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deeper regions of the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Yu, &apos;69; Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78b; Turner and Zimmer, &apos;84; De Olmos et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">In this sense, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> as defined here is more similar to the 
    recent description of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    amygdalohippocampal transition area</neuroanatomicalLocation> by 
    Price and his colleagues (&apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s74">
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>Posterior cortical nucleus of the amygdala 
    (COAp)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    COAp</neuroanatomicalLocation> can be divided into 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a lateral (COApl) and a medial (COApm) 
    part</neuroanatomicalLocation>, <neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> lies in <neuroanatomicalLocation>
    the caudal third of the amygdala</neuroanatomicalLocation>, ventral 
    to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and 
    is innervated by <neuroanatomicalLocation>the accessory olfactory 
    tract</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Scalia and Winans, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">In frontal sections it appears rostrally as a densely 
    packed mass of cells that becomes more loosely arranged 
    caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">In contrast to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation>, <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> has a poorly defined trilaminar 
    structure, consisting of a molecular layer, a very thin superficial 
    cell layer, and a deep layer, where the cells appear to be less 
    densely packed when compared to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deep 
    layer of the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation>, a feature that allows 
    one to delineate more or less a border between them.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> as described here corresponds 
    approximately to that of De Olmos et al. (&apos;85) and most of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the posterior cortical 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> of Yu (&apos;69), Krettek and 
    Price (&apos;78b), and Price et al. (&apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> extends in the rostrocaudal 
    dimension from the caudolateral border of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
    the anterior cortical nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> to the 
    rostral two-thirds of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and is innervated by 
    <connxTermination>the lateral (main) olfactory 
    tract</connxTermination> (Scalia and Winans, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">It has a fairly well-defined trilaminar structure, with a 
    molecular layer; a superficial cell layer made up of very 
    chromatophilic, tightly packed pyramidal neurons; and a deep layer, 
    presenting darkly stained, large cells that tend to arch over 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deep layer of the 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> and merge with 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>ventrolateral regions of the 
    PA</neuroanatomicalLocation>, part of which has been regarded as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the superficial division of the accessory 
    basal nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Price et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Proceeding caudally through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation>, there is a gradual decrease in the 
    cell density of this deep layer, especially near the border with 
    the superficial cell layer (Fig. lD), making it more difficult to 
    distinguish from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> at this level.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Embedded within <neuroanatomicalLocation>rostral parts of 
    COApl layer I1</neuroanatomicalLocation> is a massive bundle of 
    fibers that surrounds an oval aggregate of what may be small 
    neurons (Fig. lA), called by De Olmos et al. (&apos;85) 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>a small-celled part of the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Our experimental observations indicate that many of these 
    fibers arise from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApm</neuroanatomicalLocation> and course rostrally to join 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the body of the stria 
    terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> (see Fig. 8M).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> of De Olmos et al. (&apos;85) 
    corresponds largely to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the periamygdaloid 
    cortex</neuroanatomicalLocation> of Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;78b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">However, it is important to point out that Krettek and 
    Price (&apos;78b) also included in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> a regon that we have recognized 
    here as <neuroanatomicalLocation>the piriform-amygdaloid 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which appears to be a distinct 
    structure based on its cytoarchitecture and connections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Piriform-amygdaloid area 
    (PA4)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    PAA</neuroanatomicalLocation> is a relatively well-defined, 
    three-layered structure that lies medial to <neuroanatomicalLandmark
    >the piriform area</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and lateral to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>rostral parts of the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">It extends only a short distance rostrocaudally and the 
    more loosely arranged cells in its deep layer readily distinguish 
    it from both <neuroanatomicalLocation>the COApl and the piriform 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Crosby and Humphrey (&apos;41) described, in the human 
    brain, a region interposed between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    COA</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    cortex of the piriform lobe</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and named it 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the cortico-amygdaloid transitional 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation> (hence our more specific 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>piriform-amygdaloid 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation>).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">Brodal (&apos;47) labeled a similar region in the rat 
    &quot;Y,&quot; which also includes part of <neuroanatomicalLocation>
    the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> as defined here.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Posterior part of the basomedial 
    nucleus of the amgygdala (BMAp)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    BMAp</neuroanatomicalLocation> is a group of neurons that first 
    appears deep to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the rostralmost tip of the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, and continues almost to the caudal 
    end of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, where it abuts 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>deeper regions of the 
    COApl</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">It lies between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the basolateral 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> dorsolaterally, and 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PAiCOApl</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
    ventromedially.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    BMAp</neuroanatomicalLocation> consists predominantly of smallto 
    medium-sized neurons that become rather densely packed medially at 
    midrostrocaudal levels.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">In agreement with the earlier description of De Olmos et 
    al. ( 851, we have also recognized <neuroanatomicalLocation>an 
    anterior part of the basomedial nucleus 
    (BMAa)</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which is a distinct group of 
    cells deep to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    COAa</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The basomedial 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> of Krettek and Price ( 78b) 
    corresponds to <neuroanatomicalLocation>our 
    BMAp</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which has also been referred to as 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the accessory basal 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> by Price et al. ( 87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
    BMAp</neuroanatomicalLocation> of the present account corresponds 
    approximately to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the basal 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> described by Gurdjian ( 28), and 
    to <neuroanatomicalLocation>the basomedial 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> delineated by Brodal 47).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Area TR 
    (TR)</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Area 
    TR</neuroanatomicalLocation> appears rostrally as a narrow region 
    interposed between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the caudal end of the 
    piriform area</neuroanatomicalLandmark> laterally, and 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the posterior part of the basolateral 
    nucleus of the amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark> medially.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">It becomes much larger caudally, where it intercalates 
    between <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the lateral entorhinal 
    area</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    caudal pole of the amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, which is 
    replaced caudally by <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ventral zone of 
    the medial entorhinal area</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Area 
    TR</neuroanatomicalLocation> has a very distinctive structure, with 
    a well-developed molecular layer, and a cellular layer that is 
    rather indistinctly divided into superficial and deep layers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">This region was first described and named by Haug ( 76), 
    who listed it as the area interposed between 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>area 
    entorhinalis</neuroanatomicalLandmark> caudally, and 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the piriform cortex and the posterior pole 
    of the amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark> rostrally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103"><neuroanatomicalLocation>Area 
    TR</neuroanatomicalLocation> also corresponds more or less to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the amygdalopiriform transition 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation> described by De Olmos et al. ( 85), 
    although it occupies a mostly postpiriform location.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s104">Neuronal inputs to 
    <connxTermination>the PA</connxTermination></S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105">The distribution of neurons that project to or through 
      <connxTermination>the region of the PA</connxTermination> was 
      examined using <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> as a 
      retrograde tracer.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106"><exptLabel>In five experiments</exptLabel> the deposit 
      of tracer was centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      PA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">Three of the injection sites appeared to be confined 
      almost entirely to <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, 
      with two centered in its rostral half and one centered more 
      caudally.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">In one other experiment there was some additional 
      involvement of <injectionSpread>the MEApd</injectionSpread>, and 
      in yet another there was additional involvement of adjacent parts 
      of <injectionSpread>the ventral hippocampai 
      formation</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">In addition, we obtained two relevant control 
      injections, each with a deposit centered in one of the latter two 
      regions.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">The appearance and location of a representative 
      <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> injection site in 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation> is shown in Figure 
      3.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">Each injection site consisted of a dense dye deposit 
      in the center, a surrounding zone of intensely labeled cells, and 
      an outer zone with faintly labeled cells.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">Based on our control deposits, the concentration of 
      tracer in the outer zone is not sufficient to label effectively 
      afferent pathways to <connxTermination>the caudal 
      amygdala</connxTermination>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">The distribution of <labelingDescription>retrogradely 
      labeled neurons</labelingDescription> following the injection 
      shown in Figure 3 is illustrated schematically in Figure 4.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">The results of this experiment are described in detail 
      since the injection site is virtually confined to 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, and at the same 
      time involves most of the nucleus.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Furthermore, the pattern of retrograde labeling in 
      this experiment was representative of that seen in each of the 
      others with deposits centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      PA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">For most of the structures that contained 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> we were able to confirm a projection 
      to <connxTermination>the PA</connxTermination> with control 
      experiments using PHAL as an anterograde tracer.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">The following is a summary of regions that appear to 
      send fibers to the region of <connxTermination>the 
      PA</connxTermination>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118"><neuroanatomicalLocation>
      Telencephalon</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      septal region, amygdala, and hippocampal 
      formation</labelingLocation>; <labelingDescription>no 
      retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> were found in 
      <labelingLocation>the isocortex</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">In <labelingLocation>the septal 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation>, particularly in its 
      ventral part (Fig. 4A) (see Swanson and Cowan, 79 for 
      nomenclature).</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><exptLabel>A <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> 
      injection centered in <injectionLocation>this 
      region</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labeled 
      <labelingDescription>a small number of fibers with terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> scattered throughout 
      <labelingLocation>the PA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122"><labelingLocation>The principal (encapsulated) nucleus 
      (BSTpr) of the BST</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>several faintly labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> (Fig. 4B-D), although both the number 
      of cells and the intensity of labeling were considerably 
      increased if the deposit of fluorogold involved <injectionSpread>
      the MEApd</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123"><labelingDescription>A very few labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were also consistently found in 
      <labelingLocation>other nuclei of the BST</labelingLocation>, 
      including <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal area, dorsomedial 
      nucleus, interfascicular nucleus, and transverse 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4A-D) (see Ju and Swanson, 
      &apos;89 for parcellation).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">In one experiment with a large 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit virtually confined 
      to <injectionLocation>the BSTpr</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>many labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      coursed through <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> and formed <labelingDescription>a 
      dense terminal field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
      the MEApd</labelingLocation>, whereas only <labelingDescription>a 
      very few fibers</labelingDescription> continued caudally to 
      provide <labelingDescription>a small numbers of terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      PA</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125"><labelingDescription>Several retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription>, which very often displayed 
      <labelingDescription>intense labeling</labelingDescription>, were 
      found in <labelingLocation>lateral parts of the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation>, in <labelingLocation>the anterior 
      amygdaloid area (AAA)</labelingLocation>, and in <labelingLocation
      >rostral parts of the medial division of the central nucleus of 
      the amygdala</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4B-F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">This was found consistently in all experiments with a 
      <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> deposit involving 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, and the intensity 
      and extent of retrograde labeling did not appear to be influenced 
      by the involvement of surrounding regions.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">Despite the fact that these labeled cells were located 
      in different areas, their morphology was very similar; most were 
      medium-sized stellate or fusiform neurons.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128"><labelingLocation>The medial nucleus of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>several retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription>, which were <labelingDescription>more 
      frequent</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the deepest 
      sublayer of the posterodorsal part (MEApd)</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 4G,H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129">In several experiments with 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections in 
      <injectionLocation>rostral parts of the MEA</injectionLocation> 
      we observed (throughout <labelingLocation>the entire rostrocaudal 
      extent of the PA</labelingLocation>) <labelingDescription>a few 
      labeled fibers and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the white matter just dorsal to the 
      PA</labelingLocation>, as well as <labelingDescription>a dense 
      plexus of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> just ventral to 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus in the COA</labelingLocation>, at 
      caudal levels <labelingDescription>this 
      plexus</labelingDescription> also extended into <labelingLocation>
      the PA</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130">In contrast, <exptLabel>experiments with a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit involving 
      <injectionLocation>the MEApd</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      labeled <labelingLocation>fibers</labelingLocation> that were 
      located mainly within <labelingLocation>the rostral third of the 
      PA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">Ventral to <labelingLocation>the rostral end of the 
      MEA</labelingLocation> we consistently found 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus 
      of the accessory olfactory tract (BA)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      4F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">The number of <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> (and their intensity) in this nucleus 
      increased considerably when the fluorogold deposit involved 
      <injectionLocation>the MEA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133"><exptLabel>In one experiment</exptLabel>, a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit involved 
      <injectionLocation>the BA</injectionLocation>, and we observed 
      <labelingDescription>a moderate number of anterogradely labeled 
      axons and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>rostral parts of the 
      PA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134">Lateral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark> we found several 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the deep layer 
      of the COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4H-K); this labeling 
      extended caudally to the level where <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark> comes to lie adjacent to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ventral 
      subiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">This group of labeled neurons was found in all 
      experiments with a <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> 
      deposit centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      PA</injectionLocation>, but not in the experiment with a 
      retrograde tracer deposit confined to <injectionLocation>the 
      MEApd</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136">Experiments with <exptLabel>a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the COAp</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      labeled <labelingDescription>a sparse to moderate plexus of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      PA</labelingLocation>, providing the injection site involved to 
      some extent deeper parts of layer 111 of the COApl (see Fig. 
      7L).</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137">Finally, as far as <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> is concerned, <labelingDescription>a 
      few very faintly labeled cells</labelingDescription> were 
      observed near <labelingLocation>the boundary between the lateral 
      nucleus and the posterior part of the basolateral 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4H-J).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138">However, they were <labelingDescription>more numerous 
      and more intensely labeled</labelingDescription> in those 
      experiments to involve the in which the deposit of fluorogold 
      spread <injectionSpread>hippocampal 
      formation</injectionSpread>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139">In <labelingLocation>the hippocampal 
      formation</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the pyramidal 
      layer of both the ventral subiculum and ventral parts of field 
      CAI</labelingLocation> contained <labelingDescription>a large 
      number of retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
      4K,L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140">With <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections 
      centered in <injectionLocation>these parts of the hippocampal 
      formation</injectionLocation>, <labelingDescription>a moderate 
      number of anterogradely labeled fibers and terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> were observed in <labelingLocation>
      the PA</labelingLocation> (see Canteras and Swanson, 
      &apos;92).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s141"><labelingDescription>A few retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation>
      the ventral zone of the medial entorhinal 
      area</labelingLocation>, near its border with 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ventral 
      subiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 4L).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142"><neuroanatomicalLocation>
      Thalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143">In each experiment with a 
      <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> deposit restricted to 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>a very few retrogradely labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4EG).</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144">Correspondingly, <exptLabel>a 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection involving 
      <injectionLocation>this nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      labeled <labelingDescription>a very small contingent of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      PA</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
       format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145"><labelingDescription>Several very faintly labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were also found throughout 
      <labelingLocation>the rostrocaudal extent of the parvicellular 
      part of the subparafascicular nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      4K,L) (see Faull and Mehler, &apos;85 for parcellation).</S></TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146">Perhaps it is significant that retrograde labeling in 
      <labelingLocation>the subparafascicular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> was markedly increased in experiments 
      with fluorogold deposits involving <injectionLocation>the 
      MEA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147"><neuroanatomicalLocation>
      Hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148">By far <labelingDescription>the greatest density of 
      retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in this part 
      of the diencephalon was found in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      premammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> (Figs. 45, lOB), 
      although <labelingDescription>a moderate number of labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> as well.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149"><labelingLocation>Other hypothalamic 
      regions</labelingLocation> contained only <labelingDescription>a 
      small number of labeled neurons</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150">Within <labelingLocation>the preoptic 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a very few 
      retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> were found in 
      <labelingLocation>the preoptic periventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, in <labelingLocation>the medial 
      preoptic area</labelingLocation>, and in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial preoptic nucleus (MPN)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4B-D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151">These findings are in agreement with a previous study 
      on the efferent projections of <connxOrigin>the MPN</connxOrigin> 
      that reported only <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> ending within <connxTermination>the 
      region of the PA</connxTermination> (Simerly and Swanson, 
      &apos;88).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s152"><labelingDescription>Scattered retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were found consistently in 
      <labelingLocation>a region of the lateral hypothalamic area just 
      dorsal to the optic tract</labelingLocation> that was coextensive 
      with <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior hypothalamic region 
      and the rostral half of the tuberal 
      region</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 4D-G).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153">In experiments with a 
      <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> deposit confined to 
      <injectionLocation>the MEA</injectionLocation> or to 
      <injectionLocation>ventral parts of the hippocampal 
      formation</injectionLocation>, this retrograde labeling was 
      <labelingDescription>barely detectable</labelingDescription>, 
      i.e., it was clear only in those cases in which the injection 
      site involved <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s154">At tuberal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingLocation>the 
      ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      reliably contained <labelingDescription>a few labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> (Fig. 4G,H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155">Occasionally, <labelingDescription>retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> was also observed in 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of this 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and in <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsomedial nucleus of the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> as 
      well.</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156">In experiments with 
      <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections 
      centered in <injectionLocation>the ventromedial 
      nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel>, only 
      <labelingDescription>a very few anterogradely labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were detected within 
      <labelingLocation>the PA</labelingLocation>.</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157">Immediately caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      ventromedial nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingLocation>
      the ventral premammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>a massive number of retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> (Figs. 45, 10B).</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158"><tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injections 
      centered in this nucleus anterogradely label 
      <labelingDescription>many fibers</labelingDescription> that 
      course through <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> to end preferentially in 
      <labelingLocation>the PA</labelingLocation>, which contains 
      <labelingDescription>a dense terminal field 
      throughout</labelingDescription> (see Canteras et al., 
      &apos;92).</S></TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159">Dorsal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ventral 
      premammillary nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> 
      a<labelingDescription>few labeled neurons</labelingDescription> 
      were consistently found in <labelingLocation>the posterior 
      hypothalamic nucleus</labelingLocation>, and occasionally 
      <labelingDescription>a very few labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation>
      the posterior periventricular nucleus, premammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 414).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">At the mammillary level, <labelingDescription>a few 
      retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> were 
      consistently found in <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the 
      supramammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4K).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161"><labelingDescription>The retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in this nucleus increased whenever 
      the fluorogold deposit spread to involve <injectionSpread>the 
      hippocampal formation</injectionSpread>, although it was 
      consistently found in experiments with injection sites that 
      appeared to be confined entirely to <injectionLocation>the 
      PA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162"><neuroanatomicalLocation>
      Midbrain</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">Caudal to the diencephalon, <labelingDescription>a 
      small number of retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      periaqueductal gray (Fig. 4K), the dorsal nucleus of the raphe 
      (not illustrated), and the ventral tegmental 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 4K,L).</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">It should be noted that retrograde labeling of all 
    regions was essentially ipsilateral, although 
    <labelingDescription>a few retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    contralateral ventral premammillary and subparafascicular 
    nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s165">Neuronal outputs from 
    <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Injection sites.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">The parameters used to produce iontophoretic injections 
    of <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> resulted in very discrete 
    injections sites, usually with hundreds of clearly labeled cell 
    bodies.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">In nine experiments the 
    <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection labeled many 
    neurons within <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, and 
    of these, six injection sites were confined almost entirely to this 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169"><labelingLocation>The rostral end of the 
    PA</labelingLocation> (before the nucleus adjoins 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the ventral 
    subiculum</neuroanatomicalLandmark>) contained the majority of 
    PHAL-labeled neurons in three of these experiments, whereas in the 
    other three, labeled cells were found more caudally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">The location of the injection sites of three 
    representative <exptLabel>experiments iAHZ-35, AHZ-18, and 
    AHZ-42</exptLabel>) involving different rostrocaudal levels of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the PA</neuroanatomicalLocation> is 
    indicated in the parcellation map of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    caudal amygdala</neuroanatomicalLocation> illustrated in Figure 
    2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">The appearance of the PHAL injection site in experiment 
    <exptLabel>AHZ-42</exptLabel> is illustrated in Figure 5.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Five control injections were placed in different regions 
    of <injectionLocation>the posterior cortical 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> and one in <injectionLocation>the 
    piriformamygdaloid area</injectionLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">The location of the injection site in each of these 
    experiments is also shown in Figure 2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The injection in experiment <exptLabel>AHZ-2</exptLabel> 
    labeled <labelingDescription>many superficial 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    COApm</labelingLocation>, as well as <labelingDescription>a small 
    number of neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layer 
    111 of the COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 2B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">The injection in <exptLabel>experiment 
    POCL-4</exptLabel> labeled neurons confined entirely to 
    <labelingLocation>layer 11</labelingLocation>, and superficial 
    parts of layer 111, of the COApl (Fig. 2B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">A further experiment (<exptLabel>POCL-3</exptLabel>) 
    labeled <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> 
    primarily in <labelingLocation>the piriform-amygdaloid 
    area</labelingLocation>, although <labelingDescription>several 
    cells</labelingDescription> were also labeled in <labelingLocation>
    layer 11 of the COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 2A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Several neurons in <labelingLocation>deep parts of the 
    COApl</labelingLocation> bordering <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
    PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, in addition to <labelingDescription>a 
    few cells</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    PA</labelingLocation> itself, were labeled in 
    <exptLabel>experiments POCL-2, PCO-2, and AHZ-15</exptLabel>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">In contrast to <exptLabel>experiment POCL-2</exptLabel>, 
    which appears to label specifically only <labelingLocation>the 
    deepest part of the COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 2C), 
    <exptLabel>experiments PCO-2 and AHZ-15</exptLabel> also involve 
    <injectionSpread>substantial parts of the COApm</injectionSpread> 
    (Fig. 2B,D).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Efferents of <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s180">No consistent differences in either the pattern or 
      density of labeled projections were observed in <exptLabel>the 
      six experiments with <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> 
      injection sites confined almost entirely to <injectionLocation>
      the PA</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s181">The following description is based primarily on 
      <exptLabel>experiment AHZ-42</exptLabel>, and is illustrated 
      schematically (and in detail) in Figure 6.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s182">It is convenient for descriptive purposes to divide 
      anterogradely <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PA</connxOrigin> into five pathways: 1) a lateral pathway, 2) a 
      medial pathway, 3) a ventral pathway, 4) a rostral pathway, and 
      5) a pathway that courses through <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      stria terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s183">1.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s184">Lateral pathway.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s185"><labelingDescription>A small number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course laterally from <connxOrigin>
      the PA</connxOrigin>, through <labelingLocation>deep parts of the 
      COAp and caudal parts of the basomedial and basolateral 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6M,N), where they issue 
      <labelingDescription>few terminal boutons</labelingDescription>, 
      to end in <connxTermination>the dorsal part of the endopiriform 
      nucleus</connxTermination>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s186">In addition, <labelingDescription>a few 
      axons</labelingDescription> continue caudally and seem to provide 
      <labelingDescription>a very sparse 
      innervation</labelingDescription> to <connxTermination>deeper 
      parts of area TR and the lateral entorhinal 
      area</connxTermination> (Fig. 60,P).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s187">Virtually <labelingLocation>the entire rostrocaudal 
      extent of the dorsal endopiriform nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      contains <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription>, which are much more numerous 
      caudally (Fig. 6B-N).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s188">Interestingly, these fibers tend to remain strictly 
      within the borders of the nucleus, and are poorly branched.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s189">2.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s190">Medial pathway.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s191">At caudal levels of the PA <labelingDescription>a 
      small number of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> course 
      medially toward <neuroanatomicalLocation>the hippocampal 
      formation</neuroanatomicalLocation> where they innervate 
      <connxTermination>the ventral subiculum and adjacent, ventral 
      parts of field CAI</connxTermination> (Fig. 6N-PI.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s192">These <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> tend to remain in <labelingLocation>
      the stratum lacunosum-moleculare and the stratum 
      radiatum</labelingLocation>, although (especially in 
      <labelingLocation>field CAI</labelingLocation>) 
      <labelingDescription>a few of them</labelingDescription> actually 
      course through <labelingLocation>the pyramidal 
      layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6P).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s193"><labelingLocation>The hippocampal 
      formation</labelingLocation> also receives 
      <labelingDescription>very few fibers</labelingDescription> that 
      course dorsally from the PA to reach <connxTermination>the 
      pyramidal layer of field CAI</connxTermination> (Fig. 60).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s194">3.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s195">Ventral pathway.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s196"><labelingLocation>Many labeled 
      fibers</labelingLocation> course ventrally from the injection 
      site to provide <labelingDescription>a very dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> that is restricted to a narrow band 
      in <labelingLocation>the medialmost region of the molecular layer 
      of the COApm</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6M-0).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s197">This terminal field can be identified in Figure 5, 
      ventral to the PHAL deposit, and it is worth noting here that the 
      density of <labelingDescription>terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> in this field seems to be much 
      higher in <labelingLocation>the outer part of the molecular 
      layer</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s198"><labelingDescription>Some labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in this ventral pathway continue 
      rostrally through <labelingLocation>adjacent parts of the 
      MEApd</labelingLocation> and enter <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6L).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s199">4.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s200">Rostra1 pathway.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s201"><labelingLocation>The MEA</labelingLocation> is the 
      main intraamygdaloid target of projections from <connxOrigin>the 
      PA</connxOrigin>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s202">Labeled fibers coursing rostrally from an injection 
      site in <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation> form in 
      <labelingLocation>the posterodorsal part of this 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>an impressive 
      terminal field</labelingDescription>, which is 
      <labelingDescription>particularly dense</labelingDescription> 
      within <labelingLocation>the deepest zone of the cell 
      layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6K,L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s203">Proceeding rostrally, the number of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the MEA</labelingLocation> decreases gradually 
      and they are located especially in <labelingLocation>the 
      anterodorsal part of the nucleus</labelingLocation>, although 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      are also found in <labelingLocation>the immediate vicinity of the 
      MEA</labelingLocation>, as well as in <labelingLocation>the 
      central nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      6H-J).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s204">At rostral levels of the amygdala, 
      <labelingDescription>some labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      enter <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation> and course toward <labelingLocation>
      caudal parts of the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis 
      (BST)</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6G-J).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s205"><labelingDescription>Only scattered terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> were found along the fibers that 
      course through <labelingLocation>the substantia 
      innominata</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s206">5.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s207">Stria terminalis.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s208">The majority of <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the 
      PA</connxOrigin> course through <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> to end in a number of telencephalic 
      and diencephalic sites, including <labelingLocation>the septa1 
      region, nucleus accumbens, infralimbic area of the prefrontal 
      cortex, and several nuclei in the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s209">Many axons in this pathway course through 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> and provide <labelingDescription>a dense 
      innervation</labelingDescription> to its <labelingLocation>
      principal (encapsulated) nucleus</labelingLocation> before 
      entering <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> 
      (Figs. 6F,G, 9C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s210"><labelingLocation>A smaller number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingLocation> appear to innervate <labelingLocation>
      the anterodorsal and anteroventral areas of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>, whereas <labelingDescription>only a 
      few</labelingDescription> seem to reach <labelingLocation>the 
      anterolateral area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6D-F).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s211"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> from <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> also continue rostrally, coursing 
      through <labelingLocation>the dorsal border of the anterodorsal 
      area of the BST</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6D,E), and provide 
      <labelingDescription>a significant input</labelingDescription> to 
      other parts of <labelingLocation>the septal 
      region</labelingLocation>, as well as other parts of 
      <labelingLocation>the telencephalon</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s212">Furthermore, just rostral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>
      the anterior commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, some of 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled axons</labelingDescription> in 
      this pathway take a ventral course, where they form a bundle that 
      proceeds caudally to end in <labelingLocation>several 
      hypothalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6D).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s213"><labelingDescription>A very dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral part of the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      and it was unusually prominent at levels where this nucleus 
      borders <labelingLocation>the anterodorsal area of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6D,E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s214">Rostrally, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> run near <labelingLocation>the 
      ependymal wall of the lateral ventricle</labelingLocation>, and 
      some of them assume a ventral course toward <labelingLocation>the 
      nucleus accumbens and the olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 6B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s215"><labelingDescription>Labeled terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> were strikingly more dense in 
      <labelingLocation>caudalmost parts of the nucleus 
      accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6 0 , with only 
      <labelingDescription>scattered labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>more rostral 
      parts of the nucleus</labelingLocation>, primarily near its 
      border with <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the lateral septal 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 6B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s216"><labelingDescription>A very small number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> associated with this pathway were 
      also found to end in <labelingLocation>medial parts of the 
      olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6B,C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s217">The rostralmost target of this pathway seems to be 
      <labelingLocation>the infralimbic area</labelingLocation>, which 
      contains <labelingDescription>a small number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> (Fig. 6A).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s218"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> appear to follow three distinct 
      routes to the hypothalamus: 1) <labelingDescription>some 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course through <labelingLocation>the 
      posterior division of the BST</labelingLocation> to enter 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation> at caudal levels of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>; 2) <labelingDescription>other 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course rostrally through 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal border of the anterolateral area of 
      the BST</labelingLocation> and, just rostral to 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior 
      commissure</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, continue ventrocaudally 
      toward <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>; and 3) 
      <labelingDescription>a very small contingent of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> skirts over <labelingLocation>the 
      descending column of the fornix</labelingLocation> to enter 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation> through 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the medial corticohypothalamic 
      tract</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s219">Together these fibers innervate <labelingLocation>
      several hypothalamic nuclei</labelingLocation>, particularly in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial zone</labelingLocation>, although it 
      does not seem possible in our 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> material to determine the 
      ultimate destination of fibers in each of the three pathways just 
      mentioned since there is extensive intermixing of fibers from the 
      three within <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</neuroanatomicalLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s220">In <labelingLocation>the preoptic 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingLocation>the anteroventral 
      periventricular and medial preoptic nuclei</labelingLocation> 
      contain <labelingDescription>a truly impressive number of labeled 
      fibers and terminal boutons</labelingDescription> from 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> (Figs. 6D-G, 9A-C), in sharp 
      contrast to what was seen in all of the experiments with 
      injection sites centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      COAp</injectionLocation> (see below).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s221">Within <labelingLocation>the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, the density of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> tended 
      to be somewhat greater in <labelingLocation>the medial 
      part</labelingLocation>, and somewhat less in <labelingLocation>
      the central part</labelingLocation> (Figs. 6F, 9B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s222"><labelingDescription>Several labeled fibers with 
      terminal boutons</labelingDescription> were also found in 
      <labelingLocation>the posterodorsal preoptic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 6F).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s223">From <labelingLocation>the preoptic 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a number of 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> continue caudally through 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation>; here their morphology resembles 
      <labelingDescription>fibers-of-passage</labelingDescription> in 
      the sense that varicosities are widely spaced and terminal 
      boutons rare (Fig. 6H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s224">At rostral levels of <labelingLocation>the 
      ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation>, most of 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled axons</labelingDescription> take 
      a ventromedial course, running through <labelingLocation>the 
      arcuate nucleus and adjacent ventral parts of the lateral 
      hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 61,J).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s225"><labelingDescription>These 
      fibers</labelingDescription> seem to provide 
      <labelingDescription>a dense innervation</labelingDescription> to 
      <labelingLocation>caudal levels of the ventrolateral part of the 
      ventromedial nucleus</labelingLocation>; thus, 
      <labelingDescription>high densities of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> are found within this subdivision, 
      within <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the relatively 
      cell-free zone that surrounds the nucleus</labelingLocation>, and 
      within adjacent parts of <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> (Figs. 6K,L, 9D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s226">In contrast, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were rarely found within 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the ventromedial 
      nucleus or within the dorsomedial nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s227"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> coursing through <labelingLocation>
      the arcuate nucleus</labelingLocation> display 
      <labelingDescription>very few terminal boutons and 
      varicosities</labelingDescription>; because of this morphology, 
      most of them are likely to be 
      <labelingDescription>fibers-of-passage</labelingDescription>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s228"><labelingDescription>Many labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue caudally to form 
      <labelingDescription>an impressively dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      premammillary nucleus</labelingLocation>, which seems to be the 
      caudalmost region densely innervated by <connxOrigin>the 
      PA</connxOrigin> (Figs. 6M,N, 10A).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s229">However, <labelingDescription>some labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> from this pathway can be seen to run 
      ventral to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the mammillary 
      body</neuroanatomicalLandmark> and appear to end in the fiber 
      capsule around caudal aspects of <labelingLocation>the cellular 
      part of the medial mammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      6P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s230"><labelingDescription>A very few labeled fibers and 
      boutons</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation
      >the posterior hypothalamic nucleus, the posterior 
      periventricular nucleus, the tuberomammillary nucleus, and 
      rostral parts of the periaqueductal gray</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      6M-0).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s231">It should also be noted that, at rostral levels of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the anterior hypothalamic 
      area</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>a few 
      fibers</labelingDescription> take a dorsal course toward 
      <labelingLocation>the thalamus</labelingLocation>, where they 
      provide <labelingDescription>a relatively sparse 
      innervation</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>rostral 
      zones of the medial part of the mediodorsal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 61-L).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s232">In addition, <labelingDescription>a very few labeled 
      fibers and boutons</labelingDescription> were also found in 
      <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus of the 
      thalamus</labelingLocation>, as well as in <labelingLocation>the 
      paratenial nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s233">Finally, it is important to point out that projections 
      from <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin> are by and large 
      ipsilateral, although a very small number of axons cross the 
      midline in <labelingLocation>the anterior commissure, the 
      supraoptic commissures, and the supramammillary 
      decussation</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s234">Only in those regions with <labelingDescription>a very 
      dense ipsilateral innervation</labelingDescription>, such as 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septal nucleus, the BST, the 
      anteroventral periventricular nucleus, the medial preoptic 
      nucleus, the ventromedial nucleus and adjacent lateral 
      hypothalamic area, and the ventral premammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, were <labelingDescription>occasional 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> observed on the 
      contralateral side.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s235">Injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the COApl</injectionLocation> immediately 
    aGacent to the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">The distribution of labeled axons from neurons in 
    <connxOrigin>the COApl</connxOrigin> that lie adjacent to 
    <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark> appears 
    to be distinct from the pattern of projections from both the PA and 
    more superficially located neurons in the COApl or COApm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">In three experiments (POCL-2, PCO-2, and AHZ-151, the 
    injection labeled many neurons in the deepest parts of the COApl 
    just lateral to the PA, although a small number of cells within the 
    PA itself were also labeled (see Fig. 2).</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s238">However, only in <exptLabel>experiment 
      POCL-2</exptLabel> (Fig. 2C) did the injection site appear to be 
      virtually confined to <injectionLocation>the deepest parts of the 
      COApl</injectionLocation>; in the other two experiments (PCO-2 
      and AHZ-15) there was also substantial involvement of 
      <injectionSpread>the adjacent COApm</injectionSpread> (Fig. 
      2B,D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s239">To compare the pattern of projections from the PA with 
      that from the deepest neurons in the adjacent COApl, we shall 
      therefore use as a prototype experiment POCL-2, which is 
      illustrated schematically in Figure 7, and refer to the others 
      where relevant.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s240">Labeled axons in experiment POCL-2 appear to follow 
      four major routes that may be divided (at least for descriptive 
      purposes) into lateral, and the stria terminalis.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s241"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> that 
      course laterally from the injection site take either a dorsal 
      route through <labelingLocation>caudal parts of the basomedial 
      and basolateral nuclei, and ventral regions of the lateral 
      nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation>, or pass ventrally 
      toward <labelingLocation>superficial layers of the 
      COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7K,L).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s242"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> coursing through this dorsal route 
      issue <labelingDescription>a small number of terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription>, and ultimately appear to provide 
      <labelingDescription>a sparse innervation</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the claustrum, dorsal endopiriform nucleus, 
      and deeper layers of the piriform, perirhinal, agranular insular, 
      and entorhinal areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7B-N).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s243">In contrast, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> coursing through the ventral 
      component of this route form <labelingDescription>a sparse 
      terminal field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      molecular layer of area TR</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7M,N), and 
      <labelingDescription>a very few</labelingDescription> of them 
      continue caudally to <labelingLocation>the lateral entorhinal 
      area</labelingLocation>, where <labelingDescription>a small 
      number of labeled terminal boutons</labelingDescription> were 
      found.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s244">Medial to the injection site, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> course 
      through <labelingLocation>the PA and nearby parts of the 
      COAp</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7L), both of which contain 
      <labelingLocation>labeled terminal boutons</labelingLocation> and 
      thus appear to be innervated.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s245">More caudally, <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the 
      hippocampal formation</labelingLocation>, where they end in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of 
      field CAI</labelingLocation>, in a fashion reminiscent of that 
      described for <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      PA,</neuroanatomicalLocation> although in the case of 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation> much 
      more densely (Fig. 7M,N).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s246">Compared to what has just been described for 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the PA</neuroanatomicalLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>more fibers</labelingDescription> also seem 
      to course rostral to the injection site, though <labelingLocation>
      the amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s247">Thus, in <exptLabel>experiment POCL-2</exptLabel> (and 
      in <exptLabel>experiments PCO-2 and AHZ-15</exptLabel>) inputs to 
      <labelingLocation>the MEApd</labelingLocation> were far 
      <labelingDescription>less dense</labelingDescription> than in 
      experiments with injections in <injectionLocation>the 
      PA</injectionLocation> (Fig. 7K).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s248">However, in all three experiments involving 
      <injectionLocation>the COAp</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>a denser plexus of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> was found in and around 
      <labelingLocation>the MEAad</labelingLocation>, as well as in 
      <labelingLocation>the central nucleus of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation>, where <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were particularly obvious in 
      <labelingLocation>the capsular subdivision</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 7H-K).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s249">At rostral levels of the amygdala, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> enter 
      <labelingLocation>the substantia innominata</labelingLocation>, 
      coursing toward <labelingLocation>caudal parts of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7GJ), and appear to be more numerous 
      in this experiment than in any of those centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s250">In addition, <labelingDescription>a very few 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were seen continuing rostral to 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation>, where they 
      seem to provide <labelingDescription>a very sparse 
      input</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the fundus of 
      the striatum and to medial parts of the olfactory 
      tubercle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7C-GI.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s251">As with <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      PA</neuroanatomicalLocation>, the major route followed by 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> from 
      neurons located in <connxOrigin>deeper parts of layer I11 of the 
      COApl</connxOrigin> appears to be <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s252">These axons provide inputs to <connxTermination>the 
      same general regions of the telencephalon and 
      diencephalon</connxTermination> as do those from <connxOrigin>the 
      PA</connxOrigin>, although quite often both display 
      characteristically different patterns of innervation within each 
      region.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s253">In the case of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the deeper 
      parts of layer I11 of the COApl</neuroanatomicalLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>many labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      course through <labelingLocation>the posterior division of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> as they leave <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      stria terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> to enter 
      <connxTermination>the hypothalamus</connxTermination>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s254">In <labelingLocation>the BST</labelingLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> tend to 
      avoid <labelingLocation>the principal nucleus</labelingLocation>, 
      and instead seem to provide <labelingDescription>a dense 
      innervation</labelingDescription> to <connxTermination>the 
      interfascicular and transverse nuclei</connxTermination> (Fig. 
      7G).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s255">On the other hand, the projection to 
      <connxTermination>the anterior division of the 
      BST</connxTermination> is quite similar to that from 
      <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin>, such that 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> appear 
      to innervate <connxTermination>the anterodorsal and anteroventral 
      areas</connxTermination>, and tend to avoid <labelingLocation>the 
      anterolateral area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7D-F).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s256"><labelingDescription>Some fibers</labelingDescription> 
      in this pathway continue rostrally through <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsal border of the anterodorsal area of the 
      BST</labelingLocation> to end in <connxTermination>the septal 
      region, nucleus accumbens, and infralimbic 
      area</connxTermination>, while other fibers take a ventral course 
      just rostral to the anterior commissure (Fig. 7D); these fibers 
      continue on to targets in <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s257">In this experiment (as well as in 
      <exptLabel>experiments PCO-2 and AHZ-15</exptLabel>), 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> enter 
      <labelingLocation>the septal region</labelingLocation> at 
      <labelingLocation>the rostral pole of the BST</labelingLocation>, 
      and innervate <connxTermination>the ventral part of the lateral 
      septal nucleus</connxTermination>, as well (to a lesser extent) 
      as <connxTermination>the intermediate and dorsal parts of the 
      nucleus</connxTermination> (Fig. 7B-E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s258">Compared to the projection from the PA, 
      <labelingDescription>the plexus of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      part of the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation> is 
      <labelingDescription>far less dense</labelingDescription>, 
      although in all three experiments involving <injectionLocation>
      the deepest parts of the COApl</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingLocation>labeled fibers</labelingLocation> appear to be 
      more evenly distributed throughout all parts of the lateral 
      nucleus.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s259">In <exptLabel>experiment POCL-2</exptLabel>, the 
      patterns of projections to <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
      accumbens and infrahbic area</labelingLocation> were very s i d a 
      r to those described earlier for the PA (Fig. 7A-C).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s260">In contrast to experiments with injection sites more 
      restricted to <injectionLocation>superficial parts of the COApl 
      and to the COApm</injectionLocation>, <exptLabel>experiments 
      POCL-2, PCO-2, and AHZ-15</exptLabel> labeled 
      <labelingDescription>a very striking 
      projection</labelingDescription> to <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s261">Also, in contrast to experiments with injections 
      confined to <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>very few axons</labelingDescription> in 
      these experiments seem to end in <labelingLocation>the preoptic 
      region</labelingLocation>; <labelingDescription>these few 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were located mainly in 
      <labelingLocation>the undifferentiated part of the medial 
      preoptic area</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral part of the medial preoptic nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 7E-G).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s262">Both the preand postcommissural components of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> from 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</neuroanatomicalLocation> merge at caudal levels of 
      <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the medial preoptic 
      nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark> (Fig. 7G) before continuing 
      caudally through <labelingLocation>the anterior hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7H) to end 
      <labelingDescription>massively</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>medial parts of the tuberal region of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s263">Thus, experiments POCL-2 and PCO-2 labeled 
      <labelingDescription>a dense terminal field</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>ventral parts of the lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> adjacent to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      ventromedial nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, in 
      <labelingLocation>the cell-sparse zone surrounding the 
      ventrolateral part of the ventromedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, and in <labelingLocation>the caudal 
      half of the ventrolateral part of this nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 7J,K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s264">In addition, <labelingDescription>some labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      cell-sparse zone around the dorsomedial part of the ventromedial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7K), although such fibers were 
      much more obvious in experiment AHZ-15, in which the injection 
      labeled more medially placed <labelingDescription>deep 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      COApl</labelingLocation> than in <exptLabel>experiments POCL-2 
      and PCO-2</exptLabel> (see Fig. 2).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s265">Just caudal to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      ventromedial nucleus</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, 
      <labelingDescription>several labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      were seen within <labelingLocation>the ventral premammillary 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 7L), and <labelingDescription>a 
      small group of fibers</labelingDescription> continued on ventral 
      to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the mammillary 
      body</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, where they seem to end in 
      <labelingLocation>the fiber capsule around the caudal cellular 
      border of the medial mammillary nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      7N).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s266">The pattern of thalamic projections in these 
      experiments was very similar to that described for 
      <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin>, with <labelingDescription>only 
      scattered fibers</labelingDescription> that seem to end rostrally 
      in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the mediodorsal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation>, as well as in <labelingLocation>the 
      paraventricular and paratenial nuclei</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      7H-K).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s267">Finally, in <exptLabel>experiment POCL-2</exptLabel>, 
      only <labelingDescription>a few fibers</labelingDescription> were 
      observed on <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
      side</labelingLocation>, in contrast to the results presented 
      next in <exptLabel>experiments PCO-2, AHZ-15</exptLabel>, and 
      others, in which the injection site labeled 
      <labelingDescription>superficial cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the COApl or COApm</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s268">As discussed below, the latter experiments labeled 
      <labelingDescription>a significant number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> that seem to cross mainly through 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior commissure</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s269">Injections in <injectionLocation>the 
      COApm</injectionLocation> and in <injectionLocation>superficial 
      parts of the COApl</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s270">A similar pattern of projections was observed in 
      <exptLabel>experiment AHZ-2</exptLabel> (in which the injection 
      site involved mainly <injectionLocation>the 
      COApm</injectionLocation> and to a lesser extent <injectionSpread>
      superficial parts of the COApl</injectionSpread>, as shown in 
      Fig. 2B), and in <exptLabel>experiment POCL-4</exptLabel> (in 
      which the injection site was restricted to <injectionLocation>
      layer 11 and superficial regions of layer I11 of the 
      COAp</injectionLocation>l, as shown in Fig. 2B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s271">However, both of these experiments labeled a pattern 
      of projection very distinct from those just described for 
      injection sites involving <injectionLocation>deeper parts of 
      layer I11 of the COApl</injectionLocation>, immediately adjacent 
      to <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the PA</neuroanatomicalLandmark>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s272">To illustrate this pattern, we shall discuss 
      <exptLabel>experiment AHZ-2</exptLabel> (Fig. 8) in detail, and 
      refer when necessary to <exptLabel>experiment POCL-4</exptLabel>, 
      as well as to other experiments that involved substantially 
      <injectionSpread>the COApm</injectionSpread> 
      (<exptLabel>experiments PCO-2 and AHZ-15</exptLabel>) (Fig. 
      2B,D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s273">We shall also refer to <exptLabel>experiment 
      POCL-3</exptLabel>, in which the injection site was centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the pirifom-amygdaloid 
      area</injectionLocation> (Fig. 2A).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s274">From the injection site in <exptLabel>experiment 
      AHZ-2</exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>an impressive plexus of 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> diverges immediately to fill 
      virtually <labelingLocation>all cellular parts of the 
      COAp</labelingLocation>, except for <labelingLocation>rostral 
      parts of layer I1 in the COApl</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8L-0).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s275">It is worth pointing out that <labelingLocation>the 
      PA</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>virtually free of 
      anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 8M-0).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s276">At caudal levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      COAp</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> take a lateral course and form 
      <labelingDescription>a moderate terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the molecular 
      layer of area TR</labelingLocation> (Fig. 80,P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s277">Furthermore, <labelingDescription>a number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> pass through this area on their way 
      to <labelingLocation>the entorhinal area</labelingLocation>, 
      where they seem to end <labelingDescription>relatively 
      densely</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      part</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>to a lesser 
      extent</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>superficial 
      layers (especially layer 11) of the medial 
      part</labelingLocation> (Fig. 80-Q).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s278"><labelingDescription>A very few labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> extended even farther into 
      <labelingLocation>the adjacent parasubiculum</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 8Q).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s279">At the caudal pole of the COAp, <labelingDescription>a 
      massive group of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> enters 
      <labelingLocation>the hippocampal formation</labelingLocation>, 
      where <labelingDescription>labeled axons and terminal 
      boutons</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral subiculum and field CAI</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      80,P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s280">This projection is <labelingDescription>especially 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>ventral parts of 
      field CAI</labelingLocation>, where <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> tend to be confined to 
      <labelingLocation>the stratum 
      lacunosum-moleculare</labelingLocation>, but occasionally enter 
      <labelingLocation>the stratum radiatum</labelingLocation>, where 
      they extend toward <labelingLocation>the pyramidal 
      layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8P).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s281">A similar (but somewhat more dense) projection to 
      <labelingLocation>the entorhinal area, subiculum, and Ammon s 
      horn</labelingLocation> was also observed in experiments POCL-4 
      and POCL-3.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s282"><labelingDescription>Many labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> course laterally and seem to provide 
      distinct inputs to <labelingLocation>the endopiriform nucleus, 
      piriform area, and dorsal and ventral agranular insular 
      areas</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8C-N).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s283"><labelingDescription>A smaller number of labeled 
      axons</labelingDescription> were also found in <labelingLocation>
      the posterior agranular insular area</labelingLocation>, as well 
      as in <labelingLocation>the perirhinal area</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 8F-Q).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s284"><labelingLocation>More medial parts of the piriform 
      area</labelingLocation> received <labelingDescription>a 
      particularly striking innervation</labelingDescription>, which 
      included <labelingDescription>a number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the deep half 
      of the molecular layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8H-N).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s285">It is worth noting that in experiment POCL-3, in which 
      the injection site spread to involve <injectionSpread>the 
      piriform-amygdaloid area</injectionSpread>, projections to 
      <labelingLocation>the endopiriform nucleus</labelingLocation> and 
      to <labelingLocation>the agranular insular 
      areas</labelingLocation> were clearly <labelingDescription>more 
      dense</labelingDescription> than in experiments with injections 
      restricted to <injectionLocation>the COAp</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s286">Rostral to the injection site, <labelingDescription>a 
      dense bundle of labeled fibers</labelingDescription> coursing 
      through <labelingLocation>the small-celled part of the COAp 
      (associated with layer I1 of the posterolateral 
      part)</labelingLocation> was particularly obvious in this 
      experiment (Fig. 8M), and to a lesser extent in experiment 
      POCL-4.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s287">Many of these fibers enter <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation>, while others continue through 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala and adjacent 
      regions</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s288">From the injection site, <labelingDescription>a 
      massive contingent of fibers</labelingDescription> continues 
      rostrally and seems to provide <labelingDescription>a heavy 
      innervation</labelingDescription> to virtually <labelingLocation>
      all parts of the amygdala ventral to the central and basolateral 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s289"><labelingLocation>The MEA</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>an exceedingly dense plexus of labeled 
      fibers and boutons</labelingDescription>, which, interestingly 
      enough, tend to avoid <labelingLocation>the deepest sublayer in 
      its posterodorsal subdivision (Fig. 8L,M), and the anteroventral 
      part</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s290">Ventral to rostral parts of the MEA, <labelingLocation>
      the bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory 
      tract</labelingLocation> was also <labelingDescription>heavily 
      innervated</labelingDescription>, in stark contrast to 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the lateral olfactory 
      tract</labelingLocation>, which was virtually 
      <labelingDescription>free of anterograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> (Fig. 81-K).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s291">This experiment, along with <exptLabel>experiment 
      POCL-4</exptLabel>, displayed similar patterns of inputs to 
      <connxTermination>the amygdala</connxTermination>, in contrast 
      to<exptLabel> experiment POCL-3</exptLabel>, in which the 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposit also involved 
      <injectionSpread>the piriform-amygdaloid area</injectionSpread>, 
      and <labelingDescription>a remarkably dense plexus of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
      the lateral nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s292">At rostral levels of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the 
      amygdala</neuroanatomicalLandmark> in <exptLabel>experiment 
      AHZ-2</exptLabel>, <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> entered <labelingLocation>the 
      substantia innominata</labelingLocation>, coursing toward 
      <labelingLocation>the caudal end of the 
      BST</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s293">In addition, some of <labelingDescription>the 
      rostrally directed fibers</labelingDescription> were found to 
      provide inputs to <connxTermination>medial parts of the olfactory 
      tubercle</connxTermination>, to <connxTermination>the fundus of 
      the striatum</connxTermination>, and to <connxTermination>ventral 
      regions of the nucleus accumbens</connxTermination> (Fig. 
      8D-H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s294"><labelingDescription>A few of these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> continue on through <labelingLocation
      >anteromedial parts of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation>, 
      where they join <labelingDescription>a group of 
      axons</labelingDescription> that travels through <labelingLocation
      >the stria terminalis</labelingLocation> and then along 
      <labelingLocation>the medial wall of the lateral 
      ventricle</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s295">Together, <labelingDescription>these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> project to <connxTermination>the 
      infralimbic area</connxTermination> and <connxTermination>the 
      accessory olfactory bulb</connxTermination>, as discussed 
      below.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s296"><labelingDescription>An impressive number of labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> leave <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> by way of <labelingLocation>the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8M).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s297">At the level of <neuroanatomicalLandmark>the posterior 
      division of the BST</neuroanatomicalLandmark>, fibers coursing 
      through this pathway provide <labelingDescription>a dense 
      input</labelingDescription> to <connxTermination>the 
      interfascicular and transverse nuclei</connxTermination>, tending 
      to avoid <labelingLocation>the principal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 81), as do 
      <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> from 
      <connxOrigin>deeper parts of the COApl</connxOrigin> 
      (<exptLabel>experiment POCL-2</exptLabel>).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s298"><labelingLocation>At the rostral pole of the posterior 
      division of the BST</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>many 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> cross through 
      <labelingLocation>the anterior commissure</labelingLocation> 
      (Fig. 8H), while another contingent of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled axons</labelingDescription> 
      continues rostrally through <labelingLocation>the dorsal edge of 
      the anterodorsal area of the BST</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      8F,G).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s299">The projection to <connxTermination>the anterior 
      division of the BST</connxTermination> appears to be 
      <labelingDescription>much less dense</labelingDescription> than 
      that described for <connxOrigin>the PA</connxOrigin>, and 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled fibers</labelingDescription> are 
      more restricted to <labelingLocation>its anterodorsal 
      area</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8F-H).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s300"><labelingDescription>The labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> coursing through <labelingLocation>
      the dorsal edge of the anterolateral area</labelingLocation> 
      appear to provide inputs to <connxTermination>the septal region, 
      nucleus accumbens, infralimbic area, taenia tecta, anterior 
      olfactory nucleus and accessory olfactory 
      bulb</connxTermination>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s301">In addition, just rostral to the anterior commissure, 
      <labelingDescription>a very small number of these 
      fibers</labelingDescription> take a ventral route toward 
      <labelingLocation>the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      8F).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s302"><connxTermination>The septal region</connxTermination> 
      is <labelingDescription>very sparsely 
      innervated</labelingDescription>, in sharp contrast to results 
      obtained in experiments with injections involving either 
      <injectionLocation>the PA</injectionLocation> or 
      <injectionLocation>the deep cells of the 
      COApl</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s303">Nevertheless, <labelingDescription>scattered labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
      septofimbrial nucleus, triangular nucleus, and lateral septal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8D-H).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s304">In experiments POCL-4 and POCL-3, 
      <labelingDescription>even fewer labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were observed within 
      <labelingLocation>the septal region</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s305">At rostral levels of <labelingLocation>the septal 
      region</labelingLocation>, <labelingDescription>a number of 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> continue on rostrally, near 
      <labelingLocation>the wall of the lateral 
      ventricle,</labelingLocation> while others course ventrally to 
      end in <labelingLocation>caudal parts of the nucleus 
      accumbens</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8D,E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s306"><labelingDescription>A moderately dense terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
      infralimbic area</labelingLocation>, where <labelingDescription>a 
      particularly obvious plexus of fibers</labelingDescription> could 
      be seen in <labelingLocation>the molecular 
      layer</labelingLocation> (Fig. 8C).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s307">In all experiments with an injection involving 
      <injectionLocation>the COApm</injectionLocation>, 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> were 
      observed to end in <connxTermination>the granule cell layer of 
      the accessory olfactory bulb</connxTermination>, where they form 
      <labelingDescription>a dense plexus</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
      8A).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s308">In <exptLabel>experiment AHZ-2</exptLabel>, as well as 
      <exptLabel>experiment POCL-4</exptLabel>, 
      <labelingDescription>only a few scattered 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were labeled in <labelingLocation>
      the hypothalamus</labelingLocation>, in sharp contrast to 
      experiments with a deposit of PHAL that also labeled 
      <labelingDescription>deeper cells</labelingDescription> of 
      <labelingLocation>layer I11 in the COApl</labelingLocation>, 
      immediately adjacent to the PA.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s309">Finally, the prominent fiber bundle seen crossing 
      through the anterior commissure was found to provide especially 
      <labelingDescription>dense terminal fields</labelingDescription> 
      to <labelingLocation>the interfascicular and transverse nuclei of 
      the BST</labelingLocation> on the other side of the brain.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s310">In addition, some of these fibers enter 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> and eventually reach 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s311">Some of these <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appear to end within 
      <labelingLocation>the MEA</labelingLocation>, as well as within 
      <labelingLocation>the COAp</labelingLocation>, particularly in 
      the region precisely contralateral to the injection site.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s312">It is important to point out that in 
      <exptLabel>experiments PCO-2, AHZ-15, POCL-4, and 
      POCL-3</exptLabel>, the number of crossed fibers was very much 
      smaller.</S>
    </TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s313">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">The major conclusion that can be drawn from the 
    experimental results presented here is that one can identify a 
    relatively homogeneous group of neurons deep within the caudal tip 
    of the amygdala with characteristic neuronal inputs and outputs 
    that are distinct from the adjacent posterior cortical nucleus of 
    the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">The major neuronal inputs to this cell group, which we 
    have called the posterior nucleus of the amygdala, appear to arise 
    in the medial nucleus of the amygdala, the deeper parts of the 
    posterolateral subdivision of the posterior cortical nucleus of the 
    amygdala, the ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of the 
    hippocampal field CAI, and especially the ventral premammillary 
    nucleus, while its major neuronal projections appear to end in 
    these same regions, as well as in the principal nucleus of the BST 
    and a number of cell groups associated with the periventricular and 
    medial zones of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">In the following discussion, we shall consider the 
    experimental techniques upon which these conclusions have been 
    drawn, the relationship of these results to evidence in the earlier 
    literature, and the possible functional implications of our 
    work.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s317">Neuronal inputs to the 
    PA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">To clarify the distribution of neurons that project to 
    the PA we first used fluorogold, since it has been shown to be a 
    very sensitive retrograde tracer that provides relatively discrete, 
    effective injection sites (see Schmued and Fallon, &apos;86; 
    Pieribone and Aston-Jones, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Nevertheless, it has the disadvantage that damaged and 
    undamaged fibers passing through the region of the injection site 
    may take up the tracer and retrogradely label cells that do not 
    give rise to terminals in the injection site (see Dado et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">To address this problem, most of the regions that 
    contained retrogradely labeled cells after tracer injections in the 
    PA received an injection of the anterograde tracer PHAL, in control 
    experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">To our knowledge, the only attempt to define possible 
    inputs to the PA was reported by Ottersen (&apos;801, who described 
    a few retrogradely labeled neurons in the lateral hypothalamic 
    area, substantia innominata, medial preoptic area, and medial 
    division of the BST, in one experiment with a small horseradish 
    peroxidase deposit that was centered in the region of the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">The results of our retrograde and anterograde axonal 
    transport experiments extend considerably these previous 
    observations, and indicate that the PA may receive inputs from 
    several widely distributed areas in the forebrain, and also to a 
    much lesser extent from the brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">From this, it would appear that the main sources of 
    inputs to the PA from the telencephalon are the medial nucleus of 
    the amygdala, the bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, 
    deeper parts of the COApl, the ventral subiculum and ventral parts 
    of field CAI, and a group of neurons with similar morphological 
    features distributed throughout lateral parts of the substantia 
    innominata, the anterior amygdaloid area, and rostra1 parts of the 
    central nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">In the diencephalon, inputs to the PA seem to arise 
    mainly from the ventral premammillary nucleus, which supplies by 
    far the most dense known input to the PA, as well as from a group 
    of cells located just dorsal to the optic tract in the lateral 
    hypothalamic area throughout the anterior hypothalamic region and 
    rostral parts of the tuberal region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">In the brainstem we found only a few retrogradely 
    labeled neurons, located in the dorsal nucleus of the raphe, the 
    ventral tegmental area, and the periaqueductal gray.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">It also became apparent in our experimental material 
    that the PA seems to receive sparse inputs from several areas that 
    provide a very dense input to the nearby MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">These regions include the principal nucleus of the BST 
    (Ottersen, &apos;80), the medial preoptic area (Conrad and Pfaff, 
    &apos;76; Ottersen, &apos;80; Chiba and Murata, &apos;85; Simerly 
    and Swanson, &apos;881, and the parvicellular part of the 
    subparafascicular nucleus (Faull and Mehler, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Based on our retrograde tracer experiments, this also 
    seems to be the case for the posterior part of the basolateral 
    nucleus of the amygdala and for the supramammillary nucleus, both 
    of which are known to innervate densely the ventral subiculum and 
    adjacent parts of field CAI (Krettek and Price, &apos;77b; see 
    Swanson et al., &apos;87), and both of which contained only a few 
    labeled neurons whenever the fluorogold deposit was centered in the 
    PA and did not spread to involve the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Our retrograde transport experiments did not label a 
    projection from the basomedial nucleus of the amygdala to the PA, a 
    pathway reported in the cat by Krettek and Price (&apos;78b), who 
    used the autoradiographic method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">This discrepancy would easily be explained if the 
    injection site in the experiment described by these authors 
    encroached slightly on deeper parts of the adjacent COApl (see 
    below), although we cannot rule out the possibility of species 
    differences in this projection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">In agreement with previous studies, we did not label a 
    projection from the olfactory bulb directly to the PA, although it 
    seems likely (see below) that the nucleus receives olfactory 
    information relayed from the medial nucleus of the amygdala, the 
    bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, and less directly 
    from deep parts of the COApl, and/or the ventral subiculum and 
    adjacent parts of field CAI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Using the autoradiographic method in the cat, Krettek 
    and Price (&apos;78b) described a projection to the region of the 
    PA from the periamygdaloid cortex, which, according to the 
    cytoarchitectonic parcellation scheme adopted here, corresponds to 
    the piriform-amygdaloid area and the COApl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Based on our retrograde and anterograde tracer 
    experiments, the source of this projection is almost certainly 
    neurons in the deeper regions of the COApl.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">As far as we can determine, projections to the PA from 
    the bed nucleus of the accessory olfactory tract, the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala, and the ventral subiculum and adjacent 
    parts of field CAI have not been reported before.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">It is known that both the medial nucleus and the bed 
    nucleus receive a direct projection from the accessory olfactory 
    bulb (Scalia and Winans, &apos;751, and the medial nucleus is also 
    innervated by superficial neurons in the COApl and COAa (Krettek 
    and Price, &apos;78b; Ottersen, &apos;821, both of which in turn 
    receive direct inputs from the main olfactory bulb (Price, 
    &apos;73; Scalia and Winans, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Another site where indirect influences from the 
    accessory and main olfactory pathways may well converge is the 
    deeper regions of the COApl, since it is densely innervated by 
    superficial neurons in both the posteromedial and posterolateral 
    parts of the COA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">In addition, olfactory information may well be relayed 
    to the PA by the ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of field CAI, 
    which are known to be densely innervated by several areas that 
    receive direct inputs from either the main or the accessory 
    olfactory bulb, including the posteromedial and posterolateral 
    parts of the COA, the piriform-amygdaloid area, and the lateral 
    entorhinal area (Price, &apos;73; Scalia and Winans, &apos;75; 
    Krettek and Price, &apos;77b; Witter et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">It may also be important to point out that the 
    apparently massive projections from the ventral subiculum and 
    adjacent parts of field CA1 constitute a potential route for the 
    relay of information in the hippocampal trisynaptic circuit to the 
    PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">The trisynaptic circuit in turn receives information, 
    either directly or indirectly, from virtually all parts of the 
    isocortex, and is somehow involved in the &quot;short-term&quot; 
    storage of memories, as well as their transfer to isocortical 
    regions involved in their storage for much longer periods of time 
    (see Swanson et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Turning now to subcortical afferents, our retrograde 
    tracer experiments indicate that at least a few neurons in the 
    substantia innominata project to the PA, in agreement with previous 
    results based on the use of PHAL as an anterograde tracer (Grove, 
    &apos;88b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Hellendall et al. (&apos;86), using a monoclonal 
    antibody against choline acetyltransferase (ChAT), found a dense 
    plexus of presumably cholinergic fibers in the region of the 
    amygdalo-hippocampal area, although according to the parcellation 
    used here this plexus appears to be much more dense just lateral to 
    the PA itself, in what we regard as the deep part of the COApl, and 
    in medial parts of the basomedial nucleus (see Fig. 1F in 
    Hellendall et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">It is tempting to suggest that the CUT-immunoreactive 
    fibers in the PA might arise from the substantia innominata, which 
    also appears to be the source of a cholinergic input to the 
    basolateral nucleus of the amygdala (Woolf and Butcher, &apos;82; 
    Carlsen et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">The anterior amygdaloid area, as well as rostral parts 
    of the medial division of the central nucleus, also contained 
    retrogradely labeled neurons after fluorogold injections in the PA, 
    and these cells were morphologically similar to labeled neurons in 
    the substantia innominata.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">It has been pointed out that the substantia innominata, 
    anterior amygdaloid area, and medial division of the central 
    nucleus share certain cytoarchitectonic (Yu, &apos;69; De Olmos et 
    al., &apos;85; Price et al., &apos;87) and connectional (Grove, 
    &apos;88a) features in common, although it is not known whether the 
    cells in all three regions that project to the PA are 
    cholinergic.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">The results of our retrograde transport experiments 
    indicate strongly that the PA receives a projection from a very 
    specific group of neurons in the lateral hypothalamic area that is 
    located just dorsal to the optic tract, at the level of the 
    anterior hypothalamic region and rostral parts of the tuberal 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">The possible functional significance of this projection 
    is entirely unknown, although considering the number of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons, it should provide at least a moderate 
    input to the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Our results indicate that the ventromedial nucleus of 
    the hypothalamus sends very few axons to the PA, in agreement with 
    previous autoradiographic studies (Saper et al., &apos;76; Krieger 
    et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">On the other hand, our results demonstrate that the 
    ventral premammillary nucleus is by far the most prominent source 
    of inputs to the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">It is known that the ventral premammillary nucleus 
    contains a very high density of cells that concentrate circulating 
    gonadal steroids (Pfaff and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, 
    &apos;75; Stumpf et al., &apos;7.51, and recently it has been shown 
    that neurons in this nucleus express high levels of the mRNA 
    encoding the androgen and, to a lesser extent, the estrogen 
    receptors (Simerly et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Furthermore, the ventral premammillary nucleus receives 
    afferents mainly from structures related to the sexually dimorphic 
    circuit, including the PA, the medial nucleus of the amygdala, the 
    principal nucleus of the BST, and the medial preoptic nucleus 
    (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Kevetter and Winans, &apos;81; 
    Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88; see Canteras et al., &apos;921, 
    which are also among the regions of the brain containing the 
    highest density of neurons with gonadal steroid hormone receptors 
    (Pfaff and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;75; Stumpf et 
    al., &apos;75; Simerly et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Thus, information generated in the sexually dimorphic 
    circuit appears to be transmitted to the PA mainly by way of the 
    ventral premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Unfortunately, we have as yet no clue about the 
    neurotransmitters used in this pathway from the ventral 
    premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">In agreement with the results of our retrograde tracer 
    experiments, previous evidence based on the autoradiographic method 
    indicates that a few neurons in the dorsal nucleus of the raphe 
    project to the PA (Conrad et al., &apos;74; Azmitia and Segal, 
    &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">The rostra1 two-thirds of the PA contains a plexus of 
    serotoninergic fibers (Steinbusch, &apos;81; N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Swanson, unpublished observations), and it appears 
    likely that these fibers arise from the dorsal nucleus of the 
    raphe, since no other serotoninergic cell group contained 
    retrogradely labeled neurons in our experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Our fluorogold results also suggest that the ventral 
    tegmental area provides a small input to the PA, in agreement with 
    previous autoradiographic studies (Fallon and Moore, &apos;78; 
    Simon et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">In addition, it has been shown by Fallon et al. 
    (&apos;78) with the glyoxylic acid method that there are a small 
    number of catecholaminergic fibers in the region of the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Since we found no retrograde labeling in brainstem 
    regions that contain noradrenergic cell groups, and since 
    dopamine-0-hydroxylase-immunoreactive fibers have not been reported 
    in the PA (see Swanson and Hartman, &apos;75), the evidence as a 
    whole suggests that the ventral tegmental area sends a small number 
    of dopaminergic fibers to the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Hormonal inputs to the PA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">The PA contains high levels of mRNA encoding the 
    mineralocorticoid receptor (MR), which binds with high affinity 
    both the naturally occurring mineralocorticoid aldosterone, and the 
    glucocorticoids (Arriza et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">It has also been reported that many neurons 
    concentrating gonadal steroid hormones are found in the PA (Pfaff 
    and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;74), as are neurons 
    that express high levels of mRNAs for the androgen (AR) and 
    estrogen (ER) receptors (Simerly et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Thus, in addition to neural inputs, the PA may be 
    influenced significantly by circulating steroid hormones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Furthermore, if individual neurons in this nucleus do in 
    fact express each of these receptors, complex interactions between 
    various steroid hormones may combine in unique ways to influence 
    neuronal function in this region of the brain (see Ankenbauer et 
    al., &apos;88; Green and Chambon, &apos;87; Arriza et al., In 
    summary, olfactory information may be relayed to the PA by the 
    medial nucleus of the amygdala, the bed nucleus of the accessory 
    olfactory tract, deeper parts of the COApl, and the ventral 
    subiculum and adjacent parts of hippocampal field CAI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">It is also possible that the latter two regions transmit 
    to the PA information related to activity generated in widespread 
    areas of the isocortex as well as in the trisynaptic circuit of the 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">The PA also receives a relatively small number of 
    cholinergic, serotoninergic, and dopaminergic fibers, which appear 
    to arise, respectively, in the substantia innominata, the dorsal 
    nucleus of the raphe, and the ventral tegmental area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Nevertheless, neural influences on the PA seem to be 
    dominated by information generated in the sexually dimorphic 
    circuit, which is especially transmitted to the nucleus by way of 
    the ventral premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">In addition, it is important to bear in mind that 
    neurons in the PA may be strongly influenced by circulating steroid 
    hormones as well.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Neuronal outputs of the PA</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Our results confirm and extend in many ways what was 
    previously known about the projections of the PA, as well as the 
    adjacent COAp (for summary see Fig. 11).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">However, because the validity of our findings rests on 
    the properties of the PHAL method, we should consider its major 
    features before discussing our results.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">As originally described by Gerfen and Sawchenko 
    (&apos;84), the PHAL method allows the production of very small 
    iontophoretic injections, and the effective limits of the injection 
    site can be determined precisely because the cells that give rise 
    to labeled axons are themselves clearly labeled.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Another advantage of this method is that the detailed 
    morphology of each labeled axon can be visualized with the clarity 
    of a Golgi impregnation, and the presence of terminal boutons 
    (including boutons-of-passage) can be established with 
    certainty.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">While it is true that the presence of morphologically 
    defined synapses must be established at the ultrastructural level, 
    it is also true that everywhere terminal boutons have been examined 
    with the electron microscope, they have been shown to form synapses 
    (see, e.g., Rockel and Jones, &apos;73; Wouterlood and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">The final major advantage of the method is that under 
    the injection conditions recommended by Gerfen and Sawchenko 
    (&apos;84), retrograde labeling is absent or extremely rare, and 
    labeling of fibers-of-passage has never been demonstrated 
    unequivocally (i.e., from regions that clearly contain no dendrites 
    that could take up the tracer and confound the interpretation of 
    axonal uptake).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">One important point to make at the outset is that our 
    results are based on five PHAL injection sites with labeled neurons 
    confined almost entirely to the PA, and that virtually all parts of 
    the PA were labeled by one or another of these injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Nevertheless, the patterns of labeled projections in 
    each of these five experiments were indistinguishable, suggesting 
    that neurons throughout the PA as we have defined its borders give 
    rise to very similar projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">It is equally important to point out, however, that 
    there is no evidence to indicate whether these projections arise 
    from a single cell type or from multiple cell types that are 
    intermixed in some uniform or reproducible way.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Finally, it is worth pointing out that neurons in 
    immediately adjacent parts of the posterior cortical nucleus give 
    rise to a different pattern of connections, as discussed more fully 
    in the next section.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">With this information in mind, we can now summarize the 
    output of the PA as follows: it appears to be largely ipsilateral 
    and, at least for descriptive purposes, to travel through five 
    basic pathways: 1) a lateral pathway that seems to innervate mainly 
    the dorsal endopiriform nucleus; 2) a medial pathway that projects 
    to the ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of hippocampal field 
    CAI; 3) a ventral pathway that seems to provide a dense input to 
    the molecular layer of the COApm; 4) a rostra1 pathway that courses 
    through the amygdala, and provides an input to the MEApd, before 
    entering the ansa peduncularis; and 5) a pathway through the stria 
    terminalis, which is by far the main route followed by axons from 
    the PA, to several regions of the telencephalon and 
    diencephalon.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Anterogradely labeled axons coursing laterally from PHAL 
    deposits in the PA provide a relatively moderate input to the 
    dorsal endopiriform nucleus, although in contrast to experiments 
    with PHAL injections in the posterior cortical nucleus or the 
    piriform-amygdaloid area, very few fibers were found in the 
    adjacent piriform area, or in adjacent cortical areas near the 
    rhinal fissure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Projections from the COApl and piriform-amygdaloid area 
    to cortical areas near the rhinal fissure have been reported in the 
    rat (Luskin and Price, &apos;83; McDonald and Jackson, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Furthermore, McDonald and Jackson (&apos;87) used HRP as 
    a retrograde tracer to describe a projection from lateral parts of 
    the amygdalo-hippocampal area to the perirhinal area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">The amygdalo-hippocampal area defined by these authors 
    does not correspond exactly to our delineation of the PA, since 
    their area also includes deeper parts of the posterolateral 
    cortical nucleus that actually contain many more retrogradely 
    labeled neurons than the PA itself in the experiment with an HRP 
    deposit centered in the perirhinal area that they illustrated (see 
    case R-123 in McDonald and Jackson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">In short, their observations are in complete agreement 
    with the results of our anterograde tracer experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Our results also indicate that the ventral subiculum and 
    adjacent parts of field CAI receive a moderate input from the PA, 
    whereas the entorhinal area seems to receive very few inputs from 
    this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">In contrast, a significantly more dense projection to 
    all of these components of the hippocampal formation appears to 
    arise from the posterior cortical nucleus, as discussed below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Projections from the periamygdaloid cortex (which 
    according to our parcellation includes both the piriform-amygdaloid 
    area and the COApl) to the ventral subiculum, to ventral parts of 
    field CAI, and to the entorhinal area have been described with the 
    autoradiographic method (Krettek and Price, &apos;77b; Luskin and 
    Price, &apos;831, and our results suggest that the COApm projects 
    heavily to these same areas as well.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Within the amygdala, the main recipients of projections 
    from the PA are the MEApd and medialmost parts of the molecular 
    layer of the COApm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">The latter projection is of interest because the 
    accessory olfactory tract also ends mainly in superficial parts of 
    the molecular layer of the COApm (Scalia and Winans, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">It will be important to determine whether the PA input 
    acts presynaptically on these fibers or whether it interacts with 
    the distal dendrites of neurons in deeper parts of the COApm.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">A projection from the PA to the region of the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala was suggested by Ottersen (&apos;82) on the 
    basis of HRP retrograde tracer experiments in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">According to our results, the projection from the PA to 
    the medial nucleus is directed mainly to its posterodorsal part, in 
    contrast to inputs from the posterior cortical nucleus, which tend 
    to avoid the deepest sublayer of the MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">It is worth remarking here that the projection from the 
    PA to the MEApd appears to be far stronger than the reverse PA, 
    which has been projection from the MEApd to the discussed earlier 
    in this paper.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Interestingly, the PA and the MEApd project to the same 
    regions of the BST and hypothalamus, all of which are known to be 
    related to the sexually dimorphic circuit (Simerly and Swanson, 
    &apos;86; Simerly et al., &apos;89; N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Swanson, unpublished observations), as discussed 
    below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Like the PA, the MEApd contains many neurons that 
    concentrate gonadal steroids (Pfaff and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and 
    Stumpf, &apos;741, and express high levels of the mRNAs encoding 
    the androgen and estrogen receptors (Simerly et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">In addition, the medial nucleus is larger in males and 
    its synaptic organization is sexually dimorphic as well (see Arai, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Nevertheless, the MEApd and the PA appear to be 
    influenced differentially by areas related to the sexually 
    dimorphic circuit.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">In contrast to the PA, the MEApd receives a direct input 
    from the accessory olfactory pathway and is densely innervated by 
    the principal nucleus of the BST and the medial preoptic nucleus 
    (Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88; Simerly et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">In addition, unlike the PA, neurons within the MEApd 
    appear to express very low levels of mRNA encoding nuclear 
    receptors for mineralocorticoids (Arriza et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Our experimental material demonstrates that a great 
    majority of the fibers arising in the PA leave the amygdala through 
    the stria terminalis, in agreement with previous suggestions based 
    on the autoradiographic method (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a) or on 
    retrograde tracing combined with lesions of the stria terminalis 
    (Maragos et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">A small number of fibers were also observed coursing 
    through the ansa peduncularis in our material, although the number 
    of such fibers increased considerably whenever the PHAL deposit 
    involved the posterior cortical nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Fibers coursing through the stria terminalis from the PA 
    provide inputs to a number of telencephalic and diencephalic 
    regions, including the BST, lateral septal nucleus, nucleus 
    accumbens, olfactory tubercle, infralimbic area, several 
    hypothalamic nuclei, and certain thalamic nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">The PA and the posterior cortical nucleus also give rise 
    to very different patterns of input to the BST.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Both project mainly to the posterior division of the 
    BST, although efferent fibers from the PA give rise to a dense 
    terminal field within the principal nucleus, whereas the posterior 
    cortical nucleus projects densely to the interfascicular and 
    transverse nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Krettek and Price (&apos;78a), using the 
    autoradiographic method, reported that both the amygdalohippocampal 
    area and the posterior cortical nucleus project to the medial 
    division of the BST.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">The medial division of Krettek and Price (&apos;78a) 
    appears to encompass both the principal nucleus and at least parts 
    of the interfascicular and transverse nuclei of the present account 
    (see Fig.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Id in Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; and Fig. 7 in Ju and 
    Swanson, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">It should be pointed out, however, that none of the 
    injections reported by Krettek and Price (&apos;78a) were 
    restricted to the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Interestingly, the PA and the principal nucleus of the 
    BST have virtually the same pattern of projections to the 
    hypothalamus (Simerly et al., &apos;891, and, as noted above, both 
    innervate densely the MEApd.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">The principal nucleus also contains a high density of 
    neurons that concentrate gonadal steroids, as well as express high 
    levels of mRNAs encoding the androgen and estrogen receptors (Pfaff 
    and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;74; Simerly et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">This nucleus is also larger in males as compared to 
    females, in guinea pigs and rats (Hines et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Thus, the PA together with the MEApd and the principal 
    nucleus of the BST form an interconnected circuit within the 
    telencephdon that can be influenced by circulating gonadal 
    steroids, and that shares practically the same pattern of 
    projections to the hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">The PA supplies a particularly dense input to the 
    ventral part of the lateral septal nucleus, in contrast to the 
    posterior cortical nucleus, which appears to provide a much sparser 
    projection that also tends to be more dispersed through other parts 
    of the septal region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Evidence for a projection from the PA to the ventral 
    part of the lateral septal nucleus was adduced by Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;78a) in the rat with the autoradiographic method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Interest in this projection centers around the fact that 
    the ventral part of the lateral septal nucleus is another 
    telencephalic region densely innervated by the PA that also seems 
    to be related to the sexual dimorphic circuit.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Thus, the ventral part of the lateral septal nucleus 
    contains many neurons that concentrate gonadal steroids, as well as 
    express mRNAs encoding the androgen and estrogen receptors (PfdF 
    and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and Stumpf, &apos;74; Simerly et al., 
    &apos;90); it, along with certain other parts of the lateral septal 
    nucleus, contains a greater density of vasopressin-immunoreactive 
    fibers in male as compared to female rats (DeVries et al., 
    &apos;84); it shares strong bidirectional connections with the 
    medial preoptic nucleus (Simerly and Swanson, &apos;86, &apos;88); 
    and it receives a dense projection from the ventral premammillary 
    nucleus (Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Turning now to the striatum, the caudalmost regions of 
    the nucleus accumbens receive a moderate plexus of labeled fibers 
    from the PA, in agreement with earlier suggestions based on the 
    autoradiographic method (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a), and on the 
    retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase (Phillipson and 
    Griffiths, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Ventral to the nucleus accumbens, only scattered fibers 
    from the PA course to the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">The latter is in sharp contrast to what was observed in 
    experiments with PHAL deposits in the postrior cortical nucleus, 
    where labeled fibers continue rostral to the amygdala to provide a 
    more dense input to the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">The rather sparse projection from the PA to the 
    prefrontal cortex appears from our anterograde material to be 
    restricted to the infralimbic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">A projection from the PA to the medial prefrontal region 
    in the rat was reported by McDonald (&apos;87), who used 
    fluorescent retrograde tracer injections that involved both the 
    prelimbic and infralimbic areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">According to our anterograde results, the posterior 
    cortical nucleus projects more densely to the infralimbic area than 
    does the PA, which agrees with our observations in an experiment 
    with a fluorogold deposit centered in this cortical region; in this 
    experiment the posterior cortical nucleus contained considerably 
    more retrogradely labeled neurons than the PA (N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Swanson, unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">The mediodorsal nucleus of the thalamus, which is known 
    to be intimately related to the prefrontal region (see Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77a), also receives a very sparse projection from the 
    PA, in agreement with previous observations based on retrograde 
    tracer experiments (McDonald, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">In addition, this projection appears to be directed 
    especially to the rostral end of the medial part of this 
    nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Fibers from the PA provide a massive input to several 
    nuclei within the periventricular and medial zones of the 
    hypothalamus, including the anteroventral periventricular nucleus, 
    the medial preoptic nucleus, the ventrolateral part of the 
    ventromedial nucleus and adjacent parts of the lateral hypothalamic 
    area, and the ventral premammillary nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">The projection to the medial preoptic nucleus has been 
    shown with retrograde tracer methods (Berk and Finkelstein, 
    &apos;81; Simerly and Swanson, &apos;86; Maragos et al., &apos;891, 
    and we were able to determine here that it is directed mainly to 
    the medial part of this nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Just rostral to the MPN in the preoptic region, another 
    dense plexus of labeled fibers from the PA was found in the 
    anteroventral periventricular nucleus; this pathway does not seem 
    to have been reported previously.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Injections of retrograde tracers centered in the 
    ventromedial nucleus have been found to label cells within the 
    region of the PA (Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Kita and Oomura, 
    &apos;82; Zaborsky, &apos;82; Ono et al., &apos;85; Fahrbach et 
    al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">According to our anterograde tracer experiments, fibers 
    arising in the PA form a dense terminal field within the caudal 
    half of the ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus and 
    within adjacent parts of the basal lateral hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">This finding is at variance with the results of previous 
    autoradiographic studies in the rat, in which a projection to the 
    entire extent of the cell-sparse zone or shell surrounding the 
    nucleus has been reported (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Post and 
    Mai, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">A reasonable explanation for this discrepancy may well 
    be that in the experiments reported by these authors the injection 
    site spread to include small parts of the ventral subiculum, which 
    clearly project densely to the entire shell region surrounding the 
    ventromedial nucleus (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Canteras and 
    Swanson, &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">In this study we have also established the existence of 
    a very dense projection to the ventral premammillary nucleus from 
    the PA that was previously suggested by Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">In all of our experiments with PHAL deposits in the PA 
    we also observed a moderate number of fibers coursing through the 
    arcuate nucleus, although they give rise to very few terminal 
    boutons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Any substantial influence of the PA on the arcuate 
    nucleus, as well as on the hypothalamic paraventricular nucleus, 
    appears to be mediated primarily in an indirect way, most obviously 
    through its projections to the anteroventral periventricular 
    nucleus, the medial part of the medial preoptic nucleus, and the 
    ventral premammillary nucleus, all of which are known to project 
    massively to these two components of the periventricular region 
    (Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88; Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">From earlier parts of this discussion it should perhaps 
    come as no surprise that all hypothalamic areas receiving a dense 
    input from the PA contain many neurons that concentrate gonadal 
    steroids and express high levels of mRNAs encoding the androgen 
    and/or estrogen receptors (Pfaff and Keiner, &apos;73; Sar and 
    Stumpf, &apos;74; Simerly et al., &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Furthermore, all the major hypothalamic targets of the 
    PA display clear structural sexual dimorphisms (Gorski et al., 
    &apos;80; Bleier et al., &apos;82; Arai, &apos;84; Simerly et al., 
    &apos;84, &apos;85; Akesson and Micevych, &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">The deeper parts of layer I11 of the COApl (immediately 
    adjacent to the PA) also provide a dense input to the 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">In contrast to the PA, however, this projection is 
    mainly directed to the medial zone of the tuberal region and to the 
    ventral premammillary nucleus, with very few endings in the 
    preoptic region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Based on autoradiographic experiments, Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;78a) suggested the existence of a projection from the 
    posterior cortical nucleus to the ventral premammillary nucleus, 
    and several experiments with fluorogold deposited in this 
    hypothalamic nucleus retrogradely labeled many cells in the 
    posterior cortical nucleus, mainly in a zone just surrounding the 
    borders of the PA (see Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">However, neither anterograde nor retrograde tracing 
    studies have previously reported a projection from the posterior 
    cortical nucleus to the medial zone of the hypothalamus at tuberal 
    levels (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Berk and Finkelstein, 
    &apos;81; Kita and Oomura, &apos;82; Zaborsky, &apos;82; Ono et 
    al., &apos;85; Fahrbach et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">The reason for this discrepancy may well be related to 
    the fact that the amygdalo-hippocampal transition area delineated 
    by these authors also encompasses part of what we now regard as the 
    deepest part of the COApl, for reasons to be discussed shortly.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">In summary, the PA, as we have defined it, has a very 
    characteristic pattern of efferent pathways that can be 
    distinguished from the outputs both of nearby cells and of more 
    superficial neurons in the posterior cortical nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Interestingly, the major telencephalic and diencephalic 
    targets of the PA are components of the sexually dimorphic circuit, 
    including the posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala, the principal nucleus of the BST, the ventral part of the 
    lateral septal nucleus, the anteroventral periventricular nucleus 
    of the preoptic region, the medial preoptic nucleus, the 
    ventrolateral part of the ventromedial nucleus and adjacent parts 
    of the lateral hypothalamic area, and the ventral premammillary 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">In addition, the PA projects to several other parts of 
    the telencephalon, including the dorsal endopiriform nucleus, the 
    ventral subiculum and adjacent parts of hippocampal field CA1, the 
    nucleus accumbens, and the infralimbic area of the medial 
    prefrontal region.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Finally, considering the remarkable hodological 
    relationships between the PA and the sexually dimorphic circuit, it 
    would be of interest to compare the connectional patterns of this 
    nucleus between male and female animals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">In the present study we have not specifically examined 
    the projections of the PA in female animals, although the results 
    of previous anatomical studies in the medial preoptic nucleus and 
    other sexually dimorphic areas suggest that this circuitry is 
    qualitatively similar in both sexes, whereas quantitative 
    differences within particular terminal fields may be expected (see 
    Simerly and Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s455">Output of the posterior 
    cortical nucleus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">In the preceding section, the output of the PA was 
    discussed and compared with certain projections of the posterior 
    cortical nucleus as a whole, where appropriate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">However, even though our collection of PHAL experiments 
    is not extensive enough to provide a complete account of the 
    efferent projections of the posterior cortical nucleus, it does 
    include enough injections for us to make general statements about 
    possible differences between its medial and lateral subdivisions, 
    as well as between the deeper parts of layer I11 and more 
    superficial regions of the COApl.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Our results indicate that projections from the COApm and 
    superficial parts of the COApl (layer I1 and adjacent regions of 
    layer 111) share several features in common.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Thus, both of these structures appear to provide 
    extensive projections to other parts of the amygdala, as well as to 
    a number of other cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Within the amygdala, superficial regions of the COApl 
    and the COApm share heavy bidirectional projections and both 
    provide dense inputs to the same parts of the amygdala ventral to 
    the central and basolateral nuclei, which, remarkably, tend to 
    avoid the deepest sublayer of the MEApd as well as the 
    anteroventral part of the medial nucleus (MEAav).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">The hippocampal formation (ventral subiculum, field CAI, 
    and entorhinal area), area TR, piriform area, dorsal and ventral 
    agranular insular areas, and infralimbic area also receive an 
    appreciable input from both subdivisions of the COAp, whereas the 
    posterior agranular insular area as well as the perirhinal area 
    appear to receive a much less dense innervation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">It is noteworthy that, in contrast to the PA and to 
    deeper regions of layer I11 of the COApl, these other areas of the 
    COAp have more widespread projections to other cortical areas, and 
    in this particular case to other regions within the amygdala as 
    well.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">As mentioned above, our results clearly indicate that 
    there is also a strong convergence of inputs from the 
    posterolateral and posteromedial parts of the cortical nucleus 
    within the interfascicular and the transverse nuclei of the BST.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">In view of the fact that the posteromedial and 
    posterolateral parts of the posterior cortical nucleus receive 
    direct inputs from the accessory and main (lateral) olfactory 
    tracts, respectively, the great overlap in the distribution of 
    efferents from the two subdivisions of the posterior cortical 
    nucleus may well play a critical role in some behaviors that depend 
    on the convergence of olfactory cues from the vomeronasal organ and 
    from the rest of the olfactory mucosa.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">For example, it has been shown that removal of the 
    vomeronasal organ alone produces severe deficits in the mating 
    behavior of sexually inexperienced but not sexually experienced 
    male hamsters (Meredith, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Furthermore, lesions confined to parts of the amygdala 
    related to the vomeronasal system produce serious deficits in the 
    mating behavior of male hamsters, even if the animals are sexually 
    experienced (Lehman and Winans, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Taken together, these findings raise the possibility 
    that in experienced male hamsters, olfactory inputs relayed by the 
    main olfactory system may be able to sustain mating behavior 
    through their direct accesses to regions of the amygdala that 
    normally receive direct input from the accessory olfactory 
    system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">In contrast to superficial regions of the COApl, it is 
    important to reiterate that the COApm provides a dense input to the 
    granule cell layer of the accessory olfactory bulb, as well as a 
    heavy projection to the opposite side of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Projections from the COApm to the accessory olfactory 
    bulb have been described in previous retrograde tracttracing 
    studies, which (in agreement with the present study) also suggest 
    that the COApl does not provide direct inputs to this region 
    (Broadwell and Jacobowitz, &apos;76; De Olmos et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Our observations indicate that axons from the COApm 
    projecting through the anterior commissure arise primarily from 
    more superficially located cells, and that they provide a very 
    distinct input to the region exactly contralateral to the injection 
    site, in addition to a number of other terminal fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">The projection to the contralateral COApm has been 
    described previously with both anterograde and retrograde 
    tract-tracing methods (Krettek and Price, &apos;78b; Ottersen, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">The results of the present study also provide clear 
    evidence that projections from deeper regions of COApl layer I11 
    are quite different from those arising in more superficial regions 
    (layer I1 and adjacent regions of layer 111) of the same area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Unlike superficial regions of the COApl, deeper regions 
    of layer I11 give rise to fibers that end in the PA, as well as 
    dense projections to the septal region and to parts of the medial 
    zone of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">However, it should be emphasized that all other regions 
    that appear to be innervated by the deeper cells of layer I11 also 
    receive inputs from cells located more superficially in the 
    COApl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Thus, neurons throughout the depth of the COApl appear 
    to provide a similar pattern of inputs to the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala and to the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis, as well to 
    the same cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">However, it should be noted that, with the possible 
    exception of a dense input to the ventral subiculum and field CAI, 
    the projections from deeper cells of COApl layer I11 to other 
    cortical areas appear to be far less dense than those arising from 
    cells located more superficially in the COApl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Taken together, our results indicate that the pattern of 
    outputs from the COApl is similar to that for other cortical 
    fields, where more superficial neurons tend to project more densely 
    to other cortical areas (and in this case to other structures 
    within the amygdala), while cells located more deeply tend to 
    project more densely to subcortical regions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Finally, it is important to point out here that our 
    delineation of the COApl differs from that used by De Olmos et al. 
    (&apos;851, which corresponds largely to the periamygdaloid cortex 
    of Krettex and Price (&apos;78b) and also includes a region that we 
    have identified here as the piriform-amygdaloid area (PAA).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">As described above, the COApl and PAA present distinct 
    cytoarchitectonic features as well as clearly distinct outputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Thus, our anterograde tracing experiments show that, 
    compared to the COApl, the piriform-amygdaloid area provides a much 
    more dense input to the endopiriform nucleus and agranular insular 
    areas, as well as a much more massive projection to the lateral 
    nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s481">Borders of the PA and 
    posterior cortical nucleus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">The ability to localize so precisely the limits of PHAL 
    injection sites allowed us to refine the subdivision of the caudal 
    amygdala by taking account of both cytoarchitectonic and 
    connectional information.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">The parcellation scheme that we finally adopted was 
    based on a synthesis of historical, architectonic, and connectional 
    information referred to throughout earlier parts of the paper.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Despite the fact that this scheme must still be regarded 
    as quite provisional, it seems useful to summarize concisely here 
    some the major issues that have emerged and some of the major 
    problems that remain to be solved.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">The major conceptual issue that must be dealt with in 
    any study of the caudal amygdala is the widespread lack of 
    agreement about nomenclature and the boundaries of particular cell 
    groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">We have come to the conclusion that the posterior 
    cortical nucleus consists of two parts, medial and lateral, which 
    are distinguished most clearly by inputs from the accessory and 
    main (lateral) olfactory tracts, respectively, and that the PA lies 
    deep to the COApl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">These basic assumptions raise two questions that require 
    further comment: what is the boundary between the PA and the COApl, 
    and what is the boundary between deeper parts of the COApl and 
    COApm?</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">To address the first issue, it should be recalled that 
    all parts of the PA as defined here appear to give rise to a 
    similar pattern of subcortical projections, whereas neurons in 
    adjacent (deep) regions of the COApl give rise to a distinct 
    pattern of inputs to the amygdala, septal region, and 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">The boundary between the PA and COApl shown in Figure 2 
    is thus based primarily on cytoarchitectonic criteria (the 
    relatively homogeneous appearance of the PA), supplemented by 
    information from our PHAL experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">The second major issue concerns the basic structure of 
    the posterior cortical nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">We agree with the general view that it is best regarded 
    as a trilaminar component of the olfactory cortex (see Price et 
    al., &apos;87), although beyond this, the precise limits of the two 
    cellular layers is not at all clear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">The only exception is layer I1 of the COApl, which is 
    relatively thick and well defined.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Beyond this, our tentative conclusion is that layer I1 
    (or at least a recognizable part of layer 11) of the COApm is thin 
    and poorly developed, while layer I11 of the COApm is less 
    cell-dense than layer I11 of the COApl, which can be seen 
    relatively clearly to arch medially over it and thus form the 
    ventral border of the PA.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">One final point about layer I11 of the COApl is worth 
    mentioning.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">As suggested by our findings, and more clearly 
    visualized in experiments with retrograde tracer injections in the 
    hypothalamus (N.S.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Canteras, R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Swanson, unpublished observations), it seems likely that 
    this layer in fact contains at least two sublayers, one (deep, 
    adjacent to the PA) projecting rather heavily to the hypothalamus, 
    and the other (more superficial) projecting only very sparsely to 
    the hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">One final question deserves mention; what is the most 
    useful way to view the position of the PA within the amygdala as a 
    whole?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">When all of the available evidence is taken into 
    account, we suggest that the PA may be regarded as a component of 
    the deep amygdalar nuclei, as opposed to the corticomedial 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">There are two major reasons for this.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">First, like the lateral, basal, and central nuclei, the 
    PA does not have a molecular layer, and thus does not appear to 
    receive direct olfactory input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Second, it is clear from Figure 2 that the PA is related 
    topographically to posterior parts of the basomedial and 
    basolateral nuclei, all three lying between deep white matter and 
    more superficial parts of the olfactory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">As such, we suggest that the PA represents the 
    posteromedial tip of the deep nuclear complex of the amygdala, 
    rather than a component of the olfactory corticomedial complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">This argument cannot be extended to the connectional 
    level until the outputs of the posterior basomedial nucleus are 
    understood in detail.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s506">Comparison of 
    projections from the PA and ventral subiculum</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">In view of the fact the the PA adjoins the ventral tip 
    of the pyramidal layer of the ventral subiculum, some workers have 
    referred to it as a transitional area between the amygdala and 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">As discussed above, evidence gathered thus far indicates 
    that the PA may be viewed as a deep nucleus of the amygdala, while 
    the ventral subiculum clearly seems to be a cortical field within 
    the hippocampal formation with well-defined molecular and cellular 
    layers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">The following comparison is based on our reexamination 
    of the outputs of the ventral subiculum with the PHAL method 
    (Canteras and Swanson, &apos;92), as well as on previous 
    anterograde tract-tracing studies (Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75, 
    &apos;77; Meibach and Siegel, &apos;77; Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78a; Groenewegen et al., &apos;87; Witter and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Projections from the ventral subiculum course either 
    obliquely through the angular bundle to innervate the amygdala and 
    adjacent parts of the temporal lobe, or travel through the alveus 
    and fimbria to the precommissural fornix and medial 
    corticohypothalamic tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">In the temporal pole, the ventral subiculum projects to 
    the entorhinal and piriform areas and area TR, to the dorsal 
    endopiriform nucleus, and to several nuclei within the amygdala, 
    particularly to the posterior part of the basomedial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Of all these structures in the temporal pole that 
    receive a substantial input from the ventral subiculum, only the 
    dorsal endopiriform nucleus also appears to receive a substantial 
    projection from the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">In addition, it should be recalled that the PA projects 
    densely to the posterodorsal part of the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala, which seems to be only sparsely innervated by the ventral 
    subiculum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Like the PA, the ventral subiculum projects to the 
    ventral part of the lateral septal nucleus, to virtually the same 
    regions of the nucleus accumbens, and to the infralimbic area, 
    although by way of the precommissural fornix.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Efferent fibers from the ventral subiculum coursing 
    through the precommissural fornix also provide substantial inputs 
    to the BST and anterior olfactory nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Remarkably, the pattern of projections from the ventral 
    subiculum to the BST is quite similar to what we have described in 
    the present study for the posterior cortical nucleus of the 
    amygdala: both regions provide a rather dense input to the 
    transverse and interfascicular nuclei, and clearly tend to avoid 
    the principal nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">In sharp contrast to the PA, most efferent fibers from 
    the ventral subiculum reach the thalamus and hypothalamus by way of 
    the medial corticohypothalamic tract, providing a very distinct 
    pattern of innervation to these regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Thus, in the thalamus, the paraventricular nucleus and 
    nucleus reuniens receive a substantial input from the ventral 
    subiculum, whereas the PA appears to provide only a sparse 
    innervation, which extends to rostral zones of the medial part of 
    the mediodorsal nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">In the preoptic region, the projection from ventral 
    subiculum is mainly directed toward undifferentiated parts of the 
    medial preotic area as well as toward the lateral part of the 
    medial preoptic nucleus, while the medial part of this nucleus as 
    well as the anteroventral periventricular nucleus appear to receive 
    a more sparse input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">As pointed out above, the anterior hypothalamic region 
    receives only a very sparse input from the PA, whereas the ventral 
    subiculum provides a rather dense terminal field just dorsal to the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus; proceeding caudally, this terminal field 
    extends dorsally to fill the subparaventricular zone (of Watts et 
    al., &apos;87) along the medial border of the anterior hypothalamic 
    nucleus and the ventrolateral border of the paraventricular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">In addition, we have observed in our PHAL experiments 
    that the projection from the ventral subiculum to the tuberal 
    region is directed chiefly to dorsal and medial regions of the 
    cell-sparse shell that surrounds the ventromedial nucleus, as well 
    as to the dorsomedial nucleus, in contrast to the PA, which appears 
    to innervate primarily caudal regions of the ventrolateral part of 
    the ventromedial nucleus and adjacent parts of the basal lateral 
    hypothalamic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">In the mammillary region, both the PA and the ventral 
    subiculum provide inputs to the ventral premammillary nucleus and 
    to the cell-poor zone that surrounds the medial mammillary 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">In addition, the ventral subiculum projects 
    substantially to the posterior periventricular nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">In conclusion, although the PA and ventral subiculum may 
    share some common targets (such as the dorsal endopiriform nucleus, 
    ventral lateral septal nucleus, nucleus accumbens, and ventral 
    premammillary nucleus), they present quite distinct patterns of 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">However, in spite of these differences it is important 
    to bear in mind that the ventral subiculum is more like adjacent 
    parts of the amygdala than the rest of the hippocampal formation, 
    especially when its projections to the septal region and 
    hypothalamus are taken into account.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s526">Functional 
    implications</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">There appear to be no reports in the literature that 
    deal specifically with the functional role of the PA.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">On the other hand, experiments with lesions that very 
    often involved the PA and/or its efferent fibers indicate rather 
    clearly that, as a whole, regions in or near the corticomedial 
    complex of the amygdala participate in the control of salt appetite 
    (Nitabach et al., &apos;89; Schulkin et al., &apos;891, 
    antagonistic behavior (Koolhaas et al., &apos;80; Bolhuis et al., 
    &apos;84; Luiten et al., &apos;85; Vochteloo and Koolhaas, 
    &apos;87), and reproductive behavior (Harris and Sachs, &apos;75; 
    Masco and Carrer, &apos;80; Lehman et al., &apos;80; Fleming et 
    al., &apos;83; Lehman et al., &apos;83; Chateau and Aron, 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">In view of the neuronal connections established by the 
    PA, as well as clear indications that neurons here are influenced 
    by circulating gonadal and adrenal steroid hormones, we will 
    discuss in this section its possible involvement in the expression 
    of these behaviors.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Recently, Schulkin et al. (&apos;89) have shown that 
    electrolytic damage to the medial region of the amygdala, including 
    the PA and/or the stria terminalis, abolishes aldosteroneinduced 
    salt appetite in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">It is important to note in this context that neurons in 
    the PA express very high levels of the mRNA encoding the 
    mineralocorticoid receptor (Arriza et al., &apos;881, and that the 
    nucleus sends a very dense projection to the anteroventral 
    periventricular nucleus of the preoptic region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Although the specific role of the latter in controlling 
    salt appetite has not been shown unequivocally, electrolytic 
    lesions in the region surrounding the anteroventral tip of the 
    third ventricle known as the AV3V region (which includes the 
    anterovental periventricular nucleus and other cell groups; see 
    Johnson, &apos;85) interfere with sodium consumption (Chiaraviglio 
    and Perez Guaita, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Furthermore, neuronal cell bodies within the 
    anteroventral periventricular nucleus contain high concentrations 
    of atriopeptin (Standaert et al., &apos;86), a peptide that 
    inhibits salt intake in salt-deprived animals when injected into 
    the third ventricle (Antunes-Rodrigues et al., &apos;861, and 
    appears to be regulated by circulating aldosterone (Geiger et al., 
    &apos;91).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Nitabach et al. (&apos;89) have shown that the daily 
    need-free saline intake of female rats is eliminated or reduced 
    after bilateral electrolytic lesions that involve medial parts of 
    the amygdala (including the PA).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Need-free salt intake, which refers to an 
    overconsumption of salt that is apparently not needed to maintain 
    homeostasis, appears to be greater in females, and may actually 
    reflect a suppressive effect of androgens in the male (see for 
    references, Epstein, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Because neurons in the PA express high levels of both 
    androgen and estrogen receptors (as well as mineralocorticoid 
    receptors), in addition to massive neuronal interconnections with 
    the sexual dimorphic circuit, it is tempting to suggest a role for 
    this nucleus in the control of sexually dimorphic aspects of salt 
    appetite.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Further studies are obviously needed to clarify this 
    important issue.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">It appears to be fairly well established that animals 
    with electrolytic lesions in medial parts of the amygdala that very 
    often comprise the PA and/or intraamygdaloid parts of the stria 
    terminalis often display alterations of the aggressive behavior 
    accompanying one kind of learning process or another that is an 
    integral part of the test situation (Koolhaas et al., &apos;80; 
    Bolhuis et al., &apos;84; Luiten et al., &apos;85; Vochteloo and 
    Koolhaas, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Although the specific role of the PA has never been 
    addressed in these studies, it should be pointed out that this 
    nucleus projects densely to several regions that have been 
    implicated in the control of aggressive behavior, including the 
    lateral septal nucleus, medial preoptic nucleus, ventromedial 
    nucleus, and ventral premammillary nucleus (see van den Berg et 
    al., &apos;83; Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Furthermore, it is known that activation thresholds for 
    such behavior depend on circulating levels of gonadal steroid 
    hormones (Floody and Pfaff, &apos;741, suggesting another link 
    between the PA and the control of aggressive behavior.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Considering the results presented here, it seems obvious 
    that the PA must exert some control over reproductive behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Lesions involving rostral parts of the corticomedial 
    complex of the amygdala appear to decrease the frequency of 
    lordotic responses in females (Masco and Carrer, &apos;80) as well 
    as to impair mating behavior in males (Lehman et al., &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">The possible role of more medial regions of the amygdala 
    in the control of mating behavior has been more extensively 
    investigated in the male hamster, in which lesions centered in 
    rostral parts of the medial nucleus appear to compromise male 
    mating behavior; furthermore, since knifecuts of the stria 
    terminalis may only interfere with temporal patterning of the 
    copulatory sequence, it has been suggested that the ansa 
    peduncularis may be an important route by which the medial nucleus 
    of the amygdala influences this behavior (Lehman et al., &apos;80, 
    &apos;83; Lehman and Winans, &apos;82, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Considering the fact that lesions of the stria 
    terminalis seem to modify the expression of copulatory behavior, 
    further studies are needed to determine whether the PA plays a 
    specific role in the control of this behavior.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Fleming et al. (&apos;83) have shown that lesions 
    centered in the corticomedial complex of the amygdala facilitate 
    the expression of maternal behavior in rats, and that this effect 
    seems to be mediated through the medial preoptic area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">It is known that the medial preoptic area plays a 
    critical role in both maternal behavior and masculine sexual 
    behavior, and there is evidence to suggest that within this region, 
    more rostral parts are preferentially involved in the control of 
    maternal behavior whereas caudal parts are preferentially related 
    to mounting behavior (Gray and Brooks, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">It may be important to point out in this context that 
    the PA gives rise to a particularly dense projection to rostral 
    parts of the medial preoptic area (Simerly and Swanson, &apos;861, 
    suggesting that this amygdaloid nucleus plays an as yet unknown 
    role in the control of maternal behavior.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">The expression of any behavior involves the elaboration 
    of complex sequences of relatively stereotyped movements and 
    postures that require a great deal of somatomotor integration.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">In view of this, it is important to point out that the 
    PA has direct inputs to the nucleus accumbens, which has been 
    proposed to mediate locomotor aspects of certain goal-directed 
    behaviors (for reviews see Swanson and Mogenson, &apos;81; Mogenson 
    et al., &apos;83, &apos;89; Mogenson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Moreover, it is possible that the PA influences the 
    general arousal level of the animal by way of its projection to the 
    lateral septal nucleus, which is known to innervate densely the 
    lateral zone of the hypothalamus, which in turn seems to Play a 
    role in attentional and arousal mechanisms (for reviews see Kohler 
    et al., &apos;84; Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">One of the most interesting findings of the present 
    study is the pattern of projections from the PA to medial parts of 
    the hypothalamus, which strongly suggests that the PA must play an 
    important role in controlling the output of the neuroendocrine 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Cells that project to the neurohemal zone of the median 
    eminence and contain factors controlling the release of hormones 
    from the anterior pituitary gland are localized to specific regions 
    in and around the periventricular zone of the hypothalamus, 
    particularly in the arcuate nucleus and in parvicellular regions of 
    the paraventricular nucleus (see Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Because the latter two regions are only sparsely 
    innervated by the PA, the influence of this amygdaloid nucleus on 
    these periventricular regions appears to be mainly indirect, most 
    probably by way of its projections to the anteroventral 
    periventricular nucleus, the medial part of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus, and the ventral premammillary nucleus (Simerly and 
    Swanson, &apos;88; Canteras et al., &apos;92).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">The first two cell groups project heavily to the medial 
    parvicellular part of the paraventricular nucleus, which contains 
    neurons that synthesize corticotropin-releasing hormone (Swanson, 
    &apos;87) or thyrotropin-releasing hormone (Lechan and Jackson, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">And all three hypothalamic regions may also influence 
    the secretion of prolactin and growth hormone by way of their dense 
    projections to the arcuate nucleus, where the majority of 
    neurosecretory cells synthesizing dopamine (Bjorklund and Lindvall, 
    &apos;84) or growth hormone-releasing hormone (Sawchenko et al., 
    &apos;85) are found.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">All three hypothalamic targets of the PA also project to 
    the region of the anterior periventricular nucleus that contains 
    neurosecretory somatostatin cells (see Swanson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">The secretion of luteinizing hormone and 
    folliclestimulating hormone may also be influenced significantly by 
    the anteroventral periventricular nucleus (Wiegand and Terasawa, 
    &apos;82) and the ventral premammillary nucleus (Beltramino and 
    Taleisnik, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Finally, it also seems possible that the medial preoptic 
    nucleus and the anteroventral periventricular nucleus influence the 
    output of the magnocellular neurosecretory system (see Simerly and 
    Swanson, &apos;88).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s559">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s560">We thank Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s561">David Warren for document 
    preparation, and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s562">Kris Trulock for photographic 
    assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s563">This work was supported in 
    part by CNPq Fellowship 2009691 90-0, FAPESP Fellowship 8811289-0 
    to N.S.C., and NINDS 2ROlNS16686 to L.W.S.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s564">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Aktssson, T K., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Miccvych (1991) l&apos;achykinin immunoreactive cells in 
    the rat ventral premammillary nucleus: Sex differences, castration 
    effects, and gonadal steroid binding.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Abstr. 17:418.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Ankenhaucr, W., U.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Strahle, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Schutz 11988) Synergistic action of glucocorticoid and 
    estradiol responsive elements.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Natl Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="16" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Sci. 1T.S.A. 85:7526-7530.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Antunes-Kodrigues, J., S M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">McCann, L.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Rogers, and W K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Samson 11986) Central administration of atrial 
    natriuretic factor inhibits saline preference in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Endocrinology I18:1726-1728.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Arai, Y. (1984) Synaptic sexual differentiation of the 
    neuroendocrine brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">In K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Ochiai, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Arai, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Shoida, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Takahashi (eds): Endocrine Correlates of Keproduction 
    Berlin: Springer, pp. 2940.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Arriza, J.L., K.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Simerly, L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Swanson, and K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Evans (19881 The neuronal mineralocorticoid receptor as 
    a mediator of glucocorticoid response.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Neuron 1:887-900.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Azmitia, E.C., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Segal (1978) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    differential ascending projections of the dorsal and median rdphe 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Neurol. 179:641-668.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Beltramino, C , and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Taleisnik (1985) Ventral premammillaiy nuclei mediate 
    pheromonal-induced LH release stimuli in the rat Nruroendocrinology 
    41,119-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Finkelstein 11981) AfTerent projections to the preoptic 
    area and hypothalamic regions in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Neuroscience fi.16011624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Bjorklund, A,, and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Lindvall (19841 Dopamine-containing systems in the 
    CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Bjorklund and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    2, Classical Transmitters in the CNS, Part I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 55-122.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Uleier, R., W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Byne, and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Siggelkow 11982) Cytoarchitectonic sexual dimorphisms 
    (if the medial preoptic and antwior hypothalamic areas in guinea 
    pig, rat, hamster, and mouse.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Neurol. 212,118-130.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Bolhuis, J.J., K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Fitzgerald, D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Dijk, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Koolhaas 119841 The corticomedial amygdala and learning 
    in an agonistic situation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Behav. .?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">2:575-579.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Broadwell, K.D., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Jacohowitz (1976) Olfactciry relationships of the 
    telencephalon and diencephalon in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Ill.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">The ipsilateral centrifugal fibers to the olfactory 
    hulhar and retrobulbar formations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Neurol. 170,321-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Brodal, A. (1947) The amygdaloid 87.1-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">Canteras, N.S., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Swanson (1992) Projections of the ventral subiculum to 
    the amygdala, septum. and hypothalamus: A PHAL anterngrade 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Neurol. ,724: 180-194.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Canteras, N.S., K.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Simerly, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Swanson (1989) The efferent connections of the 
    amygdaln-hippocampal area: A Phaseolus tdgur[s leucoagglutinin 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Abstr. 15:1249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Canteras, N.S., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Simerly. and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Swanson (1992) Projections ventral premammillary 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Neurol. 324.195-212.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Carlsen, J., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Zaborszky, and L Heimer (1985) Cholinergic projections 
    from the basal forebrain to the basolateral amygdaloid complex: A 
    combined retrograde fluorescent and immunohistochemical rol. 
    234t155-167.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Chateau, D., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Aron (1989) Lordosis behavior in male rats after lesions 
    in different regions of the corticomedial amygdaloid nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Horm.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Behav. 23t448-455.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Chiaraviglio, E., and M.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Perez-Guaita (1984) Anterior third ventricle (A3V) 
    lesions and homeostasis regulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">(Paris) 79t446452.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Chiba. -.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">T.. and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Murata (1985) Afferent and efferent connections of the 
    medii preoptic area in the rat: A WGA-HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Bull 14t261-272.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Conrad, L.C.A., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Pfaff (1976) Efferents from medial basal forebrain and 
    hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">An autoradiographic study of the medial preoptic 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Neurol. 169: 185-220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Conrad, L.C.A., C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Leonard, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">PfafF (1974) Connections of the median and dorsal raphe 
    nuclei in the rat: An autoradiographic and degeneration study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Neurol. 156:179-206.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Crosby, E.C., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Humphrey (1941) Studies of the vertebrate telencephdon. 
    11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">The nuclear pattern of the anterior olfactory nucleus, 
    tuberculum olfactorium and the amygdaloid complex in adult man.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Neurol. 74t309-352.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Crosby, E.C., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Humphrey (1944) Studies of the vertebrate telencephalon. 
    111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">The amygdaloid complex in the shrew (Blarina 
    breuicauda).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Neurol. 81.285-305.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Dado R.J., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Burstein, K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Cliffer, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Giesler Jr. (1990) Evidence that Fluoro-Gold can be 
    transported avidly through fibers of passage.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Brain Res. 533t329-333.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Olmos, J.S., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Hardy, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Heimer (1978) The afferent connections of the main and 
    accessory olfactory bulb formations in the rat: An experimental 
    HRP-study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Neurol. 181.213-244.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Olmos, J.S., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Beltramino (1985) Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System, Vol. 1, Forebrain 
    and Midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">New York: Academic Press, pp. 223-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">DeVries, G.J., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Buijs, and F.W. van Leeuwen (1984) Sex differences in 
    vasopressin and other neurotransmitter systems in the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">In G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">DeVries, J.P.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">DeBruijn, H.B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Uylings, and M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Corner (eds): Sex Differences in the Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Progress in Brain Research, Vol. 61.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 185-203.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Epstein, A.N. (1990) Prospectus: Thirst and salt 
    appetite.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">In E.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Stricker (ed): Handbook of Behavioral Neurobiology, Vol. 
    10, Neurobiology of Food and Fluid Intake.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">New York: Plenun Press, pp. 489-512.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Fahrbach, S.E., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Morrell, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">PfafF (1989) Studies of ventromedial hypothalamic 
    afFerents in the rat using three methods of HRP application.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Brain Res. 77t221-233.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Fallon, J.H., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Moore (1978) Catecholamine innervation of the basal 
    forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">IV.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Topography of the dopamine projection to the basal 
    forebrain and neostriatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Neurol. 18Ot545-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Fallon, J.H., D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Koziell, and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Moore (1978) Catecholamine innervation of the basal 
    forebrain. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Amygdala, suprarhinal cortex and entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Neurol. 180:509-532.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">d , R.L.M., and W.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Mehler (1985) Thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System, Vol. 1, Forebrain 
    and Midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">New York: Academic Press, pp. 129-168.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Fleming, AS., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Miceli, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Moretto (1983) Lesions of the medial preoptic area 
    prevent the facilitation of maternal behavior produced by amygdala 
    lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">Behav. 31:503-510.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Floody, D.R., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Pfaff (1974) Steroid hormones and aggressive behavior: 
    Approaches to the study of hormone-sensitive brain mechanisms for 
    behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Assoc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Nervous Mental Dis. 52149-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Geiger, H., U.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Bahner, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Palkovits, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Nicklas, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Hugo, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Heidland (1991) Effects of aldosterone and dexamethasone 
    on atrial natriuretic peptide levels in preoptic and hypothalamic 
    nuclei of adrenalectomized and intact rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Neuroendocrinology 53:63-68.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus uulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Gorski, R.A., R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Harlan, C.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Jacobson, J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Shryne, and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Southam (1980) Evidence for the existence of a sexually 
    dimorphic nucleus in the preoptic area of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Neurol. 193:529-539.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Gray, p., and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Brooks (1984) Effect of lesion location within the 
    medial Preoptic-anterior hypothalamic continuum on maternal and 
    male sexual behaviors in female rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Neurosci. 98:703-711.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Green, S., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Chambon (1987) Oestradiol induction of a 
    glucocorticoidresponsive gene by a chimaeric receptor.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Nature 325t75-78.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">Groenewegen, H.J., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Vermeulen-Van der Zee, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Te Kortschot, and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Witter (1987) Organization of the projections from the 
    subiculum to the ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">A study using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Neuroscience 23: 103-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Grove, E.A. (1988a) Neural associations of the 
    substantia innominata rat: Afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Neurol. 277t315-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Grove, E.A. (1988b) Efferent connections of the 
    substantia the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Neurol. 277:347-364.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Gurdjian, E.S. (1928) The corpus striatum 45249-281.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Harris, V.H., and B.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Sachs (1975) Copulatory behavior following amygdaloid 
    lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Brain Res. 86t514-518.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Hartman, B.K. (1973) Immunofluorescence of 
    dopamine-P-hydroxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Application of improved methodology to the localization 
    of the peripheral and central noradrenergic nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Cytochem.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">21r312-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">Haug, F.M.S. (1976) Sulphide silver pattern and 
    cytoarchitectonics of parahippocampal areas in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Special reference to the subdivision of area 
    entorhinalis (area 28) and its demarcation from the pyriform 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Cell Biol. 521-73.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Hellendall, R.P., D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Godfrey, C.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">Ross, D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Armstrong, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Price (1986) The distribution of choline 
    acetyltransferase in the rat amygdaloid complex and adjacent 
    cortical areas, as determined by quantitative microassay and 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Neurol. 249t486-498.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">Hines, M., F.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Davis, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Coquelin, R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Goy, and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Gorski (1985) Sexually dimorphic regions in the medial 
    preoptic area and the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis of the 
    guinea pig brain: A description and an investigation of their 
    relationship to gonadal steroids in adulthood.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">Neurosci. 5:4047.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Hsu, S.M., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Raine (1981) Protein A, avidin and biotin 
    inimmunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Cytochem. 29: 1349-1353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Hsu, S.M., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Raine, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">Fanger (1981) The use of avidin-biotinperoxidase complex 
    (ABC) in immunoperoxidase techniques: A comparison between ABC and 
    unlabeled antibody (PAP) procedures.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Cytochem. 29:577-580.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Johnson, A.K. (1985) Role of the periventricular tissue 
    surrounding the anteroventral third ventricle (AV3V) in the 
    regulation of body fluid homeostasis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">In R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Schrier (ed): Vasopressin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">New York: Raven Press, pp. 319-331.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">G., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Swanson (1989) Studies on the cellular architecture of 
    the bed nuclei of the stria terminalis in the rat: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Neurol. 280:587-602.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Kevetter, G.A., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Winans (1981) Connections of the corticomedial amygdala 
    in the golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Efferents of the vomeronasal amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Neurol. 197%-98.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Kita, H., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Oomura (1982) An HRP study of the afferent connections 
    to rat medial hypothalamic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Bull. 8:53-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">Koolhaas, J.M., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Schuurman, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">Wiepkema (1980) The organization of intraspecific 
    agonistic behaviour in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Neurobiol. 15:247268.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">Kohler, C., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Haglund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Swanson (1984) A diffuse alfa-MSHimmunoreactive 
    projection to the hippocampus and spinal cord from individual 
    neurons in the lateral hypothalamic area and zona incerta.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Neurol. 223:510-514.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Price (1977a) The cortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus and adjacent thalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">I7lt157-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Price (1977b) Projections from the amygdaloid complex 
    and adjacent olfactory structures to the entorhinal cortex and to 
    the subiculum in the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Neurol. 172723-752.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">Price (1978a) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Neurol. 178t225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">Price (1978b) A description of the amygdaloid complex in 
    the rat and cat with observations on intra-amygdaloid axonal 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Neurol. 178255-280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Krieger, M.S., L.C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Conrad, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">PfafF (1979) An autoradiographic study of the efferent 
    connections of the ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Neurol. 183t785-816.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Lechan, R.M., and I.M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Jackson (1982) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    thyrotropin-releasing hormone in the rat hypothalamus and 
    pituitary.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Endocrinology 1 I1:55-65.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Lehman, M.N., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Winans (1982) Vomeronasal and olfactory pathways to the 
    amygdala controlling male hamster sexual behavior: autoradiographic 
    and behavioral analyses.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">Brain Res. 240:2741.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Lehman, M.N., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">Winans (1983) Evidence for a ventral non-strial pathway 
    from the amygdala to the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis in the 
    male golden hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Brain Res. 268t139-146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Lehman, M.N., S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">Winans, and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Powers (1980) Medial nucleus of the amygdala mediates 
    chemosensory control of male hamster sexual behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Science 210:557-560.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">Lehman, M.N., J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Powers, and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">Winans (1983) Stria terminalis lesions alter the 
    temporal pattern of copulatory behavior in the male golden 
    hamster.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Brain Res. 8t109-128.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Luiten, P.G.M., J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">Koolhaas, S. de Boer, and S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Koopmans (1985) The corticomedial amygdala in the 
    central nervous system organization of agonistic behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Brain Res. 332t283-297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Luskin, M.B., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Price (1983) The topographic organization of 
    associational fibers of the olfactory system in the rat, including 
    centrifugal fibers to the olfactory bulb.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">Neurol. 216.964-291.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">Maragos, W.F., S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">Newman, M.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Lehman, and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">Powers (1989) Neurons of origin and fiber trajectory of 
    amygdalofugal projections to the medial preoptic area in Syrian 
    hamsters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Neurol. 28Ot59-71.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Masco, D.H., and H.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Carrer (1980) Sexual receptivity in female rats after 
    lesion or stimulation in different amygdaloid nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Behav.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">24t1073-1080.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">McDonald, A.J. (1987) Organization of amygdaloid 
    projections to the mediodorsal thalamus and prefrontal cortex: A 
    fluorescence retrograde transport study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">Neurol. 26246-58.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">McDonald, A.J., and T.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">Jackson (1987) Amygdaloid connections with posterior 
    insular and temporal cortical areas in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">26259-77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Meibach, R.C., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Siege1 (1977) Efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">Brain Res. 124:197-224.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">Meredith, M. (1986) Vomeronasal organ removal before 
    sexual experience impairs male hamster mating behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Behav. 36t737-743.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Mogenson, G.J. (1987) Limbic-motor integration.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Psychobiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Psychol. 12:117-170.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">Mogenson, G.J., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Swanson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">Wu (1983) Neural projections from nucleus accumbens to 
    globus pallidus, substantia innominata, and lateral 
    preoptic-lateral hypothalamic area: An anatomical and 
    electrophysiological investigation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Neurosci. 3:189-202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Mogenson, G.J., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">Wu, and C.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">Tsai (1989) Subpallidal-pedunculopontine projections but 
    not subpallidal-mediodorsal thalamus projections contribute to 
    spontaneous exploratory locomotor activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">Brain Res. 485396398.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Nitabach, M.N., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">Schulkin, and A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">Epstein (1989) The medial amygdala is part of a 
    mineralocorticoid-sensitive circuit controlling NaCl intake in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">Brain Res. 35127-134.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">Ono, T., P.G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">Luiten, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">Nishijo, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Fukuda, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">Nishino (1985) Topographic organization of projections 
    from the amygdala to the hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Res. 21221-239.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Ottersen, O.P. (1980) Afferent connections of the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat and cat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">Merents from the hypothalamus and the basal 
    telencephdon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Neurol. 194.267-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Ottersen, O.P. (1982) Connections of the amygdala of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">IV Corticoamygdaloid and intraamygdaloid connections as 
    studied with axonal transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">Neurol. 2053048.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Pfaff, D.W., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">Keiner (1973) Atlas of estradiol-concentrating cells in 
    the central nervous system of the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">Neurol. 151t121-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Phillipson, O.T., andA.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">Griffiths (1985) The topographic order of inputs to the 
    nucleus accumbens in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">Neurosci. 16275-296.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">Pieribone, V.A., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Aston-Jones (1988) The iontophoretic application of 
    Fluoro-Gold for the study of afferents to deep brain nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">475:259-271.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">Post, S., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">Mai (1980) Contribution to the amygdaloid projection 
    field in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">A quantitative autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">Hirnforsch. 21t199225.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Price, J.L. (1973) An autoradiographic study of 
    complementary laminar patterns of termination of afferent fibers to 
    the olfactory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">Neurol. 150:87-108.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">Price, J.L., F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">Russchen, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Amaral (1987) The limbic region. 11: The amygdaloid 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 279-388.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">Rockel, A.J., and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Jones (1973) The neuronal organization of the inferior 
    colliculus of the adult cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">The central nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">147t11-60.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">Cowan (1976) The efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Neurol. 169t409-442.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">Sar, M., and W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Stumpf (1975) Distribution of androgen-concentrating 
    neurons in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">In W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Grant (eds): Anatomical Neuroendocrinology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Basel: Karger, pp. 120-133.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Sawchenko, P.E., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">Swanson, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Rivier, and W.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">Vale (1985) The distribution of 
    growth-hormone-releasing factor (GRF) immunoreactivity in the 
    central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">An immunohistochemical study using antisera directed 
    against rat hypothalamic GRF.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Neurol. 237t100-115.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Scalia, F., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">Winans (1975) The differential projections of the 
    olfactory bulb and accessory olfactory bulb in mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Neurol. 161.31-56.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Schrnued, L.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Fallon (1986) Fluoro-Gold: A new fluorescent retrograde 
    axonal tracer with numerous unique properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">377t147-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">Schulkin, J., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Marini, and A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">Epstein (1989) A role for the medial region of the 
    amygdala in mineralocorticoid-induced salt hunger.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">Neurosci. 103t178-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Swanson (1986) The organization of neural inputs to the 
    medial preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Neurol. 246t312-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">Swanson (1988) Projections of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus: A Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Neurol. 270t209-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Simerly, R.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">Swanson, and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1064">Gorski (1984) Demonstration of a sexual dimorphism in 
    the distributon of serotonin-immunoreactive fibers in the medial 
    preoptic nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1065">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1066">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1067">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1068">225151-166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1069">Simerly, R.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1070">Swanson, R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1071">Handa, and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1072">Gorski (1985) Influence of perinatal androgen on the 
    sexually dimorphic distribution of tyrosine 
    hydroxylase-immunoreactive cells and fibers in the anteroventral 
    periventricular nucleus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1073">Neuroendocrinology 40:501-510.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1074">Simerly, R.B., B.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1075">Young, M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1076">Capozza, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1077">Swanson (1989) Estrogen differentially regulates 
    neuropeptide gene expression in a sexually dimorphic olfactory 
    pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1078">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1079">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1080">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1081">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1082">U.S.A. 86:47664770.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1083">Simerly, R.B., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1084">Chang, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1085">Muramatsu, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1086">Swanson (1990) Distribution of androgen and estrogen 
    receptor rnRNA-containing cells in the rat brain: An in situ 
    hybridization study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1087">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1088">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1089">Neurol. 294:7&amp;95.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1090">Simon, H., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1091">Le Moal, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1092">Calas (1979) Efferents and afferents of the ventral 
    tegmentaldl0 region studied after local injection of (3H)leucine 
    and horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1093">Brain Res. 178t1740.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1094">Standaert, D.G., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1095">Needleman, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1096">Saper (1986) Organization of atriopeptin-like 
    immunoreactive neurons in the central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1097">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1098">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1099">Neurol. 253t315-341.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1100">Steinbusch, H.W.M. (1981) Distribution of 
    serotonin-immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1101">Cell bodies and terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1102">Neuroscience 6t557-618.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1103">Stumpf, W.E., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1104">Sar, and D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1105">Keefer (1975) Atlas of estrogen target cells in rat 
    brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1106">In W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1107">Stumpf and L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1108">Grant (eds): Anatomical Neuroendocrinology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1109">Basel: Karger, pp. 104-119.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1110">Swanson, L.W. (1987) The hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1111">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1112">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1113">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1114">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1115">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 1-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1116">Swanson, L.W. (1992) Brain Maps: Structure of the Rat 
    Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1117">Amsterdam: Elsevier, in press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1118">Swanson, L.W., and B.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1119">Hartman (1975) The central adrenergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1120">An immunofluorescence study of the location of cell 
    bodies and their efferent connections in the rat utilizing 
    dopamine-P-hydroxylase as a marker.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1121">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1122">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1123">Neurol. 163t467-506.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1124">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1125">Cowan (1975) Hippocampo-hypothalamic connections: 
    Origin in subicular cortex not Ammon s horn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1126">Science 189:303304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1127">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1128">Cowan (1977) An autoradiographic study of the 
    organization of the efferent connections of the hippocampal 
    formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1129">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1130">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1131">Neurol. 172r49-84.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1132">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1133">Cowan (1979) The connections of the septal region in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1134">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1135">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1136">Neurol. 186621-656.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1137">Swanson, L.W., and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1138">Mogenson (1981) Neural mechanisms for the functional 
    coupling of autonomic, endocrine and somatomotor responses in 
    adaptive behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1139">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1140">Rev. 3:l-34.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1141">Swanson, L.W., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1142">Kohler, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1143">Bjorklund (1987) The limbic region.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1144">I: The septohippocampal system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1145">In T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1146">Hokfelt, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1147">Bjorklund, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1148">Swanson (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    5, Integrated Systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1149">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 125-277.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1150">Turner, B.H., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1151">Zimmer (1984) The architecture interconnections of the 
    rat s amygdala and lateral Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1152">Neurol. 227540-557.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1153">den Berg, M.J., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1154">Ter Horst, and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1155">Koolhaas (1983) The nucleus premammillaris ventralis 
    (PMV) and aggressive behavior in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1156">Aggress.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1157">Behav. 9:4147.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1158">Vochteloo, J.D., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1159">Koolhaas (1987) Medial amygdala lesions in male rats 
    reduce aggressive behavior: Interference with experience.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1160">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1161">Behav. 41:99-102.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1162">Watts, A.G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1163">Swanson, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1164">Sanchez-Watts (1987) Efferent projections of the 
    suprachiasmatic nucleus: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1165">Studies using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris leucoagglutinin in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1166">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1167">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1168">Neurol. 258t204-229.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1169">Wiegand, S.J., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1170">Terasawa (1982) Discrete lesions reveal functional 
    heterogeneity of suprachiasmatic structures in regulation of 
    gonadotropin secretion in the female rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1171">Neuroendocrinology 34t395-404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1172">Witter, M.P., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1173">Groenewegen (1990) The subiculum: Cytoarchitectoni d l 
    y a simple structure, but hodologically complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1174">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1175">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1176">Witter, M.P., A.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1177">Griffioen, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1178">Jorritsma-Byham, and J.L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1179">Krijnen (1988) Entorhinal projections to the 
    hippocampal CA1 region in the rat An underestimated pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1180">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1181">Lett. 85193-198.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1182">Woolf, N.J., and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1183">Butcher (1982) Cholinergic projections to the 
    basolateral amygdala: A combined Evans Blue and 
    acetylcholinesterase analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1184">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1185">Bull. 8:751-763.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1186">Wouterlood, F.G., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1187">Groenewegen (1985) Neuroanatomical tracing by use of 
    Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) electron microscopy of 
    PHA-L tilled neuronal somata, dendrites, axons, and axon 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1188">Brain Res. 326:18&amp;191.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1189">Yu, H. (1969) The amygdaloid complex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1190">Masters Thesis, University of Ottawa.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1191">Zaborszky, L. (1982) Afferent connections of the medial 
    basal hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1192">Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1193">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1194">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1195">Cell Biol. 69:l-107.</S>
  </References>

</File>

