<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Afferent Connections of the Lateral Agranular Field of the Rat 
  Motor Cortex</Title>

  <Authors>JOHN P. DONOGHUE AND CAROL PARHAM</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Retrograde axonal transport techniques were used to 
    identify the afferent connections of the lateral agranular field 
    (AGl) of the rat frontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">This cytoarchitectonically distinct cortical field forms 
    the bulk of the primary motor cortex (MI) as defined by 
    intracortical microstimulation studies (Donoghue and Wise, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Following injections of horseradish peroxidase (HRP) or 
    wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to HRP into AGI, retrogradely 
    labeled cells are found in the forebrain, thalamus, and 
    brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Within the cerebral cortex labeled neurons are mainly 
    present in the first somatic sensory area (SI), the second somatic 
    sensory area (SII), and the medial agranular field, which lies 
    medial and rostral to AGl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">In SI, labeled cells are found primarily in a 
    cytoarchitecturally distinct region called the dysgranular field of 
    SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Labeled neurons are present in layers I1 and 111, Va, and 
    the deepest part of layer VI in this field and in SII.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Labeled cells are also present in layers Va and VI of the 
    densely granular field of SI, which is the part of SI that is 
    strongly activated by cutaneous inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Commissural inputs to AG1 arise from layers 11-VI of the 
    contralateral AG1 and thalamic inputs arise from the ventrolateral, 
    ventromedial, posterior medial, and central lateral nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Additional afferent fibers originate from neurons in the 
    basal forebrain, the ventral thalamus, the midbrain raphe nuclei, 
    and the locus coeruleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">This combination of inputs to AGI from somatic sensory 
    and frontal cortical fields, thalamic motor centers, and several 
    other subcortical areas implies that AGl forms a subdivision of 
    sensorimotor cortex that is important in centrally directed 
    movements as well as those that are guided by somatic sensory 
    feedback.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The distinct cytoarchitecture of the rat somatic 
    sensorimotor cortex and the large body of neurobiological data for 
    this species make the rat extremely useful for studies of 
    functional organization in cerebral neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The location, general organization, and cytoarchitectural 
    correlates of the principal fields of the rat somatic sensorimotor 
    cortex have been established with anatomical and 
    electrophysiological techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">These studies have suggested that the sensorimotor cortex 
    of rats contains several distinct cortical fields with precise 
    functional correlates.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The classically defined first somatic sensory area (SI) 
    lies within the parietal cortex and appears to have two functional 
    subdivisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">One subdivision contains the representation of cutaneous 
    receptors and coincides with cytoarchitecturally distinct areas 
    that are marked by their densely granular layer IV.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Each of these &quot;granule cell a g gregates&quot; 
    contains the cortical representation of cutaneous inputs from a 
    particular region of the body, such as the forelimb, hindlimb, or 
    head (Welker, &apos;71, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Surrounding this granular field is a second subdivision 
    of SI, termed the dysgranular field of SI, because it has a 
    relatively thin layer IV (Donoghue and Wise, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">In this field neurons respond poorly to light tactile 
    stimuli of the body surface, at least during barbiturate anesthesia 
    (Welker, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">The second somatic sensory area (SII) is located in the 
    parietal cortex lateral to SI and also contains a somatotopically 
    organized cutaneous map (Welker and Sinha, &apos;72).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Both SI and SII appear to receive their cutaneous input 
    from connections with the ventrobasal complex of the thalamus 
    (Killackey and Leshin, &apos;75; Wise and Jones, &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The primary motor cortex (MI), identified as the region 
    of the cortex where intracortical stimulation produces movements at 
    the lowest thresholds (Hall and Lindholm, &apos;74; Sanderson et 
    al., %l), occupies two cytoarchitectonic fields (Donoghue and Wise, 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">The bulk of MI coincides with a distinct frontal 
    agranular area called the lateral agranular field (AGJ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">This part of MI contains the head, trunk, and part of the 
    forelimb representation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The remainder of MI is contained in the rostral part of 
    the granular parietal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">This part of MI overlaps with the SI cortex and contains 
    the representation of the hindlimb and part of the forelimb (Hall 
    and Lindholm, &apos;74).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Neurons in the overlapping MI-SI area, as in the 
    remaining parts of the granular cortex, are activated by light 
    tactile stimulation (Welker, &apos;76), and, in at least the region 
    of the hindlimb representation, there is direct thalamic input from 
    both the ventrobasal complex (VB) and ventrolateral complex (VL) 
    (Donoghue et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Thus, MI consists of two subdivisions in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">The region of overlapping SI and MI cortex lies within 
    granular cortex, receives cutaneous inputs relayed from VB, and is 
    related to control of the hindlimb and forelimb.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The larger, non-overlapping part of MI corresponds to the 
    lateral agranular field (AGl) and appears to be involved with 
    movements of the head, trunk, and forelimb.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Despite the extensive knowledge of the functional 
    organization of the granular fields of sensorimotor cortex, 
    relatively little is known about the intracortical connectivity or 
    the subcortical relations of the agranular part of MI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The completion of baseline studies to establish a precise 
    localization of MI in the rat (Hall and Lindholm, &apos;74; 
    Donoghue and Wise, &apos;82) now permits a detailed analysis of the 
    functional organization of MI and the entire sensorimotor cortex in 
    this species.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">In the present study, retrograde axonal tracers were 
    injected into AG1 in order to identify the various sources of input 
    that might regulate, influence, or control the intrinsic and output 
    neurons of this part of MI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">The results show that AGI receives input from somatic 
    sensory and frontal cortical areas, at least four thalamic nuclei, 
    and basal forebrain and brainstem cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">This diverse combination of inputs from sensory and motor 
    control centers suggests that AGl has a role in the generation and 
    guidance of movement in the rat.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s35">METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">A single injection of horseradish peroxidase (HRP) was 
    made in the frontal or parietal cortex of 16 albino rats (175-225 
    gm) during ketamine anesthesia (150 mglkg, supplemented as needed 
    with doses of 5-10 mg, i.p.).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to HRP (WGA-HRP, Sigma) 
    was injected in the same cortical region of 17 additional rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">In five animals the injection site was localized to the 
    MI cortex by microstimulation mapping with a tungsten 
    microelectrode (1-3 MQ at 1 kHz).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">The cortex was stimulated through this electrode at a 
    depth of 1.5-1.8 mm below the surface, by using currents of 5-100 
    pA (333 Hz, 200 psec pulses, 30-msec train) at three or four 
    different sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Few penetrations were made in order to avoid extensive 
    damage to the cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">In all other cases injections were placed under visual 
    guidance, with the map of Hall and Lindholm (&apos;74) as 
    reference.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">This method provides only a rough guide to the location 
    of cytoarchitectonic fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Injections were aimed at AGl, medial agranular field 
    (AG,), or the parietal cortex so that the pattern of connectivity 
    of AG1 could be compared with the surrounding fields.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">HRP (30% weightivolume) or WGA-HRP (4%), dissolved in 
    TRIS buffer (pH 7.6) plus 0.9% NaCl, was deposited 
    iontophoretically through glass micropipettes having tips of 15-50 
    p, by using currents of 1-10 pA for 1-30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Various parameters of injection time and current were 
    employed in an effort to make restricted injections that labeled 
    many neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The injection pipette was left in place for 5-15 minutes 
    before it was removed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Following a 2or 3-day post-injection survival the rats 
    were perfused with 0.9% NaCl followed by 1 liter of a solution 
    containing 2% paraformaldehyde and 1.5% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">In 17 animals the brains were stored for 2-3 hours in the 
    same fixative after perfusion, then transferred to phosphate 
    buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The next day these brains were cut on a vibratome.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">For the remaining 16 animals, perfusion with the same 
    type of fixative described above was followed by perfusion with 500 
    ml of 10% sucrose in the aldehyde fixative.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">These brains were stored overnight in 30% sucrose in 
    phosphate buffer and then sectioned on a freezing microtome.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">All brains were cut at 50 pm in the frontal plane.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">One series of sections was treated with the chromagen 
    tetramethyl benzidine (TMB) according to the procedure of Mesulam 
    (&apos;78) and a second series was treated with diaminobenzidine 
    (DAB) by the method of LaVail et al. (&apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Each series was composed of one-quarter of the sections 
    and each section in a series was separated from the next by 150 
    pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">TMB reacted sections were air dried after mounting and 
    cleared in xylene.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">These sections were not counterstained or dehydrated in 
    alcohols, in order to prevent loss of TMB reaction product.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Sections treated with DAB were counterstained with 
    thionin, dehydrated, and cleared in xylene.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The location of injection sites and peroxidase-labeled 
    cells was charted on X26 projection drawings of selected unstained, 
    TMB-reacted sections with the aid of a microscope and drawing 
    tube.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">All chartings were taken from the TMB-reacted tissue 
    because cell labeling was more pronounced and because a greater 
    number of cells were labeled with this method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">DAB-reacted sections were used mainly to localize the 
    center of the injection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Cytoarchitectonic boundaries were placed on each drawing 
    by projecting an adjacent Nissl-stained, DAB incubated section onto 
    the charting.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The two adjacent sections were aligned on blood vessels 
    and surface landmarks.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The subdivisions of somatic sensorimotor cortex were 
    labeled according to the description of Donoghue and Wise ( 82) and 
    Welker ( 71; see also Zilles et al., 80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Thalamic parcellation followed the descriptions of 
    Donoghue et d. ( 79) and Herkenham ( 79).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s65">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s66">Cortical areas and 
    injection sites</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The principal cytoarchitectonic fields of sensorimotor 
    cortex consist of the medial and lateral agranular fields of the 
    frontal cortex and the granular and dysgranular fields of parietal 
    cortex .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Aspects of the cytoarchitecture of these areas can be 
    seen in Figures 1 and 4 and a surface reconstruction of the 
    relative locations of these fields is shown in Figure 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Briefly , AGI is distinguished by its relatively 
    indistinct lamination compared to surrounding fields .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">The medial agranular field ( AG , ) is marked by a pale 
    band in layer 111, while the granular SI cortex can be discerned by 
    its well - developed layer IV , which is absent in the frontal 
    cortex .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">The dysgranular part of SI has a thinner , less distinct 
    layer IV and surrounds the granular cortex ( Fig . 2 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">A full description of these areas is presented in 
    Donoghue and Wise ( 82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Descriptions of the cytoarchitecture of other frontal and 
    insular fields can be found in Krettek and Price ( 77a ) , and 
    their nomenclature for these fields is used in the present study 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Injections of <tracerChemical>HRP or WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> were contained within single fields or 
    involved multiple fields .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">In five cases <exptLabel>the entire injection, as seen in 
    TMB-reacted sections, was confined to 
    <injectionLocation>AGI</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Nineteen other injections were centered in 
    <injectionLocation>AGl</injectionLocation> but spread into 
    <injectionSpread>AG,, the granular cortex, or both 
    areas</injectionSpread>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">Five injections included AG, and spread into 
    <injectionSpread>frontal fields other than 
    AG1</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Four injections involved only <injectionLocation>the 
    granular and dysgranular fields of SI cortex</injectionLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The appearance of injection sites of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone was quite different than 
    those with <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Large <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections had 
    a dense center with a lighter halo that consisted of granular 
    reaction product , <labelingDescription>labeled neurons , and 
    fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Small injections of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    ( with dense cores less than 500 pm ) often appeared to consist 
    only <labelingDescription>of densely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> and axons , much like the halo of large 
    injections .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    consisted almost entirely of <labelingDescription>a 
    dense</labelingDescription> , well - demarcated core , as shown by 
    the DAB method in Figure 1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The TMB method produced a similar, slightly larger 
    injection site (compare Fig. 1 with the illustration of the same 
    injection in an adjacent TMB reacted section in Fig. 7B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Attempts at making very small injections of 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> by using low currents ( 
    1 PA ) for short times ( 1 - 3 minutes ) produced injections larger 
    than expected with HRP alone .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Even though these <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injection sites were 200 - 500 pm in diameter 
    they often produced <labelingDescription>few or no labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">Longer injection times (5-30 minutes) and higher currents 
    (2-10 PA) produced injections as shown in Figure 1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">These injections were often no more than two or three 
    times larger than the smallest WGAHRP injections , but these 
    injections usually labeled <labelingDescription>large numbers of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">Since boundaries of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injections are distinct it was possible to 
    make large injections that were relatively restricted to AG1 with 
    this tracer .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">These large but restricted injections allowed some degree 
    of confidence that all of the inputs to AGl were labeled.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">In contrast , the halo of large injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> without lectin always 
    encompassed two or more cortical areas .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">In some cases the pattern of labeling produced by these 
    injections indicated that retrograde transport occurred from the 
    halo , because , for example , <labelingDescription>labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were present in thalamic nuclei 
    throught to project to a cortical field included only in the 
    injection halo ( see Results ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">Small injections of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    alone labeled only <labelingDescription>a relatively small number 
    of neurons</labelingDescription> but were more effective in 
    producing <labelingDescription>cell labeling</labelingDescription> 
    compared to similar - sized injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">Thus , cases with very small injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> that were clearly restricted 
    to <injectionLocation>one cortical field</injectionLocation> were 
    used to confirm the projections seen with large injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP or WGAHRP</tracerChemical> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Changing survival time from 2 to 3 days had no apparent 
    effect on labeling patterns.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s95">Afferent connections of 
    AG,</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">The pattern of afferent connections of AGl will be 
      illustrated from chartings of four representative cases : 
      <exptLabel>a large injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> placed rostrally in 
      <injectionLocation>AG1</injectionLocation> near AGm</exptLabel> ( 
      PM 17, Fig . 3 ) , a small injection of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in 
      <injectionLocation>AGI</injectionLocation> ( PM 3, Fig . 5 ) , a 
      large injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> in 
      <injectionLocation>the caudal part of AG1 near 
      SI</injectionLocation> ( PM 31, Fig . 7 ) , and a large injection 
      of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> in 
      <injectionLocation>the frontal pole</injectionLocation> , rostral 
      to AG1 ( PM 34, Fig . 8 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">The approximate size of each injection site, seen in 
      TMB-reacted material, and its relative location with respect to 
      cytoarchitectonic boundaries is reconstructed on a standard view 
      of the neocortex in Figure 2.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98">The approximate level of each section that is 
      illustrated in <labelingLocation>the subsequent 
      figures</labelingLocation> is also indicated in this figure .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Injections of either HRP or <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> into 
      <injectionLocation>AG1</injectionLocation> label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral and contralateral cortex , the 
      thalamus , the basal telencephalon , the midbrain , and the locus 
      coeruleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">An example of the pattern of labeling when a large 
      injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> is made 
      in the rostral part of AGl is shown in Figure 3.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">The dense part of this injection is largely confined 
      to AGI but a small amount of dark reaction product, as well as 
      <labelingDescription>densely labeled axons and 
      cells</labelingDescription> (Fig. 5, hatching) around the 
      injection lies within AG, (Fig. 3B).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">The region of <labelingDescription>dense 
      label</labelingDescription> and halo seen in an adjacent DAB - 
      reacted section coincides roughly in size with the entire dark 
      area seen in TMB - reacted sections .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">Subsequent to this and five other cases with similar 
      injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> in AGI , 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> are 
      located ipsilaterally in <labelingLocation>AG</labelingLocation> 
      , and in <labelingLocation>the parietal cortex</labelingLocation> 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Labeling is present in <labelingLocation>layers I11 
      and V of AG , rostral and medial to the AGI</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 3A , C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105">In <labelingLocation>the parietal 
      cortex</labelingLocation> most of <labelingDescription>the 
      labeled cells</labelingDescription> are situated in 
      <labelingLocation>the dysgranular field of SI</labelingLocation> 
      ( Figs . 3D , E , 4 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">Here , they are most numerous in 
      <labelingLocation>layer 11, the upper three - quarters of layer 
      111, the upper part of layer V ( layer Va )</labelingLocation> , 
      and in <labelingLocation>the deepest part of layer 
      VI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>other 
      layers of the dysgranular region</labelingLocation> , but 
      <labelingLocation>the deep part of layer V and the bulk of layer 
      VI</labelingLocation> are largely <labelingDescription>devoid of 
      labeled cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">Injections in AGI also label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the densely granular part of 
      SI</labelingLocation> , but this field has 
      <labelingDescription>many fewer labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> and a more restricted laminar 
      distribution compared to <labelingLocation>the dysgranular area 
      of SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3D - G ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">In the granular field <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are mainly contained in 
      <labelingLocation>a compact band in layer Va</labelingLocation> , 
      and usually only <labelingDescription>few 
      cells</labelingDescription> are present in layer 111, except near 
      <labelingLocation>the edges of granule cell</labelingLocation> 
      aggregates where a greater number of labeled cells is commonly 
      present ( Fig . 3C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">The same band of labeled cells that is found in 
      <labelingLocation>the deep part of layer VI in the dysgranular 
      area</labelingLocation> is also found in <labelingLocation>the 
      granular cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">This deep <labelingLocation>layer VI 
      band</labelingLocation> is generally found below labeled cells in 
      <labelingLocation>layer V and</labelingLocation> is more 
      pronounced in <labelingLocation>the medial parts of 
      SI</labelingLocation> , where the forelimb and hindlimb are 
      represented .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">In all cases only <labelingDescription>a few layer VI 
      cells</labelingDescription> are labeled in <labelingLocation>the 
      region of the trigeminal representation</labelingLocation> ( Fig 
      . 3E , F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">This negative result may have been a consequence of a 
      failure to make large enough injections in <injectionLocation>the 
      appropriate subdivision</injectionLocation> of AG1.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are also present in 
      <labelingLocation>the area of the second somatic sensory 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( SII ) in the same laminar arrangement 
      as in <labelingLocation>the dysgranular cortex</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 3E - G ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Three cases with injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone that had dense cores 
      similar in location and size to PM 17 resulted in approximately 
      the same cortical labeling pattern .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">However , the extensive spread of the halo in these 
      cases made it difficult to delineate the site of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> uptake .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">Subsequent to large injections into AG1 
      <labelingDescription>a few labeled cells</labelingDescription> 
      are present in <labelingLocation>layers I11 and V of the ventral 
      orbital area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3A ) , as defined by 
      Krettek and Price ( &apos; 77a ) ; at the juncture between 
      <labelingLocation>the caudal part of AG , and the retrosplenial 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3F ) ; near 
      <labelingLocation>the border of parietal and occipital 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3H , I ) ; and along 
      <labelingLocation>the rhinal fissure</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      3G ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">These areas contain labeled neurons after injections 
      near <injectionLocation>the medial border of 
      AG1</injectionLocation> that spread into 
      <injectionSpread>AG</injectionSpread>,, suggesting that they 
      mainly project to AG, and not AGl.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">As will be shown below , injections clearly confined 
      to <injectionLocation>AGI</injectionLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>do not label</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingDescription>cortical neurons</labelingDescription> 
      outside of <labelingLocation>AG , , SI , or 
      SII</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">Contralaterally , <labelingDescription>a large number 
      of labeled cells</labelingDescription> is present in 
      <labelingLocation>all layers of AGl</labelingLocation> , except 
      for the deeper two - thirds of <labelingLocation>layer 
      VI</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 3B , 7B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121">Injections that spread into 
      <injectionSpread>AG</injectionSpread> , , or 
      along<injectionSpread> the AGrAG border </injectionSpread>, label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> contralaterally 
      in <labelingLocation>layers I11 and Va of SI</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 3C ) and <labelingLocation>the ventral orbital cortex 
      </labelingLocation>( Fig . 3A ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">In the thalamus most of the cells labeled by AGl 
      injections are located in <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral 
      complex ( VL ) , the ventromedial nucleus ( VM ) , the central 
      lateral ( CL ) and paracentral intralaminar nuclei , and the 
      posterior medial nucleus ( POm ) </labelingLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123"><labelingDescription>A few cells</labelingDescription> 
      are also found in <labelingLocation>the parafascicular nucleus ( 
      Pf ) , lateral nuclear group ( L ) , the mediodorsal nucleus ( MD 
      ) , and the central medial nucleus of the midline 
      group</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3G , H ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">By comparing cases with greater or lesser involvement 
      of AG , in the injection , it became evident that the number of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>MD , Pf , and the midline 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> depends on the extent of spread of the 
      injection into <injectionSpread>AG</injectionSpread> , .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">The more the injection spreads into 
      <injectionSpread>AG</injectionSpread> , the greater 
      <labelingDescription>the labeling</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>these thalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">Large injections well away from the AG , - AGI 
      boundary , or small injections within AGl which do not spread 
      into AG , do not label cells in MD ( see below ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">Large injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> as in case PM 17 
      <labelingDescription>densely label many 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the basal part 
      of the telencephalon</labelingLocation> and in 
      <labelingLocation>the globus pallidus ( Figs . 3E , F , 7E , F 
      )</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128">Similarly large injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> alone also 
      <labelingDescription>label neurons</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>these areas</labelingLocation> , but 
      <labelingDescription>fewer neurons</labelingDescription> are 
      labeled and <labelingDescription>the labeling of individual 
      neurons is less dense</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in this basal forebrain region have 
      medium to large fusiform or spindleshaped somata and may be 
      widely separated from each other or may occur in clusters of two 
      to four neurons ( Fig . 6B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> similar in morphology to these basal 
      forebrain neurons are found in <labelingLocation>the preoptic 
      area</labelingLocation> , in <labelingLocation>the region of the 
      mammillary bodies , and in Forel &apos;s 
      fields</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3G - I ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">In the brainstem <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are present ipsilaterally in 
      <labelingLocation>the midbrain periaqueductal gray , the nucleus 
      raphe magnus , and locus coeruleus ( Fig . 6A 
      )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132"><exptLabel>Smaller injections ( 300 - 500 pn ) of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> into AG1</exptLabel> produce a 
    pattern of labeling similar to that of larger injections , with two 
    expected differences .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s133">First , 
    <labelingDescription>fewer labeled cells</labelingDescription> are 
    found in each of the areas that are labeled by large injections and 
    second , areas that contain <labelingLocation>a comparatively small 
    number of neurons</labelingLocation> subsequent to large injections 
    ( such as the locus coeruleus ) may not contain 
    <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">An example of one of three cases that has a very small 
    injection of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> ( without lectin 
    ) completely restricted to 
    <injectionLocation>AG1</injectionLocation> is shown in Figure 5.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">Microstimulation in this rostral part of AGl at 15 pA 
    produced extension of the forelimb digits.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s136">The 
    location of this injection and the microstimulation effect suggests 
    that it involves the MI rostral forelimb zone recently described by 
    Neafsey and Sievert (&apos;82).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s137">In this case the 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injection involved all layers 
    except the deeper one - half of layer VI .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><labelingDescription>Corticocortical 
    cells</labelingDescription> are again found mainly in 
    <labelingLocation>the dysgranular fields and SII 
    ipsilaterally</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5 ) , but unlike large AG1 
    injections , the bands of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layers V and VI of 
    SI</labelingLocation> are not evident .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><labelingDescription>The sparse 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layers V and 
    VI</labelingLocation> could indicate that these SI neurons project 
    to the deeper layers of AG1, since they are labeled mainly with 
    large injections that spread into <injectionSpread>the deep 
    layers</injectionSpread> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s140">Alternatively , 
    <labelingDescription>the presence of labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the deep layers</labelingLocation> could 
    depend on the quantity of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injected .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s141">With small AGI injections 
    thalamic labeling is confined to <labelingLocation>VL, VM, C1, and 
    POm</labelingLocation> (Fig. 5F-H).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142">In all 
    cases with small injections , labeling in <labelingLocation>the 
    midbrain , locus coeruleus , and ventral diencephalic and basal 
    forebrain regions</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>sparse 
    or absent</labelingDescription> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>HRP or WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> placed more caudally in 
      <injectionLocation>AGl</injectionLocation> near the SI 
      cortex</exptLabel> confirm the principal connections of this 
      field .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144">Case PM 31 ( Fig . 7 ) illustrates the labeling 
      following an injection that is largely within the caudolateral 
      part of AGl but also involves to a small extent 
      <injectionLocation>the medial edge of the granular 
      cortex</injectionLocation> , where the forelimb is represented in 
      SI .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145">In the cortex the majority of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> are 
      contained in <labelingLocation>SI , SII , and 
      AG</labelingLocation> , .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146">Thus , <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are present in <labelingLocation>each 
      of these three cortical fields</labelingLocation> following any 
      injection that involves 
      <injectionLocation>AGl</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147"><labelingDescription>The absence of 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>perirhinal , 
      retrosplenial , orbital , or posterior parietal 
      fields</labelingLocation> that is present following large , 
      rostrally and medially placed injections suggests that these 
      frontal fields are labeled as a result of spread of the injection 
      zone into <injectionSpread>AG , or other frontal 
      fields</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148"><labelingLocation>The same thalamic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> are labeled in this case as with other 
      injections of AG1, except for <labelingDescription>a small number 
      of cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>VB</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149">Whenever <injectionSpread>the granular 
      cortex</injectionSpread> is involved in an injection , 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> are 
      found in <labelingLocation>VB</labelingLocation> , but 
      <labelingLocation>VB</labelingLocation> is 
      <labelingModifier>never labeled</labelingModifier> from 
      injections restricted to <injectionLocation>agranular 
      cortex</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150">In some cases <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are found in 
      <labelingLocation>VB</labelingLocation> when the halo from the 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injection ( DAB substrate ) 
      spreads into SI .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151">None of the <injectionLocation>caudal 
      AGl</injectionLocation> injections labels cells in 
      <labelingLocation>MD</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s152">Differences in the location of 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>various thalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> 
      indicate that there is <labelingDescription>a topographic 
      organization of input</labelingDescription> to AG1.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153">Injections placed more caudally in AGl tend to label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the rostrolateral part of VL</labelingLocation> 
      , while more rostral injections label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the more caudomedial portions of 
      VL</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">However, there appears to be substantial overlap of the 
    parts of VL labeled by injections in different parts of AG1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">This general pattern of medial to rostral and lateral to 
    caudal appears to be true for the projections of POm and the 
    intralaminar nuclei to AGl .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s156">Injections rostral to 
    AGI</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157"><exptLabel>Five injections of 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> were centered in the frontal 
      cortex rostral to AGl</exptLabel> , both to compare the pattern 
      of labeling from these cortical fields with that following AG1 
      injections and to control for labeling of pathways that occur 
      when AG1 injections spread into AG , .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">When <tracerChemical>WGA-HRP or HRP</tracerChemical> 
      injections are confined to <injectionLocation>fields rostral to 
      AGl</injectionLocation> a markedly different pattern of labeling 
      results.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159">The most striking differences are first , 
      <labelingDescription>the general lack of 
      labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>SI 
      cortex</labelingLocation> , and second , the large number of 
      labeled areas in <labelingLocation>the cortex and 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">An example of the labeling from a large injection in 
      <injectionLocation>the frontal pole of the 
      neocortex</injectionLocation> is shown in Figure 8.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161">This injection involves <injectionLocation>the 
      rostromedial part of AG</injectionLocation> , as well as 
      <injectionSpread>the medially adjacent prelimbic 
      field</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">Within the cortex <labelingDescription>many labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>the 
      rostralmost parts of the cerebral cortex</labelingLocation> that 
      surround the frontal pole ( Fig . 8A ) , in <labelingLocation>the 
      agranular insular and adjacent parts of the perirhinal 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8B - E ) , and in 
      <labelingLocation>AG</labelingLocation> , caudal to the injection 
      site ( Fig . 8B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">All injections that spread into <injectionSpread>the 
      frontal cortex medial to AG</injectionSpread> , also label 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the pyramidal cell layer of the 
      hippocampus</labelingLocation> , which confirms a previous report 
      of a projection from Ammon &apos;s horn to limbic cortex in the 
      rat ( Swanson , &apos; 81 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s164">Large injections rostral to AG1 label 
      <labelingDescription>a small number of 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>AGl , SII , and 
      the posterior parietal cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8D ) 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s165">These <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> 
      are mainly found in <labelingLocation>layers V ( a and b ) and 
      VI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8D ) , except in 
      <labelingLocation>SII</labelingLocation> where 
      <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> are 
      found in <labelingLocation>all layers except I and 
      IV</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s166">Each injection in 
      <injectionLocation>AG</injectionLocation> , that clearly does not 
      involve AG1 labels only <labelingDescription>a few 
      cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the SI 
      cortex</labelingLocation> , which contrasts dramatically with 
      <labelingDescription>the large numbers of 
      cells</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>SI</labelingLocation> that are seen following 
      injections of similar size in 
      <injectionLocation>AG1</injectionLocation>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s167"><labelingDescription>The few 
      cells</labelingDescription> labeled in 
      <labelingLocation>SI</labelingLocation> are not restricted to 
      either <labelingLocation>the granular or dysgranular 
      regions</labelingLocation> and are usually in 
      <labelingLocation>layer Va or the deep part of layer 
      VI</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s168">Commissural cells marked by these frontal injections 
      are present in <labelingLocation>all layers of the contralateral 
      homotopic area of cortex</labelingLocation> and are also present 
      in <labelingLocation>orbital fields , caudal 
      AG</labelingLocation> , , and in <injectionLocation>the agranular 
      insular cortex</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s169"><labelingDescription>Another small group of 
      cells</labelingDescription> is present caudally along the rhinal 
      fissure , immediately adjacent to the pyriform cortex ( Fig . 8F 
      arrow ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170">Injections of the frontal cortex rostral to AG1 label 
      numerous subcortical areas including <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala and a number of thalamic nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s171"><labelingLocation>The basolateral nucleus of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> after all injections that spread 
      into <injectionSpread>the prelimbic and infralimbic cortical 
      fields that lie</injectionSpread> medial to AG , .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s172">In an earlier study , Krettek and Price ( &apos; 77b ) 
      demonstrated projections from <labelingLocation>the amygdala to 
      these cortical fields</labelingLocation> using anterograde 
      transport techniques .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">Following any injection that includes AG , or medially 
      <labelingLocation>adjacent fields</labelingLocation> , there are 
      numerous <labelingDescription>labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      mediodorsal nucleus of the thalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are also present in 
      <labelingLocation>many other thalamic nuclei including VL , VM , 
      and several intralaminar ( mainly the central lateral , 
      paracentral , and parafascicular nuclei ) and midline thalamic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175"><labelingLocation>The large number of thalamic 
      nuclei</labelingLocation>  labeled by these injections may 
      reflect convergence of thalamocortical inputs or could be a 
      consequence of large injections that involve many different , 
      <labelingDescription>smaller cortical 
      fields</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s176">Common to all injections into frontal or parietal 
      cortex , parts of <labelingLocation>the basal forebrain , globus 
      pallidus , hypothalamus , and Forel &apos;s 
      fields</labelingLocation> contain <labelingDescription>labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">However, there appear to be more labeled cells in each 
    of these regions following injections that involve the cortex 
    rostral to AG1, compared to injections of AG1 alone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">The rostral frontal cortex also appears to receive 
    bilateral input from the region of the mammillary bodies (Fig. 
    8F).</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s179">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">These retrograde transport experiments show that the 
    lateral agranular field of the rat motor cortex receives a variety 
    of inputs from ipsilateral and contralateral cortical areas, 
    several thalamic nuclei, the basal forebrain region, and at least 
    two brainstem regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">The specific sources of input to AGl and the differences 
    in the connections of surrounding cortical fields support our 
    conclusion that AG1 is a distinct cortical field that coincides 
    with all of the MI cortex, except for the region of overlap with SI 
    (Donoghue and Wise, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The nature of the inputs to AGl suggests that this 
    cortical area has an important role in sensorimotor control in the 
    rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s183">Methodological 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The conclusions of this study are based on experiments 
    employing retrograde transport techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">The major problem in the interpretation of results from 
    such studies is the determination of the effective zone of 
    transport.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">WGA-HRP was used in addition to unconjugated HRP, 
    because use of WGA-HRP appears to result in a sharply defined 
    injection zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">However, with either type of HRP it is impossible to 
    determine the exact zone of transport by examination of the 
    injection site itself.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">For this reason, injections were made in various parts 
    of AG1, in the surrounding fields, and along boundaries.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Comparisons of the differences in the pattern of 
    labeling from injections that involve different cytoarchitectonic 
    fields allow a more secure conclusion that a particular projection 
    is limited to one or another field.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Nevertheless, it cannot be definitively stated with this 
    method that certain inputs precisely follow cytoarchitectonic 
    boundaries.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s191">Cortical connections of 
    AGI</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">The major ipsilateral cortical inputs to AG1 arise from 
    SI, SII, and AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Within SI the majority of cells that project to AGl are 
    found in a distinct cytoarchitectonic area, the dysgranular 
    field.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">This projection arises from supragranular layers and 
    from parts of layer V and VI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">The dysgranular field appears to be a separate 
    subdivision of SI because, during barbiturate anesthesia, cells in 
    this area respond poorly to cutaneous stimuli, while those in the 
    adjacent granular zones respond well (Welker, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">This difference in response properties of these two 
    parts of SI also correlates with a difference in thalamic 
    connectivity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">The dysgranular cortex apparently does not receive input 
    from VB (Killackey and Leshin, &apos;75; Wise and Jones, &apos;78), 
    but instead, its main thalamic input appears to arise from POm 
    (Herkenham, &apos;80; Lin and Chapin, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Akers and Killackey (&apos;78) have shown that there are 
    direct projections from the granule cell region to the dysgranular 
    cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Thus, the dysgranular cortex appears to form a link 
    between the granular cortex and AGI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">There is also a direct projection from the granular 
    field of SI to AGl that arises almost entirely from layer Va and 
    the deepest part of layer VI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The projection from layer Va of SI to the &quot;motor 
    cortex&quot; has been previously reported by Ivy and Killackey 
    (&apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">The labeling of the deep part of layer VI after large 
    AGI injections could be a result of uptake from fibers that pass 
    through the deep part of AGI to more rostral areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">However, the sparse labeling in SI following even very 
    large injections rostral to AGI leads to the conclusion that the 
    main cortical target of the deep layer VI cells in SI is AGI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">In addition to intracortical connections, it is possible 
    that some of the AGlprojecting neurons in the infragranular layers 
    have branched projections to subcortical structures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">A large number of cells in layer Va project to the 
    striatum (Wise and Jones, &apos;77; Hedreen, &apos;77) and layer VI 
    is a major source of corticothalamic projections (Wise and Jones, 
    &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Since cells projecting to AGI are found in both of these 
    layers, motor cortex could receive a copy of some of the same 
    output from SI cortex as the neostriatum and thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">These speculations require testing with appropriate 
    anatomical or electrophysiological methods.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Other pathways appear to be segregated so that 
    collateralized projections are not possible.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">For example, throughout parietal cortex there are very 
    few cells in the deeper part of layer V that project to AG1, but 
    many of these neurons project to the brainstem or spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Thus, at least part of the major descending output of SI 
    is not directly transferred to AGl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">This is consistent with the finding that commissural and 
    corticospinal cells are completely separate in the rat 
    (Catsman-Berrevoets et al., &apos;80).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Another cortical input to AGI arises from SII.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Since SII is a target of VB (Wise and Jones, &apos;78) 
    and SII neurons are responsive to cutaneous inputs (Welker and 
    Sinha, &apos;78), this area is potentially another cortical route 
    for somatic sensory input to reach AG1.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">A third source of cortical input to AGl is the medial 
    agranular cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">This input originates in both hemispheres but is 
    strongest ipsilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">AG, is considered to be separate from AGI and not part 
    of MI because it has different cytoarchitecture and 
    microstimulation thresholds (Donoghue and Wise, &apos;82), and 
    because MD projects to AG, and not to AG1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">However, consistent with the idea of a motor function 
    for this field, AG, receives input from VL, contains corticospinal 
    neurons (Wise et al., &apos;79; Donoghue and Wise, &apos;82), and 
    projects to MI cortex (i.e., AGI).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Together, these functions seem to be sufficient to 
    conclude that AG, is part of the sensorimotor cortex but is also 
    distinct from AGI and, therefore, MI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">The similarity of position, cytoarchitecture, and 
    connectivity of the supplementary motor cortex (MII) of primates to 
    AG, suggests that there is an MI1 in the rat that occupies part or 
    perhaps all of AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">Without further information, however, any attempt to 
    infer homology to any field of primate sensorimotor cortex is 
    tenuous.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Alternatively, it is possible that AG, is a uniquely 
    specialized field or group of fields of the rat sensorimotor 
    cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">Orbital areas of frontal cortex, perirhinal cortex, 
    posterior parietal cortex, and retrosplenial cortex appear to 
    project to AG, but not to AGI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">This conclusion is supported by two observations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">First, injections that involve AG,, but do not include 
    AGl, label cells in these cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Second, very large injections in the caudal or lateral 
    parts of AGI do not label cells in any cortical area outside of 
    AG,, SI, and SII.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">The difficulty in making injections of HRP that are 
    sufficiently large to label all inputs to an area without involving 
    an adjacent area makes it possible, however, that there are 
    subdivisions of AG1near AG, that receive input from areas of cortex 
    outside of SI, SII, and AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Except for this possibility, AG, appears to be the major 
    cortical route between frontal and limbic cortical areas and MI 
    cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">The remarkable density of commissural connections of AGI 
    suggests that there is a massive interchange of information from 
    the motor cortex of one hemisphere to the other.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">A similar commissural pattern is also seen in the MI 
    cortex of monkeys (Zant and Strick, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">A few cells are labeled in the contralateral SI cortex 
    subsequent to large injections in the rostral part of AGI near the 
    border of AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Since the contralateral SI does not contain labeled 
    cells after large injections of AG, (not involving AGl), it seems 
    likely that a few cells in SI may project directly to AGI or near 
    the border of AGI and AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Whether these fibers terminate within AG1 or AG, or both 
    would require a number of well-localized HRP injections in these 
    areas, or injection of an anterograde tracer in SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The pattern of intracortical connectivity of the 
    sensorimotor fields of the rat has many similarities to that of the 
    squirrel and macaque monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">As in the rat, the region of SI activated by cutaneous 
    input (area 3b) projects to another subdivision of SI (area 2), 
    which in turn projects densely to MI (Jones et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">In this respect the dysgranular field of SI is like area 
    2 in these monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">However, it is possible that the dysgranular field 
    represents a specialized cortical field not present in the monkey 
    or that it is an amalgamation of several parietal fields found in 
    other species.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="24" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s237">Thalamic connections of 
    AGI</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">On the basis of numbers of labeled neurons, the 
    principal thalamic input to AG1 arises from VL. which is the target 
    of ascending fibers from the globus pallidus (Severin et al., 
    &apos;76; Carter and Fibiger, &apos;77) and the cerebellum (Faull 
    and Carman, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">However, AGI cannot be defined as the sole target of VL, 
    since VL projects to cytoarchitectonic fields outside of AG1, 
    including AG,.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">The pattern of connections of VL with a large part of 
    frontal agranular cortex described here is in substantial agreement 
    with earlier studies (Jones and Leavitt, &apos;74; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77a; Herkenham, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">However, precise comparison of data from these studies 
    with the present one is difficult because the cytoarchitectonic 
    correlates of MI have been only recently established.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">It would be of interest to show that AG, and AGI receive 
    inputs from separate subdivisions of VL.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">However, a strong case cannot yet be made for 
    subdividing VL into separate nuclei in the rat, at least based on 
    cytoarchitecture or on our present knowledge of the termination of 
    fibers from the cerebellum and the globus pallidus in this nuclear 
    region.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Although AG, and AG1 both receive VL input, of these 
    two, only AG, receives fibers from MD, as shown in the present 
    experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Several other studies have demonstrated projections from 
    MD to an area that includes AG,, but does not include AG1 (Leonard, 
    &apos;69; Domesick, &apos;72; Beckstead, &apos;76; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Thus, the projection from MD serves to differentiate AG, 
    from AGI and this major connectional difference supports our 
    speculation that these cortical areas have separate functions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Although AG1 can be distinguished from surrounding 
    somatic sensorimotor fields on the basis of different thalamic 
    inputs, AGl shares a number of thalamic inputs with SI and with 
    AG,, in addition to its thalamic input from VL.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">All three of these fields receive input from the central 
    lateral nucleus (Jones and Leavitt, &apos;74; Wise and Jones, 
    &apos;78; Donoghue et al., &apos;79) and the ventromedial nucleus 
    (Leonard, &apos;69; Herkenham, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">In addition, POm appears to project to the entire 
    sensorimotor cortex (Wise and Jones, &apos;78; Donoghue et al., 
    &apos;79; Herkenham, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Pf projects to AGm and may also project to AG1 because a 
    few cells are labeled in Pf with large injections in AGl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Herkenham (&apos;80) also identified a projection from 
    Pf to the deep layers of &quot;the motor area,&quot; which probably 
    includes AG1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">The lack of labeling in Pf with small HRP injections may 
    be a result of lack of spread of the tracer to layer VI in these 
    cases.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s253">Other subcortical inputs 
    to AGl</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Neurons are labeled in the basal telencephalon, the 
    hypothalamus, and the ventral thalamic region after HRP injection 
    in any part of the frontal or parietal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">It has been suggested that neurons in each of these 
    telencephalic and diencephalic areas form part of a cholinergic 
    system that projects to all areas of cerebral cortex in the rat and 
    in other species (Divac, &apos;75; Kievitt and Kuypers, &apos;75; 
    Mesulam and Van Hoesen, &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Similarly, the midbrain raphe nuclei and the locus 
    coeruleus project widely to all cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">The projection from the raphe nuclei probably provides a 
    serotonergic input (Lidov et al., &apos;80) and the locus coeruleus 
    provides a noradrenergic input to AGl (Freedman et al., &apos;75; 
    Lindvall et al., &apos;78; Morrison et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Each of these systems with widespread cortical 
    projections are thought to have a modulatory influence on the 
    general level of neuronal activity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Norepinephrine, for example, has been suggested to 
    enhance the response of neurons to afferent inputs in the cortex 
    while having little or no direct effect on the neuronal discharge 
    by itself (Waterhouse et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s260">The role of AG1 as a 
    cortical field</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">The combination of inputs from several sensory and motor 
    areas suggests that AG1 is a cortical field that plays an important 
    role in the control of movements guided by sensory feedback as well 
    as in the execution of centrally programmed movements.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">A role in the sensory guidance of movements would 
    require a route for rapid peripheral sensory feedback to AG1 and 
    there appear to be a number of pathways for somatic sensory 
    information to reach AGl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">The dysgranular field could serve to transfer processed 
    sensory information from the granular field of SI to AGl.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">The dysgranular field could also transfer input from 
    deep (joint, muscle spindle) receptors to MI, since information 
    from these sensory receptors appear to activate in the dYsgranular 
    field (Chapin and Woodward, &apos;82)The smaller direct projection 
    from the granular field to AGl may provide a parallel route for 
    cutaneous information to reach MI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">The restricted laminar origin of this projection 
    suggests that only a specific type of information is transferred 
    from the granular field of SI to AG~. s11 is another possible 
    direct cortical Source of cutaneous input to MI in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Thalamic pathways for somatic sensory input to AG1 are 
    less evident.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">The principal thalamic source of somatic sensory 
    information, VB, does not project to AG1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">However, peripheral sensory input may reach AGl through 
    VL or C1, which appear to be targets of ascending spinothalamic 
    pathways, or through POm, which receives some dorsal column and 
    spinal input in the rat (Lund and Webster, &apos;67a,b; McAllister 
    and Wells, &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">In addition to somatic sensory inputs, AG1 is also a 
    major target of areas that are likely to be involved in the 
    generation and execution of central motor programs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">The major cortical input to AGl, outside of SI and SII, 
    is AG,.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">This field appears to form a route for diverse cortical 
    areas, such as the posterior parietal cortex and the prelimbic 
    field, as well as juxtallocortical (perirhinal) areas, to influence 
    to the motor cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Subcortical motor structures are connected to AGl 
    largely through abundant thalamic connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Pallidal and cerebellar information reaches AG1 through 
    VL (Severin et al., &apos;76; Carter and Fibiger, &apos;77; Faull 
    and Carman, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">It is not yet clear whether basal ganglia and cerebellar 
    routes are relayed through separate parts of VL or whether these 
    pathways are kept separate in cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Output from the pars reticulata of the substantia nigra, 
    another subcortical structure with a role in motor control, reaches 
    MI through VM.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">This thalamic nucleus projects densely to layer I 
    throughout the rostral part of the cortex (Herkenham, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">As suggested by Herkenham (&apos;79) this projection 
    could provide another input that affects the general level of 
    cortical activity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Other features of the rat MI suggest that it has an 
    important role in motor control, particularly for the forelimb.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Elger et al. (&apos;77) have reported that corticospinal 
    neurons in the rat may monosynaptically influence motor neurons for 
    the forelimb, but not for the hindlimb (Janzen et al., 
    &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Cortical lesions involving AG1 have been shown to alter 
    the force output of the forelimb (Price and Fowler, &apos;81) and 
    to disrupt skilled forelimb movements in the rat (Castro, 
    &apos;72), suggesting a role for MI in the rat that is not unlike 
    that of the macaque monkey (Evarts, &apos;68; Lawrence and Kuypers, 
    &apos;68).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">The availability of a detailed description of MI in the 
    rat by cytoarchitecture, microstimulation, and connectivity 
    provides a background for future studies to identify the role of MI 
    neurons and their various inputs in generating, modulating, and 
    shaping cortical output and finally, movement.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s282">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s283">We would like to thank Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s284">Betty Al-Aish and Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s285">Susan Wine for their 
    invaluable secretarial skills, Ms.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s286">Lori Budzinski for her 
    assistance with photography, Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s287">S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s288">Wise for his critical review 
    of this manuscript, and Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s289">E.V.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s290">Evarts for his support.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s291">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Akers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">R.M., and H.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Killackey (1978) Organization of corticocortical 
    connections in the parietal cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Neurol. 181.513-538.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Beckstead, R.M. (1976) Convergent thalamic and 
    mesencephalic projections to the anterior medial cortex in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Neurol. 166:403Cartir:D.A., and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Fibiger (1977) The projection of the entopeduncular 
    nucleus and globus pallidus in rat as demonstrated by 
    autoradiography and horseradish peroxidase histochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Neurol. 177:113124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Castro, A.J. (1972) The effects of cortical ablations on 
    digital usage in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Brain 37&apos;173-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Catsman-Berrevoets, C.E., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Lemon, C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Verburgh, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Bentivoglio, and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Kuypers (1980) Absence of callosal collaterals derived 
    from rat corticospinal neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">A study using fluorescent retrograde tracing and 
    electrophysiological techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Brain Res. 39433440, Chapin, J.K., and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Woodward (1982) Cortico-cortical connections between 
    physiologically and histologically defined zones in the rat SI and 
    MI cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Abstr. 8.353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Divac, I. (1975) Magnocellular nuclei of the basal 
    forebrain projects to neocortex, brainstem, and olfactory bulb.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Review of some functional correlates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Brain Res. 93385-398.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Domesick, V.B. (1972) Thalamic relationships rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Evol. 6:457-483.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Donoghue, J.P., K.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Kerman, and F.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Ebner (1979)Evidencefor twoorganizational plans in the 
    somatic sensorymotor cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Neurol. 1833647-663.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Donoghue, J.P., and S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Wise (1982) The motor cortex of the rat: 
    Cytoarchitecture and microstimulation mapping.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Neurol. 212~76-88.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Elger, C.E., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Speckman, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Caspers, and R.W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Janzen (1977) Corticospinal projections in the rat 
    -I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Monosynaptic and polysynaptic responses of cervical 
    motoneurons to epicortical stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Brain R~s. 28:385-404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Evarts, E.V. (1968) Relation of pyramidal tract activity 
    to force exerted during voluntary movement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Neurophysiol. 31:14-27.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Faull, R.L.M., and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Carman (1978) The cerebellofugal projections in the 
    brachium conjunctivum of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">The contralateral ascending pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Neurol. 178:495-518.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Freedman, R., S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Foote, and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Bloom (1975) Histochemical characterization of a 
    neocortical projection of the nucleus locus coeruleus in the 
    squirrel monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Neurol. 164:209-232.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Hall, R.D.. and E.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Lindholm (1974) Organization of motor and somatosensory 
    neocortex in the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Brain Res. 66:23-38.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Hedreen, J.C. (1977) Corticostriatal cells identified by 
    the method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Lett. 4:l-7.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Herkenham, M. (1979) The afferent and efferent 
    connections of the ventromedial thalamic nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Neurol. 183:487-518.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Herkenham, M. (1980) Laminar organization of thalamic 
    projections to rat neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Science 207:532-535.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Ivy, G.O., and H.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Killackey (1982) Ontogeneticchanges of neocortical 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Neurosci. 2:735-743.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Janzen, R.W.C..</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">E:J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Speckmann, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Caspers, and C.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Elger (1977) Corticospinal projections in the rat 
    -11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Oligosynaptic and polysynaptic responses of 
    lumbarmotoneurons to epicortical stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Brain Res. 28:405-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Jones, E.G., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Leavitt (1974) Retrograde axonal transport and the 
    demonstration of non-specific connections to the cerebral cortex 
    and striatum in the rat, cat, and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">J. a m p .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Neurol. 154:349-378.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Jones, E.G., J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Coulter, and S.H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Hendry (1978) Intracortical connectivity of 
    architectonic fields in the somatic sensory, motor and parietal 
    cortex of monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Neurol. 181~291-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Kievitt, J., and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Kuypers (1975) Basal forebrain and hypothalamic 
    connections to frontal and parietal cortex in rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Science 1873660-662.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Killackey, H.P., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Leshin (1975) The organization of specific 
    thalamocortical projections to the posteromedial barrel subfield of 
    the rat somatic sensory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Brain Res. 86;469-472.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Price (1977a) The cortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus and adjacent thalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">171:157-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Price (1977b) Projections from the amygdaloid complex to 
    the cerebral cortex and thalamus in the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Neurol. 172~687-722.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">LaVail, J.H., K.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Winston, and A.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Tish (1973) A method based on retrograde intraaxonal 
    transport of protein for identification of cell bodies of origin of 
    axons terminating within the CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Brain Res. 5R470-477.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Lawrence, D.G., and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Kuypers (1968) The functional organization of the motor 
    system in the monkey: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">The effects of bilateral pyramidal lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Brain 91:l-14.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Leonard, C.M. (1969) The prefrontal cortex of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Cortical projections of the mediodorsal nucleus. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Efferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s423">12:321-343.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Lidov, H.G.W., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Grzanna, and M.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Molliver (1980) The serotonin innervation of the 
    cerebral cortex in the rat - an immunohistochemical analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Neuroscience 5t207-227.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Lin, C.S., and J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Chapin (1981) Some connections of SI and SII in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Abstr. 7:396.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Lindvall.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">O., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Bjorklund, and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Divac (1978) Organization of catecholamine neurons 
    projecting to the frontal cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">142~1-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Lund, R.B., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Webster (1967a) Thalamic afferents from the dorsal 
    column nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">An experimental anatomical study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Neurol. 130:301-312.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Lund, R.B., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Webster (1967b) Thalamic afferents from the trigeminal 
    nuclei and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">An experimental anatomical study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Neurol. 130:313-328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">McAIlister, J.P., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Wells (1981) The structuralorganization of the ventral 
    posterolateral nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Neurol. 197:271-301.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">-M., and G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Van Hoesen (1976) Acetylcholinesterase rich projections 
    from the basal forebrain of the rhesus monkey to neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Brain Res. 109:152-157.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Mesulam, M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for horseradish 
    peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue reaction 
    product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural afferents 
    and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Cytochem. 26:106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Morrison, J.H., R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Grzanna, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Coyle, and M.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Molliver (1978) The distribution and orientation of 
    noradrenergic fibers in neocortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">An immunofluorescence study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Neurol. 181:17-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Neafsey, E.J., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Sievert (19821 A second forelimb area exists in the rat 
    frontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Brain Res. 232~151-156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Price, A.W., and S.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Fowler (19811 Deficits in contralateral and ipsilateral 
    forepaw motor control following unilateral motor cortical 
    ablations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Brain Res. 205%-90.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Sanderson, K.J., W.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">WeIker, and G.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Shambes (1981) Sensory andmotor maps in rat somatic 
    sensorimotor cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Aust.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Mtg.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">p.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">S77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Severin, C.M., P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Young, and L.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Massopust (1976) Pallidothalamic projections in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Neurol. 166:491-502.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Swanson, L.W. (1981) A direct projection from Ammon s 
    horn to the prefrontal cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Brain Res. 21T150-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Waterhouse.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">B.D., H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Moises, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Woodward (1981) Locus coeruleus stimulation potentiates 
    somatosensory cortical responses to afferent synaptic input.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Abstr. 6:448.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Welker, C. (1971) Microelectrode delineation of fine 
    grain somatotopic organization in SmI cerebral neocortex in albino 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Brain Res. 26r259-275.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Welker, C. (1976) Receptive fields of barrels in the 
    somatosensory neocortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Neurol. 166~173-190.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Welker, C., and M.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Sinha (1972) Somatotopic organization of SmII cerebral 
    neocortex in albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Brain Res. 37:132-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Wise, S.P., and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Jones (1977) Cells of origin and terminal distribution 
    of descending projections of the rat somatic sensory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurol. 175:129-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Wise, S.P., and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Jones (1978) Development studies of thalamocortical and 
    commissural connections in the rat somatic sensory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Neurol. 178r187-208.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Wise, S.P., E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Murray, and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Coulter (1979) Somatotopic organization of corticospinal 
    and corticotrigeminal neurons in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Neuroscience 4:65-78.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Zant, J.P., and P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Strick (1978) The cells of origin of interhemispheric 
    connections in the primate motor cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Abstr. 4t308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Zilles, K., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Zilles, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Schleicher (1980) A quantitative approach to 
    cytoarchitectonic.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">VI.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">The areal pattern of the cortex of the albino rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">(Berl.) 159;335-360.</S>
  </References>

</File>

