<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Proportion of Glutamate- and Aspartate-Immunoreactive Neurons 
  in the Efferent Pathways of the Rat Visual Cortex Varies According to 
  the Target</Title>

  <Authors>I. DORI, A. DINOPOULOS, M.E. CAVANAGH, AND J.G. 
  PARNAVELAS</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Immunohistochemistry, with antisera directed against 
    glutamate (Glu) or aspartate (Asp), was combined with wheat germ 
    agglutinin-horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRP) histochemistry to 
    examine the distribution, morphology, and proportions of Gluand 
    Asp-containing neurons that give rise to corticofugal and callosal 
    projections of the rat visual cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">WGA-HRP injections in the dorsal lateral geniculate 
    nucleus resulted in retrograde labelling of small and medium-sized 
    cells throughout layer VI of the visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Of these cells, 60% were also Glu-immunoreactive and 6 1% 
    Asp-positive.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">WGA-HRP injections in the superior colliculus labelled 
    large and medium-sized neurons in the upper portion of layer V of 
    the visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Of these cells, 46% were also stained for Glu and 66% for 
    Asp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Injections in the pontine nuclei resulted in retrograde 
    labelling of cells in the deeper part of cortical layer V.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Retrogradely labelled cells, which were also 
    immunoreactive for Glu or Asp, were large pyramidal cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Corticopontine neurons, which were also Glu-positive, 
    accounted for 42% of the total number of WGA-HRP labelled cells, 
    whilst for Asp-positive neurons this percentage was 51%.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Finally, after injections in the visual cortex, 
    retrogradely labelled small and medium-sized cells were found 
    throughout layers 11-VI in the contralateral visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Of these neurons, 38% were also labelled for Glu while 
    49% were also Asp-immunoreactive.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The present results demonstrate that substantial 
    proportions of projection neurons in the rat visual cortex are 
    immunoreactive for Glu or Asp, suggesting that these excitatory 
    amino acids are the major transmitters used by the cortical 
    efferent systems examined.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Furthermore, the proportions of these immunoreactive 
    neurons in the efferent pathways vary according to the target. e 
    1992 Wiley-Liss, Inc.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Extensive investigations during the past 30 years have 
    shown that the amino acids L-glutamate (Glu) and L-aspartate (Asp) 
    have excitatory actions on many neurons in the central nervous 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The excitatory effects of these amino acids on cerebral 
    cortical neurons were first demonstrated by Krnjevic and Phillis 
    (&apos;63) and later confirmed by others (Hess and Murata, 
    &apos;74).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Since then, a plethora of neurochemical, pharmacological, 
    physiological, and morphological studies have provided a 
    substantial body of evidence suggesting that these amino acids may 
    be involved in cortical transmission (see Fagg and Foster, 
    &apos;83; Ottersen and Storm-Mathisen, &apos;84a; Streit, &apos;84, 
    for reviews).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Until recently, the direct demonstration of neurons 
    likely to use these substances as neurotransmitters has proved very 
    difficult as Glu and Asp, being key metabolites in the brain, are 
    present in all cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Thus, earlier investigations have used indirect 
    approaches to demonstrate that Glu and Asp are present within 
    cortical projection neurons or in cortical efferent pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Lesions of various cortical efferent systems including 
    the corticopontine, corticocollicular, corticothalamic, and 
    corticostriatal pathways, resulted in decreases in the endogenous 
    level, release, and high-affinity uptake of Glu and Asp in the 
    respective subcortical targets.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Injections of the tritiated D-forms of Glu and Asp in 
    subcortical and callosal termination sites of cortical projections 
    resulted in retrograde labelling of pyramidal neurons (see Fagg and 
    Foster, &apos;83; Streit, &apos;84, for reviews).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Furthermore, iontophoretic application of specific amino 
    acid antagonists at termination sites of various corticofugal 
    fibers blocked excitation in the postsynaptic neurons (Spencer, 
    &apos;76; Stone, &apos;76, &apos;79).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The direct demonstration of cortical neurons that may use 
    excitatory amino acids as neurotransmitters has been achieved as a 
    result of the production of antibodies directed against these amino 
    acids conjugated to protein carriers that specifically demonstrate 
    Glu and Asp in perfusionfixed tissue (Storm-Mathisen et al., 
    &apos;83; Campistron et al., &apos;86; Mad1 et al., &apos;86, 
    &apos;87; Hepler et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Using these antibodies, investigators have provided 
    descriptions of the morphology and distribution of amino 
    acid-containing neurons in the neocortex of a number of mammalian 
    species (Ottersen and Storm-Mathisen, &apos;84b; Conti et al., 
    &apos;87b, &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">In a recent immunocytochemical study at the light and 
    electron microscopic level, we reported that in the visual cortex 
    of the rat Gluand Asp-immunoreactivity was found in pyramidal 
    cells, which are regarded as the projection neurons of the cortex, 
    distributed throughout layers 11-VI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The Glu-immunoreactive cells were exclusively pyramidal, 
    but of those positive for Asp 10% were nonpyramidal (Dori et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s25">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Twenty-five adult pigmented and Sprague Dawley albino 
    rats, weighing 250-300 g each, were used in this study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle" format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT"
     id="s27">peroxidase-antiperoxidase</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s28">Surgery and WGA-HRP 
    injections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The animals were deeply anaesthetized with Sagatal(25 
    mg/kg) prior to being mounted on a stereotaxic apparatus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The skull was opened and the dura removed under a 
    surgical microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">WGA-HRP (Sigma; 4% in sterile saline) was injected under 
    pressure by means of a 1 ~1 Hamilton microsyringe.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The needle was slowly directed to the appropriate 
    injection site, whose stereotaxic coordinates were determined with 
    reference to the atlas of the rat brain by Paxinos and Watson 
    (&apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">For injections into the dorsal lateral geniculate nucleus 
    (dLGN), a glass micropipette glued to the Hamilton microsyringe was 
    used in order to achieve a restricted delivery of the tracer.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Seven rats each received 0.02 pl of the WGA-HRP solution 
    in the dLGN.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The micropipette tip was directed to the target through 
    the contralateral hemisphere.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Another three animals each received 0.10 pl WGA-HRP in 
    the superior colliculus (SC).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">In these animals, the needle-tip was directed to the 
    target through the contralateral hemisphere in order to avoid the 
    ipsilateral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">A group of five rats each received a total of 0.25 p1 
    WGA-HRP solution in four separate sites in the pontine nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">In these injections the needle was angled towards the 
    brain stem via the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Finally, in each of 10 rats, a total of 0.50 p1 of the 
    tracer was injected unilaterally in four sites at the borders of 
    cortical area 17 with areas 18 and 18a.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">In all animals, WGA-HRP was delivered over a period of 
    10-15 minutes, and the needle remained in place for 10 minutes 
    following completion of each injection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s42">Perfusion and tissue 
    preparation</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">The animals were allowed to survive for 48 hours, after 
    which they were deeply reanaesthetized with ether and perfused 
    through the ascending aorta with 200 ml of fixative solution 
    containing 4% paraformaldehyde and 0.2% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffer, pH 7.4 (PB), followed by 300 ml of the same 
    fixative without glutaraldehyde.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">This schedule was selected after preliminary experiments 
    to determine the optimal fixation conditions for staining of Gluand 
    Asp-containing neurons and is very similar to that recommended by 
    Hepler et al. (&apos;881, who raised and characterized the antisera 
    used in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">The brains were immediately removed from the skulls, 
    postfixed in 4% paraformaldehyde in PB for 1 hour, and then 
    transferred into PB or 30% sucrose in PB for approximately 18 hours 
    at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Serial sections were cut from the occipital cortex at 40 
    km in the coronal plane, with either a Vibratome or a freezing 
    microtome.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Sections through the visual cortex were collected in PB 
    in groups of three.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The first and second sections of each group were first 
    processed for WGA-HRP-histochemistry and subsequently every first 
    section was processed for Glu and every second one for Asp 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The third section of each group was stained with 
    toluidine blue.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Control sections were kept for WGA-HRP histochemistry or 
    immunohistochemistry alone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Sections through each of the injection sites were cut and 
    processed for WGA-HRP histochemistry .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s52">WGA-HRP histochemistry 
    and amino acid immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Free-floating sections were processed according to the 
    protocol of Horn and Hoffman (&apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The sections were rinsed six times in ice-cold distilled 
    water and then preincubated in a mixture of two solutions 
    containing 100 mg sodium nitroferricyanide, 92.5 ml distilled 
    water, and 5 ml of 0.2 M citrate buffer, pH 3.3 (solution A), and 5 
    mg tetramethyl benzidine (TMB) dissolved in 2.5 ml absolute alcohol 
    (solution B) for 20 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">They were then incubated for 40 minutes in a fresh 
    solution of 100 ml preincubation medium to which 200 mg 
    P-D-glucose, 0.5 mg glucose oxidase, and 40 mg ammonium chloride 
    were added.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Sections were subsequently incubated in an icecooled 
    stabilization medium of 5% ammonium heptamolybdate in distilled 
    water for 20 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">They were then rinsed in PB for 30 seconds and incubated 
    for 8 minutes in a solution of 33&apos;-diaminobenzidine 
    tetrahydrochloride (DAB; Sigma; 0.05% in PB) to which 2.5 m1/100 ml 
    of 1% cobalt acetate was added dropwise, followed by the addition 
    of 1% H,O, to give a final concentration of 0.01%.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Sections were finally rinsed five times in cold 0.1 M 
    phosphate buffered saline, pH 7.4 (PBS).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">After completion of the WGA-HRP-histochemical procedure, 
    the sections were incubated in a 10% methanol/3% H,O, solution for 
    20 minutes to destroy the residual activity of HRP and endogenous 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Sections processed for WGA-HRP histochemistry alone were 
    rinsed in PB, mounted on gelatinized slides, air-dried, dehydrated 
    through an ascending series of alcohols, and, finally, coverslipped 
    with DPX.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Sections used for combined WGA-HRP 
    histochemistryimmunohistochemistry were rinsed in PBS and 
    subsequently incubated in normal goat serum (NGS; 2% in PBS) for 15 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">They were then transferred into primary antiserum to Glu 
    or Asp (used at a dilution of 1:3,000 in PBS with 2% NGS) and 
    incubated for 1 hour at room temperature, followed by 36-40 hours 
    at 4&quot;C, and returned to room temperature for an additional 1 
    hour.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">These sections were subsequently rinsed in PBS, incubated 
    again in NGS for 15 minutes, and then processed with the 
    peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) immunohistochemical technique.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Sections were incubated in sheep anti-rabbit IgG (150) in 
    PBS with 2% NGS for 45 minutes, washed in PBS, and transferred into 
    rabbit PAP (1:80) in PBS with 2% NGS for 30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">The incubations in IgG and PAP were subsequently 
    repeated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Following the second incubation in PAP, the sections were 
    washed in Tris-buffered saline, pH 7.4 (TBS), and placed in a 
    solution of DAB (0.04% in Tris/HCl buffer) for 10 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">They were then transferred to a fresh solution of DAB 
    containing 0.01% H,O, for 10 minutes and finally rinsed in 0.1 M 
    Tris/HCl buffer and then in PB.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">After completion of the immunohistochemical procedure, 
    sections were mounted on gelatinized slides, air-dried, dehydrated, 
    and coverslipped with DPX.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The antisera to the amino acids used in the present study 
    were raised in rabbits against Glu or Asp conjugated to keyhole 
    limpet hemocyanin with glutaraldehyde.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Detailed methods of the preparation and characterization 
    of both antisera by immunoabsorption and immunohistochemistry have 
    been published earlier (Hepler et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">In addition, details of the method and antisera 
    specificity in the neocortex have been reported previously (Conti 
    et al., &apos;87b, &apos;89; Dori et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s72">Data analysis</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Sections were examined with a Zeiss light microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">For every section examined, the cytoarchitectonic borders 
    of area 17 and the extent of the cortical layers were determined 
    from adjacent Nissl-stained sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Counts of cells in this visual cortical area were made, 
    with a x25 objective, in two animals from every group of rats 
    injected with WGA-HRP, and the percentages of double 
    (WGA-HRPlabelled and immunoreactive)versus single 
    (WGA-HRPstained)-labelled cells were calculated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">In order to show the overall distribution of each group 
    of cells, Gluor Aspimmunoreactive, WGA-HRP-labelled, and 
    double-labelled cells were plotted with a drawing tube attached to 
    the microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">Profiles of both singleand double-labelled cells were 
    drawn with a camera lucida at x40, and crosssectional areas of cell 
    somata were measured with a digitizing tablet linked to a 
    microcomputer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">In order to avoid underestimating cell size, only 
    profiles that showed a nucleus and/or apical dendrite were 
    measured.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s79">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s80">Gluand 
    Asp-immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Consistent with our earlier light and electron 
    microscopic investigation in the visual cortex of the rat ( Dori et 
    al . , &apos; 89 ) , the present observations suggest that both 
    Gluand Aspimmunoreactive neurons were 
    <labelingDescription>pyramidal cells</labelingDescription> 
    distributed in <labelingLocation>layers 11 - VI of 
    area</labelingLocation> 17, with <labelingDescription>an increased 
    concentration</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>layers I1 
    and 111</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82"><labelingDescription>Aspartate - labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> differed from Glu - labelled in that 
    <labelingDescription>a few</labelingDescription> were nonpyramidal 
    and they were additionally found in <labelingLocation>layer 
    I</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>in very small 
    numbers</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s83">Double-labelling 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">In sections processed for both <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> histochemistry and <tracerChemical>amino 
    acid</tracerChemical> immunohistochemistry , three types of 
    labelling in cells were readily identified : 1 ) Cells that were 
    Gluor Asp - immunoreactive displayed an intense fine granular brown 
    reaction product evenly distributed throughout the perikarya and 
    proximal dendrites . 2 ) Neurons that had effectively transported 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> displayed a black coarse 
    granular reaction product in their somata and proximal dendrites . 
    3 ) Neurons that were Gluor Aspimmunoreactive and WGA - HRP - 
    positive ( double labelled ) demonstrated an easily distinguished 
    combination of both brown reaction product and black 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> granules in their somata 
    and proximal dendrites .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">The patterns of distribution of <labelingDescription>WGA 
    - HRP - positive cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the visual cortex</labelingLocation> corresponded 
    to those described in previous tracing studies in rats in which 
    <injectionLocation>subcortical and cortical target 
    areas</injectionLocation> were injected with 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> ( Sefton et al . , &apos; 81 ; 
    Wiesendanger and Wiesendanger , &apos; 82 ; Miller and Vogt , 
    &apos; 84 ; Olavarria and Van Sluyters , &apos; 85 ; Hallman et al 
    . , &apos; 88 ; Legg et al . , &apos; 89 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">Counts of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> - 
    <labelingDescription>labelled cells</labelingDescription> in 500 pm 
    strips of sections through the visual cortex processed for 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> histochemistry alone , 
    as well as in adjacent sections processed for both 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> histochemistry and 
    immunohistochemistry , <labelingDescription>revealed comparable 
    numbers of retrogradely labelled cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">This control suggested that the immunohistochemical 
    procedure did not result in the masking or loss of the WGA - HRP 
    reaction product .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">In addition , comparison of the distributions and 
    staining intensity of <labelingDescription>Gluor Asp - 
    immunoreactive cells</labelingDescription> between sections 
    processed for both <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    histochemistiy and immunohistochemistry , and adjacent sections 
    processed for immunohistochemistry alone , showed similar 
    frequencies as well as staining intensities of immunoreactive 
    neurons .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">This suggested that the immunohistochemical reaction 
    product was unaffected by the preceding histochemical procedure.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injections in <injectionLocation>the dorsal lateral geniculate 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s91">These 
    injections resulted in either restricted labelling within 
    <labelingLocation>the boundaries of the nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    ( Fig . lB ) , or in labelling of <labelingLocation>the dLGN and 
    the ventral lateral geniculate nucleus ( vLGN )</labelingLocation> 
    as well ( Fig . 1A ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s92">Analysis was restricted to 
    <labelingLocation>layer VI</labelingLocation> , since it has been 
    established that cortical afferents to the dLGN arise exclusively 
    in <labelingLocation>this layer of the rat visual 
    cortex</labelingLocation> ( Sefton et al . , 31 ) , whereas 
    afferents to the vLGN arise from layer V ( Cosenza and Moore , 
    &apos; 84 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s93"><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> granules were localized in 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> throughout 
    <labelingLocation>layer VI of the ipsilateral visual areas 
    17</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 4D , 5D ) and 18.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingDescription>WGA-HRP-positive 
    neurons</labelingDescription>, which were also immunoreactive for 
    Asp (Fig. 1C) or Glu (Fig. lD), were restricted to small and 
    medium-sized pyramids, but the Asp-immunoreactive neurons 
    projecting to the dLGN were smaller on average (Table I).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">In a sample of 797 <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> - stained cells in <labelingLocation>layer 
    VI</labelingLocation> , from <exptLabel>two rats with injections 
    that spread in both <injectionLocation>the dLGN and 
    vLGN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , 60% were also Glu - 
    immunoreactive ( Table 2 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s96">In a separate sample of 762 
    corticothalamic neurons from the same animals, 61% contained Asp 
    (Table 3).</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s97">When counts were made in two 
    animals with <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
    restricted to the dLGN , <labelingDescription>the double - labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were 60% and 62% , respectively 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
      in <injectionLocation>the superior colliculus</injectionLocation> 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">WGAHRP injections in <labelingLocation>the SC resulted 
      in intense labelling of its superficial layers</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 2A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were located primarily in 
      <labelingLocation>the upper half of layer V of area 
      17</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 4C , 5C ) as well as the borders 
      of area 17 with areas 18 and 18a ipsilateral to the injected 
      hemisphere .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101"><labelingDescription>WGA-HRPstained 
      neurons</labelingDescription> that were also immunoreactive for 
      Glu (Fig. 2B,C) or Asp were medium or large pyramids (Table 
      1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">The Asp neurons projecting to the SC were on average 
      larger than the Glu neurons , but the large Meynert cells which 
      were Asp - immunoreactive ( Dori et al . , &apos; 89 ) 
      <labelingDescription>were not retrogradely 
      labelled</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">In sections processed for both <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> histochemistry and immunohistochemistry for 
      Glu , <labelingDescription>a total of 634 retrogradely labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> from two animals were counted .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Of these, 46% were also Glu-immunoreactive (Table 
      2).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105">In double - labelled sections stained with the 
      antiserum to Asp , 544 
      <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> that project 
      to the SC were counted , 66% of which were also Asp - positive ( 
      Table 3 ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
      injections in <injectionLocation>the pontine 
      nuclei</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107"><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
      in <labelingLocation>the pons</labelingLocation> ( P ) resulted 
      in complete and intense labelling throughout 
      <injectionLocation>the rostrocaudal extent of the pontine 
      nuclei</injectionLocation> , with minor diffusion into 
      <injectionSpread>the neighbouring reticular formation or into the 
      contralateral side</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 3A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">The <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> was 
      retrogradely transported into cell bodies in 
      <labelingLocation>area 17</labelingLocation>, ipsilateral to the 
      injection .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">Perikarya filled with <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> were located in <labelingLocation>layer 
      V</labelingLocation> , almost exclusively in 
      <labelingLocation>its deeper portion ( Vb ) </labelingLocation>( 
      Figs . 4B , 5B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> that were also immunoreactive for Glu 
      or Asp included <labelingDescription>the largest cortical 
      neurons</labelingDescription> that were stained with either of 
      the two antisera , although these were <labelingDescription>very 
      few in number</labelingDescription> ( Table 1 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">The Asp-labelled corticopontine cell population 
      included the large Meynert cells (Fig. 3B,C) as well as small to 
      medium-sized neurons located at the border between layers Va and 
      Vb.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">The presence of these small cells reduced the mean 
      size below that of Glu-immunoreactive neurons (Table 1).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">The Glu - immunoreactive projection 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> were almost 
      exclusively <labelingDescription>the largest 
      neurons</labelingDescription> labelled with the Glu antiserum ( 
      Fig . 3D ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">In sections processed for <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> histochemistry and immunohistochemistry for 
      Glu , <labelingDescription>a total of 513 retrogradely labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> was counted .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">Of these cells, 216 (42%) were also Glu-immunoreactive 
      (Table 2), a proportion very similar to that reported in an 
      earlier study of Glucontaining cortical projection neurons 
      (Dinopoulos et al., &apos;89).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">In sections processed for visualization of both WGAHRP 
      and Asp - immunoreactivity , <labelingDescription>a total of 667 
      neurons</labelingDescription> labelled with the retrograde tracer 
      was counted .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">Of these, 337 (51%) were also Asp-immunoreactive (Table 
    3).</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
      injections in <injectionLocation>the visual 
      cortex</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">After WGAHRP injections in <labelingLocation>the 
      visual cortex</labelingLocation> , staining was observed 
      throughout <labelingLocation>area 17 but more intensely at the 
      border regions between area 17 and areas 18 and 
      18a</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were observed predominantly in 
      <labelingLocation>two &quot; columns &quot; around the boundaries 
      of area 17 and areas 18 and 18a of the contralateral 
      hemisphere</labelingLocation> , but a substantial number was also 
      found throughout area 17.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121">WGA - HRP - <labelingDescription>positive 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were distributed 
      <labelingLocation>throughout layers 11 - VI</labelingLocation> ( 
      Figs . 4A , 5A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">Analysis restricted to <injectionLocation>the border 
      of area 17 with 18a showed</injectionLocation> that cells with 
      callosal connections that were also Gluor Asp - immunoreactive 
      were small or mediumsized pyramidal neurons ( Table 1 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">Large cells in <labelingLocation>layer 
      V</labelingLocation> , which were immunoreactive for Glu or Asp , 
      <labelingDescription>were not retrogradely 
      labelled</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124"><labelingDescription>In a sample of 1,165 retrogradely 
      labelled neurons</labelingDescription> that were counted through 
      <labelingLocation>layers 11 - VI , 447 ( 38% )</labelingLocation> 
      were also Glu - positive ( Table 2 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">However, this percentage increased to 50% when counts 
      were restricted to layers 11-111.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">In a sample of 952 WGA - HRP - positive neurons 
      through <labelingLocation>layers 11 - VI , 466 ( 49% 
      )</labelingLocation> were also Asp - immunoreactive ( Table 3 ) 
      .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">This percentage increased to 51% when layers 11-111 were 
    considered alone.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s128">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.body" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s129">The antisera to Glu and Asp used in the present 
    investigation have been characterized by immunoblots and 
    immunoabsorption tests on sections of various parts of the nervous 
    system including the cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.body" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s130">In these tests each antiserum showed a high degree of 
    specificity for its respective antigen (Conti et al., &apos;87b; 
    Battaglia and Rustioni, &apos;88; Hepler et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.body" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s131">A number of recently published reports have provided 
    strong evidence that the antisera used here stain the 
    neurotransmitter rather than the metabolic pool of individual 
    neurons: 1) All Gluand the vast majority of Asp-immunoreactive 
    neurons in the rat visual cortex were identified at the light and 
    electron microscopic level as pyramidal cells, which reflects 
    remarkable selectivity of the antisera (Dori et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.body" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s132">This selectivity may be a consequence of the higher rate 
    of synthesis of the neurotransmitter pool of Glu or Asp when 
    compared to the metabolic pool (Storm-Mathisen and Ottersen, 
    &apos;86). 2) The distribution of Gluand Asp-labelled neurons in 
    various areas of the cerebral cortex (Conti et al., &apos;87a,b; 
    Dori et al., &apos;89) did not correspond to the pattern of 
    labelling produced with metabolic markers, e.g., cytochrome oxidase 
    histochemistry (Conti et al., &apos;87b). 3) Gluand Asp-containing 
    cells were located in layers that previous indirect methods, such 
    as the autoradiographic localization of retrogradely transported 
    D-L3Hl-Asp, have suggested to contain glutamergic or aspartergic 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.body" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s133">In addition, Glu-positive neurons were not localized in 
    layer I, which lacks pyramidal cells (Dori et al., &apos;89). 4) 
    Gluor Asp-immunoreactive axon terminals in the rat visual cortex 
    moo 0 a a 0</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s134">Qo a</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s135">
    Q o QO a0</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="32" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT" id="s136">e 0 VI a</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="33" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-BoldMT" id="s137">e o</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-ItalicMT" id="s138">8 II o b 0 0 * o</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-ItalicMT" id="s139">0 @ o o * o</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-ItalicMT" id="s140">o o @ o</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s141">0 a $ e m</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-ItalicMT" id="s142">o o o 0 o o o</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-ItalicMT"
     id="s143">0 e o 0</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">(Dori et al., &apos;89), cat neocortex (DeFelipe et al., 
    &apos;88; Conti et al., &apos;89) and rat spinal cord (Weinberg et 
    al., &apos;87; De Biasi and Rustioni, &apos;88) appeared to engage 
    only in asymmetrical synapses, which are associated with the 
    release of an excitatory neurotransmitter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Previous investigations of the neurotransmitters used by 
    cortical efferent pathways often employed the autoradiographic 
    localization of retrogradely transported, radiolabelled 
    transmitter-related compounds.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">The most widely used compound has been C3H1-D-Asp, as 
    this can act as a false transmitter being selectively taken up by 
    synaptic terminals that release Glu and/or Asp, without being 
    readily metabolized after uptake (see Streit, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">Therefore, this compound has the advantage of being a 
    neuronal tracer and a selective neurotransmitter marker.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">However, the use of this technique results in labelling 
    of only a limited number of projection neurons depending on their 
    high affinity uptake system and, thus, may produce &quot;false 
    positive&quot; or &quot;false negative&quot; results (see Cuenod et 
    al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">In addition, this method does not allow one to 
    distinguish between glutamatergic and aspartergic neurons, as they 
    share the same high affinity uptake system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">The advantage of WGA-HRP as a neuronal tracer is that it 
    is nonselectively taken up by terminals and transported 
    retrogradely to the somata of projection neurons irrespective of 
    their biochemical properties.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">The combination of WGA-HRP histochemistry with 
    Glu-/Asp-immunohistochemistry used here allows the simultaneous 
    visualization of the two distinct types of labelling within the 
    same cell.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">The results of the control experiments performed in this 
    study suggest that the immunohistochemical procedure does not cause 
    the masking or loss of the WGA-HRP reaction product, and also that 
    the immunohistochemical reaction product is unaffected by the 
    preceding WGA-HRP histochemical procedure.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">The data presented here demonstrate that both Gluand 
    Asp-immunoreactive neurons in the rat visual cortex give rise to 
    afFerents to the dLGN, SC, pontine nuclei, and contralateral visual 
    cortex, thus confirming and extending results from earlier indirect 
    studies that proposed a neurotransmitter role for these two amino 
    acids in the four pathways examined.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">These results also suggest that the roles of Glu and Asp 
    as transmitters are not identical or interchangeable.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">Aspartate differs from Glu in that it is additionally 
    present in a few nonpyramidal cells and that it is occasionally 
    found in layer I.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">Within each pathway the proportions of the two amino 
    acids differ (Fig. 6), and the consistency of the results from the 
    individual animals (see Tables 2, 3) suggest that these proportions 
    are not the consequence of metabolic variations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">The sizes of the two types of cell also vary in that 
    Asp-immunoreactive neurons projecting to the dLGN and pontine 
    nuclei tend to be smaller than the corresponding Glu-immunoreactive 
    cells, whereas those projecting to the SC are larger.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">The different neuronal sizes could reflect differing 
    axonal projections, and thus subtly different functions within the 
    target site.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">This suggests that the two transmitters may indicate two 
    subclasses of projection neurons that might be distinguishable on 
    morphological criteria if examined in sufficient detail.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s160">cortical projecting to 
    the dorsal lateral geniculate nucleus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">The present results demonstrate that 60% of neurons in 
    the rat visual cortex that project to the dLGN were 
    Glu-immunoreactive, while 61% were Asp-immunoreactive, suggesting 
    that Glu and Asp are the major neurotransmitters in the 
    corticogeniculate pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">The similarity of percentages of Gluand Asp-labelled 
    corticothalamic neurons raised the question of whether these two 
    amino acids are colocalized in the same projection neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">This was not examined directly in the present study, but 
    the issue of coexistence has been investigated by Giuffrida and 
    Rustioni (&apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">These authors, using the same antisera as those used 
    here, estimated that in the rat sensorimotor cortex 57-60% of 
    cortieothalamic neurons were Glu-positive and 56-59% were labelled 
    for Asp, percentages very similar to the ones presented here.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Furthermore, they demonstrated that in sections 
    processed with both antisera, the majority of corticothalamic 
    neurons were either Gluor Asp-immunoreactive, and only a minority 
    (25%) was positive for both amino acids.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">These data are also in agreement with other reports, 
    suggesting that Glu and Asp are colocalized in a small percentage 
    of neurons in the somatosensory cortex of the rat (Conti et al., 
    &apos;87a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">In addition, partial coexistence of the two amino acids 
    has been reported to occur in other cortical projection systems 
    examined (Giuffrida and Rustioni, &apos;89a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Indirect evidence from this study that the two amino 
    acids are localized in largely separate populations comes from the 
    measurement of neuronal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">These measurements have shown that the mean 
    cross-sectional area for Asp-labelled neurons is 98.3 pm2 and that 
    for Glu-labelled neurons is 117.9 pm2.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Our results demonstrating the involvement of these two 
    amino acids in the corticothalamic projection system concur with 
    experiments in which the visual cortex was ablated in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">These studies showed a decrease in the level of the 
    endogenous L-Glu and in the high affinity uptake of Glu and Asp in 
    the dLGN (Lund-Karlsen and Fonnum, &apos;78; Fosse and Fonnum, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Similar results have been obtained in the cat (Young et 
    al., &apos;81; Fosse et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">Direct evidence for the involvement of Glu in 
    corticothalamic projections in the cat comes from a recent 
    immunogold analysis of corticogeniculate terminals (Montero, 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">The present findings also concur with studies in which 
    injections of the tritiated D-forms of Glu and Asp were made in the 
    rat dLGN.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Such injections resulted in retrograde labelling of 
    cells in layer VI of the visual cortex (Baughman and Gilbert, 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">The reports from these studies favour Glu as the major 
    transmitter in these pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">However, Glu and Asp share the same high affinity uptake 
    system and, therefore, a distinction between the two is not 
    possible.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s178">Cortical neurons 
    projecting to the superior colliculus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s179">Earlier studies have established the involvement of both 
    Glu and Asp in the corticocollicular pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s180">A decrease in the level of the endogenous L-Glu and in 
    the high affinity uptake of Glu and Asp has been measured in the SC 
    and the dLGN after visual cortex ablations in rats (Lund-Karlsen 
    and Fonnum, &apos;78; Fosse and Fonnum, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s181">Although in one study retrograde labelling was not 
    observed in the visual cortex after injecting D-[3H]-Asp in the SC 
    (Baughman and Gilbert, &apos;81), a more recent report (Matute and 
    Streit, &apos;85) found retrogradely labelled cells in layer V of 
    the visual cortex of the rat, cat, and rabbit following injections 
    of the tritiated D-forms of Glu and Asp in the SC.</S>
    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s182">This discrepancy may be due to the different fixatives 
    used in these two studies (see Matute and Streit, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s183">The present estimation of the proportions of 
    corticocollicular neurons that were d</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="34" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s184">LGN</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="43" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s185">
    sc</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="33" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s186">- 6111 4 2 7 o - A ~ ~ 51%</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="33" class="discussion.subtitle" format="Arial-BoldMT"
     id="s187">L GIu 3 f i Y o - A ~ ~ 49% c v c</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">also immunoreactive for Glu (46%) or Asp (66%) leads to 
    the suggestion that Asp may be a more important neurotransmitter in 
    this corticofugal system than Glu, and that Glu and Asp may be 
    colocalized in a small proportion of these projection neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">With respect to their morphology it has been shown that 
    corticocollicular neurons are long pyramids, i.e., their apical 
    dendrites extend all the way to layer I and that they are 
    predominantly found in the upper part of layer V (Schofield et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">The present study also demonstrates that 
    corticocollicular neurons that contain Glu or Asp are large or 
    medium-sized pyramidal cells, mainly located in the upper stratum 
    of layer V of the visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">However, since the reaction product is confined to the 
    perikarya and proximal dendrites, the morphological detail of the 
    labelled neurons was not sufficient to confirm the observations of 
    Schofield et al. (&apos;871, which were based on a study of 
    retrogradely or intracellularly stained corticocollicular neurons 
    in the visual cortex of the rat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s192">Cortical neurons 
    projecting to the pontine nuclei</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">The role of Glu or Asp as neurotransmitters in the 
    corticopontine pathway of the rat was first suggested following the 
    demonstration of high affinity uptake of Glu and Asp by synaptic 
    terminals of corticopontine fibers (Thangnipon et al., &apos;80), 
    and a Ca2+-dependent K+-evoked release of [3H]-D-Asp from these 
    terminals (Thangnipon and Storm-Mathisen, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Transection of the fibers in the crus cerebri resulted 
    in a severe reduction of high affinity uptake for radiolabelled Glu 
    and Asp in the pontine nuclei (Thangnipon and Storm-Mathisen, 
    &apos;81; Thangnipon et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Forty-two percent of corticopontine neurons counted here 
    were Gluand 51% were Asp-immunoreactive.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">This suggests that Asp and Glu may be the major 
    excitatory amino acid transmitters in the corticopontine pathway, 
    with Asp being a more common candidate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">However, the percentages of immunoreactive projection 
    neurons suggest that these two are not the only transmitters used 
    by corticopontine neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Similar double labelling studies in other corticofugal 
    systems have shown that a number of cortical projection neurons 
    remains unlabelled in sections incubated in a mixture of antisera 
    for both Asp and Glu (Giuffrida and Rustioni, &apos;88, 
    &apos;89b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">This study concurs with the earlier retrograde tracing 
    study of Wiesendanger and Wiesendanger (&apos;82) that 
    corticopontine neurons are located almost exclusively in the deeper 
    portion of layer V in rat visual cortex, but disagrees with a later 
    report that finds them in the upper middle part of layer V (Hallman 
    et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">These authors also find that corticpontine neurons share 
    many morphological features with corticocollicular neurons, whereas 
    the present study concludes that each projection system has its own 
    morphology and intralaminar distribution in addition to a 
    characteristic transmitter proportion (Fig. 6).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s201">Cortical neurons 
    projecting to the contralateral visual cortex</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">Although the amino acid-containing neurons that give 
    rise to callosal connections are distributed throughout layers 
    11-VI, analysis suggests that they are more concentrated in the 
    supragranular layers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">In addition, quantitative evidence is provided in favour 
    of Asp as a major transmitter in this projection system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">These results conflict somewhat with estimates from 
    similar studies in the sensorimotor cortex of rats (Giuffrida and 
    Rustioni, &apos;89a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">These authors reported that the percentages of 
    association and callosal neurons in the primary motor and the 
    somatosensory cortex that are immunoreactive for Glu are similar to 
    those labelled for Asp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">The discrepancies in the relative proportions of Gluand 
    Asp-immunoreactive callosal neurons may be due to the different 
    cortical areas examined.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">The same authors also examined the possible coexistence 
    of Glu and Asp in corticocortical projection neurons by incubating 
    sections in a mixture of the two antisera.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Their findings suggested that callosal and association 
    neurons are either glutamatergic or aspartergic, and only a small 
    proportion of them are immunoreactive for both amino acids.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Other investigators have concluded that Glu and not Asp 
    is the main transmitter of corticocortical neurons in the cat, as 
    the former amino acid was immunohistochemically localized in 50-73% 
    of these neurons (Conti et al., &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Although this may indeed be the case for the 
    corticocortical system in the cat somatosensory cortex, it should 
    be noted that in their study the proportions of putative 
    aspartergic projection neurons in the corticocortical system were 
    not investigated.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Considered together, the present results provide 
    numerical evidence in favour of Asp as the neurotransmitter used 
    most commonly by neurons in the visual cortex that project to the 
    dLGN, SC, P, and contralateral visual cortex (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Although evidence to support a transmitter role for Asp 
    has been less compelling than for Glu, it has been generally 
    considered as an excitatory neurotransmitter used by various 
    cortical efferent systems (see Fagg and Foster, &apos;83; Streit, 
    &apos;84; Hicks, &apos;87, for reviews).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">The present results also demonstrate that the 
    proportions of Gluand Asp-immunoreactive neurons in each projection 
    system examined vary among callosal and different corticofugal 
    systems.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">This is in accordance with previous reports in other 
    corticofugal systems (Dinopoulos et al., &apos;89, &apos;91; 
    Giuffrida and Rustioni, &apos;89a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">In addition to the neurochemical heterogeneity among 
    cortical projection neurons, this study also demonstrates a 
    morphological heterogeneity among Gluand Asp-labelled cells 
    projecting to subcortical and cortical sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">This morphological heterogeneity reflects differences in 
    sizes of projection neurons, as well as in their cytological 
    features.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">For example, the Meynert cells in layer V, which are the 
    largest cells in the visual cortex with a distinct cytology, are 
    exclusively Asp-immunoreactive (Dori et al., &apos;89) and project 
    to the pontine nuclei, but not to the SC or the contralateral 
    visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">The chemical and morphological heterogeneity between 
    excitatory amino acid systems reported here is consistent with the 
    functional heterogeneity of these systems at the level of receptors 
    and physiological response (Ascher and Nowak, &apos;87; MacDermott 
    and Dale, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s219">At present, only limited 
    information is available on other putative neurotransmitters used 
    by cortical efferent pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s220">There is evidence that 
    some cortical projection neurons may use the dipeptide 
    N-acetyl-aspartyl-glutamate (NAAG) as a transmitter (Tieman et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s221">Other candidates include 
    the sulfur-containing amino acids (SCAAs).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s222">It has been shown that 
    these substances exert strong excitatory effects on mammalian 
    neurons (Curtis and Watkins, &apos;63; Mewett et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s223">In addition, a 
    K+-evoked, Ca2+dependent release of SCAAs has been demonstrated in 
    the rat neocortex (Do et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s224">Most recently a study 
    combining in situ hybridization with retrograde tracing using 
    flurogold has demonstrated neurons in the rat cerebral cortex that 
    express the gene for cholecystokinin and project extensively to the 
    striatum and to some extent to the thalamus (Burgunder and Young, 
    &apos;90).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s225">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s226">We are grateful to 
    Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s227">A.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s228">Rustioni for the gift of 
    the antiglutamate and antiaspartate antisera.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s229">The work was supported 
    by the Medical Research Council.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s230">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Ascher, P., and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Nowak (1987) Electrophysiological studies receptors.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Trends Neurosci. 1Or284-288.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Battaglia, G., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Rustioni (1988) Co-existence of glutamate and substance 
    P in dorsal root ganglion neurons of the rat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Neurol. 278:302-3 12.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Baughman, R.W., and C.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Gilbert (1981) Aspartate and glutamate as possible 
    neurotransmitters in the visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Neurosci. 1:427439.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Burgunder, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">-M., and W.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Young, 111 (1990) Cortical neurons expressing the 
    cholecystokinin gene in the rat: Distribution in the adult brain, 
    ontogeny, and some of their projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Neurol. 300r26-46.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Campistron, G., R.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Buijs, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Geffard (1986) Specific antibodies against aspartate and 
    their immunocytochemical application in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Brain Res. 365r179-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Conti, F., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">DeFelipe, I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Faririas, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Manzoni (1989) Glutamate-positive neurons and axon 
    terminals in cat sensory cortex: A correlative light and electron 
    microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Neurol. 290:141-153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Conti, F., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Fabri, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Manzoni (1988) Glutamate-positive corticocortical 
    neurons in the somatic sensory areas I and I1 of cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Neurosci. 8:294a2960.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Conti, F., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Rustioni, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Petrusz (1987a) Co-localization of glutamate and 
    aspartate immunoreactivity in neurons of the rat somatic sensory 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">In T.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Hicks, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Lodge, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">McLennan (eds): Excitatory Amino Acid Transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">New York: Alan R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Liss, pp. 169-172.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Conti, F., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Rustioni, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Petrusz, and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Towle 61987b) Glutamatepositive neurons in the somatic 
    sensory cortex of rats and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Neurosci. 7r1887-1901.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Cosenza, R.M., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Moore (1984) Afferent connections of the ventral lateral 
    geniculate nucleus in the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Brain Res. 310:367-370.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Cuenod, M., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Bagnoli, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Beaudet, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Rustioni, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Wicklund, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Streit (1983) Transmitter-specific retrograde labelling 
    of neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">In V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">ChanPalay and S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Palay (eds): Cytochemical Methods in Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">New York: Alan R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Liss, pp. 1744.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Curtis, D.R., and J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Watkins (1963) Acidic amino acids with strong excitatory 
    actions on mammalian neurones.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">(Lond.) 166rl14.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Biasi, S., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Rustioni (1988) Glutamate and substance P coexist in 
    primary afferent terminals in the superficial laminae of spinal 
    cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">USA 85:7820-7824.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">DeFelipe, J., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Conti, S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Van Eyck, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Manzoni (1988) Demonstration of glutamate-positive axon 
    terminals forming asymmetric synapses in cat neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Brain Res. 455162-165.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Dinopoulos, A,, I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Dori, S.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Davies, and J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Parnavelas (1989) Neurochemical heterogeneity among 
    corticofugal and callosal projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Neurol. 105:3&amp;amp;44.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Dinopoulos, A., I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Dori, and J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Parnavelas (1991) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    aspartate in corticofugal pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Lett. 121:2528.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">K.Q., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Mattenberger, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Streit, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Cuenod (1986) In vitro release of endogenous excitatory 
    sulfur-containing amino acids from various rat brain regions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Neurochem. 46:779-786.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Don, I., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Petrou, and J.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Parnavelas (1989) Excitatory transmitter amino 
    acid-containing neurons in the rat visual cortex: A light and 
    electron microscopic immunocytochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Neurol. 290: 169-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Fagg, G.E., and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Foster (1983) Amino acid neurotransmitters and their 
    pathways in the mammalian central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Neuroscience 9:701-719.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Fosse, V.M., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Fonnum (1987) Biochemical evidence for glutamate and/or 
    aspartate as neurotransmitters in fibers from the visual cortex to 
    the lateral posterior thalamic nucleus (pulvinar) in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s340">400:219-224.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Fosse, V.M., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Heggelund, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Iversen, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Fonnum (1984) Effects of area 17 ablation on 
    neurotransmitter parameters in efferents in area 18, the lateral 
    geniculate body, pulvinar and superior colliculus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Lett. 52:323-328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Giuffrida, R., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Rustioni (1988) Glutamate and aspartate immunoreactivity 
    in corticothalamic neurons of rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Bentivoglio and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Spreafico (eds): Cellular Thalamic Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 311-320.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Giuffrida, R., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Rustioni (1989a) Glutamate and aspartate 
    immunoreactivity in cortico-cortical neurons of the sensorimotor 
    cortex of rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Brain Res. 74:4146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Giuffrida, R., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Rustioni (1989b) Glutamate and aspartate 
    immunoreactivity in corticospinal neurons of rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Neurol. 288:154-164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Hallman, L.E., B.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Schofield, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">-S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Lin (1988) Dendritic morphology and axon collaterals of 
    corticotectal, corticopontine, and callosal neurons in layer V of 
    primary visual cortex of the hooded rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Neurol. 272: 149-160.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Hepler, J.R., C.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Toomin, K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">McCarthy, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Conti, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Battaglia, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Rustioni, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Petrusz (1988) Characterization of antisera to glutamate 
    and aspartate.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Cytochem. 36:13-22.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Hess, R., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Murata (1974) Effects of glutamate and GABA on specific 
    response properties of neurones in the visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">21:285-297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Hicks, T.P. (1987) Excitatory amino acid pathways in 
    cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">In T.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Hicks, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Lodge, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">McLennan (eds): Neurology and Neurobiology, Vol. 24: 
    Excitatory Amino Acid Transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">New York: Alan R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Liss, pp. 373-380.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Horn, A.K.E., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">-P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Hoffman (1987) Combined GABA-immunocytochemistry and 
    TMB-HRP histochemistry of pretectal nuclei projecting to the 
    inferior olive in rats, cats and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Brain Res. 409:133-138.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Kmjevic, K., and J.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Phillis (1963) Iontophoretic studies of neurones in the 
    mammalian cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">(Lond.) 165274-304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Legg, C.R., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Mercier, B., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Glickstein (1989) Corticopontine projection in the rat: 
    The distribution of labelled cortical cells after large injections 
    of horseradish peroxidase in the pontine nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Neurol. 286:427441.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Lund-Karlsen, R., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Fonnum (1978) Evidence for glutamate as a 
    neurotransmitter in the corticofugal fibres to the dorsal lateral 
    geniculate body and the superior colliculus in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Brain Res. 151:457-467.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">MacDermott, A.B., and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Dale (1987) Receptors, ion channels and synaptic 
    potentials underlying the integrative actions of excitatory amino 
    acids.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Trends Neurosci. 10:280-284.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Madl, J.E., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Beitz, R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Johnson, and A.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Larson (1987) Monoclonal antibodies specific for 
    fixative-modified aspartate: Immunocytochemical localization in the 
    rat CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Neurosci. 73639-2650.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Madl, J.E., A.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Larson, and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Beitz (1986) Monoclonal antibody specific for 
    carbodiimide-fixed glutamate: Immunocytochemical localization in 
    the rat CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Cytochem. 34:317-326.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Matute, C., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Streit (1985) Selective retrograde labelling with 
    D-f3H1aspartate in afferents to the mammalian superior 
    collicullus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Neurol. 241r34-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Mewett, K.N., D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Oakes, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Olverman, D.A.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Smith, and J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Watkins (1983) Pharmacology of the excitatory actions of 
    sulfonic and sulfinic amino acids.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">In P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Mandel and F.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Defeudis (eds): CNS ReceptorsFrom Molecular Pharmacology 
    to Behaviour.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">New York: Raven Press, pp. 163-174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Miller, M.W., and B.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Vogt (1984) Heterotopic and homotopic callosal 
    connections in rat visual cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Brain Res. 297:75-89.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Montero, V.M. (1990) Quantitative immunogold analysis 
    reveals high glutamate levels in synaptic terminals of 
    retino-geniculate, corticogeniculate, and geniculo-cortical axons 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Visual Neurosci.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">4:437443.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Olavarria, J., and R.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Van Sluyters (1985) Organization and postnatal 
    development of callosal connections in the visual cortex of the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Neurol. 239:l-26.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Ottersen, O.P., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Storm-Mathisen (1984a) Neurons containing or 
    accumulating transmitter amino acids.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 3: 
    Classical Transmitters and Transmitter Receptors in the CNS, Part 
    11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 141-246.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Ottersen, O.P., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Storm-Mathisen (1984b) Glutamateand GABAcontaining 
    neurons in the mouse and rat brain, as demonstrated with a new 
    immunocytochemical technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Neurol. 229:374-392.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Schofield, B.R., L.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Hallman, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">-S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Lin (1987) Morphology of corticotectal cells in the 
    primary visual cortex of hooded rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">261:85-97.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Sefton, A.J., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Mackay-Sim, L.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Baur, and L.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Cottee (1981) Cortical projections to visual centres in 
    the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Brain Res. 21 5: 1-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Spencer, H.J. (1976) Antagonism of cortical excitation 
    of striatal neurons by glutamic acid diethylester: Evidence for 
    glutamic acid as an excitatory transmitter in the rat striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Brain Res. 102:91-101.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Stone, T.W. (1976) Blockade by amino acid antagonists of 
    neuronal excitation mediated by the pyramidal tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">(Lond.) 257:187-198.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Stone, T.W. (1979) Amino acids as neurotransmitters of 
    corticofugal neurones in the rat: A comparison of glutamate and 
    aspartate.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Br.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Pharmacol. 67:454-551.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Storm-Mathisen, J., A.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Leknes, A.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Bore, J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Vaaland, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Edminson, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">-M.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Haug, and O.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Ottersen (1983) First visualization of glutamate and 
    GABA in neurones by immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Nature 301:517-520.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Storm-Mathisen, J., and O.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Ottersen (1986) Antibodies against amino acid 
    neurotransmitters.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">In P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Panula, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Paivarinta, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Soinila (eds): Neurohistochemistry: Modern Methods and 
    Applications.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">New York Alan R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Liss, pp. 107-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Streit, P. (1984) Glutamate and aspartate as transmitter 
    candidates for systems of the cerebral cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">In E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Jones and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Peters (eds): Cerebral Cortex, Vol. 2: Functional 
    Properties of Cortical Cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 119-143.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Thangnipon, W., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Brodal, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Storm-Mathisen (1980) High affinityuptake of glutamate 
    in terminals of the corticopontine pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Scand. 109:29a.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Thangnipon, W., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Storm-Mathisen (1981) K+-evoked Ca -dependent release of 
    D-VH1-aspartate from terminals of the cortico-pontine pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Lett. 23:181-186.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Thangnipon, W., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Taxt, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Brodal, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Storm-Mathisen (1983) The corticopontine projection: 
    Axotomy-induced loss of high afmity L-glutamate and D-aspartate 
    uptake, but not of y-aminobutyrate uptake, glutamate decarboxylase 
    or choline acetyltransferase, in the pontine nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Neuroscience 8:449-457.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Tieman, S.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Cangro, and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Neale (1987) N-acetylaspartylglutamate immunoreactivity 
    in neurons of cat s visual system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">420:188-193.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Weinberg, R.J., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Conti, S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Van Eyck, P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Petrusz, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Rustioni (1987) Glutamate immunoreactivity in 
    superficial laminae of rat dorsal horn and spinal trigeminal 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">In T.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Hicks, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Lodge, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">McLennan (eds): Neurology and Neurobiology, Vol. 24: 
    Excitatory Amino Acid Transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">NewYork: Alan R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Liss, pp. 173-176.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Wiesendanger, R., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Wiesendanger (1982) The corticopontine system in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Mapping of corticopontine neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">208:215-226.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Young, A.B., M.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Bromberg, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Penney, Jr. (1981) Decreased glutamate uptake in 
    subcortical areas deafferented by sensorimotor cortical ahlation in 
    the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Neurosci. 1:241-249.</S>
  </References>

</File>

