<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>The Spinothalamic System of the Rat. I. Locations of Cells of 
  Origin</Title>

  <Authors>SHERRY L. GRANUM</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">Horseradish peroxidase retrograde transport has been used 
    to locate neurons of the rat spinal cord and lower medulla that 
    project to the thalamus, Eight groups of spinothalamic cells are 
    identified, some of which are anatomically continuous with 
    thalamically projecting groups in the lower medulla.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Most of the groups are seen only at the highest cervical 
    levels, and several of them have not been previously recognised as 
    spinothalamic relays.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">They are marginal layer (M), ventral border of the 
    substantia gelatinosa (SGu), neck of the dorsal horn (N), lateral 
    cervical nucleus (LO, ventromedial portion of the dorsal horn 
    (DHum), intermediate gray zone (ZGZ), dorsal portion of the ventral 
    horn (VHd, and ventral portion of the ventral horn (VHu).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Most of the cell bodies are contralateral to their 
    thalamic terminations; only the VHd group is ipsilateral.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The major finding conflicts with traditional concepts of 
    the spinothalamic system, and concerns the rostrocaudal 
    distribution of the cells of origin.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">With the sole exception of the DHum group, the great 
    majority of the thalamically projecting neurons of the rat are 
    confined to the most rostra1 spinal levels (medulldcord junction 
    through C4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">BeIow C4, most of the spinothalamic cells are concentrated 
    in a single DHum group between levels T9 and L4, probably concerned 
    with hindlimb proprioception.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">The spinothalamic groups at high cervical levels may be 
    relays for information ascending from lower regions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">This might help to explain why, in man, surgical 
    destruction of fibres crossing the midline in a single high 
    cervical segment can cause a loss of pain sensation over most of 
    the body.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The concept of the spinothalamic tract is 100 years old, 
    but still presents important puzzles.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Surprisingly, perhaps, it is still not clear precisely 
    which cells in the spinal cord project directly to the thalamus, or 
    what their functions are.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">According to the classical view, cells projecting 
    directly to the somatosensory thalamus are present throughout the 
    length of the spinal cord, with their somata in the contralateral 
    gray matter and their axons crossing the midline to ascend in the 
    anterolateral quadrant; and these neurons play an essential part in 
    pain and temperature transmission (e.g., Edinger, 1889, &apos;11; 
    Mott, 1892, 1895; Spiller, &apos;05; May, &apos;06; Foerster and 
    Gagel, &apos;31; Le Gros Clark, &apos;36; Kuru, &apos;49; Morin et 
    al., &apos;51; Smith, &apos;76; reviewed by Willis and Coggeshall, 
    &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Parts of the classical view, which was based largely on 
    observations of sensory deficits and patterns of neuronal 
    degeneration resulting from spinal cord lesions, have always been 
    open to question.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">From the beginning, it was clear that the vast majority 
    of ascending axons in the spinal cord did not reach as far as the 
    thalamus, but ended propriospinally or in the bulbar brainstem 
    (e.g., May, &apos;06, for early review).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">In particular, many of the fibres in the anterolateral 
    quadrant, quite possibly including those concerned with pain and 
    temperature, were reported to end in the brainstem reticular 
    formation (e.g., May, &apos;06; Kuru, &apos;49; Morin et al., 
    &apos;51; Bowsher, &apos;57; Nauta and Kuypers, &apos;58; Anderson 
    and Berry, &apos;59; Mehler et al., &apos;60; Mehler, &apos;62; 
    Breazile and Kitchell, &apos;68; Bowsher and Westman, &apos;70; 
    Schroeder and Jane, &apos;71; Kerr and Lippman, &apos;74; Kerr, 
    &apos;75b; reviewed by Willis and Coggeshall, &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">In more recent times, two methods have been chiefly used 
    to locate the cells of origin of the spinothalamic tract: 
    electrophysiology, using antidromic activation with stimulating 
    electrodes in the brain and recording electrodes in the spinal cord 
    (Dilly et al., &apos;68; Trevino et al., &apos;72, &apos;73; 
    AlbeFessard et al., &apos;74a,b; and Giesler et al., &apos;76); and 
    retrograde labelling with horseradish peroxidase (HRP) (Carstens 
    and Trevino, &apos;78a,b; Giesler et al., &apos;78, &apos;79a; 
    Willis et al., &apos;79; Granum and Webster, &apos;81, &apos;82; 
    Granum, &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">The information gleaned so far by these methods, while 
    more precise than the older findings, is nevertheless incomplete in 
    some important respects.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">With the electrophysiological approach, it is impossible 
    to be sure that one has a full or unbiased sampling of the 
    spinothalamic population, and it is difficult to locate sites of 
    origin and termination accurately.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">HRP studies using large injections to fill the thalamus 
    are liable to suffer from spread of HRP to adjacent regions, 
    especially brainstem, leading to the labelling of cells that do not 
    in fact project to the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">For reasons only partly to do with these technical 
    problems, we have still only fragmentary information about the 
    detailed topography of the spinothalamic projection-that is, about 
    the differences between the various regions of the somatosensory 
    thalamus as to the sources of their spinal input (Carstens and 
    Trevino, &apos;78a; Willis et al., &apos;79; Giesler et al., 
    &apos;79a, &apos;81a,b; Granum, &apos;83; Peschanski et al., 
    &apos;83; Kevetter and Willis, &apos;83, &apos;84; Menetrey et al., 
    &apos;84b; Peschanski and Besson, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Furthermore, the current picture of the distribution of 
    spinothalamic cells along the length of the spinal cord is 
    incomplete; most of the previous studies have foccussed attention 
    on a few selected levels-typically high cervical, cervical 
    enlargement, and/or lumbar enlargement-instead of systematically 
    examining the whole rostrocaudal extent.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">The present paper describes experiments using small 
    localised injections of HRP into the somatosensory regions of the 
    thalamus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The aim at the outset was to discover the precise 
    locations of the cells of origin of the spinothalamic 
    projection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">It was decided to plot the rostrocaudal distribution of 
    the spinothalamic cells very fully, saving and examining every 
    section of the spinal cord from the medulla down to the coccyx.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">As a first step in the analysis of the data, the results 
    from all the thalamic injections were superimposed so as to display 
    the total population of cells projecting to the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">These composite data, with which the present paper is 
    chiefly concerned, reveal some interesting and unexpected features 
    of the distribution of spinothalamic cells, especially along the 
    rostrocaudal axis.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">It appears that relatively few cells project directly to 
    the thalamus from the lower levels of the spinal cord, but large 
    numbers do so from the high cervical levels, where they are 
    arranged in eight distinct groups.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">By analogy with known groups in the brainstem, the high 
    cervical groups may perhaps be relays for somatosensory information 
    ascending from the lower part of the spinal cosd.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">If one may extrapolate from rat to man, this may help to 
    explain some remarkable clinical observations, in which a small 
    lesion of the commissural fibres at a high cervical level abolished 
    pain sensation over most of the body (Hitchcock, &apos;70, 
    &apos;74; Pap0 and Luongo, &apos;76; Schvarcz, &apos;77, &apos;78; 
    Cook et al., &apos;84).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s30">METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s31">HRP injections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Adult Wistar albino rats of 270-320-g body weight were 
    used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Following initial ether anaesthesia, the animals were 
    placed in a stereotaxic head holder and anaesthesia was maintained 
    with an inhaled COz/O&amp;alothane mixture.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Injections were made (through small holes drilled in the 
    skull) via a 30-gauge needle held in a micromanipulator and 
    connected via polythene tubing to a 1.00-pl Hamilton syringe, the 
    dead space in the hydraulic system being filled with silicone 
    fluid.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Thalamic injections of 30% HRP (Boehringer lyophilised 
    grade I, in sterile water) were made in 16 rats, in the following 
    manner: (1) Fourteen rats received single injections into specific 
    thalamic targets. (2) One rat received two injections across the 
    anterior zone of transition (anterior ventrobasal/posterior 
    ventrolateral area) on one side. (3) One rat received eight 
    separate injections that were intended to cover the somatosensory 
    thalamus, but in the event lay partly outside it, in anterior 
    thalamic regions that probably do not receive any spinal input.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">The precise sites of injection and the extent of 
    diffusion of the HRP were determined at the end of the experiment 
    by analysis of the sectioned tissue.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The intended volume of HRP administered was between 0.02 
    and 0.06 pl per injection and was given over a period of 20-30 
    minutes, by means of a motorized apparatus (B.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Braun, Melsungen) to drive the plunger of the Hamilton 
    syringe slowly.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">After each injection, the needle was left in situ for 
    5-10 minutes and then slowly retracted.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s40">Processing and 
    histochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Following the HRP injections, the animals were allowed to 
    survive for 48 hours, and were then reanaesthetised with ether and 
    killed by transcardiac perfusion with 200 ml of 0.9% saline, 
    followed by 200 ml of 1% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer 
    (pH 7.3), followed finally by 500 ml of 4% glutaraldehyde in the 
    same buffer.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">The brainstem and spinal cord were dissected out 
    immediately after perfusion and immersed in the weaker fixative.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Transverse 60-pm-thick serial sections were cut on a 
    freezing microtome, from the level of the anterior commissure 
    through the entire length of the brainstem and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">There were about 2,000 sections in the complete serial 
    set for each animal; with minor exceptions, all of them were saved 
    and processed.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">(Some sections of rats R90 and R91 between T4 and T10 
    were lost, as were the sacrococcygeal regions of rats R61, R62, 
    R64, and R90.)</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">The sections were collected in phosphate buffer and 
    reacted for HRP using the o-dianisidine method (slightly modified 
    from Colman et al., &apos;76) at room temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">The serial sections were then mounted alternately on two 
    sets of gelatinized slides: one set was counterstained with thionin 
    and one was left unstained.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s48">Analysis of material</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">From the brains of a separate set of control animals, 
    thionin-stained sections were prepared and photographed and a 
    series of 85 standard diagrams of successive levels of the 
    thalamus, brainstem, and spinal cord were made; the region from the 
    medulldcord junction down to the coccyx was spanned by a series of 
    26 of the atlas diagrams (see Fig. lD, 3C,D).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">On these diagrams, the extent of the thalamic injection 
    site in each animal was mapped, as well as all HRP-labelled cells 
    throughout the lower medulla and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Faintly labelled cells were more easily visible in the 
    uncounterstained series of sections, and they could be localised 
    accurately by darkfield illumination (which helps to clarify 
    cytoarchitectural boundaries) and comparison with the paired 
    section in the counterstained series.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Each labelled cell observed was recorded as a single dot 
    in the appropriate position relative to standard landmarks on the 
    atlas diagram for the appropriate level of the spinal cord this was 
    done for each animal separately.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Figure 1 illustrates the complete data recorded in this 
    way from a single animal (R104).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">To get quantitative data, the dots were then counted in 
    each atlas diagram for each animal.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">In a few specimens, the concentration of labeled cells in 
    certain regions was so high that dots on the record diagram 
    overlapped.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">In these cases, the counts represent estimates rather 
    than exact figures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">As a check on the magnitude of the error from this cause, 
    the counts for the specimen with the largest number of labelled 
    cells-R90-were repeated by an exact method, in which the labelled 
    cells were recorded tissue section by tissue section, as well as 
    atlas level by atlas level.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The total counts obtained by the two methods were, 
    respectively, 975 and 941-a negligible discrepancy.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">A further slight systematic error in the counts may 
    result from double counting of cells split by the microtome knife 
    into two parts on adjacent sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">No attempt was made to apply the usual Abercrombie ( 46) 
    correction for this, since the correction factor depends on the 
    average cell diameter as measured perpendicular to the plane of 
    section, which, for non-spherical cells such as neurons, cannot be 
    deduced from the dimensions seen in the plane of section.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">A rough estimate of the magnitude of the correction 
    factor can, however, be made: for a section thickness of 60pm, the 
    counts should be scaled down ~ 0 . 8 for 6 neurons with an average 
    diameter of lOpm, and scaled down x0.67 for a diameter of 30pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">These diameters roughly encompass the range of sizes 
    encountered when one compares the different groups of labelled 
    neurons identified in this study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Thus the ratios of the counts of neurons in the different 
    groups are not likely to be distorted by a factor of more than 
    0.8610.67, i.e., 1.28.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">In fact, the error from double counting is probably even 
    less than this, since profiles obviously identifiable as fragments 
    of cells whose main bodies lay in adjacent sections were not 
    included in the counts.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="25" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s65">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">The distribution of 
    <tracerChemical>thalamic</tracerChemical> injection sites is shown 
    graphically in Figure 2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">It can be seen that the injection sites are distributed 
    widely throughout <injectionLocation>the somatosensory 
    thalamus</injectionLocation> , although there is a larger 
    concentration of injections in some regions than in others .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Thus , when all the retrograde tracing results are 
    considered together , they should provide a reasonably complete 
    picture of the population of cells projecting to the somatosensory 
    thalamus , even though the picture may give somewhat exaggerated 
    weight to those populations of 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> that project to 
    the more densely sampled regions of thalamus ( see also the 
    Discussion below ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s69">In the account that follows , all 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> projecting from 
    the spinal cord to the thalamus will be counted as belonging to the 
    spinothalamic system , including those of <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral cervical nucleus ( LCN ) and the small spinal extensions of 
    the gracile and cuneate nuclei ( GN and CUM )</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s70">The term spinothalamic system in this paper, therefore, 
    will denote a broader class of cells than those of the traditional 
    spinothalamic tract.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s71">Eight spinothalamic cell groups can be distinguished</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">To obtain a picture of the total population of 
    spinothalamic cells seen in this study, the data from all the 
    separate HRP experiments were superimposed on a single set of 
    composite diagrams (Fig. 3A-C).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Figure 4 reproduces the cervical levels of Figure 3C ( 
    but with all cells plotted on the same side of the cord ) and 
    depicts schematically on cross sections of the spinal cord the 
    anatomical boundaries of the spinothalamic groups that can be 
    identified in <labelingLocation>this rostra1 
    region</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Figure 5 shows a graph of the distribution of 
    spinothalamic cells along the rostrocaudal axis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">It can be seen from these figures that the population of 
    cells projecting from the spinal cord to the thalamus consists of a 
    number of distinct groups , and that there are dramatic differences 
    in the distribution of labelled cells between different levels of 
    <labelingLocation>the spinal cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">While the spinothalamic cells fall into eight groups with 
    respect to their location in the transverse plane , none of these 
    eight groups is present at every cord level : all are distinct at 
    high cervical levels , but only <labelingLocation>the ventromedial 
    dorsal horn group</labelingLocation> , DHum , and to a much smaller 
    extent the marginal group , M , are clearly represented in lower 
    spinal cord segments ( Fig . 3C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">Apart from the DHvm group , <labelingDescription>the 
    labelled neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    lower spinal cord</labelingLocation> are few in number and 
    diffusely scattered : it is difficult to assign them to specific 
    groups .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">A still larger family of thalamically projecting nuclei 
    are found in <labelingLocation>the brainstem proper ( see below 
    )</labelingLocation> , and the eight groups of spinothalamic cells 
    clustered in <labelingLocation>high cervical 
    segments</labelingLocation> may be the most caudal members of this 
    constellation .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Indeed , at the highest cervical levels , 
    <labelingLocation>the spinal extensions of the medullary gracile 
    and cuneate nuclei ( GN and CUM )</labelingLocation> are also 
    evident , in addition to the eight groups to be described below 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Of the eight groups , seven are found on the side of the 
    spinal cord contralateral to the thalamis 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections , and only one , in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal portion of the ventral horn , VHd 
    </labelingLocation>, is ipsilateral .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Five of the eight groups are laminar in arrangement and 
    roughly parallel to <labelingLocation>the superficial border of the 
    dorsal horn , occupying regions from the marginal layer to the 
    ventral horn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">In addition, there are three groups that are nuclear 
    rather than laminar in transverse outline.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Because an exact assignment of labelled neurons to Rexed 
    ( 52, 54 ) laminae often cannot be made with certainty , and the 
    laminae formed by thalamically projecting cells do not correspond 
    exactly with Rexed laminae , the Rexed terminology will for the 
    most part be avoided in this report .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">It is , however , convenient for general orientation , as 
    follows : <labelingLocation>The marginal group</labelingLocation> , 
    M , lies in <labelingLocation>lamina I ; the group at the ventral 
    border of the substantia gelatinosa , SGu , lies at the junction 
    between laminae 11 and 111 ; the group in the neck of the dorsal 
    horn</labelingLocation> , N , is in <labelingLocation>lamina IV and 
    the most superficial part of lamina V ; the lateral cervical 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , LCN , is in the dorsolateral part of 
    the lateral white fasciculus ; the group in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventromedial part of the dorsal horn</labelingLocation> , DHum , is 
    in <labelingLocation>the most medial part of lamina VI ; and the 
    smaller</labelingLocation> and more laterally placed group in 
    <labelingLocation>the intermediate gray zone</labelingLocation> , 
    IGZ , lies in <labelingLocation>dorsal lamina 
    VII</labelingLocation> ( and perhaps includes <labelingLocation>the 
    most ventral part of lamina VI )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">The two groups found in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    horn</labelingLocation> are partially overlapping : the more dorsal 
    one , VHd , lies diagonally across <labelingLocation>the middle of 
    lamina VII ; and the more ventral group</labelingLocation> , VHu , 
    is in <labelingLocation>the deeper part of lamina VII and ( in the 
    upper cervical cord</labelingLocation> ) in <labelingLocation>the 
    upper parts of lamina VIII</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">Descriptions of the eight spinothalamic groups , shown in 
    Figures 3C and 4, and short statements regarding their relationship 
    to the medullothalamic groups seen in <labelingLocation>the lower 
    brainstem , follow : Marginal group</labelingLocation> ( MI .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87"><labelingDescription>This group of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> lies in <labelingLocation>the most 
    superficial lamina of the dorsal horn</labelingLocation> , capping 
    the substantia gelatinosa , and is continuous rostrally with 
    <labelingDescription>a similarly placed labelled 
    subdivision</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
    of the trigeminal spinal tract pars caudalis</labelingLocation> ( 
    NTSTc ; see below ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">Labelling is most common at <labelingLocation>the 
    medullaryicord junction</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the first and second cervical 
    segments</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89"><labelingDescription>Cells</labelingDescription> are 
    often clustered medially near the entry point of the dorsal 
    roots.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">A second concentration is clustered near 
    <labelingLocation>the apex of the dorsal horn</labelingLocation> , 
    in <labelingLocation>C6 - T4</labelingLocation>, but in 
    <labelingLocation>the remainder of the spinal 
    cord</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>labelled marginal 
    cells are extremely rare</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91"><labelingDescription>Occasionally 
    cells</labelingDescription> are seen embedded in the white matter , 
    quite close to the pial surface .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">Many, though not all, labelled M cells have the classic 
    Waldeyer fusiform profile, with the long axis usually lying 
    parallel to the gelatinosa surface.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93"><labelingDescription>About 94% of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in this lamina are contralateral to the 
    injection site ; about 6% are ipsilateral .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingLocation>Ventral border of the substantia 
    gelatinosa (SGv)</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">This laminar group of labelled cells is found just 
    ventral to the hyaline substantia gelatinosa and is continuous with 
    a similar group within the nucleus of the trigeminal spinal tract , 
    pars caudalis , NTSTc .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">In <labelingLocation>the cord</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>SGv neurons</labelingDescription> are 
    prominent only at <labelingLocation>the most rostra1 two 
    segments</labelingLocation> , and are extremely rare in the 
    remaining cord levels .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">(The bulk of the SGv group lies in fact in the 
    medulla.)</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">Even in <labelingDescription>Cl - C2, labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> belonging to this group are not common 
    , but when present , they are often in close proximity to ( and 
    just across the substantia gelatinosa from ) <labelingDescription>a 
    labelled M neuron</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">With very rare exceptions , <labelingDescription>SGv 
    cells</labelingDescription> are contralateral .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100"><labelingLocation>Neck of the dorsal horn ( N 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">This group of labelled cells stretches across most of 
    the neck of the dorsal horn, roughly parallel to the M and SGv 
    groups described above.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Labelled <labelingLocation>N</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> are most frequent 
    from <labelingLocation>the medulldcord junction to the fourth 
    cervical segment</labelingLocation> , but are very occasionally 
    seen throughout <labelingLocation>the rest of the spinal 
    cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">Cells are frequently grouped in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral half of the lamina , and the boundary of this group with 
    the lateral cervical nucleus ( LCN )</labelingLocation> is 
    sometimes indistinct .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104"><labelingDescription>The cells</labelingDescription> are 
    almost all contralateral .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">These three groups - M , SGU , and possibly N - are all 
    anatomically continuous with labelled 
    <labelingLocation>subdivisions of the nucleus of the trigeminal 
    spinal tract</labelingLocation> , pars caudalis , NTSTc .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">Together they account for approximately 16% of the total 
    number of spinothalamic cells seen in these experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107"><labelingLocation>Lateral cervical nucleus ( ZCN ) and 
    interstitial nucleus of the lateral funiculus ( INLF 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">This is <labelingDescription>a well - known group of 
    labelled cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal part of the lateral white matter</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">At high cervical levels this group is termed 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral cervical nucleus ( LCN ) 
    </labelingLocation> ; at lower levels it has been termed variously 
    the interstitial nucleus of the lateral fasciculus ( ZNLF ) , the 
    nucleus of the dorsolateral fasciculus ( NDLF ) , or the lateral 
    spinal nucleus ( LSN ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110"><labelingDescription>The labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> are most numerous at the most rostra1 
    levels - i . e . , in <labelingLocation>the LCN 
    proper</labelingLocation> - but <labelingDescription>a very sparse 
    population of thalamically projecting ZNLF 
    neurons</labelingDescription> extends in fact throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the full length of the cord</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">Many of <labelingDescription>the labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are in <labelingLocation>the peripheral 
    extreme of the white matter</labelingLocation> , close to the pial 
    surface ( Fig . 3C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112"><labelingDescription>Other cells</labelingDescription> 
    are more medial , and the LCN merges with the lateral part of the N 
    lamina described above .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">Most neurons of LCN (and ZNLF) are small to moderate, 
    rounded or ovoid, averaging approximately 30 pm in their longest 
    diameter.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114"><labelingDescription>Larger labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> tend to lie more laterally and 
    smaller ones lie more medially , where the nucleus merges with the 
    neck of the dorsal horn .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">In these experiments, this entire LCNIINLF system 
    accounts for about 13% of the total number of labelled cells 
    seen.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">More than 90% of <labelingDescription>the labelled LCN 
    cells</labelingDescription> were contralateral to the injection 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">Ventmmedial portion of the dorsal horn (DHvm).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118"><labelingDescription>This group of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> lies in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventromedial extreme of the dorsal horn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">It is bordered medially by the central gray area, with 
    whose dorsolateral part it may merge, and dorsally by the dorsal 
    fasciculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">Dorsolaterally it overlaps <labelingLocation>the 
    intermediate basilar nucleus ( ZBN )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">Ventrolaterally it becomes continuous with the 
    intermediate gray zone (ZGZ).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">As with all of the spinothalamic groups , DHvm is 
    distinct at high cervical levels , but in striking contrast to all 
    other groups it is also prominent at <labelingLocation>lower 
    thoracic and upper lumbar levels</labelingLocation> , from T9 to 
    L4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">At lower cord levels , the group of labelled DHvm cells 
    extends ventromedially well into <labelingLocation>the central gray 
    area</labelingLocation> : it is possible that this extension could 
    represent a separate group .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124"><labelingDescription>Labelled DHvm 
    neurons</labelingDescription> are usually moderate in size ( 30 - 
    40 pm ) , and although they are not strictly fusiform , their 
    dendrites are often aligned dorsolaterally - ventromedially .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">This profile is most common in cells nearest the 
    junction between the spinal gray and the dorsal fasciculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">In <labelingLocation>the very highest cervical 
    segments</labelingLocation> occasional thalamically projecting DHvm 
    neurons are seen within <labelingLocation>the intermediate basilar 
    nucleus ( ZBN ; the convexity on the medial border of the dorsal 
    horn</labelingLocation> - compare Giesler et al . , &apos; 79a ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">More typically , <labelingDescription>the labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> cluster just ventromedially to ZBN .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">The more dorsolateral portion of IBN, by contrast, is 
    populated by cells that appear to represent the caudalmost limits 
    of the medial cuneate nucleus (CUM, see Fig. 3C).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><labelingDescription>At least 90% of labelled DHvm 
    cells</labelingDescription> are contralateral to the injection site 
    : one or two <labelingDescription>ipsilateral 
    cells</labelingDescription> are present , however , even in 
    <labelingLocation>thoracic and lumbar cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130"><labelingLocation>Intermediate gray zone ( IGZ 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">This group of cells lies in <labelingLocation>the 
    transition zone between dorsal and ventral horns</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">It is clearly seen from <labelingLocation>the 
    medulldcord junction down to lower C3 or upper C4, and is most 
    prominent in C1</labelingLocation> and C2.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133"><labelingDescription>Occasional 
    cells</labelingDescription> are seen in <labelingLocation>this 
    lamina in the thoracic and lumbar cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">Labelled cells of IGZ vary greatly in size and shape.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">The border between this zone and DHvm is not clear at 
    any level, but as the DHvm and ZGZ groups may label independently 
    after separate injections (Granum, in preparation; also Menetrey et 
    al., &apos;84b), the two regions are considered separately.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136"><labelingDescription>The great majority of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are contralateral to the injection site 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">Dorsal portion of the ventral horn (VHd).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">This group of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> - 
    filled cells lies diagonally across the upper part of the ventral 
    horn , ventral and slightly caudal to IGZ , but ipsilateral to the 
    site of injection .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are most numerous in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral region</labelingLocation> , and some 
    cells spill over the graylwhite boundary into <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral funiculus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140"><labelingLocation>The group</labelingLocation> is 
    present from the medulldcord junction to the fifth cervical segment 
    and is most prominent in C1 - C3.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Rare members of the group are seen as far caudally as 
    <labelingLocation>lower thoracic and upper lumbar 
    segments</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">VHd is parallel to the other four spinothalamic laminae 
    (M, SGv, N, and IGZ), but it differs from all the other 
    spinothalamic groups in that it is ipsilateral to the site of 
    injection.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">The sizes and shapes of spinothalamic cells in this 
    lamina vary greatly from narrow fusiform to large multipolar: some 
    of the latter may be as large as the motor neurons of the ventral 
    horn.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Ventral part of the ventral horn (VHu).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in this group are in 
    <labelingLocation>the deepest part of the ventral 
    horn</labelingLocation> .</S>
  </Results>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">The lateral portions of VHv partly overlap the region 
    covered  Fig. 5.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">Graph of the total number of spinothalamic cells ( 
    except R59 for which <injectionLocation>the lower cord 
    segments</injectionLocation> were not by VHd .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">The VHu group is seen clearly from the medulla/ cord 
    junction to the fourth cervical segment and is most prominent in 
    Cl-C3.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">Rare spinothalamic cells are seen deep in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral horn as far caudally as lower 
    thoracic and upper lumbar segments</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">However , as with every other group except DHurn , 
    <labelingDescription>labelled VHu cells</labelingDescription> are 
    not only <labelingDescription>far less common</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the lower cord</labelingLocation> but are more 
    randomly arranged .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in this group are usually moderately 
    large multipolar cells , <labelingDescription>whose 
    axons</labelingDescription> may sometimes be seen in the same 
    section as the soma , following a steep dorsomedial trajectory - 
    possibly toward the anterior white commissure .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152"><labelingDescription>Most cells</labelingDescription> 
    are contralateral to the site of injection : occasional ipsilateral 
    members are seen at upper cervical levels , and 
    <labelingDescription>very rarely in lower thoracic 
    segments</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s155">The set of spinothalamic groups is continuous with a set 
    of medullothalamic groups</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156"><labelingLocation>The division between brainstem and 
    spinal cord</labelingLocation> is not anatomically abrupt , and 
    some of the spinothalamic groups appear to be continuous across the 
    cordlmedulla junction with lower brainstem nuclei ( see Fig . 3B , 
    C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">Numerous groups of <labelingDescription>labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    lower medulla</labelingLocation> , some of which ( e . g . , 
    <labelingLocation>the trigeminal and dorsal column nuclei 
    )</labelingLocation> are well - known sources of thalamic afTerents 
    ( Fig . 3A , B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Brief mention will be made here regarding only those 
    medullothalamic groups that are particularly relevant to the 
    spinothalamic study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s159">
    <labelingLocation>Dorsolateral reticular formation ( DLRF ) ( 
    nucleus Z ? )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">It is possible that this group represents the rodent 
    counterpart of the feline nucleus Z (Brodal and Pompeiano, 
    &apos;57).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161"><labelingDescription>The labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> lie just medial to 
    <labelingLocation>the inferior cerebellar peduncle in the dorsal 
    and lateral regions of the medullary gray</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162"><labelingLocation>The group</labelingLocation> is 
    already present at the most rostral level examined ( level 80 - 81 
    of Pellegrino et al . , &apos; 79 ; level 45 in Fig . 3A ) and may 
    extend more rostrally still .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">At this level it occupies the territory normally 
    ascribed to <injectionLocation>the spinal vestibular 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> , but more caudally the labelled 
    population shifts ventral to <labelingLocation>the spinal 
    vestibular nucleus</labelingLocation> , ending just rostral to 
    <labelingLocation>the medial cuneate nucleus</labelingLocation> , 
    or possibly shifting more ventrally to become continuous with 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial border of the nucleus of the 
    trigeminal spinal tract</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">More than 90% of the cells in this nucleus are 
    contralateral to the injection site.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165"><labelingLocation>Ventrolateral reticular formation ( 
    VLRF ) </labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">This group may be what is termed by others 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral reticular formation, 
    LRF</labelingLocation>  .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">It is in <labelingLocation>the most ventral region of 
    the lower medulla</labelingLocation> , lateral to 
    <labelingLocation>the pyramidal tract and olive</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">From level 46 to level 49 ( Fig . 3A ) 
    <labelingDescription>the labelled cells</labelingDescription> form 
    a relatively compact group ; from level 50 to level 60 ( Fig . 3A , 
    B , <labelingLocation>the medulldcord junction )</labelingLocation> 
    , it continues as <labelingDescription>a sparse 
    population</labelingDescription> , and finally appears to be 
    continuous into the spinal cord with a second concentration of 
    ventrally placed <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> - 
    the group in <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the spinal 
    ventral horn, VHu </labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169"><labelingDescription>About 85 - 90% of these labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are contralateral to the injection .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170"><labelingLocation>Nucleus of the trigeminal spinal tract 
    ( NTST )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">This nucleus shows <labelingDescription>a dense 
    concentration of labelled perikarya</labelingDescription> , which 
    extends caudally to become continuous with <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal laminae of the dorsal horn of the spinal 
    cord</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3AC ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172"><labelingLocation>The subdivisions of the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> show different degrees of labelling : 
    <labelingLocation>subnucleus oralis fNTSTo )</labelingLocation> 
    shows <labelingDescription>sparse labelling</labelingDescription> 
    at its rostra1 end , increasing caudally ; 
    <labelingLocation>subnucleus interpolaris ( NTSTi ) 
    </labelingLocation>is <labelingDescription>extremely densely 
    labelled</labelingDescription>  ; and <labelingLocation>subnucleus 
    caudalis ( NTSTc )</labelingLocation> shows 
    <labelingDescription>moderate to light 
    labelling</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">Within <labelingLocation>NTSTc</labelingLocation>, 
    lamination of labelled cells becomes apparent, and a number of 
    subgroups can be defined that are continuous through the 
    medulldcord junction with HRPlabelled dorsal horn laminae.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">For instance , <labelingDescription>labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the marginal layer 
    capping the medullary substantia gelatinosa </labelingLocation> 
    form a group that is continuous caudally with the spinal M group ; 
    and cells within <labelingLocation>NTSTc</labelingLocation> that 
    are just ventral to the medullary substantia gelatinosa compose a 
    group that is continuous with the spinal SGU group .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175"><labelingDescription>Other labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> within 
    <labelingLocation>NTSTc</labelingLocation> are in a group that 
    continues into <labelingLocation>the neck group ( N ) of the dorsal 
    horn</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176"><labelingLocation>Gracile nucleus ( GN 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are present throughout this nucleus , 
    extending down through the medulldcord junction into upper cervical 
    levels .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Almost all <labelingDescription>the labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> are contralateral .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179"><labelingLocation>Lateral cuneate nucleus ( CUL 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180"><labelingDescription>Although a number of 
    cells</labelingDescription> are seen that appear to be within the 
    boundaries of CUL , the impression from the plotted data is that 
    these really represent an overflow population of cells from GN or 
    CUM ( see Fig . 3B , C ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181"><labelingLocation>Medial cuneate nucleus ( CUM 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">This nucleus also contains <labelingDescription>labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> throughout its length in 
    <labelingLocation>the medulla</labelingLocation> , and labelling 
    extends through <labelingLocation>the medulldcord junction to the 
    upper cervical segments</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">As in GN and NTST , more than 98% of 
    <labelingDescription>the labelled cells</labelingDescription> are 
    contralateral .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">The thalamically projecting populations in 
    <labelingLocation>the trigeminal and dorsal column 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> are more strictly contralateral than any 
    others within <labelingLocation>the medulla and spinal 
    cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s185"><labelingDescription>The number of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> projecting to thalamus in 
    <labelingLocation>Cl - C4</labelingLocation> is much greater than 
    the number projecting to thalamus in <labelingLocation>the whole of 
    the rest of the spinal cord</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">From Table 1, summarising <labelingDescription>the 
    counts of labelled cells</labelingDescription> in different regions 
    , it can be seen that in every individual animal analysed , 
    <labelingDescription>the number of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> projecting to the thalamus from the 
    four uppermost spinal segments , from the medulldcord junction 
    through C4, is greater than the number projecting from the whole of 
    the lower part of the spinal cord , consisting of the 27 segments 
    from C5 down to the coccyx .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187"><labelingDescription>The maximum proportion of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lower part of 
    the cord</labelingLocation> was seen in rat R64, and amounted to 
    only 44% of the total , or 191 cells out of 439.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">If one adds together the counts for all the specimens 
    analysed , one finds that the number for the lower part of the cord 
    amounts to only 25% of the total ( or 28% if we exclude the cells 
    of the gracile and cuneate nuclei from the total ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Admittedly, combining the data in this fashion may 
    introduce some distortion of the figures since the various 
    injection sites do not represent a uniform sampling of the 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Nevertheless , the full set of specimens does represent 
    a sampling of practically every region of <labelingLocation>the 
    somatosensory thalamus</labelingLocation> , and the finding for 
    each individual animal is qualitatively similar , whether one looks 
    at , for example , rat R90 ( large injection into 
    <injectionLocation>centre of thalamus</injectionLocation> and 
    spanning practically <injectionSpread>the whole thalamus 
    )</injectionSpread> , R99 ( injection into 
    <injectionLocation>posteromedial pole</injectionLocation> ) , or 
    R106 ( injection into <injectionLocation>anterior zone of 
    transition , i . e . , anterolateral pole</injectionLocation> ) ; 
    these three specimens have , respectively , 11% , 21% , and 34% of 
    their <labelingDescription>labelled neurons</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the lower part of the spinal 
    cord</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s191">Most of <labelingDescription>the labelled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lower part 
    of the spinal cord</labelingLocation> lie in a single group ( DHum 
    ) in <labelingLocation>the ventromedial part of the dorsal 
    horn</labelingLocation> , and are confined to 
    <labelingLocation>segments T9 - L4</labelingLocation></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Focussing on the relatively small proportion of 
    spinothalamic neurons detected in <injectionLocation>the lower part 
    of the spinal cord</injectionLocation> , from C5 down to the coccyx 
    , one finds that the great majority of these are concentrated in a 
    single group in <labelingLocation>the ventromedial part of the 
    dorsal horn , DHum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Aggregating the counts from all the specimens, as 
    before, we find that 68% of the total c5-co population lie in DHvm, 
    and that 90% of those DHum cells are concentrated in just eight 
    segments, from T9 to L4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">Again, these figures may be somewhat distorted by uneven 
    sampling of the thalamus, but a qualitatively similar phenomenon is 
    seen in practically every animal.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195"><labelingDescription>The largest number of non - DHum 
    cells</labelingDescription> detected in any single animal in 
    <labelingLocation>the whole of the lower part of the 
    cord</labelingLocation> was 87 out of a total c5 - co population of 
    172 ( in R107 ) , while <labelingDescription>the largest number of 
    DHum cells</labelingDescription> detected in any single animal in 
    <labelingLocation>the lower part of the cord</labelingLocation> was 
    168, out of a total c5 - co population of 191 ( in R64 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">In no specimen were more than 21 DHum cells detected in 
    <injectionLocation>the lower part of the cord outside the segments 
    T9 -</injectionLocation> L4.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">It should be noted that besides the DHvm group in 
    segments T9 - L4, there is a large DHvm group in 
    <labelingLocation>the upper part of the cord</labelingLocation> , 
    in C4 and above .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">The total number of DHvm cells amounts to 35% of the 
    total spinothalamic population, as judged from the composite data, 
    and with the same provisos as before as to possible bias due to 
    nonuniform sampling of the thalamus.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s199">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">The chief observation to emerge from these experiments 
    is that in the rat the large majority of all monosynaptic 
    projections from the spinal cord to the thalamus are made by 
    neurons whose cell bodies are in the most rostral four segments of 
    the cervical cord, and that the relatively small number of cells 
    projecting to the thalamus from the lower part of the cord lie 
    mostly in a single highly localised group apparently associated 
    with the hindlimbs.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">This point about the craniocaudal distribution of 
    spinothalamic cells will be discussed last, after considering three 
    other observationsnamely, that spinothalamic cells are arranged in 
    eight discrete groups, or nuclei; that most spinothalamic cells are 
    contralateral to the thalamus on which they project, with one 
    clearly ipsilateral group; and that the spinothalamic projections 
    from individual groups are widespread but not uniform in 
    distribution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s202">Spinothalamic cells are 
    arranged into several distinct groups, or nuclei</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">The finding of so large a number as eight anatomically 
    distinct groups of cells projecting from spinal cord to thalamus 
    (Figs. 3C, 4) was unexpected, and suggests that there may be a 
    similar diversity of functionally distinct spinothalamic 
    pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">The spinothalamic neurons are not confined to the dorsal 
    horn (which is the traditional sensory domain of the spinal cord): 
    as previous studies (reviewed below) have also shown, some of them 
    are located in deep gray areas and even in the very deepest part of 
    the ventral horn.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">The relatively discrete groups into which thalamically 
    projecting cells are arranged for the most part do not fit easily 
    into Rexed&apos;s (&apos;52, &apos;54) laminar classification.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">And particularly since results here indicate that upper 
    cervical segments contain groups not present at other levels in the 
    cord, it seems inappropriate to use a classification designed as a 
    uniform description for the entire spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">By the same token, in speculating about the functions of 
    the individual groups described here, one must be cautious: it 
    would be rash to assume, for example, that all the lamina I cells 
    in the marginal layer of Cl-C4 have the same functional properties 
    as the lamina I cells of the lumbar cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">This is an important point, since electrophysiological 
    studies have tended to concentrate on the lower levels of the 
    spinal cord, which are more easily accessible.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">A detailed discussion of the likely functions of the 
    individual groups will be presented in another paper, in connection 
    with their differential projections to the various regions of the 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">There are, however, some general comments to be made 
    here on the relations between the present and previous findings.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s211">Findings of others</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">The major previous studies of the distribution of 
    spinothalamic and trigeminothalamic cells in the rat have been 
    those of Dilly et al. (&apos;681, Giesler et al. (&apos;76, 
    &apos;79a), Fukushima and Kerr (&apos;79), Kevetter and Willis 
    (&apos;831, and Men&amp; trey et al. (&apos;84b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">These studies describe the pattern seen in the 
    transverse plane at selected levels.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">The present work is, however, the first to record 
    systematically the distribution throughout the whole length of the 
    spinal cord.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The previous findings as to the distribution of 
    spinothalamic cells in the transverse plane, as seen at rostral 
    levels, are basically in accord with the present results: no groups 
    of cells were seen in regions where the present study saw none, nor 
    does the present study find spinothalamic cells where none were 
    found before.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">However, the arrangement of the spinothalamic cells into 
    eight relatively discrete groups, clear when the data from many 
    animals are superimposed, as here, is not generally apparent in the 
    previous studies.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">While some groups, such as LEN, VHd, and (in certain 
    figures) M and DHum, were obvious, others, more sparsely populated, 
    were not resolved as separate, but appeared merged into a single 
    diffuse distribution.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Moreover, the previous studies offer a somewhat 
    different view of the rostrocaudal distribution of the 
    spinothalamic cells (see below).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">Much work has been done on the laminar arrangement of 
    spinothalamic neurons, as seen in transverse sections, in other 
    species besides the rat (cat: Carstens and Trevino, &apos;78a,b; 
    Dilly et al., &apos;68; Trevino, &apos;76; Trevino and Carstens, 
    &apos;75a,b; monkey: Albe-Fessard et al., &apos;75; Giesler et al., 
    &apos;81b; Levante et al., &apos;73; Trevino, &apos;76; Trevino and 
    Carstens, &apos;75a,b; Willis et al., &apos;78, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">The most comprehensive studies-those of Trevino and 
    Carstens (&apos;75a,b) on cat and monkey, of Carstens and Trevino 
    (&apos;78a) on cat, and of Willis et al. (&apos;79) on the 
    monkey-show many similarities with the present results.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">Moreover, if, instead of following the Rexed laminar 
    classifications used by these authors, comparison is made between 
    original figures, it becomes clear that some of the apparent 
    species differences are largely a matter of nomenclature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">All the groups seen here in the upper cervical segments 
    of the spinal cord have counterparts in similar locations in the 
    cat (see, for example, Carstens and Trevino, &apos;78a), except 
    that no distinct SGU group is apparent.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">At upper cervical levels in the monkey, the groups 
    reported here for the rat again have similar counterparts, except 
    for SGu, DHum, and IGZ (see, for example, Trevino, &apos;76; 
    Trevino and Carstens, &apos;75a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">At lumbar levels, the apparent species differences are 
    more marked: in cat, as in rat, DHvm is the most prominent group; 
    but more cells are also seen in the marginal zonehubstantia 
    gelatinosa (M and possibly SGv) and the neck of the dorsal horn (N) 
    (Trevino and Carstens, &apos;75a,b; Willis et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">In the monkey there does not seem to be a DHvm group, 
    but a possible counterpart is visible in a more diffuse and 
    slightly more ventral group of spinothalamic cells in the 
    dorsomedial part of the ventral horn.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">The DHvm group is of special interest, since it is the 
    only major spinothalamic group in the lower part of the cord of the 
    rat, and also contains a major part of the spinothalamic population 
    in the upper part of the cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Menetrey et al. (&apos;84b) have shown that at lumbar 
    levels it deals with information from the hindlimbs, and that its 
    cells are driven by a combination of proprioceptive and cutaneous 
    inputs in a manner that suggests a role in the monitoring or 
    control of hindlimb movement.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s228">Most spinothalamic cells 
    are contralateral to the thalamus on which they project; one group 
    in the dorsal part of the ventral horn, VHd, is ipsilateral</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">In agreement with previous accounts of the spinothalamic 
    tract, and with traditional spinothalamic tract concepts, most of 
    the spinothalamic cells seen in this study are contralateral to the 
    thalamus on which they project.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Both clinical (e.g., French and Peyton, 48; Voris, 51; 
    Nathan and Smith, 59; White and Sweet, 69) and experimental (e.g., 
    Basbaum, 73; Albe-Fessard and Fessard, 75) observations have 
    indicated, however, that there must also be ipsilateral (though not 
    necessarily monosynaptic) cord-tothalamus routes for sensory 
    information.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">VHd is the only prominent ipsilateral group in the 
    spinal cord (though there are several others in the medulla).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">This group, which is largely confined to the high 
    cervical levels, is evidently the same as the ipsilateral 
    spinothalamic group identified by Trevino ( 76) in the monkey, and 
    by Carstens and Trevino ( 78a,b) in the cat, and noted also by 
    Giesler et al. ( 79a) in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The function of these ipsilateral cells remains 
    something of a mystery.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Carstens and Trevino ( 78b) found that in the cat many 
    of them were unresponsive to all the somatosensory stimuli that 
    were tried, while others had enormous receptive fields, sometimes 
    bilaterally symmetrical and extending over almost the entire body 
    surface, and responded to a wide range of different types of 
    cutaneous stimulation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">The account given by Giesler et al. ( 79a) conveys the 
    impression that there is a bilaterally projecting group of celIs in 
    the intermediate gray zone and ventral horn of the rat at high 
    cervical levels; but the present findings indicate that there are 
    three different groups, closely neighbouring but in distinct 
    locations-IGZ projecting primarily contralaterally, VHd projecting 
    primarily ipsilaterally, and VHu projecting primarily 
    contralaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">It is easy to confirm that VHd and VHu only partially 
    overlap by superimposing the composite diagram of Figure 3C on its 
    mirror image (as is done in Fig. 4), thereby bringing the 
    contralateral and ipsilateral populations together on the same side 
    of the cord for comparison.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Although every thalamically projecting group seen in the 
    present experiments projects primarily to just the thalamus of one 
    side (usually contralateral, rarely ipsilateral), small numbers of 
    nonconformist cells are also seen.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">That is, in every group that projects to one thalamus, 
    there are occasional cells projecting to the other thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">Several of the medullary reticular formation groups have 
    a significantly larger proportion of such cells, but as a rule in 
    the spinal cord, such cells are few in number (less than 3%).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">If there are any truly bilateral connections, they may 
    be likely to be found among these nonconformist cells.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">In fact, Kevetter and Willis ( 83) report, from double 
    labelling experiments, that less than 2% of spinothalamic cells 
    project bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">It is impossible to say at present whether the smaII 
    numbers of cells projecting atypically in each group have important 
    functions, or merely represent developmental anomalies or 
    superfluous connections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s243">Spinothalamic 
    projections are widespread yet nonuniform in distribution</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">The composite presentation obscures the conclusions that 
    have to do with differential projections of individual spinal 
    groups to the various thalamic targets (studied also by Giesler et 
    al., 76, 79a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">To get that differential information, one must look at 
    each experiment individually and compare the results of injecting 
    HRP into different regions of the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The general finding from the present experiments is that 
    the different thalamic targets-the three somatosensory complexes, 
    ventrobasal WB), posterolateral (LP), and intralaminar (1L)-do 
    receive different proportions of their spinal input from the 
    various spinal groups.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">And yet, most of the spinal groups project quite widely 
    throughout the somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">A short way of expressing this is to say that the 
    thalamic projection of an individual group is widespread but 
    differential, or widespread but not uniform.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Previous studies of the differential projections of 
    spinothalamic cells in the rodent have concluded that the lateral 
    thalamic areas receive most of their direct spinal input from the 
    more superficial dorsal horn laminae, while the medial thalamus 
    receives most of its spinal input from deeper laminae (Giesler et 
    al., 76, 79a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">The present experiments led basically to the same 
    conclusion, but only for the caudal half of the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">In the anterior portion, the picture is somewhat 
    different.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">The far anterior pole of the ventrobasal complex-the 
    anterior zone of transition-receives most of its spinal input from 
    DHum, and appears to receive none from M or SGU groups.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">DHvm projects to other areas in the anterior and middle 
    portions of the VB, LP, and IL complexes, but probably not to the 
    far posterior poles of either VB or K.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">The far posterior pole of VB receives most of its spinal 
    input from M, SGu, N, and LCN and the far posteromedial pole of the 
    somatosensory thalamus-the intralaminar parafascicular nucleus 
    (IUPf)) and/or the overlying pretectal area-receives most of its 
    spinal input from IGZ, VHd, and VHu.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Most of the details of differential projections will be 
    presented in a future paper.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Just one aspect of the differential projections will be 
    highlighted here: namely, that the anterior zone of the thalamus 
    receives most of its spinal input from the group in the 
    ventromedial portion of the dorsal horn, DHum; that is, from the 
    only group that has a large representation at lower as well as 
    higher levels of the spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Thus the three animals with the most anterior thalamic 
    injections-R106, R63, and R64-had, respectively, 63%, 64%, and 60% 
    of their labelled spinal cells in DHum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">By comparison, the two animals with the most posterior 
    injection sites-R99 and R105had, respectively, only 8% and 5% of 
    their labelled spinal cells in DHum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Injections placed halfway between these poles, such as 
    the very large injection of R90, mostly give an intermediate 
    figure-in the case of R90,25%.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">The present results tally in an informative way with the 
    findings of Lund and Webster ( 67).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Their degeneration study serves to reinforce the present 
    finding that most spinothalamic cells lie in the most rostra1 part 
    of the cord (see below); and the present study serves to explain a 
    main conclusion of theirs, the significance of which was previously 
    unclear: namely, the statement that most of the rodent 
    spinothalamic tract ends in the anterior one-third of the 
    somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">To find where within the rat thalamus the spinothalamic 
    fibres projected, those authors hemisected the spinal cord and 
    looked for the terminal degeneration in the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">They observed that a hemisection at almost any level of 
    the spinal cord resulted in thalamic degeneration that was confined 
    mainly to the most anterior part of the somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">It was only when they hemisected the cord at the very 
    highest cervical levels that they found much degeneraton extending 
    back through the rest of the somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">This is just what the present results would lead one to 
    expect: hemisection anywhere below C3 or C4 should provoke terminal 
    degeneration chiefly in the region of the thalamus where the 
    projection from DHvm predominates, since this would be the only 
    major projection that was severed; hemisection well above C3 might 
    sever also the axons from all the other seven spinothalamic groups, 
    and so should provoke widespread degeneration in thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Lund and Webster tentatively attributed the degeneration 
    that was seen only after high cervical hemisection to involvement 
    of fibres coming from the lateral cervical nucleus, LCN.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">The present results show that LCN is only one of a 
    family of high cervical spinothalamic groups that must contribute 
    to the degeneration and have widespread projections in the 
    somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">A chain of evidence points to anatomical and functional 
    connections relating group Ia afferent signals from the periphery, 
    through the DHvm group, to the anterior zone of transition in the 
    ventrobasal complex, and to cortical area 3a.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Brown s morphological work ( 81) indicates that group Ia 
    muscle spindle afferents have terminals in the vicinity of the DHum 
    somata.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">And Menetrey et al. ( 84b) show that DHvm cells receive 
    both cutaneous and propriospinal input from the periphery.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">The results reported here indicate that the DHvm group 
    provides the major input (in terms of numbers of spinothalamic 
    cells) to the anterior zone of transition of the ventrobasal 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">This fits with other observations that group Ia muscle 
    afferents relay in rostral VB in the cat (Andersson et al., 66), 
    and input from deep tissues relays in rostral VB in the monkey 
    (Poggio and Mountcastle, 63; Albe-Fessard, 67).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">In the monkey at least, the most anterior portion of the 
    ventrobasal complex (the so-called ventroposterolateral nucleus 
    pars oralis, VPLo) has been shown by Jones and Powell ( 70) to 
    provide the most intense input to cortical area 3a, which is the 
    transitional area between sensory and motor cortex and receives, 
    among other inputs, information from group I muscle afferents in 
    the cat and baboon (Oscarsson and Rosen, 66; Landgren et al., 67; 
    Landgren and Silfvenius, 69; Phillips et al., 71) and unspecified 
    deep stimuli in the rhesus monkey (Powell and Mountcastle, 59; 
    cited in Jones and Powell, 73).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s274">The majority of 
    spinothalamic cells are in the highest four cervical segments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Perhaps the most important finding of the present study 
    is the observation that the large majority of spinothalamic cells 
    in the rat are found in the very most rostral levels of the cord, 
    rostral even to the cervical enlargement proper.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Moreover, the more caudal spinothalamic neurons (those 
    below C4) lie mostly in a single group, DHvm, confined primarily to 
    segments T9-L4, and are apparently involved in proprioceptive 
    sensation in the hindlimbs (Menetrey et al., 84a).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Setting aside the DHvm group in segments T9L4, the 
    largest number of spinothalamic neurons detected in the whole of 
    the spinal cord below C4 in any single animal was 94 (in R107).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">In terms of the aggregated data for all the animals, the 
    cells in the 27 segments below C4 that do not belong to the DHvm 
    group in T9-L4 add up to only 10% of the total spinothalamic 
    population.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Even allowing for uneven representaton of different 
    parts of the rat s body, it seems unlikely that so small a 
    population of cells could play more than a minor part in relaying 
    the sensations of pain and temperature from the whole of the body, 
    from the neck down, or that they could contribute more than a tiny 
    proportion of the tens of thousands of axons that constitute the 
    anterolateral funiculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">It seems that the traditional simple conception of the 
    human spinothalamic tract, as presented in elementary textbooks, 
    can scarcely be regarded as even an approximation to the truth for 
    the rat; for according to this conception, the major spinothalamic 
    projection, conveying pain and temperature information, should be 
    made from cells distributed along the whole length of the spinal 
    cord, with their somata close to the sites of entry of the 
    associated primary afferents, and their axons in the anterolateral 
    fasciculus contralateral to the primary afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">The present observations suggest that, in the rat at 
    least, one must invoke other pathways, such as the well-established 
    spinoreticulothalamic, not merely as a supplement to the 
    traditional spinothalamic tract, but as a substitute for it.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Validity of the observations (technical 
    considerations).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">In view of the apparent conflict with tradition, and 
    before pursuing this line of argument further, the present findings 
    must be scrutinised with respect to two questions of experimental 
    technique.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">First, is the experimental method efficient for 
    detecting caudally placed spinal neurons projecting to the thalamic 
    injection sites?</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">The speed of retrograde axonal transport in mammals is 
    of the order of 200 mm or more per day (Grafstein and Forman, go), 
    so that the 48-hour survival time used in these experiments should 
    certainly have been sufficient-long enough for transport of HRP 
    over a distance of at least 400 mm, which is three or four times 
    the distance from thalamus to coccyx.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">In any case, although most of the spinothalamic cells 
    that were detected lay at high cervical levels, a second major 
    concentration (the DHvm group) was also seen regularly at lower 
    thoracichpper lumbar levels.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">This argues against the possibility that the relatively 
    low numbers of labelled cells in the thoracic and lumbar segments 
    might have been due to a technical artifact related to tissue 
    processing or insufficient survival times.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Variation of the order in which the tissue was cut and 
    processed (i.e., caudal to rostral vs. rostral to caudal) made no 
    apparent difference in the craniocaudal distribution of labelled 
    cells (personal observations).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Admittedly, it is conceivable that some parts of the 
    spinothalamic population might be underrepresented in consequence 
    of a feeble capacity for uptake of HRP from the injection site; but 
    there is no reason to expect that this would affect the lower 
    levels of the spinal cord more than the higher.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Thus, it is likely that the present findings are a fair 
    reflection of the relative paucity of neurons at thoracic and 
    lumbar levels projecting to the thalamic injection sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">The second technical question is whether one can be sure 
    that the injections adequately sampled the somatosensory 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">The target areas were (1) the ventrobasal complex (VB); 
    (2) the posterolateral complex (LP) (now usually called the 
    posterior (PO) or posteromedial (POm) complex, although the terms 
    are not exactly synonymous); and (3) the intralaminar complex 
    (IL).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">All of these areas were sampled in the present work, as 
    shown by Figure 2 and the isometric diagram in Figure 1A.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">But do these areas constitute the entire somatosensory 
    thalamus?</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">The question is complicated by lack of consistency in 
    the nomenclature of different authors.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">This is particularly true concerning PO and/or POm, 
    which is now widely recognised as a major thalamic sensory nucleus, 
    but previously was not.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">The terms posterior thalamic region, posterior nuclear 
    complex, posterior nucleus, or posterior group (all abbreviated 
    PO); and posteromedial nucleus, or medial division of the posterior 
    group (both abbreviated POm), have been used by different authors 
    in confusingly different senses (see Lund and Webster, 67; Mehler, 
    69; Jones and Burton, 74; Burton and Jones, 76; Boivie, 78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Emmers ( 65) believes the rat PO homologue is actually 
    within the lateral part of the ventrobasal complex.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Mehler ( 69) holds that it is probably caudal to the 
    ventroposterolateral nucleus, but certainly consists of very few 
    cells.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Lund and Webster ( 67) state that it appears to comprise 
    the medial geniculate complex pars suprageniculata . . . and may 
    include the nucleus posterior parabrachialis (but compare Mehler, 
    69).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Scheibel and Scheibel( 66) label as rodent PO a large 
    area caudal to the ventrobasal complex and assert that this area 
    receives a large amount of spinal input.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Thus, by some authors definition, the rat somatosensory 
    thalamus will have been wholly sampled in the thalamic target areas 
    injected in this study; and by other authors definitions, the most 
    caudal part of the rat PO (or POm) may have been missed.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Slightly more widespread regions have been sampled by 
    S.K.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Kemplay and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Webster (personal communication) in a later repetition 
    of the experiments reported here, using animals that were given 
    multiple HRP injections; by any author s definition, these covered 
    all of PO (or POm) and yielded the same qualitative finding-namely, 
    a relative paucity of spinothalamic cells in the lower cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Thus one can be reasonably confident that these 
    procedures have indeed detected a representative sample of 
    essentially all the cells projecting directly from the spinal cord 
    to the somatosensory thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Hence one can probably trust the conclusion that only a 
    minority of these spinothalamic neurons lie at thoracic or lumbar 
    levels, and that of that minority, only a small proportion lie 
    outside the DHvm group.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">The findings of others.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">If this picture is accurate, why has it not been 
    reported before?</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">The reason seems to lie chiefly in the way the different 
    rostrocaudal levels have been sampled.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Several of the previous studies of the distribution of 
    spinothalamic cells in the rat focus only on the most rostral 
    (Fukushima and Kerr, 79) or only on the lumbosacral (Kevetter and 
    Willis 82; Menetrey et al., 84b) part of the spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">None of the previous HRP studies recorded the 
    distribution of labelled cells in every section, throughout the 
    entire length of the spinal cord, as has been done here.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Thus Kevetter and Willis ( 83) apparently examined only 
    the upper cervical levels and the cervical and lumbar enlargements, 
    while Giesler et al. ( 79a) show data only for spinal segments C1, 
    C2, C7, T6, L3, and L6.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">For the most part these earlier findings, though they 
    convey at first sight a different emphasis, do not conflict with 
    the present, more complete, data.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Just one of the animals illustrated by Giesler et al. ( 
    79a) shows a concentration of cells in the neck of the dorsal horn 
    at lumbar levels, where they were rarely seen in the present 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">But this was an animal that had received six injections 
    of HRP intended to fill the entire thalamus, and some of the HRP 
    may have diffused beyond the boundaries of the thalamus, and in 
    particular into brainstem areas known to receive afferents from the 
    spinal cord, such as the zona incerta, pretectum, and superior 
    colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Kevetter and Willis ( 83) also show a noticeable 
    concentration of cells in the neck region at lumbar levels, but 
    this may have a similar explanation, since the volume of tracer 
    that they injected was ten times greater than in the present 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">It is striking that they found the neck region at lumbar 
    levels to contain very large numbers of labelled cells when they 
    injected their tracer into the medullary reticular formation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Essentially similar comments apply to the published HRP 
    studies of the distribution of spinothalamic cells in cat and 
    monkey (cited above).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">In these species, too, attention has generally been 
    focussed on a few selected rostrocaudal levels-most often high 
    cervical, cervical enlargement, andor lumbar enlargement-and, as 
    for the rat, it appears that through spread of the tracer some of 
    the cells classed as spinothalamic may have been spinoreticular.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">It is possible that the true picture of the rostrocaudal 
    distribution of spinothalamic cells may be roughly similar in rat, 
    cat, and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Some evidence in regard to man will be considered 
    below.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Implications.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">The traditional simple conception of the spinothalamic 
    tract was developed at the end of the last century, largely on the 
    basis of two classes of observations, attested by many 
    investigators.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">First, when the anterolateral funiculus was severed, 
    sensory deficits, especially but not exclusively with regard to 
    pain and temperature, were seen caudal to the lesion and on the 
    opposite side of the body; and second, after the same lesion, at 
    least some anterograde degeneration was seen to extend up into the 
    thalamus on the same side as the lesion (reviewed: May, 06; Willis 
    and Coggeshall, 78).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Hence it was proposed that sensations of pain and 
    temperature were carried by neurons whose axons crossed the spinal 
    cord close to the site of entry of the primary afferents, and ran 
    in the anterolateral funiculus to terminate in the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">But it was clear from the beginning that the 
    observations did not force this conclusion: it could not be assumed 
    that all the axons in the anterolateral funiculus ascend as far as 
    the thalamus; nor could it be assumed that the axons that did 
    ascend to the thalamus were the ones carrying pain and temperature 
    sensations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Indeed, degeneration studies (cited above, in the 
    beginning of this paper) indicated that most spinal cord neurons 
    with long ascending axons did not ascend as far as the thalamus, 
    but appeared to end in the brainstem reticular formation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Thus it could be argued that routes from the spinal cord 
    to the thalamus might be mostly polysynaptic, via a chain of relays 
    (e.g., Ranson, 43; Basbaum, 73).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">And, interestingly, Rothmann ( 04- 05, cited in May, 
    06), during the debate at the turn of the century over whether any 
    fibres reach from the spinal cord all the way to the thalamus, 
    affirmed that although some did, it was possible that they did so 
    only from the most rostral cervical segments.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Subsequent studies (e.g., Mehler et al., 60; Bowsher, 
    61; Mehler, 69; Boivie, 71, 791, using the more reliable silver 
    impregnation degeneration techniques, as well as 
    electrophysiological studies (e.g., Trevino et al., 72, 73; 
    AlbeFessard et al., 74; Giesler et al., 76), have shown that this 
    speculation went too far: there are certainly some fibres that 
    project directly to the thalamus from the more caudal parts of the 
    spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Yet if these fibres represent only a small part of the 
    projection ascending from the spinal cord, Rothmann s suggestion 
    may be close to the truth.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">The present findings demonstrate that it is so for the 
    rat at least: apart from the DHvm system, very few neurons project 
    to the thalamus from the lower part of the cord; much larger 
    numbers do so from the highest cervical levels; and it is tempting 
    to suggest that these high cervical cells represent relays for 
    information ascending from the lower levels.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Although degeneration studies cannot give firm 
    quantitative information, and there may well be some significant 
    species differences, it has been repeatedly noted, by different 
    workers and in a variety of species including man, that most of the 
    fibres in the anterolateral funiculus appear to terminate in the 
    reticular formation and in other regions of the brainstem, rather 
    than in the thalamus: at least, when the funiculus is cut, most of 
    the terminal degeneration is seen in those sites (e.g., Kuru, 
    &apos;49; Morin et al., &apos;51; Anderson and Berry, &apos;59; 
    Mehler et al., &apos;60; Mehler,&apos;62; Kerr, &apos;75b; Zemlan 
    et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">It is well established (Purpura and Yahr, &apos;66; 
    Iggo, &apos;73; Bonica, &apos;74; and Bonica et al., &apos;79, for 
    reviews), and also clear from the present observations, that the 
    thalamus in turn receives projections from many of these brainstem 
    cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">The present study shows that there is no obvious 
    dividing line between the set of cell groups projecting to the 
    thalamus from the brainstem and those projecting from the most 
    rostral part of the spinal cord: they all appear to belong to a 
    single archipelago.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Moreover, at least three of the groups of cells seen at 
    high cervical levels in this study-the gracile, cuneate, and 
    lateral cervical nuclei-are well known from previous work to be 
    rostral relays for information ascending from caudal regions 
    (Nathan and Smith, &apos;59; and Willis and Coggeshall, &apos;78, 
    for reviews).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">The experiments of Carstens and Trevino (&apos;78b) on 
    the VHd group in the cat suggest that the same may be true of 
    it.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">In general, there is very little evidence as to the 
    functions of the other high cervical groups seen in this study, and 
    little to contradict the suggestion that they follow the precedent 
    set by the gracile, cuneate, and lateral cervical nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">While there have been physiological investigations of 
    cells in the appropriate Rexed laminae, such as those of 
    Christensen and Per1 (&apos;70) on the nociceptive cells of the 
    marginal zone, these have mostly concentrated on more caudal 
    regions of the spinal cord (Brown, &apos;81; Willis and Coggeshall, 
    &apos;78, for review).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">The one necessary qualification to the present 
    suggestion that the high cervical groups are relays for much more 
    caudal afferents concerns the trigeminal system: it may be that 
    some of the cells seen in this study, especially in the groups M, 
    SGv, and N, are relaying trigeminal input, but probably only to a 
    very small extent if at all (Kerr, &apos;70a,b); these three groups 
    in any case represent only a small proportion of the total high 
    cervical spinothalamic population detected here.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">If it is true that the spinothalamic groups identified 
    in this work receive input from neurons located more caudally in 
    the spinal cord, then an obvious area of future study would be the 
    anatomical identification of these lower links in the chain, i.e., 
    the links between the primary afferents and the directly 
    spinothalamic (or medullothalamic) fibres.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Such identification has already been made in the case of 
    spinal input to dorsal column nuclei (which also receive primary 
    afferent input) (e.g., Rustioni, &apos;73, &apos;74; Rustioni and 
    Kaufman, &apos;77; and for reviews, Nathan and Smith, &apos;59; and 
    Willis and Coggeshall, &apos;78), and to the lateral cervical 
    nucleus (e.g., Hongo et al., &apos;68; Bryan et al., &apos;73, 
    &apos;74; Jankowska, &apos;75; Brown et al., &apos;76; Craig, 
    &apos;76; Jankowska et al., &apos;76 Snow et al., &apos;76; Cervero 
    et al., &apos;77; Willis and Coggeshall, &apos;78, for review; 
    Giesler et al., &apos;79b, in the rat).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">But very little is known specifically as to the possible 
    spinal input to the other cervical spinothalamic groups-especially 
    those in the deeper laminae (the intermediate gray, IGZ, the 
    ipsilaterally projecting dorsal area of the ventral horn, VHd, and 
    the ventral extreme of the ventral horn, VHv).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Certainly the idea that there are polyneuronal 
    (multisynaptic) routes by which sensory information ascends through 
    the spinal cord toward the brainstem, and that propriospinal and 
    spinobulbar systems are crucial to pain sensibility, is very old 
    (e.g., May, &apos;06; Karplus and Kreidl, &apos;25; Nathan and 
    Smith, &apos;59; Noordenbos, &apos;59; Poggio and Mountcastle, 
    &apos;60; Melzack and Wall, &apos;65; Basbaum, &apos;73; Kerr, 
    &apos;75a; Wall, &apos;78; Bowsher &apos;79; Cook et al., &apos;84; 
    Peschanski and Besson, &apos;84; and or reviews, Bonica and 
    AlbeFessard, &apos;76; Willis and Coggeshall, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">More recently, the importance of reticular formation 
    relays, including those in the lower medulla, in transmitting 
    ascending sensory messages has been emphasized (Herrick and Bishop, 
    &apos;58; Nauta and Kuypers, &apos;58; Albe-Fessard et al., 
    &apos;74a,b; Kerr, &apos;75a,b; Nauta, &apos;75; Kevetter and 
    Willis, &apos;82-&apos;84; Levante et al., &apos;83; Peschanski and 
    Besson, &apos;84; Menhtrey et al., &apos;84a; Wiberg and Blomqvist, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">And Basbaum (&apos;73) has demonstrated that a short 
    fibre, polysynaptic, propriospinal system is capable of conveying 
    nociceptive information rostrally in the absence of the long 
    ascending systems (Basbaum, &apos;73).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Thus while the more caudal parts of the spinal cord do 
    contain cells that project directly to the thalamus, and this 
    projection may well play some part in the perception of pain and 
    temperature, its role may be small compared with that of the 
    polysynaptic pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Neither degeneration experiments nor 
    electrophysiological studies, with their uncertainties of 
    measurement, sampling, and localization, can decide quantitative 
    questions about the relative importance of the different modes of 
    ascent to the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">There are certainly species differences in the 
    spinothalamic system (see, for example, Mehler &apos;69); but it is 
    entirely possible that other mammals may resemble rats at least to 
    the extent that cells projecting to the thalamus from the more 
    caudal regions of the spinal cord are few by comparison with those 
    projecting from the uppermost cervical segments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Relevance to man.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">There is some remarkable clinical evidence, first 
    reported by Hitchcock (&apos;70, &apos;74) and since confirmed by 
    others (Papo and Luongo, &apos;76; Nathan, &apos;77; Schvarcz, 
    &apos;77, &apos;78; Cook et al., &apos;84), which cannot be 
    explained by traditional views of the human spinothalamic tract, 
    but for which the present findings suggest a straightforward 
    interpretation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">The clinical observations have to do with the 
    consequences of commissural myelotomy, an operation in which a 
    lesion in the midline of the spinal cord is employed to interrupt 
    pain pathways in patients suffering from intractable pain.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">The rationale of the surgery is as follows: Pain, 
    temperature, and crude touch primary efferents terminate in the 
    cord at or close to their level of dorsal root entry; and 
    second-order pain and temperature fibres, arising from cells in the 
    dorsal horn, then cross the midline close to the segment in which 
    their cell bodies lie, before ascending in the anterolateral 
    funiculus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Primary afferents for discriminative fine touch and 
    proprioception, by contrast, ascend through the dorsal fasciculi 
    without crossing the midline, to synapse with the gracile and 
    cuneate nuclei in the medulla; and it is from there that 
    second-order neurons cross the midline to ascend to the 
    thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Thus, it is hoped, by interrupting only commissural 
    fibres of the spinal levels corresponding to the painful body 
    region, that one should selectively abolish the pain at those body 
    levels without losing fine touch and proprioception (and without 
    losing the ability to feel pain at other body levels both above and 
    below the lesion).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">This operation is an advance on the older technique of 
    employing an anterolateral cordotomy (a transverse cut through all 
    the anterolateral fibres at a particular cord level), which is 
    necessarily more invasive and, predictably, results in loss of pain 
    sensation at every level below and contralateral to the cordotomy, 
    as well as interrupting all other pathways in the anterolateral 
    funiculus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Commissural myelotomies performed at most cord levels, 
    like anterolateral cordotomies, result in sensory deficits largely 
    in accord with expectations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">But in patients in which a commissural myelotomy is 
    performed at the highest cervical levels or just at the medulldcord 
    junction, sensory deficits are observed far lower in the trunk and 
    periphery than predicted.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">A C1 commissural myelotomy, even one so short as to 
    extend less than a whole segment, may be observed to result in 
    sensory deficits over virtually the entire body-sparing perhaps 
    only a small muzzle area of the face (Nathan, 77, and personal 
    communication; Cook et al., 84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">These findings cannot be explained by traditional 
    concepts of the anatomy of the spinothalamic tract, and are at 
    least consistent with a specialised rostra1 cord system of 
    somatosensory nuclei that receive and relay sensory information to 
    the thalamus from lower (mainly ipsilateral) levels of the 
    neuraxis, as is proposed in the present study.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="25" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s362">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s363">These experiments were done 
    at King s College London, and I thank King s College and the 
    Medical Research Council for financial support.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s364">I am indebted to Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s365">G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s366">Vrbova and Professor G.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s367">Burnstock for their support, 
    and to Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s368">P.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s369">Nathan for helpful 
    discussions regarding the commissural myelotomy observations, and 
    constructive comments on the text.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s370">I am grateful especially to 
    Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s371">J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s372">Lewis for his comments and 
    generous help with the preparation of the present paper: it owes 
    much to him both in wording and substance.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="25" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s373">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">of nuclear population from microtome Abercrombie, M. 
    (1946) Estimation sections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Rec. 94.239-247.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Albe-Fessard, D. (1967) Organization brib.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Sensory Physiol. 2:lOl-177.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">of somatic central projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">ConAlbe-Fessard, D., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Fessard (1975) Recent advances on the neurophysiological 
    basis of pain sensation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Acta Neurobiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Exp. 35:715-740.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Albe-Fessard, D., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Levante, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Lamour (1974a) Origin of spinothalamic and 
    spinoreticular pathways in cats and monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">In J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Bonica (ed): Advances in Neurology, vol 4: International 
    Symposium on Pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">New York Raven Press, pp. 157-166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Albe-Fessard, D., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Levante, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Lamour (1974b) Origin of spinothalamic tract in 
    monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Brain Res. 65:503-509.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Albe-Fessard, D., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Boivie, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Grant, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Levante (1975) Labelling of cells in the medulla 
    oblongata and the spinal cord of the monkey after injections of 
    horseradish peroxidase in the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Letts.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">1:75-80.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Anderson, F.D., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Berry (1959) Degeneration studies of long ascending 
    fibre systems in the cat brain stem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Neurol. 111:195-229.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Andersson, S.A., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Landgren, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Wolsk (1966) The thalamic relay and cortical projection 
    of group I muscle afferents from the forelimb of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">(Lond.) 183576-591, Basbaum, A.I. (1973) Conduction of 
    the effects of noxious stimulation by short-fiber multisynaptic 
    systems of the spinal cord in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">40~699-716.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Boivie, J. (1971) The termination of the spinothalamic 
    tract in the cat: An experimental study with silver impregnation 
    methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">12:331-353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Boivie, J. (1978) Anatomical observations on the dorsal 
    column nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Their thalamic projection and the cytoarchitecture of 
    some somatosensory thalamic nuclei in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Neurol. 178:17-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Boivie, J. (1979) An anatomical reinvestigation of the 
    termination of the spinothalamic tract in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Neurol. 186~343-370.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Bonica, J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">(ed) (1974) Advances in Neurology, vol. 4; International 
    Symposium on Pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">New York: Raven Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Bonica, J.J., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Lieheskind, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Albe-Fessard (eds) (1979) Advances in Pain Research and 
    Therapy, vol. 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">New York Raven Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Bowsher, D. (1957) Termination of the central pain 
    pathway in man: The conscious appreciation of pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Brain 80:606-622.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Bowsher, D. (1979) Central mechanisms of orofacial 
    pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Br.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Oral Surg. 17:185-197.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Bowsher, D., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Westman (1970) The gigantocellular region and its spinal 
    afferents: A light and electron microscope study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Anat. 10623-36.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Breazile, J.E., and R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Kitchell (1968) Ventrolateral spinal cord afferents to 
    the brain stem in the domestic pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Neurol. 133~363-372.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Brodal, A., and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Pompeiano (1957) The vestibular nuclei in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Anat. 91:438-454.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Brown, A.G. (1981) Organization Verlag.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Brown, A.G., C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">House, P.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Rose, and P.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Snow (19761 The morphology of spinocervical tract 
    neurones in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">(Lond.) 260:719738.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Bryan, R.N., D.1,.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Trevino, J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Coulter, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Willis (1973) Location and somatotopic organization of 
    the cells of origin of the spinocervical tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Brain Res. 17:177-189.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Bryan, R.N., J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Coulter, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Willis (1974) Cells of origin spinocervical tract in the 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Weurol. 42574-586.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Burton, H., and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Jones (1976) The posterior thalamic region and its 
    cortical projection in new and old world monkeys. 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">168:249-302.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Carstens, E., and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Trevino (1978a) Laminar origins of spinothalamic 
    projections in the cat as determined by the retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Neurol. 182151-166.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Carstens, E., and D.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Trevino (1978b) Anatomical and physiolgical properties 
    of ipsilaterally projecting spinothalamic neurons in the second 
    cervical segment of the cat s spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Neurol. 182:167-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Cervero, F., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Iggo, and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Molony (1977) Responses of spinocervical tract neurones 
    to noxious stimulation of the skin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">(Lond.) 267~537558.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Christensen, B.H., and E.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Per1 (1970) Spinal neurons specifically excited by 
    noxious or thermal stimuli: Marginal zone of the dorsal horn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Neurophysiol. 33:293-307.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Colman, D.R., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Scalia, and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Cahales (1976) Ligbt and electron microscope 
    observations on the anterograde transport of horseradish peroxidase 
    in the optic pathway in mouse and rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Brain Res. 102156-163.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Cook, A.W., P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Nathan, and M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Smith (1984) Sensory consequences of commissural 
    myelotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">A challenge to traditional anatomical concepts.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Brain 107:547-568.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Craig, A.D. (1976) Spinocervical tract retrograde 
    transport of horseradish 117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Dilly, P.N., P.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Wall, and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Wehster (1968) Cells of origin of the spinothalamic 
    tract in cat and rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Neurol. 21:550-562.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Edinger, L. (1889) 
    Vergleichend-entwicklungsgeschichtliche und anatomische Studien im 
    Bereiche des Centralnervensystems. 2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Uber die Forsetzung der hinteren Riickenmarkswurzeln zum 
    Gehirn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Anz. 4:121-128.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Edinger, L. (1911) Vorlesungen uher den Bau der Nervosen 
    Zentralorgane.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">F.C.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Vogel, Leipzig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Emmers, R. (1965) Organisation of the first and the 
    second somesthetic regions (SI and SII) in the rat thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Neurol. 124r215-227.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Foerster, O., and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Gage1 (1931) Die Vorderseitenstrangdurchschneidung heim 
    Menschen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Eine klinisch-patho-physiologisch-anatomische Studie.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Ges.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Psychiat. 138:l-92.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">French, L.A., and W.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Peyton (1948) Ipsilateral cordotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Neurosurg. 5:403-404.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Fukushima, T., and F.W.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Kerr (1979) Organization of trigeminal tracts and other 
    thalamic afferent systems of the hrainstem in the rat: Presence of 
    gelatinosa neurons with thalamic connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Neurol. 183:169-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Giesler, G.J.Jr., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Menetrey, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Guilhaud, and J-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Besson (1976) Lumbar cord neurons at the origin of the 
    spinothalamic tract in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Brain Res. 118,320-324.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Giesler, G.J.Jr., J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Cannon, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Urca, and J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Liebeskind (1978) Long ascending projections from 
    substantia gelatinosa Rolandi and the subjacent dorsal horn in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Science 202984-986.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Giesler, G.J.Jr., D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">MenBtrey, and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Bashaum (1979a) Differential origins of spinothalamic 
    tract projections to medial and lateral thalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Neurol. 184:107-126.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Giesler, G.J.Jr., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Urca, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Cannon, and J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Liebeskind (1979h) Response properties of neurons of the 
    lateral cervical nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Neurol. 186:65-78.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Giesler, G.J.Jr., H.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Spiel, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Willis (1981a) Organization of spinothalamic tract axons 
    within the rat spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Neurol. 195:243-252.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Giesler, G.J.Jr., R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Yezierski, K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Gerhardt, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Willis (1981b) Spinothalamic tract neurons that project 
    to medial and/or lateral thalamic nuclei: Evidence for a 
    physiologically novel population of spinal cord neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Neurophysiol. 46:1285-1308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Grafstein, B., and D.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Forman (1980) Intracellular Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Rev. 60:1167-1283.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Granum, S.L. (1983) Spinothalamic and Bulhothalamic 
    Somatosensory Connections in the Rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Ph.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Thesis, King s College London, University of London.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Granum, S.L., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Wehster (1981) The lateral cervical nucleus of the rat: 
    Its extent in the central nervous system and its connection with 
    the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Anat. 133:655.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Granum, S.L., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Wehster (1982) The spinothalamic origin in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Neuroscience 7:(suppl):S87.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Herrick, C.J., and G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Bishop (1958) A comparative survey of the spinal 
    lemniscus systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">In L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Proctor (ed): The Reticular Formation of the Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Boston: Little, Brown &amp;amp; Co., pp. 353-360.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Hitchcock, E. (1970) Stereotactic cervical myelotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Neuro.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Neurosurg.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Psychiatry 33:224-230.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Hitchcock, E. (1974) Stereotactic myelotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Med. 67t771-772.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Hongo, T., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Jankowska, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Lundberg (1968) Post-synaptic excitation and inhibition 
    from primary afferents in neurones of the spinocervical tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">CLond.) 199:569-592.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Iggo, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">(ed) (1973) Handbook of Sensory Physiology, vol. 2: 
    Somatosensory System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">New York: Springer-Verlag.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Jankowska, E. (1975) Identification of interiieurons 
    interposed in different spinal reflex pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Santini (ed): Golgi Centennial Symposium.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">New York: Raven Press, pp. 235-246.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Jankowska, E., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Rastad, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Westman (1976) Intracellular application of horseradish 
    peroxidase and its light and electron microscopical appearance in 
    spinocervical tract cells.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Brain Res. 105,557-562.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Jones, E.G., and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Powell (1970) Connections of the somatic sensory cortex 
    of the rhesus monkey. 111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Thalamic connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Brain 93:37-56.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Jones, E.G., and T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Powell (1973) Anatomical organization of the 
    somatosensory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Iggo (ed): Handbook of Sensory Physiology, vol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">I1 The Somatosensory System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">New York Springer-Verlag, pp. 579-620.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Jones, E.G., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Burton (1974) Cytoarchitecture and somatic sensory 
    connectivity of thalamic nuclei other than the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Neurol. 154t395-432.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Karplus, J.P., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Kreidl (1925) Ein Beitrag zur Kenntnis der 
    Schmerzleitung im Ruckenmark. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Mitteilung.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Pflugers Arch. 207t134-139.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Kerr, F.W.L. (1970a) The fine structure of the 
    suhnucleus caudalis of the trigeminal nerve.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Brain Res. 23:129-145.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Kerr, F.W.L. (1970h) The organization of primary 
    afferents in the subnucleus caudalis of the trigeminal: A light and 
    electron microscopic study of degeneration Brain Res. 
    23t147-165.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Kerr, F.W.L. (1975a) Neuroanatomical substrates cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Pain 1.325-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Kerr, F.W.L. (1975b) The ventral spinothalamic tract and 
    other ascending systems of the ventral funiculus of the spinal 
    cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Neurol. 159:335-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Kerr, F.W.L., and H.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Lippman (1974) The primate spinothalamic tract as 
    demonstrated by anterolateral cordotomy and commissural 
    myelotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">In J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Bonica (ed): Advances in Neurology, vol. 4.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">International Symposium on Pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">New York: Raven, pp. 147-156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Kevetter, G.A., and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Willis (1982) Spinothalamic cells in the rat lumhar cord 
    with collaterals to the medullary reticular formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Brain Res. 238:181-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Kevetter, G.A., and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Willis (1983) Collaterals the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Neurol. 215:453-464.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Kevetter, G.A., and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Willis (1984) Collateralization in the spinothalamic 
    tract: New methodology to support or deny phylogenetic theories.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Rev. 7tl-14.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Kuru, M. (1949) Sensory Paths Tokyo: Sogensya.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Landgren, S., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Silfvenius (1969) Projection to the cerebral cortex in 
    Group I muscle afferents from the cat s hind limb.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">(Lond.) 200~353-372.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Landgren, S., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Silfvenius, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Wolsk (1967) Somato-sensory paths to the second cortical 
    projection area of the group I muscle afferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">(Lond.) 191t543-559.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Gros Clark, W.E. (1936) The termination of ascending 
    thalamus of the macaque monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Anat. 7It7-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Levante, A,, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Lamour, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Alhe-Fessard (1973) Localisation dans la couche V de 
    Rexed des cellules dorigine dun faisceau spino-thalamique croise 
    chez le Macaque.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Paris 276:1589-1592.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Lund, R.D., and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Webster (1967) Thalamic afferents from the cord and 
    trigeminal nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Neurol. 130313-328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">May, W.P. (1906) The afferent path.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Brain 293 42-803.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Mehler, W.R. (1962) The anatomy of the so-called pain 
    tract in man: An analysis of the course and distribution of the 
    ascending fibers of the fasciculus anterolateralis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">In J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Porter and R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">French (eds): Basic Research in Paraplegia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Springfield Thomas, pp. 26-55.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Mehler, W.R. (1969) Some neurological species 
    differences-- a posteriori .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">N.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Sci. 167t424-468.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Mehler, W.R., M.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Feferman, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Nauta (1960) Ascending axon degeneration following 
    anterolateral cordotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">An experimental study in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Brain 83r718-750.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Melzack, R., and P.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Wall (1965) Pain mechanisms: 150:971-979.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Menetrey, D., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">De Pommery, and J-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Besson (1984a) Electrophysiological characteristics of 
    lumhar spinal cord neurons backfired from lateral reticular nucleus 
    in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Neurophysiol. 52:595-611.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Menetrey, D., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">De Pommery, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Roudier (1984b) Properties of deep spinothalamic tract 
    cells in the rat, with spinal reference to ventromedial zone of 
    lumhar dorsal horn.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Neurophysiol. 52:612-624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Morin, F., H.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Schartz, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">O Leary (1951) Experimental study of the spinothalamic 
    and related tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Acta Psychiatr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Neurol. 26:371-396.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Mott, F.W. (1892) Ascending degenerations resulting from 
    lesions of the spinal cord in monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Brain 15:215.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Mott, F.W. (1895) Experimental enquiry upon the afferent 
    tracts of the CNS of the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Brain 18:1-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Nahin, R.L., A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Madsen, and G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Giesler Jr. (1983) Anatomical and physiological studies 
    of the grey matter surrounding the spinal cord central canal.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Neurol. 22Ot321-335.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">Nathan, P.W. (1977) Pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Br.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Med.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Bull. 33t149-156.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Nathan, P.W., and M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Smith (1959) Fasculii proprii of the spinal cord in man: 
    Review of the present knowledge.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Brain 82;610-668.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Nauta, W.J.H. (1975) Anatomical organization of pain 
    pathways in the central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">In S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Snyder and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Matthysse (eds): Opiate Receptor Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Bull. 13:84-87.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Nauta, W.J.H., and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Kuypers (1958) Some ascending pathways in the brain stem 
    reticular formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">In H.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Jasper et al.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">(eds): Reticular Formation of the Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Henry Ford Hospital Interational Symposium.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Boston: Little, Brown and Co., pp. 3-30.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Noordenbos, W. (1959) Pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Amsterdam: Elsevier.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">Oscarsson, O., and I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Rosen (1966) Short-latency projections to the cat s 
    cerebral cortex from skin and muscle afferents in the contralateral 
    forelimb.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">(Lond.) 182162-184.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Papo, I., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">Luongo (1976) High cervical commissural myelotomy in the 
    treatment of pain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Neurosurg.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Psychiatr. 39t705-710.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Pellegrino, L.J., AS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Pellegrino, and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Cushman (1979) A Stereotaxic Atlas of the Rat Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">New York: Plenum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Peschanski, M., and J-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">Besson (1984) A spino-reticulothalamic pathway in the 
    rat: An anatomical study with reference to pain transmission.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Neuroscience 12: 165-178.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Peschanski, M., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Mantyh, and J-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Besson (1983) Spinal afferents to the ventrobasal 
    thalamic complex in the rat: An anatomical study using wheatgerm 
    agglutinin conjugated to horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Brain Res. 2782.40-244.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Phillips, C.G., T.P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">Powell, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">Wiesendanger (1971) Projection from low-threshold muscle 
    afferents of hand and forearm to area 3a of baboon s cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">(Lond). 217:419-446.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Poggio, G.F., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Mountcastle (1960) A study of the functional 
    contributions of the lemmscal and spinothalamic systems to somatic 
    sensibility.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Bull.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Johns Hopkins Hosp. 106226-316.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Poggio, G.F., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Mountcastle (1963) The functional trobassal thalamic 
    neurons studied in unanesthetized rophysiol. 26,775-806.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Powell, T.P.S., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Mountcastle (1959) Some aspects of the functional 
    organization of the cortex of the post-central gyrus of the monkey: 
    A correlation of findings obtained in a single unit analysis with 
    cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">Bull.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Johns Hopkins Hosp. 105133-162.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Purpura, D.P., and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">Yahr (eds) (1966) The Thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">London: Columbia University Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Ranson, S.W. (1943) The Anatomy of the Saunders.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Rexed, B. (1952) The cytoarchitectonic cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Neurol. 96t415-495.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Rexed, B. (1954) A cytoarchitectonic atlas Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Neurol. 100:297-379.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">Rothmann, M. (1904-5) iiber kombinierte Auschaltung 
    centripetaler tungshahnen im Riickenmark.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Berlin: Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Gesellsch., no.13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">Rustioni, A. (1973) Non-primary afferents to the nucleus 
    gracilis from the lumbar cord of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Brain Res. 51:81-95.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Rustioni, A. (1974) Non-primary afferents to the cuneate 
    lumbar cord of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">Brain Res. 75247-259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Rustioni, A., and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Kaufman (1977) Identification of cells of origin of 
    non-primary afferents to the dorsal column nuclei of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Brain Res. 27.1-14.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Scheibel, M.E., and A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">Scheibel(1966) Patterns of organization in specific and 
    nonspecific thalamic fields.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">In D.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Purpura and M.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Yahr (eds): The Thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">New York and London: Columbia Univ.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Press, pp. 1346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Schroeder, D.M., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Jane (1971) Projection of dorsal column and spinal cord 
    to brainstem and thalamus in the tree shrew, glis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Neurol. 142t309-350.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Schroeder, D.M., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Jane (1971) Projection of dorsal column nuclei and 
    spinal cord to brainstem and thalamus in the tree shrew, Tupia 
    glis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Neurol. 142309-350.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">Schvarcz, J.R. (1977) Functional exploration of the 
    tion.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Acta Neurochirurg.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Suppl. 24t179-185.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Schvarcz, J.R. (1978) Spinal cord stereotactic 
    techniques re trigeminal nucleotomy and extralemniscal 
    myelotomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">Appl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Neurophysiol. 41r99112.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Smith, M.C. (1976) Retrograde cell changes in human 
    spinal cord after anterolateral cordotomies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Location and identification after different periods of 
    survival.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">In J.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Bonica and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">Albe-Fessard (eds): Advances in Pain Research and 
    Therapy, vol 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">New York: Raven Press. pp. 9198.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Snow, P.J., P.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Rose, and A.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Brown (1976) Tracing axons and axon collaterals of 
    spinal neurons using intracellular injection of horseradish 
    peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">Science 191:312-313.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Spiller, W.G. (1905) The location within the spinal cord 
    of fibres for temperature and pain sensation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Nerv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">Ment.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Dis. 32:318-320.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Trevino, D.L. (1976) The origin and projections of a 
    spinal nociceptive and thermoreciptive pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Zotterman (ed): Sensory Functions of the Skin in 
    Primates, With Special Reference to Man.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Oxford: Pergamon Press, pp. 367-377.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">Trevino, D.L., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Carstens (1975a) Confirmation of the location of 
    spinothalamic neurons in the cat and monkey by the retrograde 
    transport of HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Brain Res. 9:177-182.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Trevino, D.L., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Carstens (1975b) Location of the cells of origin of the 
    spinothalamic tract in the cat and rhesus monkey as determined by 
    the retrograde transport of HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Rec. 181:494-495.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">Trevino, D.L., R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Maunz, R.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">Bryan, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Willis (1972) Location of cells of origin of the 
    spinothalamic tract in the lumbar enlargment of cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Neurol. 34:64-77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Trevino, D.L., J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Coulter, and W.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">Willis (1973) Location of cells of origin of 
    spinothalamic tract in lumbar enlargement of the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Neurophysiol. 36:750-761.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Voris, H.C. (1951) Ipsilateral sensory loss following 
    cordotomy: A report of a case.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">Neurol Psychiatr. 65:95-96.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Wall, P.D. (1978) The gate control theory of pain 
    mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">A reexmination and restatement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Brain I01:1-18.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Wall, P.D., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Dubner (1972) Somatosensory pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Ann.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Neurophysiology 34:315-336.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">White, J.C., and W.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Sweet (1969) Pain and the neurosurgeon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Springfield: Thomas.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Wiherg, M., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Blomqvist (1984) The spinomesencephalic tract in the 
    cat: Its cells of origin and termination pattern as demonstrated by 
    the intraaxonal transport method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Brain Res. 291:l-18.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">Willis, W.D., and R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Coggeshall(1978) Sensory Mechanisms of the Spinal 
    Cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">New York: Plenum Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Willis, W.D., R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Leonard, and D.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">Kenshalo Jr. (1978) Spinothalamic tract neurons in the 
    substantia gelatinosa.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Science 202986-988.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Willis, W.D., D.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">Kenshalo Jr., and R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Leonard (1979) The cells of origin of the spinothalamic 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Neurol. 188543-574.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Zemlan, F.P., C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">Leonard, L-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Kow, and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">F faff (1978) Ascending tracts of the lateral columns of 
    the rat spinal cord: A study using the silver impregnation and HRP 
    techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Neurol. 62298-334.</S>
  </References>

</File>

