<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Parasagittal Organization of the Rat Cerebellar Cortex: Direct 
  Correlation Between Antigenic Purkinje Cell Bands Revealed by mabQll3 
  and the Organization of the Olivocerebellar Projection</Title>

  <Authors>CLAUDE GRAVEL, LEONARD M. EISENMAN, RACHEL SASSEVILLE, AND 
  RICHARD HAWKES</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The Purkinje cells of the cerebellar cortex and the 
    cortical afferent and efferent projections are organized into 
    parallel parasagittal zones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The parasagittal organization is clearly revealed by 
    immunocytochemistry with a monoclonal antibody, mabQ113.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The mabQl13 antigen is confined to a subset of Purkinje 
    cells that are clustered together to form an elaborate, highly 
    reproducible pattern of bands and patches, interspersed with 
    similar mabQ113 - regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The mabQ113 + territories have been classified into seven 
    parasagittal bands (P1 +-P7 +) in each hemicerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The degree of correspondence between the compartments 
    revealed by the anterograde labeling of the olivocerebellar 
    projection and by mabQ113 immunocytochemistry has been explored in 
    the adult rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Horseradish peroxide-wheat germ agglutinin conjugate was 
    injected as an anterograde tracer into the inferior olivary 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">When the injection site did not encompass all the olive, 
    an incomplete, patchy labeling of the molecular layer was seen in 
    the cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Labeled zones of the molecular Iaycr were interrupted by 
    unIabeled regions to give a pattern of parasagittal cortical 
    bands.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The positions of these bands were compared with the 
    distribution of lhe niabQll3 + antigenic bands as seen on the two 
    adjacent sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Labeled climbing fibers were found to terminate on both 
    mabQll3 + and mabQ113 - Purkinje cell zones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The mabQl13 clmabQ113 - boundaries and the bands of 
    climbing fibers seen by using the anterogade tracer typically 
    coincide.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The one consistent exception is the midline band of 
    mabQ113 + Purkinje cells, P1+.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The normal olivocerebellar projection is exclusively 
    contralateral and the climbing fiber projection to the paramedian 
    vermis splits PI + down the middle, implying that it consists of 
    two adjacent mabQ113+ bands not separated by mabQll3 -territory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">It is likely that the climbing fiber projection to the 
    cerebellar cortex and the distribution of the two Purkinje cell 
    phenotypes share a common compartmental organization.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">robiologie, Pavillon Notre-Dame, 2075 Ave de Vitre, 
    Quebec, P.Q., Canada GlJ 124.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The mammalian cerebeller cortex is organized into 
    parasagittal zones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">This proposal is supported by more than forty years of 
    research, based at first on anatomical and electrophysiological 
    methods, and bolstered more recently by histochemistry and 
    immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">A parasagittal zonation was shown first for the Purkinje 
    cell efferent projection to the cerebellar nuclei and the lateral 
    vestibular nuclei (eg., Jansen and Brodal, &apos;40,&apos;42; 
    Chambers and Sprague, &apos;55a,b; Courville and Diakiw, &apos;76; 
    Voogd and Bigare, &apos;80; Haines et al., &apos;82), and 
    subsequently, a similar afferent parcellation was shown to be 
    present in some mossy fiber pathways (Voogd, &apos;69; Scheibel, 
    &apos;77; Chan-Palay et al., &apos;77; Yaginuma and Matsushita, 
    &apos;86) and in the climbing fiber projection from the inferior 
    olives (Voogd, &apos;64,&apos;67,&apos;69; Oscarsson, 
    &apos;69,&apos;80; Oscarsson and Sjolund, &apos;77; Van Gilder and 
    O&apos;Leary, &apos;70; Armstrong et al., &apos;74,&apos;82; 
    Groenewegen and Voogd, &apos;77; Groenewegen et al., &apos;79; 
    Courville, &apos;75; Courville and Faraco-Cantin, &apos;78; Brodal 
    et al., &apos;75; Brodal, &apos;76,&apos;80; Beyerl et al., 
    &apos;82; Eisenman, &apos;81,&apos;84; Eisenman et al., 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">&quot;he neurons of the inferior olivary complex (IOC) 
    are the sole source of climbing fibers to the cerebellar cortex and 
    all regions receive climbing fiber input (Desclin, &apos;74; 
    Courville and Faraco-Cantin, &apos;78; Armstrong et al., &apos;82; 
    Sotelo et al., &apos;84; Blatt and Eisenman, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In the rat, incomplete filling of an inferior olive with 
    anterograde tracer results in the labeling of parasagittally 
    organized bands of climbing fibers in the molecular layer of the 
    contralateral cerebellar cortex (Armstrong et al., &apos;82; 
    Campbell and Armstrong, &apos;83, Sotelo et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Molecular correlates of a parasagittal organization 
    within the cerebellar cortex have also been demonstrated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Scott (&apos;63,&apos;64) and others (e.g., Marani, ,821, 
    by using histochemical techniques, localized the enzyme 
    5&apos;-nucleotidase to parasagittal bands in the molecular layer 
    of the mouse and rat cerebellar cortex (but not in the cat; see 
    Marani and Voogd, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">Parasagittal heterogeneity of acetylcholinesterase 
    activity has also been demonstrated histochemically in the 
    cerebellar cortex of young and adult cats (Ramon-Moliner, &apos;72; 
    Marani and Voogd, &apos;77; Marani, &apos;82; Brown and Graybiel, 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The staining is concentrated in the molecular layer and 
    appears as positive and negative parasagittal zones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Although this staining pattern is not found in the rat 
    and mouse, preliminary evidence suggests that a similar 
    acetylcholinesterase segregation can be demonstrated in the monkey 
    (Ingram et al., 85; Hess and Voogd, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">This pattern may be related to the differential 
    acetylcholinesterase staining pattern demonstrated in the IOC 
    (Marani et al., &apos;77).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Immunohistochemical methods have also been brought to 
    bear on the question of cerebellar heterogeneity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">By using antibodies against cysteine-sulfinic acid 
    decarboxylase, Chan-Palay et al. (&apos;82) demonstrated 
    differential immunostaining of Purkinje, stellate, basket, and 
    Eolgi cells and their processes in the rat, rabbit, and mouse.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The immunoreactive cells form parasagittal microzones 
    separated by nonimmunoreactive interzones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Antigenic heterogeneity in the Purkinje cell population 
    is also seen when the rat, mouse, or monkey tissue is processed 
    with an antibody raised against synthetic porcine motilin 
    (Chan-Palay et al., &apos;81; Nilaver et al., &apos;82) and has 
    also been reported for an antibody raised against glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase (ChanPalay et al., &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Combined used of these antibodies has shown on simple 
    segregation of epitopes, some Purkinje cells reacting only with one 
    or other antibody, some reacting with both, and yet others reacting 
    with neither.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">More recently, Ingram et al. (&apos;85) described the 
    monoclonal antibody B1 that revealed broad bands of positively and 
    negatively reactive Purkinje cells in the monkey cerebellar 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Some other cerebellar neurons also bear the epitope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The B1 bands do not seem to codistribute with the 
    motilin, glutamic acid decarboxylase, or taurine bands, nor do they 
    correspond to the acetylcholinesterase staining pattern (Ingram et 
    al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Another, probably different, pattern of bands and patches 
    is revealed by monoclonal antibody mabQ155 (Hawkes et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">MabQ155 recognizes an epitope associated with all the 
    major synaptic types of the rat and mouse cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">Despite its broad cellular distribution in the mouse 
    cerebellar cortex, mabQ 155-immunocytochemistry reveals 
    parasagittal zones of alternating high and low reactivity that 
    include both the granular layer and the molecular layer.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Together, these studies are highly suggestive of 
    widespread chemical heterogeneity in the cerebellar cortex, 
    particularly among the Purkinje cell population.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Perhaps the clearest demonstration of this is seen with 
    the monoclonal antibody mabQ113 (Hawkes et al., &apos;85; Plioplys 
    et al., &apos;85; Hawkes and Leclerc, &apos;86,&apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">The distribution of the mabQll3 epitope in the cerebellar 
    cortex is intriguing because it is strictly confined to a subset of 
    Purkinje cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Immunoreactivity is found throughout the cytoplasm of the 
    immunopositive cells, including dendritic spines and dendrites, the 
    somata, the axons, and the axon collaterals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Antigen-bearing Purkinje cells are arranged into highly 
    symmetrical parasagittal bands extending throughout the 
    anteroposterior extent of the cerebellum in a pattern reproducible 
    from animal to animal (Hawkes et al., &apos;85; Hawkes and Leclerc, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">These data provide multiple independent maps of 
    cerebellar organization, but few attempts have been made to 
    compare, collate, and synthesize the schemata obtained by using 
    different experimental methods (e.g., Hess and Voogd, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">In particular, the question remains open as to whether 
    the parasagittal organization of different afferent fibers and of 
    various intrinsic biochemical markers reflects a common structural 
    plan, or whether each is a unique representation in its own 
    right.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">In addition to the difficulty inherent in comparing data 
    collected by using different methodologies, a second problem is 
    that these data have been collected in many different species, thus 
    further confounding attempts at synthesis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">To address this problem, in this paper we compare the 
    band pattern produced in the cerebellar cortex following injection 
    of wheat germ agglutinin-horseradish peroxidase complex CWGA-HRP) 
    into the inferior olive with the immunocytochemical staining 
    pattern obtained with the mabQll3 antibody.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Some of these results appeared previously in abstract 
    form (Gravel et al., &apos;86).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s48">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s49">Antemgrade labeling with 
    wheat germ agglutininhorseradish peroxidase conjugate</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Adult Sprague Dawley rats were used in all 
    experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">The animals were anesthetized with an intramuscular 
    injection of ketamine hydrochloride (45 mgkg) containing 1% 
    acepromazine.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Microinjections of WGA-HRP conjugate were placed into the 
    IOC via a ventral retropharyngeal a p proach.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Tracer was injected via a 1-pl Hamilton syringe to which 
    a glass micropipette (tip diameter 50-75 pm} was attached.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">After a survival time of 24 hours, the animal was 
    sacrificed with an overdose of Nembutal and perfused through the 
    heart with saline followed by a fixative containing 4% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.2% glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer (pH 
    7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Immediately after perfusion the brain was removed, 
    postfixed for a few hours in the formaldehyde alone, and then 
    placed in buffer overnight at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The next day the brain was shipped by express mail from 
    Philadelphia to Quebec for processing to reveal the anterograde 
    transport of tracer and the bands of antigenic Purkinje cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s57">Histochemistry and 
    immunocytochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Horizontal or frontal sections of cerebellum were cut at 
    50 pm on a freezing-stage microtome.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Every third section was incubated overnight at room 
    temperature with constant agitation in mabQll3-containing culture 
    medium diluted 1:32 in 10% decomplemented normal horse serum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Then, after three 10-minute rinses in a 0.1 M 
    phosphatebuffered 0.9% saline solution (PBS), the sections were 
    incubated for 2 hours in peroxidase-conjugated rabbit antimouse 
    immunoglobulins (Dako, Denmark) diluted 1:lOO in 10% normal horse 
    serum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Following 3 additional rinses in PBS, the reaction sites 
    were revealed by using 4-chloro-lnaphthol as chromogen (Hawkes et 
    al., &apos;82) and the sections mounted on slides in a 90% 
    glycerol, 10% PBS solution.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The anterogradely transported peroxidase activity is too 
    weak to be revealed with 4-chloro-1-naphthol, and thus there is no 
    confusion between Purkinje cell immunoreactivity and climbing fiber 
    labeling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The other sections were processed for peroxidase 
    histochemistry with tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) as the chromogen 
    (Mesulam, &apos;821, then dehydrated through graded ethanol 
    solutions and mounted in Permount (Fisher, Inc.).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Transverse sections of the brainstem were cut at 50 pm 
    between the caudal limit of the pons and the rostra1 limit of the 
    IOC (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Every third section was collected, the injection site was 
    revealed by using tetramethylbenzidine, and the sections 
    counterstained with either neutral red or cresyl violet.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="25" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s66">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s67">MabQ113 
    immunocytochemical staining</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">On Western blots of the rat cerebellar cortex, monoclonal 
    antibody Q113 (mabQ113) recognizes an epitope restricted to a 
    single polypeptide of apparent molecular weight 120 Kdaltons 
    (Hawkes et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The laminar distribution of the mabQ113 epitope in 
    <labelingLocation>the cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> as 
    revealed by peroxidase immunocytochemistry is illustrated in Figure 
    1A , B .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Peroxidase reaction product is confined exclusively to 
    <labelingLocation>the Purkinje cells</labelingLocation>, where it 
    is distributed throughout the cell from the axon and axon 
    collaterals to the somata, the dendrites, and the dendritic 
    spines.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71"><labelingDescription>No other cell 
    types</labelingDescription> in the cerebcllum, neuronal or glial, 
    are immunoreactive (for other brain regions, see Plioplys and 
    Hawkes, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Details of the subcellular distribution will be presented 
    elsewhere (Leclerc et al., in preparation).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The most interesting feature of the mabQ113 epitope is 
    its restricted distribution among the Purkinje cell population; the 
    epitope is expressed in only a subset, as a whole about one-third, 
    of the cells (Hawkes and Leclerc, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The immunoreactive Purkinje cells ( mabQl13 + ) are 
    clustered together to form a family of parasagittal bands running 
    roughly rostrocaudally throughout <labelingLocation>the cerebellar 
    cortex</labelingLocation> , interposed by similar bands of 
    mabQll3cells ( Fig . 2A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">The detailed description of the immunocytochemical 
    banding pattern is provided elsewhere (Hawkes and Leclerc, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">Briefly, the parasagittal zonation revealed by mabQ113 is 
    symmetrical about the midline and is reproducible from individual 
    to individual both in the number and general arrangement of the 
    bands and in much of the fine detail.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">By calling bands of mabQ113 + cells P + and mabQ113 - 
    cells P-, we have defined a midline band (P1+) and six or seven 
    lateral P+ bands on each side (P2+ to P7 +(P8 + ); Fig. 2B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">In the vermis the bands ( P1 + , P2 + , P3 + ) are 
    continuous from lobule to lobule .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">In general , the bands tend to become weaker and less 
    well defined as they pass into the anterior lobe .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Careful observation of the midline P1 + band reveals that 
    the axons issuing from the mabQll3 + Purkinje cells segregate into 
    two fascicles divided by the anatomical midline , and enter 
    uncrossed in the white matter within the left and right sides of 
    the cerebellum , respectively ( Fig . 3A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">On this basis, the P1+ band is best described as two 
    parallel, confluent P+ bands, not separated by a negative (P-) 
    Purkinje cell zone.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">The mabQ113 + staining in <labelingLocation>the 
    hemispheres</labelingLocation> is also consistent with a rather 
    convoluted parasagittal zonation ( P4 + , P5 i , P6 + , P7 + ) , 
    but a checkerboard arrangement of Purkinje cell clusters is at 
    least as plausible .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The immunoreactivity diminishes in <labelingLocation>the 
    more lateral regions of the hemispheres</labelingLocation> , making 
    the presence of an extreme lateral P8 + uncertain .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Additional subbands of P4 + and P5 + ( called P4b + and 
    P5a + , respectively ) are seen in <labelingLocation>the crus 
    2</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">In addition to these well-ordered and highly reproducible 
    bands or mabQ113 + cells, satellite bands are also common; these 
    are defined as narrow, positively immunoreactive bands of Purkinje 
    cells, often only one cell in width, lying adjacent to one of the 
    major bands (Fig. 3B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">In contrast to the P+ bands, satellite bands are not 
    reproducible from individual to individual nor are they necessarily 
    bilaterally symmetrical.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">They do, however, extend substantially in the 
    dorsoventral plane and thus are not simply occasional mabQ113s 
    Purkinje cells isolated within mabQ113territory.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">These satellite bands, together with possible variations 
    in the depth and tilt of the plane of section and with differences 
    in the extent of foliation, require that olivocerebellar projection 
    bands and the mabQ113 imrnunocytochemical banding pattern be 
    compared directly in each individual instead of referring to an 
    idealized map of the epitope distribution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s89">
    <labelingDescription>Anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> of 
    the olivocerebellar projection</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90"><exptLabel>Either large ( nominally 30 nl ) or small ( 
      nominally 10 nl ) injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> conjugate were placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the right JOC</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      of experimental animals via a retropharyngeal approach ( Chan - 
      Palay et al . , 77 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">Typically , small injections resulted in 
      <labelingDescription>a labeling</labelingDescription> of olivary 
      cells restricted mainly to the side of the injection , whereas 
      labeling from a large injection spans <injectionLocation>the two 
      IOC</injectionLocation> to varying extents .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">Figure 4A , B shows portions of typical injection sites 
      , photographed at a similar rostrocaudal level ( approximately 13 
      mm caudal from the bregma ; Paxinos and Watson , 82 ) , resulting 
      from small ( Fig . 4A ) or large ( Fig . 4B ) tracer injections 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">It can be seen that thc peroxidase reaction product is 
      not restricted to <injectionLocation>the IOC</injectionLocation> 
      but also extends into <injectionSpread>adjacent 
      regions</injectionSpread>  , principally <injectionSpread>the 
      reticular formation</injectionSpread> dorsomedially and 
      dorsolaterally and <injectionSpread>the 
      pyramids</injectionSpread> ventromedially .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">The use of TMB may result in the overestimation of the 
      injection site due to the difference between virtual and 
      effective injection sites (Mesulam, 82).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">Axons from the labeled neurons of one IOC cross the 
      olivary commissure and spread through <labelingLocation>the 
      contralateral IOC</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">They then form a thin bundle that follows a rostral and 
      dorsal path and ascends to <labelingLocation>the cerebellum via 
      the inferior cerebellar peduncle</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">In <labelingLocation>the cerebellum</labelingLocation> 
      , they <labelingModifier>terminate</labelingModifier> as climbing 
      fibers upon <labelingLocation>the Purkinje cell primary 
      dendrites</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>Labeled collateral 
      axons</labelingDescription> are also seen entering 
      <labelingLocation>the cerebellar nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Thus , the uptake and subsequent anterograde transport 
      of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> by olivary cells 
      result in the accumulation of tracer in <labelingLocation>the 
      molecular layer of the cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> , and 
      to a lesser extent also in <labelingLocation>the cerebellar 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">Examination of the sections at higher magnification 
    reveals that the labeling consists of closely spaced, discrete 
    lines of TMB crystals running along the Purkinje cell dendritic 
    arbors from the Purkinje cell layer toward the pial surface (Fig. 
    5).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">It should be emphasized here that it is not the present 
    intention to analyze the detailed topography of the olivocerebellar 
    prqjectioln with respect to Purkinje cell compartmentation.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Rather, we wish to establish whether such a comparison 
    is at all worthwhile.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">If the Purkinje cell distribution and the 
    olivocerebellar projection are unlinked, a topographical comparison 
    may be of little value-we know already that both share broadly 
    similar organizations.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">On the other hand, if the olivocerebellar projection and 
    the Purkinje cell conipartments share a common parasagittal ground 
    plan-and it is argued below that this is indeed the case-then this 
    has important functional and developmental implications.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">With this in mind , <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> was injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    IOC</injectionLocation></exptLabel> in order to generate bands of 
    <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled climbing 
    fibers</labelingDescription> that could be compared with the 
    mabQ113 + Purkinje cell distribution .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">Relatively large injection sites were employed that 
    reliahly produce labeled bands of <labelingDescription>climbing 
    fibers</labelingDescription> but that are largely unsuitable for 
    determining the details of the topography .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Virtual injection sites were studied in neutral red 
    counterstained sections and the distribution of peroxidase activity 
    within the IOC was mapped onto the rat IOC schema of Gwyn et al. 
    ( 77).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Injection sites for the animals described explicitly in 
    the results are described below.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">Case No . 22% <exptLabel>The center of the injection 
    site in rat no . 227 is situated in <injectionLocation>the caudal 
    portion of the right MAO</injectionLocation> </exptLabel> , about 
    600 km from the caudal pole of the complex, where the dorsal cap ( 
    dc ) separates from the main portion of the medial accessory olive 
    ( MAO ) ( Fig . 6 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s110">At around this level , the 
    virtual injection site is very large and reaction product is found 
    throughout the right side and most of the left side of the 10.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">Only <labelingLocation>the most lateral portion of the 
    left MA0</labelingLocation> is completely 
    <labelingDescription>devoid of TMB 
    deposits</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s112">The extent of the territory 
    covered by reaction product narrows and becomes restricted to the 
    more medial regions more rostrally , but it still 
    <injectionLocation>covers parts of the right and left olives up to 
    the most rostral extent of the principal olive ( PO ) 
    </injectionLocation> at about 2,400 km from the caudal pole .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">Consistent with the large virtual injection site , the 
    staining in <labelingLocation>the cerebellar 
    cortex</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>extensive and 
    bilateral</labelingDescription> , and reaction product is present 
    throughout <labelingLocation>the whole dorsoventral extent of the 
    cerebellum ( the vermis</labelingLocation> is illustrated ; see 
    Figs . 8,9,10 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s114">The hemicerebellum 
    contralateral to the injection site is more completely and 
    <labelingDescription>more heavily labeled</labelingDescription> 
    than its ipsilateral counterpart .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s115">However 
    , both sides still show regions where reaction product is 
    <labelingDescription>scarce or absent</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">For example , in <labelingLocation>the 
    vermis</labelingLocation> a clearcut boundary in staining intensity 
    is seen running rostrocaudally through <labelingLocation>all 
    lobules</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s117">This boundary bisects the 
    vermis and is presumed to be the anatomical midline on the basis of 
    both its central position and its exact alignment with the raphe 
    frequently seen medially in or between lobules VIII to X.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">Such a midline demarcation was consistently observed in 
    all experimental animals ( except for animal no . 234, see below ) 
    in which the virtual injection site spanned the rnidline .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">In<labelingLocation> the vermis</labelingLocation> of 
    case no . 227, there is a band that is 
    <labelingDescription>strongly labeled by anterograde 
    transport</labelingDescription> , located adjacent to the midline 
    on the right side , extending from lobule I11 to 
    <labelingLocation>the rostral face of lobules VI - 
    VII</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s120">Several less complete 
    parasagittal vermal bands, positive and negative, are also seen on 
    this same section.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s121">In the hemispheres , there 
    are also several bands or patches of various extents , seen either 
    as negative zones within an <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> - 
    reactive background or as <labelingDescription>anterograde labeled 
    climbing fibers</labelingDescription> in an otherwise unreactive 
    molecular layer .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s122">Ipsilateral (right) to the 
    injection site, <labelingLocation>the most lateral portions of crus 
    1 and crus 2</labelingLocation> are <labelingDescription>devoid of 
    reaction product</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">Case no. 228.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124"><exptLabel>The center of the injection site in animal 
    no. 228 is situated at <injectionLocation>about 1,100 pm from the 
    caudal pole of the IOC</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">The virtual injection site is very large at this level 
    and reaction product can be found in <injectionLocation>all the 
    right olive</injectionLocation> , in <injectionLocation>the left 
    MAO , and the medial fourth of the left DAO</injectionLocation> ( 
    Fig . 6 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s126">TMB deposits can be seen 
    throughout <labelingLocation>the rostrocaudal extent of the right 
    olive</labelingLocation> but become scarcer in 
    <labelingLocation>the more lateral regions</labelingLocation> as 
    one approaches the rostral limit of the complex .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s127">However 
    , the presence of <labelingDescription>weakly labeled 
    stretches</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>molecular 
    layer in the left half of the cerebellum</labelingLocation> ( see 
    Fig . 9B ) suggests that not all olivary cells froin the right 
    olive have tansported the tracer .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s128">Caudally 
    in <labelingLocation>the left olive</labelingLocation> , the 
    staining is restricted to more medial regions and in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal one - fifth of the 
    MAO</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>no reaction 
    product</labelingDescription> is observed over 
    <labelingLocation>subnucleus a</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129">Rostrally , reaction product is present in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial fourth of the DAO , the medial half of 
    the PO , and throughout the MAO</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s130">On 
    horizontal sections , <labelingDescription>stained climbing 
    fibers</labelingDescription> are seen over <labelingLocation>the 
    whole dorsoventral extent of the cerebellum</labelingLocation> ; 
    the staining is bilateral but more extensive in 
    <labelingLocation>the left ( contralateral ) 
    side</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s131">In <labelingLocation>the more 
    dorsal regions</labelingLocation> , almost of <labelingLocation>the 
    cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> contains reaction product , 
    but a few bands of relatively weaker intensity are visible on both 
    sides .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s132">Additional weakly labeled 
    zones appear more ventrally , especially in <labelingLocation>the 
    anterior lobe</labelingLocation> , and 5 mm interaural ( Paxinos 
    and Watson , &apos; 82 ) only parts of <labelingLocation>crus 
    I1</labelingLocation> show staining in <labelingLocation>the right 
    hemisphere</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Case no. 234.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">In animal no . 234, <exptLabel>the injection site is 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the rostral half of the right 
    olive</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , at about 200 pm from the 
    caudal pole of the complex ( Fig . 6 ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s135">Again , 
    the virtual injection site is very large at this level and 
    <labelingLocation>encompasses all of the right 
    olive</labelingLocation> and most of the left one , with only 
    <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the lateral half of the 
    DAO</injectionSpread> completely free of TMB deposils .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">Although reaction product is scarcer toward the caudal 
    pole , deposits are still found <injectionSpread>over all the right 
    olive</injectionSpread> and <injectionSpread>most of the left 
    one</injectionSpread> <labelingModifier>save</labelingModifier> 
    <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the lateral DAO</injectionSpread> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">In <labelingLocation>the cerebellar 
    cortex</labelingLocation> , the staining is bilateral and 
    <labelingLocation>covers most of the dorsoventral extent of the 
    cerebellum</labelingLocation> , but is much more extensive in 
    <labelingLocation>the anterior lobe</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">Parasagittal bands of weak and strong reactivities are 
    found in both sides (see Fig. 9C).</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s139">The 
    staining is <labelingDescription>more 
    extensive</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    hemispheres ( especially the left one )</labelingLocation> than in 
    <labelingLocation>the vermis</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">Case no. 274.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141"><exptLabel>The center of the injection through 
    <injectionLocation>the IOC</injectionLocation> of rat no . 274 is 
    situated in <injectionLocation>the right 
    PO</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , at the level in the frontal 
    plane at which it reaches its maximum mediolateral extent , about 
    2,000 pm from the caudal pole of the complex ( Fig . 7 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">At this level , reaction product is also found in 
    <labelingLocation>the MAO , the dorsomedial cell column ( dmcc ) , 
    and the medial portion of the DAO</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">There is <labelingDescription>no reaction product in any 
    subdivision</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the left 
    olive</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s144">In <labelingLocation>the 
    molecular layer of the cerebellum</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>climbing fiber labeling</labelingDescription> 
    is strictly contralateral to the injection site , and takes the 
    form of patches or bands in <labelingLocation>crus 1 and crus 2 of 
    the left hemisphere</labelingLocation> ( for illustrated details , 
    see Fig . 13 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s145"><labelingDescription>The 
    molecular layer labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> extends 
    rostrocaudally over about 1,600 Fm .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146"><labelingLocation>The vermis</labelingLocation> is 
    <labelingDescription>unlabeled</labelingDescription>.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s147">
    Case rw. 275.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s148">
      In animal no . 275, <exptLabel>the injection site is centered at 
      the same rostrocaudal level as for animal no . 274 , that is , in 
      <injectionLocation>the right 
      olive</injectionLocation></exptLabel>  at about 2,000 pm from the 
      caudal pole of the complex .</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s149">
      However , the virtual injection site is larger in this case and 
      encroaches into <injectionSpread>the left olive</injectionSpread> 
      ( Fig . 5 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s150">
      At this level , reaction product is found over most of the right 
      olive with only the most lateral third of the DAO free of 
      reaction product , and in <injectionLocation>the left 
      olive</injectionLocation> covers <injectionLocation>most of the 
      MAO , the dmcc , and a small medial portion of the 
      PO</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s151">
      The reactive site becomes narrower caudally , and from about 
      1,100 pm from the caudal pole no reaction product is found in any 
      subdivision of the left olive .</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s152">
      In <injectionSpread>the right olive</injectionSpread> , the 
      virtual injection site becomes restricted to <injectionSpread>the 
      lateral portion of the MA0 and medial portion of 
      DAO</injectionSpread> in the caudal half of the complex .</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s153">
      From about 600 pm from the caudal pole, the olive is free of 
      reaction product.</S>
      <S avgH="42" class="results.body" format="Arial-BoldMT" id="s154">
      Rostrally , TMB deposits are found <injectionLocation>over most 
      of the right olive</injectionLocation> and in 228 - A0 A</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156">t.he MA0 and dmcc of the left olive.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157">In <labelingLocation>the cerebellar 
      cortex</labelingLocation> , <labelingLocation>the 
      vermis</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>almost devoid 
      of reaction product and labeled climbing fiber bands or patches 
      </labelingDescription>appear in <labelingLocation>the paravermal 
      area</labelingLocation> and hemispheres on both sides ( see Fig . 
      12 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">The staining is <labelingDescription>more 
      intense</labelingDescription> on the left side and is mainly 
      concentrated in <labelingLocation>crus I1 and paramedian 
      lobules</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Variations in the location and size of the injection 
    sites are by far the most important contributor to interindividual 
    differences when comparing the olivocerebellar banding pattern 
    following tracer injections in the IOC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">Clearly, however, the accuracy of comparisons of this 
    kind is inherently limited in the absence of reproducible (or 
    better, individualized) landmarks, especially at the level of the 
    cerebellar cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Figure 9A - C shows the pattern of 
    <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled climbing 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in horizontal sections from 
    <labelingLocation>the posterior vermis ( lobules VIII - IX 
    )</labelingLocation> of 3 different animals that had received 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> tracer injections in 
    <labelingLocation>the IOC</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">In all 3, the virtual injection site included parts of 
    both olives but is centered at a differcnt rostrocaudal level in 
    the IOC (shown in Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">Correspondingly, <labelingDescription>the cortical 
    staining</labelingDescription> is bilateral and takcs the form of 
    parasagittal bands distributed about the midline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">The extent of labeling in <labelingLocation>the 
    molecular layer</labelingLocation> varies from case to case, with 
    animal no. 234 (Fig. 9A) and animal no, 227 (Fig. 9C) being the 
    least and most extensively labeled, respectively, and animal no. 
    228 (Fig. 9B) being intermediate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Animal no. 227 received the most caudal injection in the 
    IOC and animal no. 234 the most rostral one (Fig. 6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">Thus , the anterograde labeling in the cerebellum 
    supports previous results ( Eisenman &apos; 81, &apos; 84 ) showing 
    that lobules VIII and IX receive climbing fibers arising mainly 
    from the caudal half of the IOC .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">In animal no . 227, the almost complete staining of the 
    contralateral vermis of lobules VIII and IX ( at the left in Fig . 
    9 ) suggests that complete filling of the molecular layer will 
    occur given a large enough injection in the corresponding olive 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">This is in accordance with several previous studies 
    (Desclin, &apos;74; Courville and Faraco-Cantin, &apos;78; 
    Armstrong et al., &apos;82; Blatt and Eisenman, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Crossing the midline from left to right, in all 3 
    animals there is first a weakly labeled zone and then a strongly 
    labeled one, the latter at about 200-300 bm from the midline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Despite the similarities in the staining patterns, 
    comparison with adjacent sections reacted for the mabQ113 antigen 
    revealed that the strongly labeled ipsilateral zones do not 
    correspond to the a0 same mabQl13 territory in all 3 cases: in 
    animal no. 234 the labeled band is congruent with the right P 1 
    territory ~ (this point is emphasized in Fig. 111, but in animals 
    nos. 227 and 228, it corresponds to the P2+ territory (see also 
    Fig. 10).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">This situation exemplifies thc fact that interindividual 
    comparisons of olivocerebellar projection are difficult when based 
    solely on planimetric data collected from <labelingLocation>the 
    cerebellar cortex</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">For this reason, all subsequent cases shown in this 
    paper concern comparisons of the anterograde pattern of 
    olivocerebellar projection with the mabQl13 staining pattern 
    between closely spaced sections (100 pn or less) taken from the 
    same animal.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s173">Comparison of 
    olivocerebellar projection zones with</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s174">rnabQ113 
    imrnunohistochernical compartmentalization</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">Given that all regions of the cerebellar cortex are 
    innervated by climbing fibers derived from the IOCs ( Desclin , 
    &apos; 74 ; Courville and Faraco - Cantin , &apos; 74 ; Blatt and 
    Eisenman , &apos; 85 ) , differential accumulation of &apos; the 
    anterograde tracer in two adjacent zones of the cerebellar cortex 
    is interpreted as resulting from the differential uptake of tracer 
    by the groups of olivary cells projecting to each cortical zone 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">This will occur when the projecting neurons in the olive 
    are situated at unequal distances from the center of the injection 
    site .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Conversely, adjacent regions of the cerebellar cortex 
    will accumulate similar levels of tracer if the olivary regions 
    projecting to them are contiguous (or if the whole TOC is saturated 
    with tracer).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Consequently, adjacent zones of the cerebellar cortex 
    displaying an abrupt change in the level of the tracer are 
    interpreted as being innervated by noncontiguous olivary zones.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">However, no similar conclusions can be drawn about the 
    relative locations of olivary groups projecting to similarly 
    stained cortical regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Therefore , when comparing the banding pattern resulting 
    from an olivary injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> with the banding pattern revealed 
    immunocytochemically by mabQ113, the abrupt transitions observed in 
    the tracer accumulation in <labelingLocation>the molecular layer of 
    the cortex</labelingLocation> have been considered as indicative of 
    the organization of the olivocerebellar projection , and this 
    organization has been compared with the transition zones between 
    mabQllS + and <labelingDescription>mabQ113Pur - kinje 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the adjacent 
    sections</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">Figure 10A , B shows adjacent horizontal sections of 
    lobules VIII and IX of animal no . 227 revealed for 
    <labelingDescription>either anterograde 
    transport</labelingDescription> of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> by using TMB ( Fig .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">lOAj, or for antigenic bands by using mabQll3 (Fig.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">IOB).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Typically , for almost all boundaries between cortical 
    regions containing high or low levels of the anterograde tracer ( 
    arrowheads in Fig . lOA ) , a corresponding transition zone between 
    mabQll3 - positive and mabQ113 - negative stretches of cerebellar 
    cortex can be found ( arrowheads in Fig .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">IOB).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">The one consistent exception to this rule concerns the 
    midline where the clear transition between high and low tracer 
    accumulation passing from the contralateral to the ipsilateral 
    cortex does not correlate with the boundary between a mabQ113+ and 
    a mabQ113zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">This is consistent with the idea, noted above, that the 
    (rnabQ113S) P1+ band that straddles the midline is in fact two 
    contiguous mabQ113 + bands, one in each hemicerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Starting in <labelingLocation>the 
    cortex</labelingLocation> contralateral to the injection site ( 
    left ) , at least two subtle transitions in the density of 
    anterograde tracer in <labelingLocation>lobule 
    VIII</labelingLocation> ( those between P1and P2 + , arrowheads ) 
    have corresponding transitions in the mabQll3 staining pattern .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">On the side ipsilateral to the injection site ( right ) 
    , the boundaries of high and low accumulation of anterograde tracer 
    in <labelingLocation>lobules VIII</labelingLocation> and IX 
    correspond to the boundaries of the P2 + band .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">Another example of concordance between the 
    olivocerebellar and antigenic zonation in <labelingLocation>the 
    vermis</labelingLocation> is shown in Figure 11A , B .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Again, in this animal (234) the boundaries of 
    olivocerebellar projection zones (Fig. 11A) correspond to the 
    similarly situated boundaries between rnabQ113 +/mabQ113zones seen 
    on a closely spaced section (Fig. 11B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">In this particular case, the anatomical midline is not 
    highlighted by a clear edge in the density of anterogradely 
    transported material, and the cortical zones that correspond to the 
    P1 + bands have accumulated only low levels of tracer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">On the left side of lobules VIII and IX , the zone of 
    high tracer accumulation delineated by arrowheads corresponds to 
    the territory of the P2 + band .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">On the right side , however , the cortical region 
    showing dense accumulation of tracer neareast the midline 
    corresponds to the territory of the P1band .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Thus, as anticipated, parasagittal bands in the 
    olivocerebellar projection can be situated in either a mabQ113 + or 
    mabQll3 zone</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">~ same correspondence between olivocerebellar and 
    antigenic zones can also be demonstrated in the cerebellar 
    hemispheres .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Figure 12A-D shows parts of the hemispheres of animal 
    no. 235 either contralateral (left panel) or ipsilateral (right 
    panel) to the injection side.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Tracer accumulation can be found in 
    <labelingLocation>the two sides ( A and C )</labelingLocation> , 
    but it is much stronger contralaterally .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">As in the vermis , most of the clear boundaries between 
    labeled and unlabeled bands in the olivocerebellar projection 
    correspond to boundaries between positive and negative mabQ113 
    zones ( I3 and D ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">In A, the most lateral transition zone between high and 
    low levels of tracer (extreme left) corresponds in B to the medial 
    edge of P5b+.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">The more medial transition zone in the olivocerebellar 
    projection pattern in A corresponds in a very precise manner to the 
    lateral border of the P4a + band .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Finally , another transition boundary in the 
    olivocerebellar projection , situated in the vermis ( extreme right 
    of A ) , corresponds to the medial border of P4a + ( Fig . 12B ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">In panel C , the arrowheads delineate a band of 
    <labelingDescription>dense anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> that is exactly congruent with the 
    P5bi band marked by arrowheads in D .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Finally , Figure 13 ( animal no . 234 ) provides a 
    second example of the correspondence between olivocerebellar and 
    antigenic zones in the hemispheres .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">The three most rostra1 edges that are indicated by 
    arrowheads in the olivocerebellar projection pattern in Figure 13A 
    match the medial boundary of the P5b + band.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">The lower thin band of high tracer accumulation marked 
    in Figure 13A corresponds to the location of the P5a + band in 
    B.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">Moreover, comparing the patterns of olivocerebellar 
    projections in Figures 12A and 13A emphasizes that striking 
    similarities are seen between hemispheres after similar anterograde 
    tracer injections in the IOC.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s209">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">MabQ113 recognizes an intracellular epitope expressed in 
    a subpopulation of Purkinje cells that are aligned in parasagittal 
    bands in the cerebellar cortex (Hawkes et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">The projection domains of various fiber afferents and 
    the efferent Purkinje cell axons are also organized into 
    parasagittally oriented zones in the cortex, so it is natural to 
    ask how many organizational maps are represented in the 
    cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">Although the Purkinje cell axons are the sole efferent 
    projection from the cerebellar cortex, there are multiple afferent 
    pathways, falling into two classes based on their modes of 
    termination: the climbing fibers synapsing directly on Purkinje 
    cells and the mossy fibers that contact the Purkinje cells 
    indirectly via the granule cells, Mossy fibers originate from very 
    diverse regions of the brain (reviewed in Bloedel and Courville, 
    &apos;81) and so bring in a wide variety of information to be 
    processed; likewise the climbing fibers, although of homogenous 
    origin, seem to convey information from different modalities to the 
    cortex and these modalities can converge on relatively restricted 
    regions of the cerebellar cortex, even if they come from widely 
    different parts of the body (reviewed in Ito, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Likewise, several studies with biochemical markers have 
    concluded that multiple, overlapping zones are represented 
    (Chan-Palay et al., &apos;81,82; Nilaver et al., &apos;82; Ingram 
    et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">In consequence, there is no a priori basis for a unique 
    organizational map of the cerebellum, and the existence of one or 
    many maps has to be assessed empirically.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">In particular, there are no studies in the rat that have 
    delineated clearly a common plan for the mossy and climbing fiber 
    afferents, or for afferents and the intrinsic molecular markers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">This task is technically complex and the problem may be 
    more easily addressed by using mabQ113 bands as a constant and 
    reproducible reference set.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">We have started to answer this question by looking at 
    the relationship between the topography of the climbing fiber 
    projection and the topography of mabQ 113 expression.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">We believe that bands are seen in the olivocerebellar 
    projection primarily because, although the projection is completely 
    filled and all Purkinje cells receive climbing fiber input, the map 
    is discontinuous so that adjacent regions of the IOC do not 
    necessarily project to adjacent regions of the cerebellar 
    cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">For example, HRP-WGA tracer studies of the 
    olivocerebellar projection to the uvula and pyramis of both the rat 
    (Eisenman, &apos;81,&apos;84; Eisenman and Goracci, &apos;83) and 
    cat (reviewed in Brodal and Kawamura, &apos;80) have shown that 
    contiguous parasagittal bands in the cerebellar cortex can receive 
    afferents from noncontiguous groups of olivary cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">In this study, we reported that the climbing fiber 
    projection from the inferior olive and the expression of the 
    mabQ113 epitope seem to respect a common compartmentation, This is 
    supported by the following observations: both patterns are arranged 
    into parasagitally organized bands or patches in the cerebellar 
    cortex; the two patterns are reproducible (to demonstrate this for 
    the climbing fiber projection pattern requires that similar 
    injections of anterograde tracer are achieved, e.g., nos. 274,275 
    in Fig, 12,13; there is a high level of concordance between the 
    cortical localization of transition zones delineating discrete 
    olivocerebellar projection territories and the location of 
    transition zones between mabQ113 + and mabQ113 - cortical 
    regions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">It remains to be determined whether every cluster of 
    mabQ113 -t and mabQll3 - Purkinje cells receives afferent input 
    from an individual, specific subgroup of olivary cells; that is, 
    are there finer subdivisions in the olivocerebellar plan than are 
    suggested by mabQ113 immunocytochemistry?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">This will be more easily addressed by combining mabQ113 
    immunocytochemistry with the retrograde mapping of the 
    olivocerebellar pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">Even though bands in the olivocerebellar projection seem 
    to be coupled to bands of mabQ113 + and mabQll3 - immunoreactive 
    Purkinje cells, the situation with respect to other molecular 
    markers remains unclear given the several claims of overlapping 
    antigenic Purkinje cell categories (Chan-Palay et al. 
    &apos;81,&apos;82; Nilaver et al., &apos;82; Ingram et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">One possible explanation is that the expression of some 
    molecular markers is related to the dynamic metabolic state of the 
    cell rather than to its permanent phenotype, a situation that could 
    presage a distinction between topographically defined cerebellar 
    compartments and functional units.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">The one case in which the olivocerebellar topography and 
    the mabQ113 +/ mabQ113 - boundaries do not correspond is at the 
    midline, where the purely contralateral olivocerebellar projection 
    splits the P1+ band.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">In this special case it seems more probable that P1+ is, 
    in fact, two confluent mabQ113+ bands, one in each hemisphere, in 
    which case the agreement between mabQ113 and anterograde transport 
    seems to be complete.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">&quot;he purely ipsilateral corticonuclear projection 
    and our observations of Purkinje cell axon fasciculation at the 
    midline both support this assertion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Although a common plan relates the expression of the 
    mabQ113 epitope and the olivocerebellar projection, the possibility 
    of a causal link between the two Purkinje cell immunological 
    phenotypes and the climbing fiber zonation is still unclear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">As already cited, it seems that all regions of the 
    cerebellar cortex receive climbing fiber afferents and that the 
    sole source of climbing fibers is the IOC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Moreover, our results show that the labeled patches of 
    molecular layer obtained following injection of an anterograde 
    tracer in the inferior olive can share boundaries with either a 
    mabQ113+ of mabQll3zone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">So it is clear that the pattern of positive and negative 
    immunoreactive Purkinje cells is not caused by the presence or 
    absence of climbing fibers innervating the cells composing these 
    bands.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Likewise, although the nature of the epitope recognized 
    by mabQ113 is still poorly understood, its intracellular location 
    (Hawkes et al., &apos;85) and late appearance during Purkinje cell 
    development (Hawkes and Leclerc, &apos;85) make it an unlikely 
    candidate as a cell recognition molecule for ingrowing climbing 
    fibers during development.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The possibility remains that there exist two different 
    populations of climbing fibers, one projecting to mabQll3 + bands, 
    the other to mabQ113 - bands.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Marani et al. (&apos;77) have shown in the cat a 
    differential staining pattern for acetylcholinesterase in the 
    inferior olive and have suggested that this is in relation with the 
    pattern of parasagittally oriented bands of Ache staining seen in 
    the cerebellar cortex of kittens (Ramon-Moliner, &apos;72; Marani 
    and Voogd, &apos;77; Marani, &apos;82) and adult cats (Brown and 
    Graybiel, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Both anatomical (Sotelo et al., &apos;74) and 
    physiological Glinas et al., &apos;74) studies have shown 
    electrotonical coupling between cells of the IOC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Simultaneous recording from multiple Purkinje cells in 
    the cerebellar cortex reveals spontaneous synchrony of complex 
    spikes in rostrocaudal stretches (Bower and Llinris, &apos;83; 
    Sasaki and Llinas, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Administration of picrotoxin leads to the mediolateral 
    spread of the synchrony, which suggests that 
    gamma-aminobutyric-acid (GABA)-mediated inhibition can modulate 
    electrotonic coupling between precise sets of IOC cells projecting 
    to distinct parasagittal zones (Sasaki and Llinas, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Recently, Sotelo et al. (&apos;86) have provided an 
    anatomical substrate for the modulatory role of GABA inhibition in 
    the spatial organization of olivary firing.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">These &quot;physiological subpopulations&quot; of IOC 
    cells may correspond to the &quot;topographical 
    subpopulations&quot; implicit in our results.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">It remains to be determined whether the expression of 
    the mabQ113 antigen is sustained or induced by climbing fibers or 
    other afferent cues, or if the mabQ113 phenotype is intrinsic to 
    two different populations of Purkinje cells.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s241">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s242">We wish to thank Helene 
    Boettcher, Jamel Rafrafi, and Line Thivierge for their technical 
    assistance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s243">This work was supported by 
    grants from the Medical Research Council of Canada (R.H.), P.H.S. 
    grants NS 16531 (L.M.E., R.H.)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s244">and NS 22093 (L.M.E.), and by 
    a studentship from the F.R.S.Q.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s245">(C.G.).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s246">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Armstrong, D.M., R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Harvey, and R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Schild (1974) Topographical localization in the 
    olivocerebellar projection: an electrophysiological study in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Neurol. 154:287-302.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">Armstrong, D.M., N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">Campbell, S.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Edgley, R.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Schild, and J.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Trott (1982) Investigations of the olivocerebellar and 
    spino-olivary pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">In S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Palay and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Chan~Palay (eds): The Cerebellum-New Vistas.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp, 195-232.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Beyerl, B.D., L.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Borges, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Swearingen, and R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Sidman (1982) Parasagittal organization of&apos;the 
    olivocerebellar projection in the mouse.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Neural. 209:339-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Blatt, G.J., and L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Eisenman (1985) Autoradiographic study of the 
    oliuocerebellar projection in adult normal and weaver mutant 
    mice.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">Abstr. 11:181.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Bloedel, J.R., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Courville (1981) Cerebellar afferent systems.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">In J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Brookhart, V.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Mountcastle, and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Brooks (eds): Handbook of Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Betheada, MD: Am.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">SOC., 2:735-829.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Bower, J., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Llinas (1983) Simultaneous sampling of the responses of 
    multiple, closely adjacent, Purkin.je cells responding to climbing 
    fiber activation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Abstr. 9607.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Brodal, A. (1976) The olivwrebellar projection in the 
    cat as studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">IT.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">The projection to the uvula.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">J Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Neurol. 166417-426.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Brodal, A. (1980) Olivocerebellocortical projection in 
    the cat as determined with the method of retrograde axonal 
    transport of horseradish peroxidase 2.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Topographical pattern in relation to the longitudinal 
    subdivision of the cerebellum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">In J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Comville, C. de Montigny, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Lamarre (eds): The Inferior Olivary Nucleus: Anatomy and 
    Physiology.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">New York Raven Press, pp. 187-205.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Brodal, A., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Kawamura (1980) Olivocerebellar Adv.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Embryol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Cell Rid. 64:l-140.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Brodal, A,, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Walberg, and G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Hoddevik, G.H. (1975) The olivocerebellar projection in 
    the cat as studied with the method of retrograde axonal transport 
    of horseradish peroxidase I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">The projection to the paramedian lobule.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurol. 164:449-470.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Brown, B.L., and A.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Graybiel (1983) Zonal organization vermis of the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Rec. 205:25A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Campbell, N.C., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Armstrong (1983) The olivocerebellar projection in the 
    rat: An autoradiographic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Brain Res. 275215-233.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Chambers, W.W., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Sprague (1955a) A functional localization in the 
    cerebellum: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Organization in longitudinal cortico-nuclear zones and 
    their contribution to the control of posture, both extrapyramidal 
    and pyramidal.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Neurol. 103:105-130.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Chambers, W.W., and J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Sprague 11955b) Functional localization in the 
    cerebellum: IT.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Somatotopic organization in cortex and nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Arch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Psychiat. 74:653-680.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Chan-Palay, V., S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Palay, and J-Y Wu. (1982) Sagittal cerebellar microbands 
    of taurine neurons: Immunocytochemical demonstration by using 
    antibodies against the taurine synthesizing enzyme cysteine 
    sulfinic acid decarboxylase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">U.S.A. 79:4221-4225.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Chan-Palay, V., S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Palay, J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Brown, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Van Itallie (1977) Sagittal organization of 
    olivocerebellar and reticulocerebellar projections: 
    Autoradiographic studies with 35s-methionine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Brain Res. 30:561-576.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Chan-Palay, V., G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Nilaver, S.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Palay, M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Beinfeld, E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Zimmerman, JY.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Wu, and T.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">O Donohue (1981) Chemical heterogeneity in cerebellar 
    Purkinje cells: Existence and co-existence of glutamic acid 
    decarboxylase~like and motilin-like immunoreactivities.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">U.S.A. 787787-7791.</S>
    <BR />

  </References>

</File>

