<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Cytoarchitecture, Fiber Connections, and Some Histochemical 
  Aspects of the Interpeduncular Nucleus in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>H.J. GROENEWEGEN, S. AHLENIUS, S.N. HABER, N.W. KOWALL, AND 
  W.J.H. NAUTA</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The organization of afferent and efferent connections of 
    the interpeduncular nucleus (IP) has been examined in correlation 
    with its subnuclear parcellation by using anterograde and 
    retrograde tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Based on Nissl, myelin, and acetylcholinesterase staining 
    five paired and three unpaired IP subnuclei are distinguished.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The unpaired division includes the rostral subnucleus 
    UP-R), the apical subnucleus (IP-A), and the central subnucleus 
    (IP-C).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The subnuclei represented bilaterally are the paramedian 
    dorsal medial (IP-DM) and intermediate subnuclei (IP-I) and the 
    laterally placed rostral lateral (IP-RL), dorsal lateral (IP-DL), 
    and lateral subnuclei (IP-L).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Immunohistochemical techniques showed cell bodies and 
    fibers and terminals immunoreactive for substance P, 
    leu-enkephalin, met-enkephalin, or serotonin to be differentially 
    distributed over the different IP subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Substance P-positive perikarya were found in IP-R, 
    enkephalin neurons in IP-R, IP-A, and the caudodorsal part of IP-C, 
    and serotonin-containing cell bodies in IP-A and the caudal part of 
    IP-L.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Efferent IP projections were studied both by injecting 
    tritiated leucine in IP and by injecting HRP or WGA-HRP in the 
    presumed termination areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">The results indicate that the major outflow of IP is 
    directed caudalward to the median and dorsal raphe nuclei and the 
    caudal part of the central gray substance, i.e., the dorsal 
    tegmental region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The projection appears to terminate mainly in the raphe 
    nuclei, around the ventral and dorsal tegmental nuclei of Gudden, 
    and in the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The descending projection to the dorsal tegmental region 
    originates in virtually all IP subnuclei, but the main contribution 
    comes from IP-R and the lateral subnuclei IP-RL, IP-DL, and 
    IP-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Sparser projections to the dorsal tegmental region 
    originate in IP-C and IP-I, whereas the contribution of IP-A is 
    only minimal.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The projections from IP-R are mainly ipsilateral and 
    those from IP-DM are mainly contralateral.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">IP fibers to the median and dorsal raphe nuclei originate 
    predominantly in IP-R and IP-DM, and to a lesser extent in IP-C, 
    IP-I, IP-RL, and IP-DL.</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Accepted January 18,1986.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Address reprint requests to Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Groenewegen at his present address, Department of Anatomy 
    and Embryology, Faculty of Medicine, Vrije Universiteit, Van der 
    Boechorststraat 7, 1081 BT Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">S.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Ahlenius&apos; present address is the Astra 
    Pharmaceutical ComPanY, Research and Development, Department Of 
    PharmacohY, s-15185 Sodertaljer Sweden.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Haber&apos;s present address is the Department of 
    Anatomy, University of Rochester, Medical School, 601 Elmwood Ave., 
    Rochester, NY 14642.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">Parts of this study have been reported elsewhere in 
    abstract (Ahlenius and Nauta, &apos;80; Groenewegen et al,, 
    &apos;83a,b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The interpeduncular nucleus constitutes an important link 
    in the descending pathways of the limbic systemmidbrain circuit 
    (Nauta, &apos;58; Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79; Nauta and 
    Domesick, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Limbic forebrain structures such as the septa1 region and 
    the preoptic area are connected through the medial habenular 
    nucleus to the interpeduncular nucleus (Wang and Aghajanian, 
    &apos;77; Herkenham and Nauta &apos;77, &apos;79; Marchand et al., 
    &apos;80), which itself projects prominently to the region of the 
    mesencephalic raphe nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The median and dorsal raphe nuclei in turn affect all of 
    the principal subdivisions of the forebrain by way of widespread 
    serotoninergic projections that directly involve such diverse 
    structures as the hippocampus, the amygdala, the striatum, and the 
    cerebral cortex (Conrad et al., &apos;74; Bobillier et al., 
    &apos;75; Azmitia and Segal, &apos;78; Steinbusch, &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">A descending projection to the mesencephalic raphe, first 
    described by Ganser in 1882, doubtless represents the most 
    substantial and well-defined efferent connection of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Much less is known about other efferent connections of 
    the nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Older studies by the aid of fiber-degeneration methods 
    have yielded some impression of these less prominent projections 
    (Massopust and Thompson, &apos;62; Mitchell, &apos;63; Smaha and 
    Kaelber, &apos;731, but a more detailed analysis by such methods 
    has been impeded by the small size of the nucleus and its position 
    between large ascending and descending fiber tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Both degeneration experiments and more recent anterograde 
    (Stofer and Edwards, &apos;78) and retrograde tracer studies have 
    indicated that the interpeduncular nucleus, in addition to its 
    major descending projections, gives rise to ascending pathways as 
    well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Thus, retrogradely labeled cells have been found in the 
    interpeduncular nucleus following HRP injections into the 
    hippocampus (Baisden et al., &apos;79; Wyss et al., &apos;79; Riley 
    and Moore, &apos;811, the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus (Velayos and 
    Reinoso-Suarez, &apos;82; Groenewegen and Nauta, &apos;821, and the 
    lateral hypothalamus (Stofer and Edwards, &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">The nucleus interpeduncularis consists of several 
    cytoarchitectonically distinct cell groups (Ives, &apos;71; Hamill 
    and Lenn, &apos;81, &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Moreover, specific parts of the interpeduncular nucleus 
    can be distinguished from other parts by a higher or lower content 
    in substances such as acetylcholinesterase and one or the other of 
    several peptides or transmitter substances, either in fibers and 
    terminals or in cell bodies (Ljungdahl et al., &apos;78; Sar et 
    al., &apos;78; Cuello and Kanazawa, &apos;78; Steinbusch, &apos;81; 
    Finley et al., &apos;81; Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;82, 
    &apos;84; Hamill et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Little is known, however, of the specific inputoutput 
    relationships of such individual parts of the nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">In the present study the autoradiographic fiber-tracing 
    method was used to trace the efferent connections of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Subsequently, the retrograde-tracing techniques were 
    employed to corroborate the results of these and previously 
    reported anterograde-tracing experiments and to determine the 
    pathways in question with respect to the cytoarchitectonically and 
    histochemically specified subdivisions of the interpeduncular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">The results of these experiments provided a rather 
    detailed picture of the interpeduncular afTerents, and in view of 
    this it seemed worthwhile to restudy a number of afferent fiber 
    systems of the interpeduncular nucleus with anterograde-tracing 
    techniques in an attempt to correlate the afferent and efferent 
    relationships of the nucleus.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s37">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">The present report is based on observations and 
    experiments in female rats of the Charles River CD strain, weighing 
    250-500 g.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">In a number of brains one or a combination of the 
    following stains was used to study the normal structure and 
    histochemistry of the nucleus interpeduncularis (IP).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">The cytoarchitecture was studied in material stained with 
    cresyl violet and by silver impregnation of Nissl substance 
    according to Merker&apos;s technique (&apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">For the staining of the myelin pattern the Loyez method 
    was used.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">The distribution of acetylcholinesterase (AChE) activity 
    was determined with the aid of Geneser-Jensen and Blackstad&apos;s 
    (&apos;71) method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">All procedures were carried out on aldehydefixed tissue 
    cut on a freezing microtome at 20,30, or 40 pm.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s44">Immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">For the localization of enkephalin-like, serotonin-like, 
    and substance P-like immunoreactivity nine rats were deeply 
    anesthetized and subsequently perfused with 4% paraformaldehyde in 
    a 5% solution of sucrose in 0.1 M phosphate buffer of pH 7.2 and 
    cooled to 4째C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Three of the animals had been pretreated 24-48 hours 
    prior to perfusion with an intraventricular injection of 5 pl 
    colchicine (15 pg/pl), and three other animals received an 
    injection of 1 pl colchicine (15 pgIp1) near the interpeduncular 
    nucleus to enhance staining of cell bodies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">The brains were removed, postfixed for 90 minutes, 
    transferred to increasing sucrose gradients (lo%, 15%, 20%), and 
    finally stored in 30% sucrose in phosphate buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The brains were frozen and cut on a freezing microtome at 
    20 or 30 pm.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Antisera to leu-enkephalin were kindly provided by Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Miller, University of Chicago (Miller et al., &apos;78; 
    Miller and Pickel, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Antibodies to met-enkephalin, serotonin, and substance P 
    were generously provided by Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Robert P.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Elde, University of Minnesota.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Antisera to met-enkephalin (Haber and Elde, &apos;82) and 
    substance P (Ho and DePalatis, &apos;80) were generated in response 
    to immunogens produced by linking the peptides to bovine 
    thyroglobulin and keyhole limpet hemocyanin, respectively, by means 
    of glutaraldehyde coupling.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Antisera against serotonin (5HT) were generated by 
    linking the monoamine to bovine serum albumin by formaldehyde 
    coupling (Maley and Elde, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Absorption controls for met-enkephalin, 5HT, and 
    substance P were prepared by incubating each antiserum overnight 
    with synthetic met-enkephalin, 5HT, or substance P (10 pg/ml 
    diluted antiserum).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) technique of 
    Sternberger (&apos;79) was used throughout the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The sections were incubated overnight at 4째C with the 
    primary antisera diluted 11500 with 0.3% Triton X-100 in 
    phosphate-buffered saline (hereafter called PBS/T).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">After rinsing, the tissue was incubated in goat 
    antirabbit IgG (1/100 in PBS/T) for 1 hour at room temperature and 
    then rinsed and incubated in rabbit PAP (11500 in PBS/T) for 1 hour 
    at 22째C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">After rinsing with Tris (0.05 M, pH 7.6) the tissue was 
    incubated in 3,3&apos;-diaminobenzidine tetrahydrochloride (0.5 
    mg/ml in Tris buffer containing 0.01% HzOz) for approximately 7 
    minutes at 22째C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The sections were rinsed, dehydrated, and coverslipped 
    with Permount.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Alternate sections were stained with cresyl violet or 
    processed for enkephalin-like, 5HT-like, and substance P-like 
    immunoreactivity, respectively.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s64">Tracing experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">For the purpose of anterograde tracing of the projections 
    from the nucleus interpeduncularis (IP) iontophoretic injections of 
    tritiated leucine were placed in 18 animals in the nucleus or its 
    immediate vicinity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Prior to surgery the animals were deeply anesthetized by 
    intraperitoneal injection of 0.4 m1/100 g body weight Chloropent (a 
    mixture of chloralhydrate and pentobarbital, Fort Dodge 
    Laboratories).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The following stereotaxic approach was followed: after 
    determining the desired anteroposterior level of the injection, the 
    occipital pole of the right hemisphere was removed by aspiration in 
    order to expose the superior colliculus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">A glass micropipette, measuring 15-20 pm ID at the tip, 
    was introduced through the superior colliculus at an inward angle 
    of 20&quot; and lowered to the intended depth.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">The pipette contained a solution of L-(3.4.5-3H) leucine 
    (specific activity 110 Ciipmol, New England Nuclear) in 0.01 N 
    acetic acid (20 pCi1pl).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Ejection of the tritiated leucine was accomplished by the 
    passage of a positive current of 0.2-0.5 pA, pulsed at a rate of 7 
    seconds oni7 seconds off, for 5-15 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Upon completion of the injection, the pipette was left in 
    situ for an additional 30 minutes.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Six to 8 days after surgery the animals were given an 
    overdose of Chloropent and were perfused transcardially with 
    saline, followed by formol-saline.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The brains were postfixed for at least 7 days and 
    subsequently transferred to 30% sucrose-formalin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Sections 30 pm thick were cut on a freezing microtome, 
    mounted, defatted, and coated with Kodak NTB2 or NTB3 emulsion.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Following exposure times of 8-16 weeks at -2O&quot;C, the 
    emulsion was developed in Kodak D 19 at 16&quot;C, and the sections 
    were counterstained with cresyl violet.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">In a second group of six animals, for the purpose of 
    tracing both the afferents and efferents of IP, an injection of 
    either free horseradish peroxidase (HRP Sigma, type VI) or the 
    conjugate of wheat germ agglutinin with HRP (WGAHRP, Sigma, Tritium 
    vulgaris, peroxidase type VI) was placed in the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">In these experiments a stereotaxic approach similar to 
    that used in the autoradiographic experiments was followed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Injections were placed electrophoretically from a glass 
    micropipette with an internal tip diameter of 15-35 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">The free HRP was used in a 13% solution and the WGA-HRP 
    in a 10% solution Tris-buffered at pH 8.6.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">A constant positive current of 2.0-3.0 pA was passed 
    through the pipette for 5-15 minutes, and the pipette was left in 
    situ for an additional 15-30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">After a survival of 48-72 hours, the animals were once 
    again deeply anesthetized and perfused through the heart with a 
    solution of 3% sucrose, 1.25% glutaraldehyde, and 0.5% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer at pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">The brains were stored overnight in a 20% solution of 
    sucrose in phosphate buffer and sectioned on a freezing microtome 
    at 50 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">In experiments in which free HRP was used as a tracer, 
    alternating series of sections were processed for the 
    diaminobenzidine (DAB, Graham and Karnovsky, &apos;66) and 
    tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) reactions (Mesulam, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">In some cases an additional series of sections was 
    processed for the benzidine dihydrochloride method (BDHC, Mesulam, 
    &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">The DAB-treated sections were counterstained with cresyl 
    violet, the BDHC and TMB material with neutral red, and the 
    remaining half coverslipped without counterstaining.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The DAB and BDHC material was exam ined in brightand 
    darkfield illumination and the TMBstained sections were examined in 
    brightfield and polarized light (Illing and Wassle, &apos;79; Hess 
    and Schneider, &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">In a third group of experiments smaller or larger 
    injections of HRP or WGA-HRP were placed in the various structures 
    in which anterogradely transported label had been found in the 
    first two groups of experiments.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">Iontophoretic injections were placed in two animals in 
    the lateral hypothalamus, and in three rats in the septum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">In another three rats pressure injections of 0.2 p1 of 
    30% HRP were placed in the hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">In ten animals an iontophoretic injection was placed in 
    the region of the dorsal tegmental nucleus and in three animals in 
    the median raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">Both of these mesencephalic structures were reached after 
    exposure of the floor of the anterior recess of the fourth 
    ventricle by aspiration of the anterior lobe of the cerebellum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">Included in this last group of experiments are a number 
    of cases separately reported elsewhere (Groenewegen and Nauta, 
    &apos;82) in which the retrograde tracer had been injected into the 
    mediodorsal thalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">Several of these injections had been placed under direct 
    visual guidance following aspiration of the overlying cortex, 
    corpus callosum, and dorsal hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Further surgical and histological procedures for this 
    group of HRP experiments were similar in detail to those described 
    above for the second group of experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">In a fourth and last group of experiments, anterograde 
    tracers were injected in regions known to project to the IP (our 
    results; Marchand et al., &apos;80; Flumerfelt et al., 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">Injections of tritiated amino acids or WGA-HRP were 
    placed in the caudal central gray substance (16 rats), the median 
    raphe nucleus (two rats), the habenular complex (three rats), the 
    lateral hypothalamus (four rats), the nucleus of the diagonal band 
    (four rats), and the parabigeminal region (two rats).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97">The experimental procedures used for this group of 
    experiments were similar to those described above.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s98">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s99">Cytoand 
    myeloarchitecture</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">The interpeduncular nucleus ( IP ) can be subdivided 
    into several subnuclei with different architectonic characteristics 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">As will be described below, these subnuclei differ among 
    each other also by histochemical and hodological criteria.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">The delineation of the various IP subnuclei proposed in 
    the present paper largely agrees with recent cytoarchitectural 
    descriptions (Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">In order to facilitate comparison of our results with 
    those of other studies, the compromise nomenclature recently 
    proposed by Lenn and Hamill (&apos;84) has been adopted.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">The IP is here considered to be made up of three 
    unpaired midline nuclei, two bilateral paramedian nuclei, arid two 
    lateral groups, each consisting of three subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">The border between the mediadparamedian and lateral 
    groups roughly coincides with a row of paramedian blood vessels, 
    extending from the ventral surface dorsally into the mesencephalic 
    raphe on either side of the midplane.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">This collection of blood vessels is most conspicuous in 
    the caudal half of the IP but can usually be recognized also at 
    more rostral levels ( e . g . , Figs . 1, 4 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">In sections stained with the Loyez method for myelin the 
    IP contrasts sharply with all adjacent structures , except the 
    interfascicular nucleus , in its low myelin content ( Fig . 3 ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">Differences in concentration and orientation of 
    myelinated fibers support the proposed subdivision of the IP based 
    on cytoarchitectonic criteria (Figs. 1-3).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">The most prominent representative of the median group of 
    the IP is the rostral subnucleus ( IP - R Figs . lA , 2A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">This unpaired cell group consists of small cells lightly 
    stained in Nissl preparations and rather closely spaced.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">At the rostral pole the Ip - R occupies almost the 
    entire dorsoventral extent of the IP ; more caudally it becomes 
    progressively confined to the dorsal half of the nucleus Figs . lA 
    , B , 2A , B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">At a level approximately halfway through the length of 
    the IP , the IF &apos; - R is replaced - vr possibly augmented - by 
    a pair of subnuclei only vaguely delineated from each other in the 
    midplane and composed of numerous very small , closely spaced cells 
    ( Figs . lB , 2B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">In sections stained for myelin this pair of paramedian 
    subnuclei can be distinguished from the IP-R by its slightly higher 
    content in myelinated fibers (Fig. 3A,B).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">This striking bilateral parvicellular cell group , here 
    to be named the dorsal medial subnucleus ( IPDM ) , extends 
    caudalward over only a short distance , to be replaced in the 
    caudal one - third of the IF &apos; by a similarly shaped but 
    distinctly large - celled region , the apical subnucleus ( IP - A ) 
    ( Figs . lC , 2C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">The latter is composed mainly of large, dark-staining, 
    spindle-shaped neurons, many of which are oriented in the 
    horizontal plane (Fig. 9A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">At the caudal pole of the IP the IP - A cannot be 
    sharply demarcated from the dorsally adjacent raphe region , which 
    contains numerous neurons of similar size , shape , and Nissl - 
    staining properties .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">Together , the three foregoing cell groups ( IP - R , IP 
    - DM , and IP - A ) compose approximately the dorsal half of the 
    median zone of the IP .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">The ventral half of this zone is occupied by the 
    bilateral intermediate ( IP - I ) and the unpaired central 
    subnucleus ( IP - C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119">These subnuclei are most prominent in the caudal two - 
    thirds of the IP , where they can be demarcated from adjoining cell 
    groups also in myelin preparations , as <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>a rather high 
    concentration of myelinated fibers</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 3B 
    , C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">Characteristic of <labelingLocation>the IP - C and IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> in Nissl preparations is the uneven , 
    <labelingDescription>clustered distribution of the small and medium 
    - sized neurons</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">In the rostra1 half of <labelingLocation>the 
    IP-C</labelingLocation> such clustering appears in the form of 
    <labelingDescription>several transversely oriented cell rows 
    separated by cellpoor zones</labelingDescription> (Fig. 1A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">Caudally this horizontal pattern gradually changes into 
    <labelingDescription>a less orderly one</labelingDescription> ( Fig 
    . lB ) , and in <labelingLocation>the caudal half of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> most of the cells are aggregated into three 
    irregular , vertically oriented columns , the median one of which 
    identifies the centrally located IP - C and is on either side 
    separated by a relatively cell - poor zone from the laterally 
    adjoining intermediate subnucleus ( IP - I ; Figs . lC , 2C ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">The lateral part of the interpeduncular nucleus is 
    subdivided into three subnuclei .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">The rostra1 lateral subnucleus ( IP - RL ) is a somewhat 
    triangular region forming the lateral tip of the IP , and it 
    consists of a rather cell - poor ventromedial part and a smaller 
    lateral zone containing most of the small and medium - sized 
    neurons that populate the IP - RL ( Fig . 1A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">It seems likely that the cell - poor zone of the IPRL 
    corresponds to the habenulo - interpeduncular tract of the 
    fasciculus retroflexus , a correspondence also suggested by the 
    arrangement of fibers ( Fig . 3A ) and <labelingDescription>the 
    very high acetylcholinesterase</labelingDescription> content of 
    this region ( see below ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">At middle longitudes of the IP <labelingLocation>the 
    separate dorsal lateral subnucleus ( IP - DL )</labelingLocation> 
    consists of rather <labelingDescription>closely spaced , lightly 
    stained , ovoidal neurons</labelingDescription> , slightly smaller 
    than the darkerstaining neurons in the ventrally adjacent lateral 
    subnucleus ( IP - L ; Figs . lB , 2B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">Caudally , this latter subnucleus constitutes a sickle - 
    shaped region just medial to <labelingLocation>the medial 
    lemniscus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">Most of <labelingDescription>the 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    L</labelingLocation> are somewhat larger and more closely spaced 
    than those of the IP - RL , but in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> - L likewise <labelingDescription>the 
    cells</labelingDescription> tend to form clusters separated from 
    each other by cell - poor intervals ( Fig . 1C ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s129">Acetylcholinesterase 
    activity</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">The pattern of distribution of acetylcholinesterase 
    (AChE) activity is, with a few minor exceptions, remarkably similar 
    to that of substance P-like immunoreactivity (see below).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131"><labelingLocation>The habenulo - interpeduncular 
    tract</labelingLocation> in <labelingLocation>the rostral 
    IP</labelingLocation> displays <labelingDescription>a strong 
    acetylcholinesterase activity</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 4A , B 
    ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132"><labelingDescription>Moderate - to - high activity of 
    acetylcholinesterase</labelingDescription> is observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - RL and IP - DL</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Staining over the laterally located 
    <labelingDescription>cell clusters</labelingDescription> of 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - L</labelingLocation> , by contrast , is 
    <labelingDescription>only weak to moderate</labelingDescription> , 
    but it is <labelingDescription>dense</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial , cell - poor zone of the 
    subnucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><labelingLocation>The rostral part of the IP - R shows a 
    strong AChE reaction</labelingLocation> , but more caudally the 
    reactivity of this nucleus wanes .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">In <labelingLocation>the caudal two - thirds of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>AChE 
    staining</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - DM and 
    IP - A</labelingLocation> is generally 
    <labelingDescription>somewhat darker</labelingDescription> than in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - R</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4B , C ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">The lowest AChE activity is shown by 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - C and IP - I</labelingLocation> ; in 
    <labelingLocation>the rostral part of the two 
    subnuclei</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>the AChE reaction 
    is virtually negative</labelingDescription> , but 
    <labelingLocation>more caudally</labelingLocation> the three 
    vertically oriented cell columns show <labelingDescription>a 
    faintly positive reaction</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 4C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">Two heavily stained paramedian fiber bundles leave the 
    caudal pole of the IP in a dorsocaudal direction on either side of 
    the midplane (Fig. 8A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">After traversing <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>these fiber 
    bundles</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the central 
    gray substance</labelingLocation> by passing through the narrow 
    interval between the left and the right medial longitudinal 
    fasciculus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">&quot; here can be no doubt that this discrete fiber 
    system , earlier noted for its strong AChE reactivity ( Wilson and 
    Watson , &apos; 801, and according to the present findings also 
    containing substance P - positive fibers ( Fig . 8B ) , corresponds 
    to the interpedunculotegmental tract of Ganser ( 1882 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s140">Distribution of 
    substance P-like, enkephalin-like, and serotonin-like 
    immunoreactivity</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Substance P.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142"><labelingDescription>Numerous substance P - positive 
    cell bodies</labelingDescription> are present in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP</labelingLocation> , all of them located 
    in <labelingLocation>the IP - R , throughout the rostrocaudal 
    extent of this cell group</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">Staining of cell bodies is evident in both 
    colchicinetreated (Fig. 9F) and nontreated animals, but in the 
    latter the staining is considerably weaker.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Substance P-like immunoreactivity of fibers-and 
    presumably terminals-in the IP appears to be very specific.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">In <labelingLocation>the rostral half of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>substance P - reactive 
    fibers are relatively sparse</labelingDescription> and almost 
    entirely confined to <labelingLocation>a thin layer marking the 
    dorsal border of IP</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 5A , 9F ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">However , <labelingLocation>the habenulo - 
    interpeduncular tract</labelingLocation> , entering the IP &apos;s 
    rostral pole in an extreme ventrolateral position , contains a 
    substance P - positive fiber bundle that is slender rostrally but 
    expands considerably at middle levels ( Fig .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">SB ) , and farther caudally almost completely enmeshes 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - L</labelingLocation> in 
    <labelingDescription>a dense fiber plexus</labelingDescription> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148"><labelingLocation>The central part of the 
    IP-L</labelingLocation> exhibits <labelingDescription>a somewhat 
    lower substance P-immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> (Fig. 
    5C).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">In <labelingLocation>the rostral part of the IP - 
    R</labelingLocation> , except for processes of the local substance 
    Ppositive neurons , <labelingDescription>very few substance P - 
    positive fibers</labelingDescription> are seen ( Fin . 9F ) , while 
    <labelingLocation>the most caudal part of the IP - 
    R</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>a moderate 
    number of such fibers</labelingDescription> , as also do 
    <labelingLocation>the IPDM and IP - A</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">In contrast to their surrounding subnuclei , 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - C and IP - I</labelingLocation> display 
    <labelingDescription>virtually no substance P - like 
    immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 5B , C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">Leaving the caudal pole of the IP, a paired substance 
    P-positive fiber bundle courses dorsocaudally in a paramedian 
    position (Fig. 8B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">These fibers appear to be part of the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract of Ganser (18821, a fiber group also 
    noted for its high acetylcholinesterase content.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Enkephalin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">The distribution patterns of met-enkephalin and 
    leu-enkeahalin immunoreactivitv over the varioiin subnuclei of the 
    IP appear to be very similar, although with the antisera here used 
    staining for leu-enkephalin is generally stronger than for 
    met-enkephalin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155"><labelingDescription>Enkephalin - positive 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> , stainable even without colchicine 
    pretreatment , are <labelingDescription>most 
    numerous</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the rostral 
    subnucleus IP - R</labelingLocation> , but are also found in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - A and in the caudal part of the IP - 
    C</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 6, 9D , E ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156"><labelingLocation>The IP - R</labelingLocation> contains 
    also <labelingDescription>a dense enkephalin - positive fiber 
    plexus</labelingDescription> that extends laterally into 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal lateral subnucleus IP - DL and 
    ventrally into the central subnucleus IP - C</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 6 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157"><labelingDescription>Less dense fiber 
    staining</labelingDescription> marks <labelingLocation>the IP - RL 
    , IP - A , and IP - I</labelingLocation> , whereas 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal medial subnucleus IP - 
    DM</labelingLocation> stands out by its 
    <labelingDescription>conspicuous enkephalin 
    negativity</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 6B ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Serotonin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Serotonin - like immunoreactivity of neuronal somata is 
    found only in <labelingLocation>the caudal one - third of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">By far <labelingDescription>the most numerous 5 - HT - 
    positive cell bodies</labelingDescription> are located in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - A</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 7C , 9B , 
    C ) , <labelingDescription>a population of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> which at <labelingLocation>the caudal 
    confines of the IP</labelingLocation> cannot be sharply demarcated 
    from <labelingDescription>the 5 - HT - positive 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">SC ) , <labelingLocation>the B8 cell group of Dahlstrom 
    and Fwe ( &apos; 64 )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">In addition , <labelingDescription>5 - HT - positive 
    cells</labelingDescription> are present in <labelingLocation>the 
    caudal half of the IP - L</labelingLocation> , concentrated for the 
    most part in the latter &apos;s ventral and lateral periphery ( Fig 
    . 7B , C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">These<labelingDescription>positive IP 
    neurons</labelingDescription> have the same morphology as the 
    scattered 5 - HT - immunoreactive cells lying between 
    <labelingLocation>the fascicles of the medial 
    lemniscus</labelingLocation> , and belonging to 
    <labelingLocation>the B9 cell group</labelingLocation> of Dahlstrom 
    and Fuxe ( &apos; 64 ).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164"><labelingDescription>The densest plexus of 5HT - 
    positive fibers and / or terminals</labelingDescription> pervades 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DM</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 7B , C , 
    19C ) , while <labelingLocation>the adjacent subnucleus IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> contains <labelingDescription>a lesser number 
    of such fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Onlv <labelingDescription>a moderate - tolow density of 
    fiber or terminal staining</labelingDescription> is &quot; seen in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - L and IP - R</labelingLocation> , but 
    <labelingDescription>a dense stratum of 5 - HT - positive 
    fibers</labelingDescription> caps <labelingLocation>the 
    rostrodorsal border of the latter subnucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 7A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166"><labelingLocation>The subnuclei IP - C and IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> are <labelingDescription>almost free of 
    serotoninlike immunoreactivity</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 7B , C 
    ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s167">Anterograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">The autoradiographic material here examined consists of 
    18 cases of <exptLabel>iontophoretic injection of 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated leucine</tracerChemical> in or directly 
    adjacent to <injectionLocation>the 
    IP</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Representative injection sites are collectively, and 
    somewhat schematically, represented in Figure 10, in which only the 
    last two digits of the experiment numbers are used to identify 
    individual cases.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170">One of the experiments , case RRIP - 15, with 
      <exptLabel>A large injection apparently confined to 
      <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , 
      provided the most comprehensive picture of ascending and 
      descending IP projections , and therefore is described here first 
      in some detail .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s171">Case RRIP-15.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s172">The center of the injection site in this case is 
      located at and about <injectionLocation>the midrostrocaudal level 
      of the IP</injectionLocation> and involves primarily 
      <injectionLocation>the IP - R and IP - DM</injectionLocation> 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">Small parts of <labelingLocation>the adjacent 
      subnuclei of the IP</labelingLocation> , particularly 
      <injectionLocation>the IP - C , IP - I, IP - A , and IP - 
      DL</injectionLocation> , are included in the center of the 
      injection ( Figs . 10, 12A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174">The periphery of the injection site includes 
      <injectionLocation>the rest of the IP except for its most rostral 
      and lateral parts</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175">Descending projections .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s176">Most of <labelingDescription>the labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> leave the IP dorsally and caudally , 
      through and lateral to <labelingLocation>the 
      interpedunculotegmental tract ( of Ganser</labelingLocation> , 
      1882 ; Fig . 11H ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s177">In <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> labeling appears in a linear pattern 
      over <labelingDescription>single fibers</labelingDescription> as 
      well as in <labelingDescription>a more random pattern suggestive 
      of labeled terminals</labelingDescription> ( Figs . 111, 12D ) 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s178">Dorsal and lateral to this nucleus the comDact , 
      <labelingDescription>heavily labeled paramedian fiber 
      bundles</labelingDescription> skirt <labelingLocation>the margins 
      of the ventral tegmental nucleus of Gudden</labelingLocation> and 
      subsequently pass between the two medial longitudinal fasciculi 
      to fan out dorsolaterally over <labelingLocation>the caudal part 
      of the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Figs . llJ , 12D 
      , E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s179"><labelingLocation>The ventral tegmental nucleus of 
      Gudden</labelingLocation> <labelingModifier>is surrounded 
      by</labelingModifier> <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription>, but <labelingDescription>only 
      few</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>pass 
      through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> (Fig. 12E).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s180">Immediately caudal to <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>a large 
      number of fibers</labelingDescription> deviate lateralward and 
      curve dorsally to enter <labelingLocation>the central gray 
      substance</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s181">In <labelingLocation>the caudal part of the central 
      gray substance</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>heavy 
      labeling</labelingDescription> appears along the midline , in and 
      around <labelingLocation>the caudal extension of the dorsal raphe 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 11K , 12B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s182">Furthermore , <labelingLocation>extremely heavy 
      labeling</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingModifier>surrounds</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the caudal half of the dorsal tegmental nucleus 
      of Gudden</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s183"><labelingLocation>The rostral two - thirds of the 
      nucleus proper</labelingLocation> contains only 
      <labelingDescription>very sparse labeling</labelingDescription> , 
      but<labelingLocation>its caudal one - third</labelingLocation>- 
      in which the cells are relatively widely spaced - is 
      <labelingDescription>densely labeled</labelingDescription> ( Figs 
      . 11L , 12C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s184"><labelingLocation>The nucleus tegmenti dorsalis 
      lateralis</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 11K , 12B ) is 
      <labelingDescription>moderately labeled</labelingDescription> 
      over its entire rostrocaudal extent but includes a few small 
      areas of higher grain concentration .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s185">Labeling in <labelingLocation>the central gray 
      substance</labelingLocation> extends for some distance caudal to 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      in rapidly diminishing intensity and reaches its caudal limit 
      near the rostral margin of the genu nervi facialis .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s186">Ascending projections .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s187"><labelingLocation>The rostral pole of the 
      IP</labelingLocation> is marked by <labelingDescription>a high 
      concentration of label</labelingDescription> , but only 
      <labelingDescription>sparse grain</labelingDescription> appears 
      in <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental area immediately 
      dorsal and lateral to the 1P</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s188"><labelingLocation>Rostra1 to the IP</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingModifier>are loosely arranged around</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the fasciculus retroflexus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 11F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s189">At <labelingLocation>the level of the mesodiencephalic 
      transition</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>moderately 
      dense fiber labeling</labelingDescription> fills 
      <labelingLocation>the supramammillary region</labelingLocation> 
      but <labelingLocation>the mammillary body</labelingLocation> 
      itself is entirely <labelingDescription>free from 
      label</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 11E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s190">From the caudal diencephalic border forward , 
      <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> follow 
      three different paths .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s191"><labelingDescription>A number of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>ascend 
      surrounding</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the fasciculus 
      retroflexus</labelingLocation> and can be followed to 
      <labelingLocation>the caudal pole of the 
      habenula</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s192"><labelingDescription>Very sparse 
      labeling</labelingDescription> marks <labelingLocation>the medial 
      half of the lateral habenular nucleus</labelingLocation> and 
      continues rostrally into <labelingLocation>the stria 
      medullaris</labelingLocation> , gradually scattering itself over 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the mediodorsal thalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11C ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s193"><labelingDescription>A second group of rather sparse 
      labeled fibers</labelingDescription> courses alongside 
      <labelingLocation>the mammillothalamic tract</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 11D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s194">Most of these fibers appear <labelingModifier>to 
      terminate</labelingModifier> in <labelingLocation>the rostral 
      part of the nucleus gelatinosus thalami</labelingLocation> (Fig. 
      11C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s195"><labelingDescription>Sparser 
      labeling</labelingDescription> appears lateral to the tract in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventromedial thalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s196"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> travel farther rostrally with 
      <labelingLocation>the mammillothalamic tract</labelingLocation> , 
      but can be followed only over a short distance .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s197">It is possible that they join <labelingDescription>the 
      sparsely labeled fibers</labelingDescription> entering 
      <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal nucleus</labelingLocation> from 
      the overlying stria medullaris .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s198">A third ascending component of the IP fibers follows 
      the medial forebrain bundle.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s199">In case RRIP - 15 this transhypothalamic fiber group 
      appears as rather loosely arranged <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> diffusely distributed over the cross 
      section of <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11B - D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s200"><labelingDescription>Some 
      labeling</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>is seen 
      around</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
      fornix</labelingLocation> , but very little is detectable in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial zone of the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s201"><labelingDescription>The same pattern of diffuse 
      labeling</labelingDescription> is found in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral preoptic area and the nucleus of the diagonal band of 
      Broca</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s202">A somewhat higher concentration of grains , however , 
      marks <labelingLocation>the medial septal nucleus and the ventral 
      part of the lateral septal nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11A 
      ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s203"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> can be seen to enter 
      <labelingLocation>the fornix</labelingLocation> , but these can 
      be followed only over a short distance into <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral part of the fimbria</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s204">Despite this difficulty in tracing interpeduncular 
      efferents beyond the septum in continuity , this case provides 
      evidence that some are distributed to <labelingLocation>the 
      temporal quarter , at least , of the 
      hippocampus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s205">In this restricted hippocampal region labeling clearly 
      above background appears in <labelingLocation>the stratum 
      moleculare and hilus of the fascia dentata</labelingLocation> , 
      as well as in <labelingLocation>the stratum radiatum of field 
      CA3</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11E , F ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s206">Differential efferent 
    projections of interpeduncular subnuclei</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Owing to the small size of the IP and, a fortiori, of 
    its constituent subnuclei, it is nearly impossible to confine 
    injections of tritiated amino acids to any particular 
    subnucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">In most cases more than two subnuclei of the IP are 
    included in the injection site , and it is therefore not possible 
    to discern more than a rough topographic organization in the 
    labeled IP projections .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">A more differentiated topographic picture emerges when 
    this autoradiographic material is studied in conjunction with the 
    cases of retrograde cell labeling .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Descending projections .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">A topographic organization is more difficult to 
    recognize in <labelingLocation>the descending</labelingLocation> 
    than in the ascending projections of the IP ( see below ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">All isotope injections that included 
    <injectionLocation>parts of the IP</injectionLocation> were found 
    to result in <labelingDescription>anterograde 
    label</labelingDescription> transport to <labelingLocation>the 
    median and dorsal raphe nuclei and to the caudal part of the 
    central gray substance</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">Differences in the labeling of the IP efferents among 
    different autoradiographic experiments are mainly quantitative and 
    do not suggest a clear-cut topographic arrangement.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">To illustrate the general nature of these differences a 
    few experiments will be compared.</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215"><exptLabel>Injections of 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated</tracerChemical> leucine in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , with a 
    preference for one - half of the IP over the other , result in 
    asymmetric fiber labeling in <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
    nucleus and the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">In experiment RRZP - 14 the injection involves 
    <injectionLocation>the IP - C , IP - I , and parts of the IP - R 
    and IPA of both sides , as well as the IP - DL and IP - L of one 
    side only</injectionLocation> ( Fig . 1OB ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217"><labelingDescription>Heavy 
    labeling</labelingDescription> appears in <labelingLocation>the 
    median raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> with a clear predominance 
    of the side ipsilateral to the involvement of IP - DL and IP - L 
    .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Projections to <labelingLocation>the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> appear to be <labelingDescription>almost 
    equal on either side of the midline</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">The distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> over <labelingLocation>the caudal 
    central gray substance</labelingLocation> is similar in pattern to 
    that noted in RRZP - 15 ( cf .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s220">Figs . 11J - L , 12B , C ) , 
    but in RRZP - 14 a marked asymmetry appears , in the sense that the 
    labeling directly surrounding <labelingLocation>the rostral two - 
    thirds of the dorsal tegmental nucleus of Gudden</labelingLocation> 
    , and especially the labeling of <labelingLocation>the dorsolateral 
    tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> , is much more massive on the 
    side contralateral to the main involvement of the IP .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">By contrast , at <labelingLocation>more caudal levels of 
    the central gray substance</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>the dense labeling</labelingDescription> 
    marking <labelingLocation>the caudal onethird of the dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus of Gudden</labelingLocation> appears to be equal 
    on both sides .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s222">Experiment RRZP - 11 ( Fig . 10B , C ) , in which 
      <exptLabel>the injection site is largely unilateral in 
      <injectionLocation>the IP - R and IP - A and involves the IP - 
      DL</injectionLocation></exptLabel> only on the same side , 
      confirms the alternating distribution of <labelingDescription>the 
      IP fibers</labelingDescription> suggested in RRZP - 14.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s223">In <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> labeling is heaviest on the side 
      ipsilateral and in <labelingLocation>the dorsolateral tegmental 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> contralatera1 to the main involvement 
      of <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s224">Contrary to cases RRZP - 14 and - 15, in RRZP - 11 the 
      projection from <labelingLocation>the IP to the caudal pole of 
      the dorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> has remained 
      <labelingDescription>unlabeled</labelingDescription> , and this 
      is the case also in several other instances of injection 
      restricted to <injectionLocation>the caudal half of the 
      IP</injectionLocation> ( RRZP - 1, - 12, and - 13 ; Fig . 1OC ) 
      .</S>
      <BR />

    </TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Most injections of retrograde tracers in 
    <injectionLocation>the raphe nuclei and the caudal central gray 
    substance</injectionLocation> label 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>almost all subnuclei of the 
    IP</labelingLocation>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s226">It must be stressed that even 
    small injections in <injectionLocation>the caudal central 
    gray</injectionLocation> tend to involve more than one of the cell 
    groups recognized in <labelingLocation>this 
    region</labelingLocation> and thus are likely to affect afferents 
    of multiple rather than single cell groups .</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Moreover , injections in <injectionLocation>the median 
    raphe nucleus</injectionLocation> are very likely to interrupt IP 
    efferents in passage to more caudal termination sites .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">Despite these difficulties the retrograde tracing 
    experiments can reveal at least some of the topographic features of 
    the descending IP projection .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Following relatively large but unilateral injections in 
    the caudal central gray substance a remarkable pattern of ipsiand 
    contralateral <labelingDescription>cell 
    labeling</labelingDescription> appears in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">In experiment RHZ - 81 <exptLabel>the 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> injection covers 
    <injectionLocation>a large part of the caudal central gray 
    substance</injectionLocation> , including <injectionLocation>the 
    dorsal tegmental nucleus of Gudden , the dorsolateral tegmental 
    nucleus , and parts of the midline 
    structures</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig . 14A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">In <labelingLocation>the IP</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>both anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> is found .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s232">In 
    <labelingLocation>the rostral one - third of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>retrograde cell 
    labeling</labelingDescription> is predominantly ipsilateral to the 
    injection site and confined to <labelingLocation>the IP - R and IP 
    - RL</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s233">Only sporadic 
    <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> appear in 
    <labelingLocation>the same subnuclei of the contralateral 
    side</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s234">In <labelingLocation>the 
    middle one - third of the IP</labelingLocation> an entirely 
    different distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> is found most are here located in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DM and IP - DL contralateral to the 
    injection site</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 14A ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s235">At this 
    middle level labeling is <labelingDescription>still almost entirely 
    ipsilateral</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    R</labelingLocation> , and <labelingDescription>scattered labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are found 
    <labelingDescription>ipsilaterally</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DM and IP - L</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236"><labelingDescription>Labeling of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - C and 
    IP - I</labelingLocation> starts at the midlevel of the IP but is 
    more pronounced farther caudally ( Fig . 14A ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s237">In the 
    caudal onethird <labelingDescription>cell 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    L</labelingLocation> is bilateral .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s238">At this 
    level <labelingDescription>labeled neurons</labelingDescription> 
    also appear along <labelingLocation>the dorsal and lateral margins 
    of the IP , immediately dorsal and medial to the medial margin of 
    the medial lemniscus</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">The pattern of retrograde labeling described above was 
    noted also in three other cases of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> ( RHZ40 and - 52 ; Fig . 16A , 
    B ) or <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> ( RHZ - 72 ) 
    injection in <injectionLocation>the caudal central gray 
    substance</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">A slightly different distribution of the cells is found 
    in cases of injection covering a smaller part of 
    <injectionLocation>the caudal central gray</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s241">In case RHZ49 <exptLabel>a unilateral 
      <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injection is centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the caudal half of the dorsal tegmental 
      nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> and extends ventrally 
      into <injectionSpread>the medial longitudinal 
      fasciculus</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 14C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s242"><labelingDescription>RetrogradeIy labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are confined largely to 
      <labelingLocation>the rostroventral part of the ipsilateral IP - 
      R</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 14C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s243">The remaining <labelingDescription>few labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> are located in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral IP - DM and IP - 
      L</labelingLocation> and bilaterally in <labelingLocation>the 
      caudal part of the IP - I</labelingLocation> ( not shown ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s244">In contrast , small injections centered in 
      <injectionLocation>more rostral parts of the dorsal tegmental 
      region</injectionLocation> ( cases RHZ - 31 and - 73 ) label 
      <labelingDescription>relatively few cells</labelingDescription> 
      in <labelingLocation>the IP - I and IP - C</labelingLocation> , 
      and in <labelingLocation>the rostral ipsilateral IP - 
      R</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s245">In these cases more labeling is found in 
      <labelingLocation>the contralateral IP - DM and bilaterally in 
      the IP - L</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 14D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s246">A small injection located in <labelingLocation>the 
      caudal part of the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> and 
      extending into <labelingLocation>the medial longitudinal 
      fasciculus and ventral tegmental nucleus of 
      Gudden</labelingLocation> ( RHZ - 44 ) labeled 
      <labelingDescription>IP neurons</labelingDescription> located for 
      the most part in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral IP - 
      L</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s247">In this case , only <labelingDescription>very few 
      cells</labelingDescription> were labeled in <labelingLocation>the 
      IP - R , IP - C , and IP - I</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248"><exptLabel>Two <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injections involve the dorsocaudal part of <injectionLocation>the 
    median raphe nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">In one of these cases ( RHZ45 ; Fig . 14B ) the 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> deposit is quite asymmetric , 
    and in this experiment retrogradely <labelingDescription>labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    R and IP - RL</labelingLocation> , predominantly ipsilateral to the 
    greatest width of the injection site .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Furthermore , cells are labeled in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP - DM</labelingLocation> on both sides but in greater number 
    ipsilaterally ( Fig . 14B ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s251">Farther caudally scattered 
    <labelingDescription>labeled cells</labelingDescription> appear in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - I and IP - L</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Conclusions with respect to descending projections : The 
    results of these anterogradeand retrograde - tracing experiments 
    suggest at least a few conclusions concerning the topographic 
    arrangements of descending interpeduncular projections .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">The <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> evidence 
    indicates that each half of the unpaired parvicellular subnucleus 
    IP - R projects mainly , though not exclusively , to the 
    ipsilateral half of the caudal central gray substance ( cf .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">RHZ-82; Fig. 14A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">These IP - R efferents most probably 
    <labelingModifier>terminate</labelingModifier> in 
    <labelingLocation>the autoradiographially demonstrated zone 
    surrounding and caudally enclosing the dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 12B , C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">A contralateral IP projection to <labelingLocation>the 
    region of the dorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> , as 
    evident in cases RRIP - 4, - 11, and - 14, stems from 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DL and IP - DM</labelingLocation> ( cf 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">RHZ-73, -82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258"><labelingDescription>The fibers</labelingDescription> 
    from the contralateral IP - DM presumably terminate medially in 
    <labelingLocation>the central gray , in the vicinity of the dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation>( cf .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">RRZP-4 and RHZ-73).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">The projection to <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
    dorsolateral tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> is likely to 
    originate in <labelingLocation>the IP - L and IP - 
    DL</labelingLocation> ( RRIP - 11 and - 14 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">The existence of additional efferents from the IP-L, 
    IP-DL, and IP-DM to regions other than those here mentioned cannot, 
    however, be excluded.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">It cannot 
    be determined from the present experiments whether the median raphe 
    nucleus receives projections from all IP subnuclei except the IP - 
    A , as suggested by RHf - 45 ( Fig . 14B ) , or merely provides a 
    passageway for some or all such projections to the caudal central 
    gray substance .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">The retrograde tracing experiments demonstrate that the 
    projection from the IP to the median raphe nucleus is predominantly 
    ipsilateral .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">The projection to the dorsal raphe nucleus appears to 
    originate mainly ipsilaterally, from all subnuclei of the IP except 
    IP-A (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">RHI-31).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Ascending projections Hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Almost all cases in which the injection of 
    <injectionLocation>tritiated leucine</injectionLocation> is located 
    in <labelingLocation>the caudal half of the IP</labelingLocation> 
    show <labelingDescription>some fiber labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the hippocampal formation</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">This labeling is most conspicuous in cases RRIP - 1 and 
    - 11, in both of which <exptLabel>the injection site is centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP - A</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig 
    . 10 B , C , ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s269">As in case RRIP - 15 
    described above , labeling in <labelingLocation>the 
    hippocampus</labelingLocation> mainly involves 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral limb</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13E , 
    case RRIP - 111, but in <labelingLocation>the dorsal limb of the 
    hippocampus( nearer the septum )</labelingLocation> labeling 
    appears to be above background as well .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s270">The 
    interpeduncular efferents seem to be distributed primarily to 
    <labelingLocation>the hilus region and the molecular layer of the 
    fascia dentata , and in lesser number to the stratum radiatum of 
    CA3</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13E ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">In retrograde tracing experiments , <exptLabel>massive 
    injections of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the hippocampus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    were invariably found to label <labelingDescription>a large 
    proportion of the neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - A</labelingLocation> , as well as 
    <labelingDescription>a few of the large 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the caudal part 
    of the IP</labelingLocation> - L Pigs . 15C , 16C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272"><labelingDescription>Many additional labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> appeared in such cases immediately 
    caudal to the IP in <labelingLocation>the median raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , in <labelingLocation>the caudal part 
    of the ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> , and in 
    <labelingLocation>the pontine reticular 
    formation</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 16D ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s273">These 
    labeled neurons exhibit morphological characteristics remarkably 
    similar to those of <labelingDescription>the labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 16C , D ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">The fact that hippocampal 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections consistently 
    labeled <labelingDescription>a number of 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the caudal part of 
    the IP - L</labelingLocation> is compatible with the presence of 
    <labelingDescription>some anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    hippocampus</labelingLocation> in autoradiographic experiments 
    RRIP13 and - 14.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">In these cases the injection site was centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP - C and IP - I</injectionLocation> , to 
    some extent involved <injectionLocation>the IP - 
    L</injectionLocation> , but did not spread into 
    <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the IP - A</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 10B 
    , C ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Septa1 region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">The present autoradiographic findings suggest that 
    efferents from the IP to <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the 
    lateral septal nucleus , the medial septa1 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , and <labelingLocation>the nucleus of 
    the diagonal band of Broca</labelingLocation> likewise originate 
    for the most part in the IP - A .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278"><labelingDescription>The largest number of such 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were labeled in cases RRIP - 1 and - 
    11, in which the center of the injection site includes 
    <injectionLocation>the IP - A</injectionLocation> ( Fig . 13D ; 
    RRIP - 111, while injections centered in <injectionLocation>other 
    parts of the IP</injectionLocation> and not , or only minimally , 
    involving <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the IP - A</injectionSpread> , 
    <labelingDescription>labeled few if any 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">The pattern of labeling in <labelingLocation>the basal 
    forebrain</labelingLocation> in cases RRIP - 2 and - 9, in which 
    the isotope deposit was confined to <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    tegmental area immediately adjacent to the IP</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . lOA ) , agrees with an earlier report by Beckstead et al . ( 
    &apos; 79 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">The distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    septum</labelingLocation> in both these cases differs markedly from 
    that of the interpeduncular efferents described above .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Moreover , <labelingDescription>such 
    fibers</labelingDescription> are distributed over 
    <labelingLocation>a much larger area of the basal 
    forebrain</labelingLocation> that includes <labelingLocation>the 
    nucleus accumbens and the olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">These conclusions from autoradiographic evidence are 
    confirmed by the results of <exptLabel>injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP or WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> in 
    <injectionLocation>the septal area</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283"><exptLabel>Two <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injections , RHI - 26 and - 28, are located in 
    <injectionLocation>the rostral half of the 
    septum</injectionLocation></exptLabel>  and involve also 
    <injectionSpread>the medial part of the nucleus 
    accumbens</injectionSpread>.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s284">In both cases , 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> are confined to <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> except for <labelingDescription>a few 
    scattered labeled cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal part of the IP - L</labelingLocation> 
    ( Fig . 15B ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s285">Continuous with 
    <labelingDescription>the cell labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - A</labelingLocation> 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely filled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> appear in <labelingLocation>the 
    median raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> , as also noted in cases of 
    intrahippocampal iniection .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s286">In accord with the 
    anterograde findings , the rostral , unlabeled pole of the IP is 
    dorvsally and rostrallv manned bv <labelingDescription>cell 
    labeling</labelingDescription> - in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    tegmental  area and interfascicular nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">In case RHI - 38 <exptLabel>a large 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injection in 
    <injectionLocation>the caudal half of the septum , involving the 
    fornix</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , 
    <labelingDescription>labeled numerous cells</labelingDescription> 
    not only in <labelingLocation>the IP - A</labelingLocation> but 
    also in <labelingLocation>the caudal part of IP - 
    L</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289"><labelingDescription>Anterograde fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    thalamus</labelingLocation> , as charted in RRIP - 15 ( Fig . 111, 
    is also observed in several other cases of 
    <injectionLocation>tritiated</injectionLocation> leucine injection 
    in <labelingLocation>the interpeduncular nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    , most clearly in case RRIP - 14.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">In this case <exptLabel>the injection site includes 
    <injectionLocation>the IP - R , IP - C , IP - I , IP - DL , and IP 
    - L</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig . 10B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">The difference between the injection site of RRIP - 14 
    and that of several cases in which fiber labeling in 
    <labelingLocation>the thalamus</labelingLocation> is 
    <labelingDescription>sparse or absent</labelingDescription> is the 
    involvement of the IP - L in RRIP - 14 ( Fig . 10B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Labeling in <labelingLocation>the rostral 
    thalamus</labelingLocation> in case RRIP - 14 is strongest in 
    <labelingLocation>the nucleus gelatinosus</labelingLocation> ( Fig 
    . 13B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">At this rostral level some labeling is seen in 
    <labelingLocation>the midline nuclei</labelingLocation> , in 
    particular in <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
    rhomboideus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294"><labelingDescription>A few labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> accompany the mammillothalamic tract 
    farther rostrally and dorsally and appear to terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the narrow zone between the nuclei 
    anteroventralis and ventralis anterior of the 
    thalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Another thalamic target for labeled interpeduncular 
    efferents in case RRIP - 14 is <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Labeling in <labelingLocation>this 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> is restricted to the lateral one - third 
    but does not extend entirely to <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    border of the nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297"><labelingLocation>The medial half of the lateral 
    habenular nucleus</labelingLocation> exhibits 
    <labelingDescription>sparse fiber labeling</labelingDescription> , 
    but it is not possible to determine whether any of it actually 
    marks axon terminals .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">It seems certain that an interpedunculohabenular 
    connection, if it exists at all, is of very small volume.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Findings in retrograde experiments indicate that 
    interpedunculothalamic projections originate predominantly or even 
    exclusively in <labelingLocation>the lateral columns of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">In case RHI - 24 with a small iontophoretic injection of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the nucleus gelatinosus of the thalamus , 
    immediately medial to the mammillothalamic 
    tract</injectionLocation> , labeled IP cells are exclusively found 
    in <labelingLocation>the IP - DL of both sides , but in largest 
    number contralaterally</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 15E ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">The results of <tracerChemical>HRP or WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injections in <labelingLocation>the 
    mediodorsal thalamic nucleus</labelingLocation> indicate that , in 
    agreement with the anterograde data , only injections involving 
    <injectionLocation>the lateral part of the 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> result in 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde filling of 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">By far <labelingDescription>the greatest number of 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> are found in case RHI - 59, in 
    which an iontophoretic injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> fills almost <injectionLocation>the entire 
    mediodorsal nucleus</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> are most numerous in 
    <labelingLocation>the IPRL</labelingLocation> , ipsilateral to the 
    injection site .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304"><labelingDescription>Further labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> appear in <labelingLocation>the 
    contralateral IP - DL</labelingLocation> , and more caudally also 
    in <labelingLocation>the ipsilateral IP - L </labelingLocation>( 
    Fig . 15D ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">When all available cases are considered together , it 
    appears that <labelingLocation>the rostral lateral subnucleus IP - 
    RL</labelingLocation> is most consistently labeled by HRP deposited 
    in <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal nucleus</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Hypothalamus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Although in <labelingLocation>almost all 
    autoradiographic experiments the hypothalamus</labelingLocation> 
    contained <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> , and injections of 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> resulted in 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> , the present experiments provide no 
    unequivocal evidence for an interpedunculohypothalamic connection 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> is 
    <labelingDescription>sparse</labelingDescription> along the entire 
    trajectory of the medial forebrain bundle .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Evidence of <labelingDescription>very 
    weak</labelingDescription> offsets from the main fiber path to 
    <labelingLocation>the medial hypothalamus</labelingLocation> was 
    found in several cases , but no clear termination areas appeared in 
    any of these .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Injections of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> in 
    <injectionLocation>the lateral hypothalamus</injectionLocation> ( 
    cases RHI - 23 and - 36 ) were found <labelingDescription>to label 
    numerous cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> and <labelingDescription>sporadic 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the caudal part of 
    the IP - L</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 15A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">It is possible that this labeling resulted from 
    interruption of <labelingDescription>interpeduncular 
    fibers</labelingDescription> ascending through 
    <labelingLocation>the medial forebrain</labelingLocation> bundle to 
    the septum and hippocampus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">An actual 
    <labelingDescription>termination</labelingDescription> of 
    interpeduncular efferents in <labelingLocation>the caudal 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , just dorsal to the mammillary 
    bodies , however , seems likely .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">In this <labelingLocation>supramammillary 
    region</labelingLocation> labeling in most autoradiographic cases 
    is denser than it is at more caudal and rostral levels.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s314">Distribution of afferent 
    fibers within IP</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">The present material includes several cases in which 
    <exptLabel>small deposits of <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> 
    or <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> were placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">The results of these experiments are in general 
    agreement with recent accounts of IP afferents based on similar 
    experiments (rat Marchand et al., &apos;80; Contestabile and 
    Flumerfelt, &apos;81; cat: Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">In summary , following injections of retrograde tracers 
    in <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely filled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> appeared in greatest number in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial habenular nucleus , the median and 
    dorsal raphe nuclei , and the caudal part of the central gray 
    substance</labelingLocation> , i . e . , dorsomedial to 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal tegmental nucleus of 
    Gudden</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318"><labelingDescription>Fewer labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral hypothalamus , the nucleus of the diagonal band of Broca , 
    the triangular nucleus of the septum , the lateral pontine 
    tegmentum , and the region of the parabigeminal 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Since the evidence obtained by 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation> has been adequately 
    dealt with in the aforementioned papers , a detailed account of the 
    present material will be omitted .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Instead , several additional experiments will be 
    described in which anterograde tracers were injected in regions 
    known to project to the 1P .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">These anterograde tracing experiments in general reveal 
    that those subnuclei of the IP that were shown in the foregoing 
    experiments to have unique efferent connections are also projected 
    upon in a more or less selective fashion.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">The next section will deal with the distribution within 
    <labelingDescription>the 1P of fibers</labelingDescription> labeled 
    by either <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> or by 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated amino acids</tracerChemical> injected 
    into , respectively , <injectionLocation>the caudal central gray 
    substance , median raphe nucleus , parabigeminal nucleus , habenula 
    , hypothalamus , and the nucleus of the diagonal 
    band</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">A short additional account will be given of intranuclear 
    connections suggested by the findings in the anterograde tracing 
    material .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Caudal central gray substance .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">This term is here used to denote that part of the 
    central gray substance which composes the dorsal tegmental nucleus 
    of Gudden and the nucleus tegmenti dorsalis lateralis , as well as 
    the generally less well - defined cell configurations in which 
    these nuclei lie embedded .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">As a consequence of the intricate composition and small 
    size of the region, none of the isotope injections placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the caudal central gray 
    substance</injectionLocation> in the present study can confidently 
    be localized to any one particular cell group.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Conclusions concerning the projections from each 
    individual cell group can therefore be drawn only with much 
    reservation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Nonetheless , some prominent contrasts between 
    individual cases were noted in <labelingDescription>the fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> , and these differences appear to convey at 
    least a general impression of how the projection from the caudal 
    central gray substance to the IP is organized .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">To illustrate that apparent organization, three of the 
    16 available cases will be described in some detail.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">In case RRLM - 18 the uptake site of the injected 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated leucine</tracerChemical> ( as determined 
    under brightfield illumination ) is very largely confined to 
    <injectionLocation>the caudal half of the dorsal teg mental 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> , spreading slightly beyond the latter s caudal , medial , and dorsal borders , but remaining entirely 
    unilaterally ( Fig . 17A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">As illustrated by Figure 17A , most of 
    <labelingDescription>the fibers</labelingDescription> labeled in 
    this case pass rostrally and ventrally over two separate pathways 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">One of these is a fairly compact , mainly contralateral 
    fiber system taking a straight paramedian course through 
    <labelingLocation>the median raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> , and 
    thus approaching the IP from the dorsocaudal side .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">The other is <labelingDescription>a largely ipsilateral 
    system composed of a multitude of slender , loosely grouped arcuate 
    fascicles</labelingDescription>  that trace a wide lateral curve 
    through <labelingLocation>the caudal midbrain 
    tegmentum</labelingLocation> and reach the base of the brain to 
    form the mammillary peduncle after <labelingModifier>passing in 
    large part through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the medial 
    one - third of the medial lemniscus and the pars compacta of the 
    substantia nigra</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">The former of these two principal efferent systems 
    traces-in the opposite direction-the path followed by the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract of Ganser.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">The other , arciform , system is the main tributary of 
    the mammillary peduncle , but in passing rostralward alongside the 
    IP issues <labelingDescription>numerous 
    fibers</labelingDescription> that enter <labelingLocation>the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> from the lateral side .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Each of these principal fiber systems has its sparser 
    counterpart on the opposite side (Fig. 17A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">The partial decussations allowing for such bilaterality 
    are diffusely scattered from <labelingLocation>the ventral region 
    of the central gray substance down to the base of the median raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Combined with further fiber crossings within the IP 
    itself , these diffuse tegmental decussations result in a 
    predominantly contralateral distribution of IP afferents from the 
    region of the dorsal tegmental nucleus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">This is particularly evident in <labelingLocation>the 
    rostral half of the IP where the contralateral half of the IP - 
    R</labelingLocation> is marked by <labelingDescription>extremely 
    dense fiber labeling</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 17A ) that 
    decreases abruptly both on the medial and lateral side along an 
    almost straight vertical plane ; <labelingLocation>the half of the 
    IP - R</labelingLocation> ipsilateral to the isotope injection 
    exhibits <labelingDescription>only moderate fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">A conspicuous leftright difference favoring the 
    contralateral side is shown also by the IP - A and IP - DM ( Fig . 
    17A ) : both these cell groups display a wide lateral zone of 
    <labelingDescription>dense labeling</labelingDescription> on the 
    contralateral side but are only <labelingDescription>moderately 
    labeled</labelingDescription> ipsilatera1 to the injection .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">A left - right contrast is less pronounced in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral IP columns</labelingLocation> : both 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - L and IP - DL</labelingLocation> exhibit 
    <labelingDescription>moderately dense 
    labeling</labelingDescription> on the contralateral side and 
    <labelingDescription>light - to - moderate 
    labeling</labelingDescription> ipsilaterally ; 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - RL</labelingLocation> is 
    <labelingDescription>only lightly labeled</labelingDescription> on 
    both sides ( Fig . 17A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342"><labelingLocation>The IP - C and IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> in this case display only 
    <labelingDescription>sparse labeling</labelingDescription> that 
    appears confined largely to <labelingLocation>the cell - poor zones 
    between their cell columns</labelingLocation> and is of about equal 
    density on both sides .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Similar cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Findings nearly identical to the foregoing were made in 
    case RRLM-24 (Fig. 18A,B).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">As in RRLM - 18, the injection in this case was strictly 
    unilateral , but it was similar and involved 
    <injectionLocation>little more than the caudal one - third of the 
    dorsal tegmental nucleus</injectionLocation> , spreading somewhat 
    beyond the latter's caudal pole .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Contrasting cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Findings different from those described above were 
    recorded in case RRLM - 6 in which the isotope injection involves 
    <injectionLocation>the rostral two - thirds but not the caudal 
    third of the dorsal tegmental nucleus</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">The injection is larger than in the foregoing cases ( 
    Fig . 17B ) and has spread into <injectionSpread>the adjacent 
    nucleus tegmenti dorsalis lateralis</injectionSpread> , as well as 
    across the midplane into <injectionSpread>the contralateral dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus</injectionSpread> ( not illustrated ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">The resulting fiber labeling is more nearly equal in 
    volume bilaterally than was the case in RRLM - 18 and - 24, but is 
    otherwise similar , at least in <labelingLocation>the caudal half 
    of the IP</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 18D ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">In the rostral half , however , a marked difference 
    appears : whereas in the two foregoing cases <labelingLocation>the 
    contralateral half of the IP - R</labelingLocation> at this level 
    exhibited profuse labeling , in this case only <labelingLocation>a 
    narrow strip marking the IP - Rs lateral border</labelingLocation> 
    is <labelingDescription>densely labeled</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">At the same rostral level <labelingLocation>the 
    IP-RL</labelingLocation> of both sides is <labelingDescription>much 
    more massively labeled</labelingDescription> than in the foregoing 
    cases (Figs. 17B, 18C).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Case RRLM-22 provides a further significant topographic 
    detail.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">In this case the isotope injection is centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the nucleus tegmenti dorsalis 
    lateralis</injectionLocation> but also involves adjoining parts of 
    <injectionLocation>the locus coeruleus and of the middle one - 
    third of the dorsal tegmental nucleus</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">In contrast to the foregoing cases , only 
    <labelingDescription>sparse fiber labeling</labelingDescription> 
    marks <labelingLocation>the median cell groups IP - A , IP - DM , 
    and IP - R</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">The only <labelingDescription>dense 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in this case appears in 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral lateral column ( IP - L , IP - 
    DL , and IP - RL ) </labelingLocation> and is 
    <labelingDescription>particularly massive</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DL</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356"><labelingDescription>The fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IF - 
    L</labelingLocation> of the ipsilateral side is of 
    <labelingDescription>only moderate density</labelingDescription> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">In summary, the following conclusions can be drawn 
    concerning the projection from the caudal central gray substance to 
    the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">First, the projection as a whole is predominantly 
    crossed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Second , although it involves all subnuclei of the IP , 
    it is not distributed to all in equal volume : the most massive 
    components of the connection pass to the contralateral half of the 
    IP - R , most likely from the caudal one - third of the dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus , and to the contralateral IP - L and IP - DL , 
    probably in part from the dorsal tegmental nucleus but in larger 
    volume from the nucleus tegmenti dorsalis lateralis .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Further substantial projections , most likely arising 
    from the caudal half of the dorsal tegmental nucleus , involve the 
    contralateral halves of the IP - A and IP - DM .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">The subnuclei IF&apos;-C and IP-I appear to be only 
    sparsely innervated by the caudal central gray.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Median raphe nucleus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">An injection of <tracerChemical>tritiated amino 
    acids</tracerChemical> was placed in <injectionLocation>the median 
    raphe nucleus</injectionLocation> in three cases , all of which 
    showed comparable patterns of <labelingDescription>anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">In case RRIP - 16 the center of the injection site is 
    located asymmetrically in <injectionLocation>the dorsocaudal part 
    of the median raphe nucleus</injectionLocation>, immediately 
    ventral to the level of the ventral tegmental nucleus of Gudden ( 
    Fig . 19 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingDescription>the 
    IP</labelingDescription> for the greater part is located in 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - C and IP - I</labelingLocation> 
    bilaterally with <labelingDescription>a slightly higher 
    density</labelingDescription> on the side of main involvement of 
    the <labelingLocation>median raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366"><labelingDescription>Labeling is 
    sparse</labelingDescription> over <labelingLocation>the IP-A, IP-R, 
    and SP-DM</labelingLocation>, and <labelingDescription>only little 
    denser</labelingDescription> over <labelingLocation>the 
    IP-L</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Especially in <labelingLocation>the dorsally located 
    subnuclei IP - R , IP - DM , and IP - A</labelingLocation> it is 
    difficult to determine whether <labelingDescription>the sparse 
    labeling</labelingDescription> represents any fiber terminals or 
    exclusively fibers passing to the IP - C and IP - I .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">In experiment RRIP - 17 the injection site is located 
    more ventrally in <injectionLocation>the median raphe 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> , only a short distance dorsocaudal to 
    the IP .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">In this case likewise , most of the label is 
    concentrated over <labelingLocation>the IP - C and IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> , but the IPL is somewhat more densely labeled 
    than it is in RRIP - 16.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Habenular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">In the following paragraphs a collective account will be 
    given of the distribution of <labelingDescription>habenulo - 
    interpeduncular fibers</labelingDescription> labeled anterogradely 
    by <exptLabel>an injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> ( case RHb9 ) in <injectionLocation>the 
    habenular complex</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">The injection involves nearly the entire habenula 
    together with <injectionSpread>adjacent parts of the lateral and 
    mediodorsal thalamic nuclei</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 20A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373"><labelingDescription>Labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> follow the ipsilateral fasciculus 
    retroflexus and enter <labelingLocation>the rostral lateral 
    subnucleus IP - RL</labelingLocation> from the rostral and lateral 
    side .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">From <labelingDescription>the densely 
    labeled</labelingDescription> lateral subnuclei most - perhaps all 
    <labelingDescription>labeled fibers</labelingDescription> sweep 
    across <labelingLocation>the cell groups IP - R , IP - I , and IP - 
    C </labelingLocation> into <labelingLocation>the medial half of the 
    contralateral IP  L</labelingLocation> where many , at least , 
    describe a sharp reverse turn that leads them across the IP for a 
    second time .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">The labeling picture indicates that afferents from the 
    habenula are distributed to all parts of the IP , but the apparent 
    density of their termination varies among the subdivisions ( Fig . 
    20D - F ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376"><labelingDescription>Very dense 
    labeling</labelingDescription> is found bilaterally throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - R</labelingLocation> and ipsilaterally 
    in <labelingLocation>the lateral subnuclei</labelingLocation> ; in 
    <labelingLocation>the latter subdivisions</labelingLocation> it is 
    concentrated in <labelingLocation>three or four 
    regions</labelingLocation> delineated by <labelingDescription>less 
    densely labeled zones</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377"><labelingLocation>The contralateral lateral 
    subnuclei</labelingLocation> show <labelingDescription>only 
    moderate to dense fiber labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>their lateral half</labelingLocation> ; 
    <labelingDescription>the dense label 
    concentration</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    half</labelingLocation> is difficult to interpret because of the 
    great crowding of recurving fibers in this part .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378"><labelingDescription>Fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the IP - I and 
    IP - C</labelingLocation> , the main traverse of crossing and 
    recrossing fasciculus retroflexus fibers , is 
    <labelingDescription>of moderate density</labelingDescription> , 
    equal on the left and right .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Of <labelingLocation>the two caudodorsal subnuclei of 
    the IP , the parvicellular IP - DM</labelingLocation> shows 
    <labelingDescription>very dense labeling 
    bilaterally</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380"><labelingLocation>The magnocellular IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> , on the other hand , is 
    <labelingDescription>much less massively</labelingDescription> 
    labeled ( Fig . 20F ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">In summary , it appears certain that the habenulo - 
    interpeduncular tract is distributed to all subdivisions of the IP 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">The present findings suggest , moreover , that it 
    terminates in greater volume in some subdivisions ( IP - R , IP - 
    DM , and ipsilateral lateral column ) than in others .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">However, a caveat must here be added.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">It is obvious , even on cursory inspection , that the 
    habenulo - interpeduncular tract in addition to its majority of 
    thin fibers ( estimated caliber about 0.5 pm ) contains 
    <labelingDescription>a considerable number of much thicker 
    axons</labelingDescription> ( estimated caliber 2 - 2.5 pm ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">These two fiber categories are not evenly distributed 
    within the IP : the thick axons seem distributed preferentially to 
    the IP - R , IP - DM , and the ipsilateral lateral subnuclei , i . 
    e . , the subdivisions in which the label concentration is highest 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">In light - microscopic experiments by anterograde 
    <tracerChemical>HRP</tracerChemical> labeling the relative volume 
    of a connection is judged by the apparent packing density of 
    labeled axon arborizations and synaptic endstructures in the target 
    area .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Since this density is determined not only by the number 
    but also by the caliber of the labeled structues, the statements 
    made in the foregoing account have at best descriptive value but 
    only limited quantitative significance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">It is possible , for example , that the comparatively 
    light - appearing IP - I , IP - C , and IP - A in actuality receive 
    a proportionally greater number of fibers from the habenula than do 
    the heavily labeled IP - R , IPDM , and IP - L .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Further studies will be needed to determine the 
    comparative volume of each individual component of the 
    habenulo-interpeduncular connection.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Lateral hypothalamic region .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">The present material includes several cases in which 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated amino acids</tracerChemical> were placed 
    in <injectionLocation>the lateral hypothalamus</injectionLocation> 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">In case RRSI - 87 the center of the isotope injection 
    lies in <injectionLocation>a frontal plane approximately 
    corresponding to the rostral pole of the ventromedial hypothalamic 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> ( Fig . 21A ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393"><labelingDescription>Massive fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> follows the medial forebrain bundle 
    to the midbrain where labeling is most concentrated ipsilaterally 
    in <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental area and in and 
    alongside the median raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">The labeling of <labelingLocation>these 
    fields</labelingLocation> is augmented by fibers that have reached 
    the midbrain by way of the stria medullaris and fasciculus 
    retroflexus .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">The labeling pattern suggests that the lateral 
    hypothalamus is not a main source of afferents to the 
    interpeduncular nucleus .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">In <labelingLocation>the rostral half of the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> labeling is 
    <labelingDescription>sparse</labelingDescription> , but from about 
    its midlevel caudalward <labelingDescription>increasing numbers of 
    labeled fibers</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> from <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsolaterally adjacent ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 21A ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Upon entering , these fibers for the most part follow 
    the border between the dorsal and lateral subnuclei , which show 
    <labelingDescription>some sparse labeling 
    bilaterally</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398"><labelingDescription>Most labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    I</labelingLocation> , where their main distribution bilaterally 
    involves <labelingLocation>a narrow zone along the dorsal and 
    lateral borders of this subnucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">In <labelingLocation>the caudal third of the 
    IP</labelingLocation> , bilateral labeling largely coincides with 
    the three vertical cell columns that occupy <labelingLocation>the 
    intermediate subnuclei IP - I and the median subnucleus IP - 
    C</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Nudeus of the diagonal band ( NDB ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">The following description is based mainly upon case RRSI 
    - 75, one of four cases of <tracerChemical>tritiated amino 
    acid</tracerChemical> injection in <injectionLocation>the nucleus 
    of the diagonal band</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">In RRSI - 75 the injection is located at 
    <injectionLocation>the base of the septum</injectionLocation> and 
    involves primarily <injectionLocation>the transition between the 
    vertical and the horizontal limb of the nucleus</injectionLocation> 
    ( Fig . 21B ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">thalamic efferents , are distributed over the ventral 
    tegmental area , from which <labelingDescription>a modest 
    number</labelingDescription> enter <labelingLocation>the 
    interpeduncular nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 21B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">In contrast to hypothalamic fibers, labeled NDB 
    efferents enter <labelingLocation>the IP</labelingLocation> 
    throughout its length.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Their main distribution involves <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal lateral subnucleus IP - DL</labelingLocation> , almost 
    exclusively on the ipsilateral side , and <labelingLocation>the IP 
    - I , IP - C , and IP - R bilaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Even in these IP divisions, labeling must be rated 
    <labelingDescription>sparse</labelingDescription>, and it thus 
    appears that the NDB, like the lateral hypothalamic region, is only 
    a minor source of afferents to the IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Parabigeminal region The parabigemino - interpeduncular 
    projection of the rat is shown most clearly in case RHLM - 11 in 
    which a small injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> fills <injectionLocation>the entire 
    parabigeminal nucleus</injectionLocation> and spreads into 
    <injectionSpread>adjacent parts of the nuclei peripeduncularis , 
    parabrachialis dorsalis , and lemnisci lateralis</injectionSpread> 
    ( Fig . 20B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">In this case <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of 
    labeled axon terminals</labelingDescription> selectively fills 
    <labelingLocation>a narrow strip of the interpeduncular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> immediately within <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsolateral border of the rostral lateral subnucleus ( IP - RL 
    )</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">This circumscript field of labeling is present on both 
    sides but is denser contralateral to the injection (Fig. 2OC).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">A slight distance farther caudally 
    <labelingDescription>much sparser labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>the IP 
    - DL</labelingLocation> , more numerous contrathan ipsilaterally 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Most or all of <labelingDescription>the terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> appears to be associated with thin 
    fibers approaching <labelingLocation>the interpeduncular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> from the lateral side and reaching 
    <labelingLocation>the contralateral IP - DL and IP - 
    RL</labelingLocation> by skirting the dorsal border of 
    <labelingLocation>the IP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">The findings in both of the two available cases of 
    successful injection clearly indicate that the parabigeminal region 
    is the source of a modest projection to the IP that is remarkable 
    chiefly for its limited , sharply defined distribution within the 
    nucleus .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Intranuclear connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Owing to the diffusion of tracer around the injection 
    site it is difficult to identify short-axon connections by the 
    autoradiographic method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Nevertheless , some of the iontophoretic injections of 
    <tracerChemical>tritiated leucine</tracerChemical> in 
    <injectionLocation>the IP</injectionLocation> are small enough to 
    permit some cautious remarks about connections between different 
    parts of the IP .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">In experiment RRZP - 6 the injection site includes 
    <injectionLocation>the rostral part of the IP - 
    R</injectionLocation> ( Figs . 10A , 22 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">The arrangement of silver grains over 
    <labelingLocation>the caudal half of the IP</labelingLocation> 
    suggests labeling that is not due to mere diffusion.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420"><labelingLocation>The caudal half of the IP - 
    L</labelingLocation> , especially on the side where most of the 
    label is deposited , is <labelingDescription>more densely 
    labeled</labelingDescription> than <labelingLocation>the adjacent 
    medial lemniscus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 22 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Likewise , <labelingLocation>the IP - 
    A</labelingLocation> appears to be <labelingDescription>more 
    heavily labeled</labelingDescription> than would be expected from 
    diffusion or labeling of passing fibers , whereas 
    <labelingLocation>the IP - DM</labelingLocation> by contrast 
    contains only <labelingDescription>sparse 
    label</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Silver grains are predominantly distributed over the 
    neuropil of the IPA, and the labeling becomes 
    <labelingDescription>less intense</labelingDescription> at the 
    boundaries of this subnucleus (Fig. 22).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">This observation clearly suggests a projection from the 
    IP-R to the IP-A.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Other experiments not here reported provide similar 
    evidence of a projection from the IP - A to the IP - C and IP - L 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Further connections intrinsic to the IP cannot be 
    recognized in the present material.</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s426">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">As could be expected from preexisting data, the present 
    study has revealed a complexity of cytoarchitecture, connectivity, 
    and histochemical parcellation that is remarkable for a structure 
    as small and circumscript as the interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Not surprising in view of such intricacy, the numerous 
    studies done thus far-including the present one-have left many 
    questions concerning each of these three major aspects of 
    interpeduncular anatomy unanswered.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">As will become evident from the discussion to follow, 
    such questions are particularly likely to be encountered when 
    attempts are made to correlate cytoarchitectural with connectional 
    data, and the latter with the histochemical aspects of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">In the first part of this discussion, the 
    cytoarchitectural subdivision and the fiber connections of the IP 
    will be considered together.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">A later section will deal with the problem of 
    correlating these more strictly morphological data with the 
    distribution of acetylcholinesterase activity, and of substance 
    P-like and enkephalin-like immunoreactivity within the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Finally, some aspects of the functional role of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus will be considered in the light of the 
    present connectional findings.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="CourierNewPS-ItalicMT" id="s433">To facilitate a 
    comparison of the various hodological and histochemical aspects of 
    the different subnuclei of the intera + a++ +</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">peduncular nucleus, the data available at present are 
    compiled in Table 1 in a semiquantitative way.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Figure 23 summarizes the main features of the 
    af&apos;ferent and efferent connections of the IP in a more graphic 
    manner.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s436">Cytoarchitecture and 
    fiber connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Although architectonically the interpeduncular nucleus 
    (IP) appears as a circumscript morphological entity into the 
    ventral part of the mesencephalon, parts of what now seems certain 
    to belong to the IP have been included in the ventral tegmental 
    area or the raphe nuclei (e.g., Palkovits and Jacobowitz, &apos;74; 
    Cuello et al., &apos;78; Steinbusch, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">The distinctness and unity of the IP with respect to its 
    surrounding structures are expressed most explicitly, perhaps, by 
    its afferent connections, in particular by the massive habenular 
    input that distributes over all parts of the IP (see Fig.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s439">
    20).</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s440">
    Nevertheless, when further architectonic and hodological criteria 
    are applied, it is clear that within the IP a number of more or 
    less independent units can be recognized, each having its own 
    unique cytoarchitecture and combination of afferent and efferent 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s441">
    The parcellation proposed by Ives (&apos;71) for the IP of rodents 
    provides a basic scheme, in which further subdivisions can be 
    made.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s442">
    Ives&apos;s pattern of organization of the IP implies a central 
    region (pars medialis) flanked laterally on either side by a 
    lateral cell column (pars lateralis) and covered dorsally by two 
    unpaired nuclei that form a bridge between the two lateral 
    columns.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s443">
    The more rostral of these dorsal subnuclei is composed of the 
    smallest cells in the IP (pars dorsalis parvicellularis of Ives; 
    see also Hamill and Lenn, &apos;W, whereas the caudal group is 
    formed by neurons that are notably larger and differ in shape from 
    those encountered farther rostrally (pars dorsalis 
    magnocellularis).</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle" format="ArialMT" id="s444">
    Although within these four basic cell groups delineated by Ives 
    further subdivisions have been proposed and confirmed (Hamill and 
    Lenn, &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84; Lenn and Hamill, 
    &apos;84; the present study), in several of the observa++ + ++ f</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">tions here described Ives&apos;s fundamental pattern is 
    apparent (e.g., acetylcholinesterase staining, substance P 
    immunoreactivity, connectivity of the IP with the habenula, the 
    raphe nuclei, and the caudal central gray substance).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Therefore, although in the present study the recently 
    proposed compromise nomenclature of Lenn and Hamill (&apos;84) has 
    been adopted, the cytoarchitecture and fiber connections of the 
    various subnuclei will be dealt with in a sequential order that 
    follows the scheme proposed by Ives (&apos;71).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s447">The rostra1 and 
    dorsal medial subnuclei (IP-R and ZP-</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">OM).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">The only important discrepancy between the parcellation 
    of the IP here followed and the recently proposed scheme of Lenn 
    and Hamill t&apos;84), which is mainly based on a number of recent 
    detailed studies (Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84; Hamill et al., 
    &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;841, concerns the rostral 
    subnucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">In the present study an area is distinguished in the 
    caudal half of the rostral subnucleus (as defined by Lenn and 
    Hamill, &apos;84) that differs cytoarchitectonically from the rest 
    of the subnucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">In Nissl-stained material this area at middle longitudes 
    of the IP takes the shape of a paired ovoid cell cluster in the 
    dorsal part of the IP that consists of neurons slightly smaller and 
    more closely spaced than those found more rostrally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Owing to their position these cell clusters are here 
    called the dorsal medial subnuclei GP-DM) to distinguish them from 
    the rest of the unpaired rostral subnucleus (IP-R).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">IP-DM is bordered caudally by the more magnocellular 
    apical subnucleus (IP-A); depending on the plane of sectioning, the 
    IP-DM may appear as the more dorsally placed of the two 
    last-mentioned nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">The present study has provided several reasons besides 
    cytoarchitecture to delineate the IP-DM from the IPR (see Figs. 
    1-7, Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">The two differ with respect to myelin content, 
    acetylcholinesterase activity, and substance P-like, 
    enkephalin-like, and serotonin-like immu.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">noreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Furthermore, although the IP-R and LP-DM are both 
    reciprocally connected with the median and dorsal raphe nuclei and 
    the caudal central gray substance, and both receive fibers from the 
    medial habenular nucleus, these connections differ with respect to 
    volume and topography (see Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Though Hamill et al. (&apos;84) and Hemmendinger and 
    Moore (&apos;84) did not distinguish between the IP-R and IP-DM as 
    separate entities, they found differences in the distribution of 
    substance P, enkephalin and serotonin immunoreactivity between the 
    two regions similar to those here described.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Moreover, as indicated in the schemes of Hamill et al. 
    (&apos;84), differences in cholecystokinin (CCK) and vasoactive 
    intestinal polypeptide (VIP) immunoreactivity might also 
    distinguish the IP-R from the IP-DM.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">The present findings indicate that the main efferent 
    projections of the IP-R and IP-DM follow the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract to the median and dorsal raphe nuclei 
    and the caudal central gray substance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">These projections appear to terminate in greatest 
    density around the dorsal and ventral tegmental nuclei of Gudden, 
    but only sparsely within the borders of these cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">This pattern is very similar to that followed by the 
    direct projections to these regions from the lateral habenular 
    nucleus (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Similarly, the reciprocating projection from the caudal 
    central gray substance to the interpeduncular nucleus for the 
    greater part does not originate in the circumscript dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus itself but immediately dorsomedial to it in the 
    nucleus incertus and in the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus 
    (Marchand et al., &apos;80; Hamill and Jacobowitz, &apos;84; the 
    present observations).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">It is interesting to note that, according to the present 
    retrograde-labeling evidence, the projections from the IP-R and 
    IP-DM to the raphe nuclei and the caudal central gray substance are 
    for the most part ipsilateral, with the exception of the fibers 
    from the IP-DM to the dorsolateral teg mental nucleus, which are 
    mainly crossed (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">This contrasts with the predominantly crossed 
    disposition of the reciprocating projections from the caudal 
    central gray to the IP-R and IP-DM.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Isotope injections involving the caudal half of the 
    central gray substance or, more rostrally, its medial part, result 
    in a very characteristic labeling pattern: in the midline a 
    surprisingly sharp border appears between the heavy contralateral 
    and much sparser ipsilateral labeling in the IP-R, a subnucleus 
    that by all other histological or hodological criteria is an 
    unpaired structure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">Except for recent autoradiographic evidence 
    (Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84), this remarkable laterality has 
    not been noted in earlier reports on these projections (Nauta and 
    Kuypers, &apos;58; Morest, &apos;61; Ban and Zyo, &apos;63; Briggs 
    and Kaelber, &apos;71), which is most likely due to the inherent 
    restrictions of the lesion techniques used in these earlier 
    studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">It is apparent from the present study that the efferent 
    fibers from onehalf of the caudal central gray follow four routes 
    to the IP and more rostra1 structures: the ipsiand contralateral 
    mammillary peduncles and the ipsiand contralateral 
    interpedunculotegmental tracts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">As the decussating fibers in part travel over some 
    distance through the contralateral half of the caudal central gray 
    substance, lesions of the central gray may well interrupt these 
    fibers, thus obscuring the laterality of the projection.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">The functional significance of the topographic 
    arrangement of the reciprocal connections between the caudal 
    central gray and the interpeduncular nucleus remains unclear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">However, it is apparent that one-half of the caudal 
    central gray may affect its contralateral counterpart both directly 
    via crossing homologous projections (Groenewegen et al., &apos;83c; 
    Groenewegen and Van Dijk, &apos;84; Liu et al., &apos;84) and, more 
    massively, by way of the contralateral half of the IP-R.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">The results of the present anterograde-tracing 
    experiments suggest a further point-to-point relationship between 
    the caudal central gray and the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Evidence was found that the most medial part of the 
    dorsal tegmental region projects (largely contralaterally) to the 
    medial part of the IP-R, while more lateral parts of the region 
    project to a more lateral zone of the IP-R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">This suggestion of an orderly medial-to-lateral 
    topography has been further substantiated in recent experiments in 
    our laboratory by the method of immunohistochemical localization of 
    anterogradely transported Phaseolus uulgaris lectin (Gerfen and 
    Sawchenko, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">These experiments (Groenewegen and Van Dijk, &apos;84) 
    have shown that the dorsal tegmental afferents of the IP are in 
    large part sagittally oriented in the IP-R and establish an orderly 
    mediolateral relationship between the dorsal tegmental region of 
    one side and the contralateral half of the IP-R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">As a consequence of this sagittal disposition, the 
    dorsal-tegmental afferents are oriented perpendicular to the fibers 
    composing the other main input to the IP-R: the 
    habenulo-interpeduncular tract, which originates in the medial 
    habenular nucleus and distributes to the IP-R in 
    transverse-horizontal planes (Cajal, &apos;11; Herkenham and Nauta, 
    &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">The projection of the medial habenula to the IP-R, 
    likewise, is topographically organized: a ventral-to-dorsal 
    gradient in the IP-R corresponds to a medialto-lateral gradient in 
    the medial habenular nucleus (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79; 
    Contestabile and Flumerfelt, &quot;81; Marchand et al., 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">This nonrandom fiber arrangement suggests the 
    possibility of a systematic integration of the inputs conveyed by 
    the two most massive afferent connections of the interpeduncular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">The apical subnucleus (IP-A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">The apical subnucleus (IP-A) forms a distinct subnucleus 
    in the caudodorsal IrP, embedded partially in the more rostrally 
    located subnuclei IP-R and IP-DM.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Furthermore, the IP-A is caudally continuous with the 
    median raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Although a number of earlier reports likewise consider 
    the IP-A part of the interpeduncular nucleus (cat: Berman, 
    &apos;68; Kapadia and DeLanerolle, &apos;84; rat: Baisden et al., 
    &apos;79; Riley and Moore, &apos;81; Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84; 
    Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84), several other authors include 
    the IP-A in the raphe nuclei Balkovits and Jacobowitz, &apos;74; 
    their &quot;nucleus linearis oralis,&quot; a term also adopted by 
    Ljungdahl et al., &apos;78; and Steinbusch, &apos;81, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">The reason to regard the IP-A as part of the 
    interpeduncular complex in the present study is its topographic 
    relationship with the other subnuclei of the IF and the fact that 
    its constituent neurons, although morphologically very similar to 
    the cells of the median raphe nucleus, show a preferential, 
    horizontal orientation and are closely spaced, in contrast to the 
    caudally adjacent raphe cells, which are more loosely packed and 
    lack any preferential orientation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">However, a clear caudal border of the IPA is not 
    evident.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Moreover, in a number of other respects, to be dealt 
    with next, the IP-A resembles the raphe nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">In agreement with earlier reports (Baisden et al. 
    &apos;79, Wyss et al., &apos;79; Riley and Moore, &apos;80; Shibata 
    and Suzuki, &apos;84) the present findings indicate that 
    projections from the IP-A ascend to the septum and hippocampus, and 
    possibly also to the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">It should be emphasized, however, that similar 
    projections originate in the caudal part of the lateral subnucleus 
    of the IP (IP-L) and in the median raphe nucleus, a matter also 
    discussed in the above-mentioned studies.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Furthermore, in accord with several immunohistochemical 
    studies (rat: Steinbusch, &apos;81; Hamill et al., &apos;84; 
    Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84; cat: Kapadia and DeLanerolle, 
    &apos;84a), the present study showed that both the IPA and the 
    mesencephalic raphe nuclei contain cell bodies immunoreactive for 
    serotonin.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">By retrograde tracing of fluorescent dyes, combined with 
    immunohistochemical staining for serotonin, Kohler et al. 
    (&apos;82) have demonstrated that part of the fibers to the septum 
    are serotoninergic and originate in the dorsal and median raphe 
    nuclei and in the nucleus linearis oralis (the present IP-A).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Accordingly, injections of retrograde fluorescent 
    tracers in the ventral part of the hippocampus were found to result 
    in retrograde labeling of some IP-A cells exhibiting serotonin-like 
    immunoreactivity (Groenewegen and Steinbusch, &apos;84), indicating 
    that the projection from the IP to the ventral hippocampus is, at 
    least in part, serotoninergic.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">According to the present findings the IP-A receives 
    fibers predominantly from the caudal central gray substance (Table 
    1) while an additional but relatively sparse input comes from the 
    habenula.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Moreover, although the present autoradiographic findings 
    cannot be taken as conclusive, there is some evidence of an 
    intrinsic projection from the IP-R to IP-A, a connection that the 
    latter subnucleus shares with the median raphe nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">The central and intermediate subnuclei (IP-C and 
    IPI).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">The central nucleus (IP-C) and the two paramedian 
    intermediate subnuclei UP-I) together constitute the core region, 
    or pars medialis (Ives, &apos;71), of the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">It is noteworthy that these three centrally placed 
    subnuclei differ in several respects from the surrounding lateral, 
    dorsal, and rostral IP subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">For example, they are collectively distinguished from 
    adjacent subnuclei by a low content in acetylcholinesterase and a 
    weak or even negative substance P-like and serotonin-like 
    immunoreactivity (Hamill et al., &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, 
    &apos;84; Rotter and Jacobowitz, &apos;84; Artymyshyn and Murray, 
    &apos;85; the present study, Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">This is not to suggest that the IP-C and IP-I are 
    indistinguishable from each other also by other criteria.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">The two subnuclei have different cytoand 
    myeloarchitectonic features, and a further reason to distinguish 
    between them is the unique presence of crest-synapses in the IP-I 
    (Lenn, &apos;76; Lenn et al., &apos;83; Murray et al., &apos;79; 
    Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Additional differences between the IP-C and IPI found in 
    the present study mainly concern the distribution of enkephalin 
    immunoreactivity and some slight contrasts in their afferent and 
    efferent connectivity.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Enkephalin is absent in the IP-I, whereas sparse 
    positive fibers are present throughout the IP-C, with a few 
    enkephalin-stained neurons in its caudodorsal part, adjacent to the 
    IP-A.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">According to the present evidence, the IP-C and IP-I 
    receive their main input from the habenula and from the median 
    raphe nucleus, while sparser afferents come from cells in the 
    dorsal tegmental region, the nucleus of the diagonal band, and the 
    hypothalamus (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Habenular fibers traverse the rostral IP-C and IP-I in 
    transverse-horizontal planes as described previously (Cajal, 
    &apos;11; Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">In their caudal part the distribution of habenular 
    afferents appears to be more irregularly clustered, with a 
    particularly dense termination in the IP-I.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">In agreement with a recent retrograde-tracing study 
    (Shibata and Suzuki, &apos;841, the present study has shown that 
    efferent IP fibers originating in the IP-C and to a lesser degree 
    in the IP-I are directed mainly to the caudal central gray 
    substance and the median raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">It must, however, be noted that, compared with other 
    subnuclei of the IP, only a relatively small number of IP-C and 
    IP-I cells are labeled by tracer injections in the above-mentioned 
    areas, and that these cells are largely confined to caudal regions 
    of these subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">This suggests the possibility that most of the neurons 
    of the IP-C and IP-I subserve intrinsic connections within the 
    IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">The lateral subnuclei (IP-RL, IP-DL, and IPL).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Although Ives (&apos;71) considered the pars lateralis 
    (PL) of the interpeduncular nucleus a cytoarchitectonic entity, 
    reasons can be found to subdivide this lateral part of the IP into 
    several subunits.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">In agreement with recent studies of the IP (cat: Berman, 
    &apos;68; rat: Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84; Hemmendinger and Moore, 
    &apos;841, the lateral IP in the present account has been 
    subdivided into a rostral (IP-RL), a dorsal (IP-DL), and a main 
    caudal (IP-L) subnucleus on the basis of differences in 
    cytoarchitecture, histochemistry, and connectivity (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">The borders between these subnuclei are not sharply 
    defined.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">In the cell-poor medial zone that forms the border 
    between the lateral subnuclei and the intermediate subnucleus IP-I 
    a multitude of habenulo-interpeduncular fibers collect, recurving 
    to traverse the medially located subnuclei IP-R, IP-C, and IP-I in 
    their peculiar &quot;figure 8&quot; course through the 
    interpeduncular nucleus (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79; the present 
    study).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Caudally, subnucleus IP-L cannot be sharply delimited 
    from the pontine gray and ventral tegmental area, a vagueness 
    comparable to that of the caudal border of the IP-A.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">The present evidence indicates that the lateral part of 
    the IP contributes to both the ascending and descending projections 
    of the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">All three of its subnuclei project ipsilaterally to the 
    caudal central gray substance, including the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Although minor differences may exist between the 
    projections from different parts of the lateral IP to the central 
    gray, no evidence of a prominent topographic relationship could be 
    found.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Projections to the median raphe nucleus appear to arise 
    mainly from the rostral IP-RL (Table I).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">These descending projections of the lateral subnuclei 
    are reciprocated by fibers from the caudal central gray substance 
    and dorsal raphe nucleus, and in lesser number also from the median 
    raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">It must be noted that these return projections to the 
    lateral subnuclei are mainly crossed and that they originate more 
    rostrally and laterally in the caudal central gray than do the 
    projections to the IPR, in keeping with the orderly mediolateral 
    organization of the central-gray projections to the IP that was 
    emphasized earlier in this discussion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">In addition to the derents from the caudal central gray 
    and the raphe nuclei, the lateral subnuclei receive a massive input 
    from the habenula, in particular from the dorsal part of the medial 
    habenular nucleus (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79; the present 
    study).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">An interesting result of the present study is the 
    evidence that all ascending IP efferents originate either in the 
    IP-A, as discussed above, or in one or more of the different 
    lateral subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Thus, the present retrograde-labeling experiments showed 
    that fibers to the septum and hippocampus arise not only from the 
    IP-A but also from the caudal part of the IP-L.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">These findings agree with the earlier accounts of Wyss 
    et al. (&apos;79, Baisden et al. (&apos;79), and Shibata and Suzuki 
    (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Kohler et al. (&apos;82) have demonstrated that the 
    projection to the septum from the IP-L-a cell group that these 
    authors include among the raphe nuclei-is serotoninergic at least 
    in part.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Recent experiments combining immunohistochemistry and 
    retrograde tracing of fluorescent dyes have shown that this is also 
    true for the projection from the IP-L to the hippocampus 
    (Groenewegen and Steinbusch, &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">The origin of the IP projections to the thalamus appears 
    to be restricted to the more rostral of the lateral subnuclei, the 
    IP-DL and IP-RL.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">A widely distributed interpedunculothalamic pathway was 
    reported from studies that used degeneration techniques in the rat 
    and cat (Massopust and Thompson, &apos;62; Smaha and Kaelber, 
    &apos;73).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">However, the results of the present autoradiographic 
    tracing experiments, in agreement with the study of Stofer and 
    Edwards (&apos;78) in the cat, indicate that interpeduncular fibers 
    to the thalamus reach only the nuclei mediodorsalis and 
    gelatinosus; no such fibers could with certainty be traced to the 
    habenula.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">As regards the projection from the IP to the mediodorsal 
    nucleus, our findings in the rat differ somewhat from those of 
    Velayos and Reinoso-Suarez (&apos;82) in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">In the latter species the projection for the most part 
    appears to innervate the medial portion of the mediodorsal 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">In addition, in the cat its origin within the IP is not 
    restricted to the lateral subnuclei, as appears to be the case in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">According to our findings, IP efferents in the rat 
    completely avoid the medial, limbic-system-related part of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus and remain confined to the latter&apos;s 
    lateral subdivision.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">This lateral zone receives additional derents from the 
    caudal central gray substance, the pars reticulata of the 
    substantia nigra, and the deep layers of the superior colliculus 
    (Groenewegen and Nauta, &apos;82, &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Projections from the interpeduncular nucleus to the 
    nucleus gelatinosus thalami, which forms part of the nucleus 
    submedius of other authors (e.g., Craig and Burton, &apos;81; Craig 
    et al., &apos;82; Price and Slotnick, &apos;831, appear not to have 
    been reported before.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">It is remarkable that this projection originates almost 
    exclusively in the IP-DL and that it exhibits a contralateral 
    predominance (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">It must be noted that its termination is restricted to 
    the most rostral part of the nucleus gelatinosus, a region probably 
    corresponding to the anterior part of the nucleus submedius (SMa of 
    Craig et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">The projection area thus lies immediately ventral to, 
    but completely avoids, the dorsal area (SMd) which according to 
    Craig and Burton (&apos;81) receives a substantial projection from 
    the pars caudalis of the spinal trigeminal nucleus and the dorsal 
    horn of the spinal cord, and is likely to be involved in 
    nociception.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">According to Craig et al. (&apos;82) the nucleus 
    gelatinosus is reciprocally connected with the ventrolateral 
    orbital cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">The recent report of Price and Slotnick (&apos;83) 
    indicates that the anterior part of the nucleus submedius (SMa; our 
    nucleus gelatinosus) may differ from its more caudal parts by being 
    less clearly associated with the olfactory system than are the 
    latter.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s539">Interpeduncular 
    connections and cholinergic transmission</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">In accord with a number of earlier reports, beginning 
    with the publication by Lewis and Shute (&apos;671, the present 
    study has demonstrated a high activity of acetylcholinesterase 
    (AChE), differentially distributed over different parts of the IP 
    (Table 1; Hamill and Lenn, &apos;84; Flumerfelt and Contestabile, 
    &apos;82; Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84; Rotter and Jacobowitz, 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">It must be emphasized, however, that any relation of 
    this AChE activity pattern to the cholinergic innervation pattern 
    of the IP remains to be established.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">First, the presence of a high activity of AChE may be a 
    prerequisite for a cholinergic system but cannot by itself reliably 
    identify a cell group or its efferents as cholinergic (Lehman and 
    Fibiger &apos;79; Fibiger, &apos;82; Wainer et al., &apos;84; 
    Butcher and Woolf, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Second, recent studies have indicated that AChE may also 
    play a role in the degradation of several peptides that are 
    abundantly present in the IP (Chubb et al., &apos;80, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">According to the lesion experiments of Flumerfelt and 
    Contestabile (&apos;821, most of the AChE activity of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus appears to be intrinsic, i.e., associated 
    with cells and their processes within the IP proper.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Even total interruption of the fasciculus retroflexus, 
    very likely to include the cholinergic pathways to the IP from the 
    habenula and, potentially, from the basal forebrain, has only 
    little effect on the AChE activity level in the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Although there is still much debate on the issue of 
    whether the habenulo-interpeduncular pathway is cholinergic or not 
    (reviews: Fibiger, &apos;82; Butcher and Woolf, &apos;84; Wainer et 
    al., &apos;84), the findings of Flumerfelt and Contestabile 
    (&apos;82) indicate that it does contain AChE, even though not 
    enough to account for more than a small proportion of the AChE 
    activity in the IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">The fact that the IP is the site of a massive 
    cholinergic mechanism is evident from earlier studies in which the 
    nucleus was found to be the site of the highest activity of the 
    acetylcholine-synthetizing enzyme choline acetyltransferase (CUT) 
    and of the highest choline uptake in the entire brain (Palkovits et 
    al., &apos;74; Sorimachi et al., &apos;74; Leranth et al., 
    &apos;75; Kuhar et al., &apos;75; Cheney et al., &apos;75; Hattori 
    et al., &apos;77; Sastry et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">The actual presence of ChAT in fibers and terminals 
    within the IP was recently confirmed with immunohistochemical 
    techniques (cat: Kimura et al., &apos;80; rat: Sofroniew et al., 
    &apos;82; Houser et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">According to the immunohistochemical study of Houser et 
    al. (&apos;83) in the rat, there appears to be a rather specific 
    distribution of intense ChAT immunoreactivity in the IP with 
    respect to its subnuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">In their material, heavy ChAT staining marks the rostral 
    subnucleus IP-R and the laterally adjacent IP-RL (their Fig. 2); 
    the latter subnucleus contains the habenulo-interpeduncular tract, 
    which is also stained.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Caudally in the IP only the central region, encompassing 
    the subnuclei IP-C and IF&apos;-I, is heavily stained (their Fig. 
    5A).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">In addition, it was established by Houser et al. 
    (&apos;83) that the ventral part of the medial habenular nucleus 
    contains ChAT-positive neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">This location of CUT-positive neurons in the habenula, 
    as well as the distribution pattern of ChAT-positive fibers and 
    terminals over the IP subnuclei, corresponds rather well with the 
    topographical organization in the habenulo-interpeduncular pathway: 
    the ventral part of the medial habenula, for example, is known to 
    project to the medial IP and the medial part of the medial habenula 
    to ventral portions of the IP (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;79; 
    Marchand et al., &apos;80; Contestabile and Flumerfelt, &apos;81; 
    Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">This similarity strongly suggests a cholinergic nature 
    of the habenulo-interpeduncular pathway, a notion supported by the 
    results of a study using transmitter-specific retrograde labeling 
    (Villani et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">In that study injections of tritiated choline in the IP 
    resulted in heavy labeling of neurons in the medial habenula.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Unfortunately, no data are available on the relation 
    between the distribution patterns of ChAT immunoreactivity and 
    cholinergic receptor sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">In a recent study Rotter and Jacobowitz (&apos;84) have 
    shown rather specific and extensively overlapping distributions in 
    the IP for both muscarinic and nicotinic receptor sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">When compared with the immunohistochemical study of 
    Houser et al. (&apos;83), there appears to be only partial overlap 
    between ChAT immunoreactivity and the distribution of cholinergic 
    receptors as determined by Rotter and Jacobowitz (&apos;84; see 
    also Clarke et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Besides emphasizing the habenula as a likely source of 
    cholinergic input to the IP, possible alternative origins of 
    cholinergic fibers may be considered.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Structures that are known to contain cholinergic cells 
    (Kimura et al., &apos;80, &apos;84; Sofroniew et al., &apos;82, 
    &apos;83; Houser et al., &apos;83; Mesulam et al., &apos;83; 
    Armstrong et al., &apos;83) and have been shown to distribute 
    fibers to the IP include the nucleus of the diagonal band and the 
    dorsolateral tegmental nucleus (Contestabile and Flumerfelt, 
    &apos;81; Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;82; Hamill and Jacobowitz, 
    &apos;84; the present study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Both anterograde and retrograde studies have shown that 
    neurons in the diagonal band project to the IP (Domesick, &apos;76; 
    Contestabile and Flumerfelt, &apos;81; Hayakawa and Zyo, &apos;82; 
    Hamill and Fass, &apos;84; Hamill and Jacobowitz, &apos;84; the 
    present study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">The present evidence suggests that this projection is 
    distributed chiefly to the ipsilateral IP-DL and to the IP-R, IP-C, 
    and IP-I bilaterally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">It also suggests, however, that fibers from the nucleus 
    of the diagonal band are among the sparsest IP afferents, and that 
    they travel mainly, if not entirely, with the medial forebrain 
    bundle rather than with the stria medullaris and fasciculus 
    retroflexus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">These findings cannot satisfactorily explain reports of 
    a marked decrease of ChAT activity in the IP following lesions of 
    the diagonalband region (Gottesfeld and Jacobowitz, &apos;78) or 
    interruption of the stria medullaris (Kataoka et al., &apos;77; 
    Gottesfeld and Jacobowitz, &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Cholinergic neurons in the dorsal tegmental region have 
    been identified with several methods (Fibiger, &apos;82; Mesulam et 
    al., &apos;83; Houser et al., &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">The suggestion that the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus 
    may be a source of cholinergic input to the IP is compatible with 
    the notion, dealt with earlier in this discussion, that the former 
    nucleus, as a lateral component of the dorsal tegmental region, 
    projects to lateral parts of the interpeduncular nucleus, the 
    region of the IP that is rich in cholinergic receptors (Rotter and 
    Jacobowitz, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">The fibers establishing this connection travel in part 
    by way of the interpedunculotegmental tract (Groenewegen et al., 
    &apos;83c; Groenewegen and Van Dijk, &apos;84; the present data), 
    but whether they are AChE-positive is at present controversial.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Wilson and Watson (&apos;80) were the first to report 
    that the interpedunculotegmental tract is strongly AChE-positive, 
    an observation confirmed in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Since the interpeduncular nucleus appears to contain no 
    cholinergic cells (Fibiger, &apos;82; Kimura et al., &apos;80; 
    Houser et al., &apos;83), it is unlikely that the AChE activity in 
    the tract reflects a cholinergic projection from the IP to the 
    dorsal tegmental region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Neither, however, does it appear to signify a 
    cholinergic projection of opposite polarity: lesions of the dorsal 
    tegmental region, even when large and bilateral, do not perceptibly 
    affect the AChE positivity of the interpedunculotegmental tracts 
    (unpublished observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">At present it therefore seems most likely that the AChE 
    activity is bound either to the fibers of the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract or to some hitherto unidentified 
    element or elements interstitial to the tract.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s572">Substance P-like 
    immunoreactivity</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">According to the present evidence all subnuclei of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus, with the exception of the IP-C and IP-I, 
    contain substance P-positive fibers and terminals in densities 
    ranging from light to heavy (Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">In the IPRL most of the immunoreactivity appears to be 
    bound to the habenulo-interpeduncular tract, but reactive terminals 
    may also be present.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">In addition to fibers, substance Ppositive cell bodies 
    were found in the IP-R both in rats pretreated with colchicine and 
    in untreated animals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">The present findings largely agree with the results of 
    previous immunohistochemical studies (rat: Ljungdahl et al., 
    &quot;78; Cuello and Kanazawa, &apos;78; Hamill et al., &apos;84; 
    Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84; Artymyshyn and Murray, &apos;85; 
    cat: Kapadia and DeLanerolle, &apos;84a,b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">In the present study a clear correlation could be made 
    between the cytoarchitecture of the IP and the pattern of substance 
    P-like immunoreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">In combination with the results of our tracing 
    experiments, such correlation provides some basis for speculation 
    upon the possible sources of substance P immunoreactivity in the 
    IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">The study of Sakanaka et al. (&apos;82) has provided 
    circumstantial evidence that most of the substance P-positive 
    fibers in the IP are of extrinsic origin: in the ontogeny of the IP 
    such fibers appear much earlier than do substance P-positive cell 
    bodies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">This is consistent with the finding of substance P-like 
    immunoreactivity in the habenulo-interpeduncular tract (Mroz et 
    al., &apos;76; Hong et al., &apos;76).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">It must be noted that only the dorsal part of the medial 
    habenular nucleus contains substance P-positive neurons (Cuello and 
    Kanazawa, &apos;78; Ljungdahl et al., &apos;78; Shinoda et al., 
    &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">There is autoradiographic evidence (Herkenham and Nauta, 
    &apos;79) that this part of the medial habenular nucleus projects 
    most heavily to lateral parts of the IP and thus could account for 
    the strong substance P-like immunoreactivity in the IP-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Lesions of the habenula or the fasciculus retroflexus 
    result in a considerable reduction of the substance P positivity in 
    the lateral subnuclei of the IP (Emson et al., &apos;77; Cuello et 
    al., &apos;78; Artymyshyn and Murray, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">In a study in which retrograde fluorescent tracing was 
    combined with staining for substance P immunoreactivity, the 
    habenular source of a substance P projection to the IP could 
    recently be substantiated (Hamill and Jacobowitz, &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">The finding that the loss of immunoreactivity in the IP 
    following habenular lesions is less than complete suggests, 
    however, the existence of an additional source of substance 
    P-positive fibers to the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">The present autoradiographic evidence indicates that the 
    IP-L receives a massive innervation not only from the habenula but 
    also from the caudal region of the central gray substance (Table 
    1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">In this region, the dorsolateral tegmental nucleus and 
    the caudal extension of the dorsal raphe nucleus contain numerous 
    substance P-positive neurons (rat Ljungdahl et al., &apos;78; 
    Sakanaka et al., &apos;81, &apos;82; cat: Moss and Basbaum, 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">In ontogeny, according to Sakanaka et al. (&apos;82), 
    such neurons appear much earlier in the dorsolateral tegmental 
    nucleus than in the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">It may thus be speculated that the dorsolatera1 
    tegmental nucleus contributes to the substance P innervation of the 
    IP-L and possibly also to that of the IP-R and IP-DM (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Table 1).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">In the context of these findings it is of interest to 
    note the presence of substance P-like immunoreactivity in the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">It is apparent from the present autoradiographic 
    experiments that efferent fibers of the IPR-the subdivision of the 
    IP containing the substance Ppositive neurons-travel in the 
    interpedunculotegmental tract to reach the caudal central gray 
    substance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">The localization of substance P-positive fibers around 
    the dorsal tegmental nwleus and in the dorsolateral tegmental 
    nucleus (rat: Ljungdahl et al., &apos;78; Cuello and Kanazawa, 
    &apos;78; cat: Moss and Basbaum, &apos;83) corresponds closely to 
    the distribution of interpedunculotegmental fibers labeled by 
    tritiated leucine deposited in the interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Accordingly, retrograde fluorescent tracers deposited in 
    the dorsal tegmental region have been found to label a number of 
    substance P-immunoreactive neurons in the IP-R (Huitinga et al., 
    &apos;85; Groenewegen, and Huitinga, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">A further interesting aspect of the pattern of substance 
    P-like immunoreactivity in the IP may be noted here.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">In agreement with the recent report of Rotter and 
    Jacobowitz (&apos;84) the present study has demonstrated a 
    remarkable overlap in the respective distributions of substance 
    P-like .immunoreactivity and acetylcholinesterase, not only in the 
    various subnuclei of the IP but also in the 
    habenulo-interpeduncular and interpedunculotegmental tracts 
    (compare Figs. 4, 5, 8; Table 1).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Chubb et al. (&apos;80) have reported evidence that 
    acetylcholinesterase hydrolyzes substance P in vitro, that these 
    two substances comigrate in polyacrylamide gels, and that they are 
    topographically closely associated with each other in the dorsal 
    horn of the chick spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">On the basis of these findings Chubb et al. (&apos;80) 
    suggested that acetylcholinesterase may play a role in the 
    biological degradation of substance P.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">As a consequence of that suggestion, the possibility 
    must be considered that the close colocalization of AChE with 
    substance P-like immunoreactivity in the IP and some of its 
    efferent fiber systems reflects a functional coupling of these two 
    biological agents.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s600">Enkephalin-like 
    immunoreactivity</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Numerous previous studies have demonstrated cell bodies, 
    fibers, and terminals in the interpeduncular nucleus that exhibit 
    an enkephalin-like immunoreactivity (rat: Watson et al., &apos;77; 
    Sar et al., &apos;78; Uhl et al., &apos;79; Wamsley et al., 
    &apos;80; Finley et al., &apos;81; Khachaturian et al., &apos;83; 
    Hemmendinger and Moore, &apos;84; cat: Kapadia and DeLanerolle, 
    &apos;84a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">In concurrence with these findings, a high concentration 
    of opiate receptors in the IP has been reported (Pert et al., 
    &apos;76; Atweh and Kuhar, &apos;77; Herkenham and Pert, 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">According to Goodman et al. (&apos;80) the 
    interpeduncular nucleus is especially rich in mu-receptors, 
    associated with the analgesic action of opiates, while 
    delta-receptors are much sparser in the IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">In most of the reports mentioned above the distribution 
    of enkephalin-like immunoreactivity or opiate receptors within the 
    IP is not specified.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">According to the present findings, enkephalin-positive 
    cell bodies are almost entirely confined to the IP-R; but some 
    additional cells were found in the IP-A and the caudodorsal part of 
    the IP-C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">This localization of enkephalin-positive cell bodies, as 
    well as the findings of an enkephalin-positive fiber plexus in the 
    IP-R, IP-A and IP-DL, is in general agreement with the recent 
    reports of Hemmendinger and Moore (&apos;84) and Hamill et al. 
    (&apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Other subnuclei of the 1P show little if any 
    immunoreactivity for leuor met-enkephalin.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">The distribution of enkephalin-positive fibers largely 
    coincides with that of opiate receptors as determined by the 
    specific binding of diprenorphine (Pert et al., &apos;76; Atweh and 
    Kuhar, &apos;77) or naloxone (Herkenham and Pert, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">The last-mentioned authors have emphasized that the 
    opiate-receptor distribution in the habenula, interpeduncular 
    nucleus, and raphe nuclei closely corresponds to the topographic 
    organization of the fiber connections sequentially linking these 
    structures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">In view of that correspondence, it would seem 
    conceivable that the enkephalin-positive fibers and terminals in 
    the IP are, at least in part, of extrinsic origin, and most likely 
    that they come from the caudal central gray substance.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Most immunohistochemical studies have indicated the 
    presence of enkephalin-positive neurons in the caudal extension of 
    the dorsal raphe nucleus, as well as around the dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus (e.g., Uhl et al., &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">The present findings and other observations (Groenewegen 
    et al., &apos;83c; Groenewegen and VanDijk, &apos;84) indicate that 
    fibers from these regions innervate the IP-R and IP-DL, the 
    subnuclei of the IP containing most of the enkephalinpositive 
    fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">A combined immunohistochemical-retrograde-tracing study 
    by Hamill and Jacobowitz (&apos;84) supports the notion of an 
    enkephalinergic projection from the dorsal tegmental region to the 
    IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Conversely, the enkephalin-positive neurons in the IP-R 
    are most likely to project to the caudal central gray substance, 
    where both enkephalin-positive fibers (rat: Uhl et al., &apos;79; 
    cat: Moss et al., &apos;83) and opiate receptors (Pert et al., 
    &apos;76; Simantov et al., &apos;77) are located around the dorsal 
    tegmental nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">In confirmation, fluorescent retrograde tracers injected 
    in the dorsal tegmental region have recently have been found to 
    label a population of enkephalin-immunoreactive neurons in the IP-R 
    (Huitinga et al., &apos;85; Groenewegen and Huitinga, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s616">Functional 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">On the basis of current data the interpeduncular nucleus 
    (IP) can be viewed first and foremost as a highly differentiated 
    processing station placed in the path of the fasciculus 
    retroflexus, the route from the habenular complex to the median 
    raphe nucleus (MRN) and to the dorsal tegmental region (DTR, 
    encompassing the dorsal raphe nucleus, the tegmental nuclei of 
    Gudden, and the nucleus tegmenti dorsalis lateralis).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">From a functional point of view it may be significant 
    that the interpeduncular nucleus almost selectively interrupts, 
    apparently with all its subdivisions, t hat component of the 
    fasciculus retroflexus that originates from the medial habenular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Since the medial habenular nucleus in turn is innervated 
    very largely by cell groups of the supraand retrocommissural 
    septum, and appears to receive few if any afferents from its 
    immediate neighbor, the lateral habenular nucleus (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;77, &apos;791, it seems 
    likely that the habenulo-interpeduncular connection conveys 
    information of predominantly hippocampal antecedents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">The lateral habenular nucleus is innervated by a greater 
    diversity of forebrain sites, but its substantial contribution to 
    the fasciculus retroflexus largely (if perhaps not entirely) 
    bypasses the interpeduncular nucleus and is distributed mainly to 
    the median raphe nucleus and dorsal tegmental region (Herkenham and 
    Nauta, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">It is nonetheless likely that the lateral habenular 
    nucleus can modulate the mechanisms of the interpeduncular nucleus 
    at least indirectly by way of the voluminous (and reciprocated) 
    projection from the MRN and DTR that provides the IP with what 
    appears to be its second-most massive input.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Like the habenulo-interpeduncular tract, this projection 
    appears to involve all of the currently recognized subdivisions of 
    the IP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">To what extent (and to what effect) these two main 
    aKerent systems interact with each other at the level of the YP 
    appears to be an unexplored question.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Thus far, only the integral effect of habenula 
    stimulation on the activity of single IP units appears to have been 
    examined, apparently without systematic attempts to differentiate 
    between afferent conduction directly from the habenula by the 
    habenulointerpeduncular tract, or indirectly by way of the dorsal 
    tegmental region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">In such studies both Lake (&apos;73) and Sastry ( 78) 
    found the effect of habenula stimulation upon single IP units to be 
    predominantly excitatory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Both these authors reported, moreover, that most (more 
    than 80% according to Lake) of the IP units recorded from, whether 
    facilitated or inhibited by habenula stimulation, were excited by 
    acetylcholine delivered by microiontophoresis; Sastry found this is 
    true also of substance P, the second neural messenger identified in 
    the habenulo-interpeduncular tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">No similar studies examining the effects of electrical 
    stimulation of the dorsal tegmental region upon IP units have come 
    to OUT attention; such studies presumably would be complicated by 
    the fact that the projection to the IP from the DTR, in contrast to 
    that from the habenula, is heavily reciprocated.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">The largely excitatory effect of habenula stimulation 
    upon IP newons is remarkable in view of Wang and Aghajanian s 1 77) 
    finding that such stimulation has a strongly inhibitory effect on 
    serotonin neurons, at least in the dorsal raphe region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Wang and Aghajanian found this inhibition to be blocked 
    by iontophoretically delivered picrotoxin, and therefore suggested 
    that it is transmitted by GABAergic fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Whether the effect in the raphe nuclei is mediated 
    directly by the lateral habenular nucleus as Wang and Aghajanian 
    suggested or by intrinsic GABA neurons in the raphe nuclei proper 
    (McGeer et al., 79) must for the present remain an open 
    question.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">From the observations of Maciewicz et al. ( 81) it 
    appears that in the cat the entire population of raphe neurons is 
    not inhibited by habenula stimulation but rather that a separate 
    group receives an excitatory input from the IP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Whether the cells of origin of this IP projection in 
    turn are influenced by the excitatory input from the habenula is, 
    as yet, unknown.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">In any case, an active involvement of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus in the mechanisms of inhibition, and 
    facilitation of the serotonin innervation of the forebrain seems a 
    distinct possibility.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">It is difficult to correlate these findings at the 
    single-unit level with the organismic aspects of 
    interpeduncular-nucleus function.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">In view of its placement in the brain s circuitry it 
    seems safe to assume that the IP is involved in some, at bast, of 
    the functions attributed to the dorsal diencephalic conduction 
    system (Sutherland, 82) descending from the forebrain to the 
    mesencephalon by way of the habenular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Not surprisingly, a wide-ranging and in part quite 
    controversial literature recently reviewed by Sutherland ( 82) 
    indicated that these functions affect endocrine (in particular 
    thyroid) and autonomic (respiratory, cardivascular, and intestinal) 
    as well as general behavioral mechanisms such as mating behavior, 
    avoidance response, and intracranial self-stimulation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Judged by the great 1011gitudinal spread of its 
    efferents, the IP would Seem capable of exerting an effect on these 
    phenomena both at the level of the hippocampand throughout the 
    extent Of the SePtohypothalamo-mesencephalic cOntinUUm (Nauta and 
    Domesick, 81) implicated in the subcortical circuitry of the Iimbic 
    system.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s639">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s640">This study extended over 7 
    years and was supported over different parts of that period by one 
    or more of the following, gratefuily acknowledged grants: a stipend 
    from the Netherlands Organization for the Advancement of Pure 
    Research (ZWO) to H.J.G.; PHS grant 5R23NS20467 to S.N.H.; Public 
    Health Service grants POlMH31154 and ROlNS19945 to W.J.H.N.; and 
    National Science Foundation grants BNS7681227, BNS8007905, and 
    BNS6306284 to W.J.H.N.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s641">It is a pleasure to 
    acknowledge the excellent assistance received from Miss Diane 
    Major, Mrs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s642">J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s643">Voerman, Mrs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s644">R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s645">Clark, and Mrs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s646">Rita Stoevelaar-de Zeeuw, as 
    well as from Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s647">S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s648">Speelman and Mr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s649">Dirk de Jong, who made the 
    photographs illustrating this paper.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s650">Drs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s651">Anthony Lohman and Fokje 
    Russchen are thanked or critically reading the manuscript.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s652">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Ahlenius, S., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Nauta (1980) Afferent and efferent connections of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus in the rat as revealed by neuroanatomical 
    tracer techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Suppl. 5188 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Armstrong, D.M., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Saper, A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Levey, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Wainer, and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Ferry (1983) Distribution of cholinergic neurons in rat 
    brain: Demonstrated by the immunohistological localization of 
    choline acetyltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Neurol. 216r53-68.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Artymyshyn, R., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Murray (1985) Substance P in the interpeduncular nucleus 
    of the rat: Normal distribution and the effects of 
    deafferentiation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Neurol. 231%-90.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Atweh, S.F., and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Kuhar (1977) Autoradiographic localization of opiate 
    receptors in rat brain. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">The brain stem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Brain Res. 129:l-12.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">hmitia, E.C., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Segal (1978) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    differential ascending projections of the dorsal and median raphe 
    nuclei in the rat. 6.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Neurol. 179641-667.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Baisden, R.H., D.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Hoover, and R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Cowie (1979) Retrograde demonstration Of hippocampal 
    afferent6 from the interpeduncular and reuniens nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Lett. 13:105-109.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Ban, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">ZYO (1963) Experimental studies on the mammillary 
    peduncle and mammil~otegmental tracts in the rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Med.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Osaka Univ.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">13:241-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Beckstead, R.M., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Nauta (1979) Efferent connections of the substantia 
    nigra and ventral tegmental area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Brain Res. 175:191-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Berman, A.L. (1968) The Brain Stem of the Cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Wisconsin Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Bobillier, P., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Petitjean, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Salvert, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Ligier, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Seguin (1975) Differential projections of the nucleus 
    raphe dorsalis and nucleus raphe cen.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">tralis as revealed by autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Brain Res. 85:205-210.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Briggs, T.L., and W.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Kaelber (1971) Efferent fiber connections of the dorsal 
    and deep tegmental nuclei of Gudden.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">An experimental study in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Brain Res. 29r17-29.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Butcher, L.L., and N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">WooIf (1984) Histochemical distribution of 
    acetylcholinesterase in the central nervous system: Clues to the 
    localization af cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">In: A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Bjorklund, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Amsterdam: Elsevier, Val. 3, Part 11, pp. 1-50.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Cajal, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Ramon y (1911) Histologie du Systeme Nerveux de 1 Homme 
    et des Vertebres.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Maloine, Paris, Vol. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Cheney, D.L., H.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Lefevre, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Racagni (1975) Choline acetyltransferase activity and 
    mass fragmentography measurement of acetylcholine in specific 
    nuclei and tracts of rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Neuropharmacology 14:801-809.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Chubb, LB., A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Hodgson, and G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">White (1980) Acetylcholinesterase hydrolyzes substance 
    P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Neuroscience 52065-2072.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Chubb, I.W., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Ranieri, G.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">White, and A.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Hodgson (1983) The enkephalins me amongst the peptides 
    hydrolyzed by purified acetylcholinesterase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Neuroscience 10:1369-1377.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Clarke, P.B.s., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Pert, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Pert (1984) Autoradiographic distribution of nicotine 
    receptors in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Brain Res. 323:390-395.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Conrad, L.c.A., C.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Leonard, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Pfaff (1974) Connections Of the median and dorsal raphe 
    nuclei in the rat An autoradiographic and degeneration study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Neurol. 156:179-205.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">Contestabile, A., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Flumerfelt (1981) Afferent connections of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus and the topographic organization of the 
    habenuloinkrpeduncular pathway: An HRP study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">COmP.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">196253-270.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">craig, A.D., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Burton (1981) Spinal and medullary lamina projection to 
    nucleus submedius in medial thalamus: A possible Pain Centre.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Neuraphysiol. 45443-466.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">craig, A.D., S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Wiegand, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">Price (1982) The thaiamo*ortical projection ofthe 
    nucleus submedius in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">COmp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Neural. 206:28-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">cue1lo, A.c., p.c.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Emson, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Paxinos, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Jesse11 11978) Substance containing and cholinergic 
    projections from the habenula.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s761">149,413-429.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Cuello, A.C., and I.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Kanazawa (1978) The distribution of substance P 
    immunoreactive fibers in the rat central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">I 78~129-156.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Dahlstrom, A,, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">Fuxe (1964) Evidence for the existence of 
    monoaminecontaining neurons in the cent.ra1 nervous system-I 
    Demonstration of monoamines in the cell bodies of brain stem 
    neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Scand. 62, Suppl. 232r1-55.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Domesick, V.B. (1976) Projections of the nucleus of the 
    Broca in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Rec. 184~391-392 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">Emson, P.C., A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Cuello, G.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">Paxinos, T Jessel, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Iversen (1977) The origin of substance P and 
    acetylcholine projection to the ventral tegmental area and 
    interpeduncular nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Acta Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Scand.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Suppl. 4524346.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Fibiger, H.C. (1982) The organization and some 
    projections of cholinergic neurons of the mammalian brain.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">Rev. 4~327-388.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">Finley, J.C.W., J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Maderdrut, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">Petrusz (1981) The immunocytochemical localization of 
    enkephalin in the central nervous system of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Neurol. 198.541-565.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">Flumerfelt, B.A., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Contestabile (1982) Acetylcholinesterase histochemistry 
    of the habenulo-interpeduneular pathway in the rat and the effects 
    of electrolytic and kainic acid lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Embryol. 263:435446.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Ganser, S. (1882) Vergleichend-anatomische Studien uber 
    das Gehirn des Maulwurfs.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Morphol.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">Jahrb. 7t591-725.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Geneser-Jensen, F.A., and T.W.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Blackstad (1971) Distribution of acetylcholinesterase in 
    the hippocampal region of the guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">I Enthorhinal area, parasubiculum and presubiculum. 
    2.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">Zellforsch.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Mikrosk.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Anat. 114:460-481.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Sawchenko (1982) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    axonally transported PHA-L lectin to demonstrate the fine 
    morphological details of efferent connections in the CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Abstr.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">8:786.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistwhemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus uulguris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">Goodman, R.R., S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Snyder, M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">Kuhar, and W.S.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Young (19801 Differentiation of delta and mu opiate 
    receptor localizations by light microscopic autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Roc.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Sei.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">U.S.A. 775239-6243.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Gottesfeld, Z., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Jacobowitz (1978) Cholinergic projection of the diagonal 
    band to the interpeduncular nucleus of the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Brain Res. 256:329-332.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">Graham, R.C., and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Karnovsky (1966) The earIy stages of absorption of 
    injected horseradish peroxidase in the proximal tubulus of mouse 
    kidney: Ultrastructural cytochemistry by a new technique.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Histmhem.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">Cytochem. 24:291-302.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">Groenewegen, H.J., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Nauta (1982) Afferent and efferent conneetions of the 
    mediodorsal thaiamic nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Neuosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">Suppl. 10217-218 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Groenewegen, H.J., and H.W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Steinbusch (1984) Serotonergic and nonserotonerbfic 
    projections from the interpeduncular nucleus to the ventral 
    hippocampus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Lett. 51:19-24.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Grwnewegen, H.J., and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Van Dijk (1984) Efferent connections of the dorsal 
    %-mental region in the rat, studied by means of anterograde 
    transport ofthe Iectin Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    (Pm-L).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">Brain Res. 304:367-371.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Gr*newegell, H.J., and I.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Huitinga (1985) Peptidergic projections from the 
    interpeduncular nucleus to the dorsal tegmental region in the rat, 
    Ne~osci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">Suppl. 22:111 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Groenewegen, H.J., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">Nauta (1986) Organization of the afferent connections of 
    the mediodorsal thalamic nucIeus in the rat, related to the 
    mediodorSal-Prefrontal topography.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Neuroscience (Submitted), Groenewegen, H.J., S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Haber, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Nauta (1983a) Structure and efferent Connections ofthe 
    interpeduncular nucleus in the rat. immunohisfxhemical and 
    neuroanatomical tracer study.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Neurosci, Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">SUPPl. 14:145 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">Groenewegen, H.J., S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">Haber, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Nauta (1983b3 Organization and efferent connections of 
    the interpeduncular nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Anat. 137~398-399 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Groenewegen, H.J., N.W.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">Kowall, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">Nauta (1983~) Efferent connections of the dorsal 
    tegmental region in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Sw. f.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Abstr. 8516.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Haber, S., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Elde (1982) The distribution of enkephalin 
    immunoreactive fibers and terminals in the monkey central nervous 
    system: An immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Neuroscience 7:1049-1095.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Hamill, G.S., and B.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">Fass (1984) Differential distribution of diagonal band 
    afferents to subnuclei of the interpeduncular nucleus in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Lett. 48~43-48.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">Hamill, G.S., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">Jacobowitz (1984) A study of afferent projections to the 
    rat interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Bull. 1352 7-539.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">Hamill, G.S., and N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Lenn (1984) The subnuclear organization of the rat 
    interpeduncular nucleus: A light and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Neurol. 222:396-408.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">Hamill, G.S., and N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Lenn (1981) A morphological and morphometric analysis of 
    the subnuclear structure of the interpeduncular nucleus in the 
    rat.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">SOC. f.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Abstr. 7:83.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Hamill, G.S., and N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Lenn (1984) The subnuclear organization of the rat 
    interpeduncular nucleus: A light and electron microscopic study. 
    3.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Neurol. 222:396-408.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Hamill, G.S., J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Olschowska, N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Lenn, and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Jacobowitz (1984) The subnuclear distribution of 
    substance P, cholecytokinin. vasoactive intestinal peptide, 
    somatostatin, leu-enkephalin, dopamine-B-hydroxylase and serotonin 
    in the rat interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">J.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Neurol. 226~580596.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">Hattori, T., E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">McGeer, V.K.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Singh, and P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">McGeer (1977) Cholinergic synapse of the interpeduncular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Neurol. 55666-679.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">Hayakawa, T., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">Zyo (1982) Organization of the habenulo-interpeduncular 
    connections in cats: A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="18" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">240~3-11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">Hemmendinger, L.M., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">Moore (1984) Inteveduncular nucleus organizstion in the 
    rat: Cytoarchitecture and histochemical analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Brain a s .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Bull. 13:163-179.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Hemmendinger, L.M., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">Moore (1982) The interpeduncular nucleus in the rat: 
    Cytoarchitecture and cytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Soc. f.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">m65.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">Herkenham, M., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Nauta (1977) Afferent connections of the habenular 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">A horseradish peroxidase study, with a note on the 
    fiber-of-passage problem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Neurol. 273~123-146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">Herkenham, M., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">Nauta (1979) Efferent connections of the habenular 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Neurol. 187:19-48.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Herkenham, M., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">Pert (1980) In vitro autoradiography of opiate receptors 
    in rat brain suggests loci of opiatergic pathways.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">U.S.A. 77:5532-5536.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">Hess, D.T., and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">Schneider (1981) Advantages of polarization microscopy 
    in horseradish peroxidase neurochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">Cytmhem. 29: 1448-1450.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Ho, R.H., and L.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">De Palatis (1980) Substance P immunoreactivity in the 
    median eminence of the North American opossum and domestic fowl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Brain Res. 189565469.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Hong, J.S., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">Costa, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">-Y.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">Yang (1976) Effects of habenular lesions on the 
    substance P content of various brain regions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Brain Res. 118523525.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Houser, C.R., G.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">Crawford, R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Barber, P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Salvaterra, and J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Vaughn (1983) Organization and morphological 
    characteristics of cholinergic neurons: An immunohistochemical 
    study with a monoclonal antibody to choline acetyltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">Brain Res. 226:97-119.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Huitinga, I., C.A. van Dijk, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">Groenewegen (1985) Substance Pand enkephalin-containing 
    projections from the interpeduncular nucleus to the dorsal 
    tegmental region in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Lett. 162:311-316.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Illing.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">R.B., and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">Wiissle (1979) Visualization of HRP reaetion product 
    using the polarization microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Lett. 13:7-11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">IVeS, (1971) interpeduncular complex of selected 
    rodents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">J. camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">I41:77-94.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">KaPadia, S% and N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">De Lanerolle (1984a) Population of substance p, 
    met-enkePhalin and serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in the 
    inkrpe.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">dunculat. nucleus of cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Brain he. 302:33-43.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">KaPadia, S.E., and N.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">De Lanerolle (1984b) Substance p neuronal organizatimin 
    the median region of the interpeduncular nucleus ofthe cat: An 
    electron microwopic analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Neuroscience 12:122g-1242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Kataoka, K., y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">Nakamura, and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">Hassler (1973) Habenulo.interpeduncu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">lar tract: A posible cholinergic neuron in the rat 
    brain, ~~~i~ R ~ 62264-267.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Khachaturian, H., M.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Lewis, and S.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">Watson (1983) Enkephalin systems in diencePhalon and 
    brain stem of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">Neural. 220:310320.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Kimva, H., P.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">McGeer, J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">Peng, and E.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">McGeer (1980) The central cholinergic system studied by 
    choline acetyltransferase chemistry in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">Neurol. 200r151-201.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">Kimura, H,, p,L, McGeer, and J,H, Peng (1984) Choline 
    acetyltransferase containing neurons in the rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">In: A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">Amsterdam: Elsevier, Vol. 3, Part 11, pp. 51-67.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">Kohler, C., V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">Chan-Palay, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">Steinbusch (1982) The distribution and origin of 
    serotonincontaining fibers in the septa1 area: A combined 
    immunohistochemical and fluorescent tracing study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">Neurol. 209r91-111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">Kuhar, M., R.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">DeHaven, H.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">Yamamura, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">Rommelspacher, and V.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Simon (1975) Further evidence for cholinergic 
    habenulo-interpeduncular neurons: Pharmacologic and functional 
    characteristics.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">97265-275.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">Lake, N. (1973) Studies of the habenulo-interpeduncular 
    pathway Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Neurol. 41t113-132.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Lehman, J,, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">Fibiger (1979) Acetylcholinesterase ergic neuron.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Life Sci. 25t1939-1947.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">Lenn, N.J. (1976) Synapses in the interpeduncular 
    nucleus: Electron microscopy of normal and habenula lesioned 
    rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">Neurol. 166:73100.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Lenn, N, J,, and G.S, Hamill (1984) Subdivisions of the 
    interpeduncular nucleus: A proposed nomenclature.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">Bull. 13203-204.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Lenn, N.J., V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">Wong, and G.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Hamill (1983) Left-right pairing at the crest synapses 
    of rat interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">Neuroscience 9:383-389.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Leranth, C.S., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">Browstein, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">Zaborsky, Z.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Jaranyi, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Palkovits (1975) Morphological and biochemical changes 
    in the rat interpeduncular nucleus following the transection of the 
    habenulo.interpeduncular tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Brain Res. 99t124-128.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">Lewis, P.R., and C.C.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Shute (1967) The cholinergic limbic system: Projections 
    to the hippocampal formation, medial cortex, nuclei of the ing 
    cholinergic reticular system, and the subfornical organ and 
    supra.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">optic crest.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">Brain 90t521-542.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">i R,, ~ L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">Chang , and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Wickern (1984) The dorsal tegmental nucleus: axoplasmic 
    transport study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Brain Res. 310:123-132.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">Ljungdahl, A,, T, ~ G k f ~ and l t , G, ~ i (1978) l 
    Distribution ~ of ~ substance ~ p.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">like immunoreactivity in the central system of the rat, 
    1, cell bodies and nerve terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Neuroscience 3:861-943.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Maciewicz, R., W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Foote, and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Bry (1981) Excitatory projection from the 
    interpeduncular nucleus to central superior raphe neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">225:179-183.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">Maley, B., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Elde (1982) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    putative neurotransmitters within the feline nucleus tractus 
    solitarius.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">Neuroscience 72469-2490.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Marchand, E.R., J.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">Riley, and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">Moore (1980) Interpeduncular afferents in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Brain Res. 193~339-352.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">Massopust, L.c., and R Thompson (1962) A new 
    interpedunculo-diencephalic pathway in rats and cats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">Neurol. 118:97-105.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">McGeer, E.G., U.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">Scherer-Singer, and E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">Singh (1979) Confirmatory data on habenular 
    projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Brain Res. 168:375-376.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Merker, B.H. (1983) Silver staining of cell bodies by 
    means development.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1064">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1065">Methods 9235-241.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1066">Mesulam, M.M. (1976) The blue reaction product in 
    horseradish peroxidase neurochemistry: Incubation parameters and 
    visibility.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1067">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1068">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1069">Cytochem. 24r1273-1280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1070">Mesulam, M.M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for 
    horseradish peroxidase neurochemistry: A noncarcinogenic blue 
    reaction product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural 
    afferents and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1071">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1072">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1073">Cytochem. 26t106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1074">Mesulam, M.M., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1075">Mufson, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1076">Wainer, and A.1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1077">Levey (1983) Central cholinergic pathways in the rat: 
    An overview based on an alternative nomenclature (Chl-Ch6).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1078">Neuroscience 10: 1185-1201.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1079">Miller, R.J., K.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1080">Chang, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1081">Cooper, and p.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1082">Cuatrecasas (1978) Radiohmunoassay and characterization 
    of enkephalins in rat tissues.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1083">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1084">Bid.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1085">Chem. 253:531-538.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1086">Miller, R.J., and V.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1087">Pickel (1980) The distribution and functions of the 
    enkephalins.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1088">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1089">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1090">Cytochem. 28r903-917.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1091">Mitchell, R. (1963) Connections of the habenula and the 
    nucleus in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1092">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1093">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1094">Neurol. 121r441-457.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1095">Morest, D.K. (1961) Connexions of the dorsal tegmental 
    rabbit.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1096">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1097">Anat. 95.229-246.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1098">MOSS, M.S., and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1099">Basbaum (1983) The peptidergic organization of the cat 
    periaqueductal grey. n.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1100">The distribution of immunoreactive substance P and 
    vasoactive intestinal polypeptide.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1101">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1102">Neurosci. 3:1437-1449.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1103">MOSS, M.S., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1104">Glazer, and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1105">Basbaum (1983) The peptidergic organization of the cat 
    periaqueductal grey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1106">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1107">The distribution of immunoreactive enkephalincontaining 
    neurons and terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1108">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1109">Neurosci. 3r603 16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1110">Mroz, E.A., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1111">Brownstein, and S.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1112">Leeman (1976) Evidence for substance P in the 
    habenulo-interpeduncular tract.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1113">Brain Res. 113t597-599.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1114">Murray, M., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1115">Zimmer, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1116">Raisman (1979) Quantitative electron microscopic 
    evidence for reinnervation in the adult rat interpeduncular nucleus 
    after lesions of the fasciculus retroflexus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1117">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1118">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1119">Neurol. 187:447468.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1120">Nauta, W.J.H. (1958) Hippocampal projections and 
    related neural pathways to the midbrain in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1121">Brain 81:319-341.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1122">Nauta, W.J.H., and H.G.J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1123">Kuypers (1958) Some ascending pathways in the brain 
    stem reticular formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1124">In H.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1125">Jasper, L.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1126">Proctor, R.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1127">Knighton, W.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1128">Noshay, and R.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1129">Costello (eds): Reticular Formation of the Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1130">London: Churchill Ltd. pp. 3-30.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1131">Nauta, W.J.H., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1132">Domesick (1981) Ramifications of the limbic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1133">In S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1134">Matthysse (ed): Psychiatry and the Biology of the Human 
    Brain: A Symposium Dedicated to Seymour S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1135">Kety.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1136">Amsterdam, Elsevier, pp, 165-188.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1137">Palkovits, M., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1138">Jacobowitz (1974) Topographic atlas of catecholamine 
    and acetylcholinesterase-containing neurons in the rat brain. 
    11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1139">Hindbrain, mesencephalon, rhombencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1140">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1141">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1142">Neurol. 1572941.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1143">Palkovits, M,, J,M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1144">Saavedra, R,M, Kobayashi, and M, Brownstein (1974) 
    Choline acetyltransferase content of limbic nuclei of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1145">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1146">79:443-450, Pert, C.B., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1147">Kuhar, and S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1148">Snyder (1976) Opiate receptor: Autoradiographic 
    localization in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1149">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1150">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1151">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1152">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1153">U.S.A. 73:37293733.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1154">Price, J.L., and B.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1155">Slotnick (1983) Dual olfactory representation in the 
    rat An anatomical and electrophysiological study, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1156">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1157">Neurol. 215r63-77.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1158">Riley, J.N., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1159">Moore (1981) Diencephalic and brainstem afferents to 
    the hippocampal formation of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1160">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1161">Bull. 6r437-444.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1162">Ratter, A., and D.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1163">Jacobowitz (1984) Localization of substance P, acetyl~ 
    cholinesterase and muscarinic receptors and alpha-bungarotoxin 
    binding sites in the rat interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1164">Brian Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1165">Bull. 12r83-94.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1166">Sakanaka, M., s.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1167">Shiosaka, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1168">Takatsuki, s.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1169">Inagaki, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1170">Takagi, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1171">Senba, y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1172">Kawai, y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1173">Haras H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1174">Iida?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1175">M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1176">Minagawa, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1177">Matsuzakis and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1178">Tohyama (1981) Evidence for the existence of a 
    substance P-containing pathway from the nucleus laterodorsalis 
    tegmenti (Castaldi) to the lateral septal area in the rat, Brain R 
    ~ 230:351-355, ~ , Sakanaka, M., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1179">Inagaki, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1180">Senba, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1181">Takagi, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1182">Takatsuki, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1183">Kawai, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1184">Iida, Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1185">Hara, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1186">Tohyama (1982) Ontogeny of substance P-containing 
    system of the rat: [mmunohis~chemical analysis, Lower brain 
    stem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1187">Neuroscience 7r1097-1126.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1188">Sar, M., W.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1189">Stumpf, R.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1190">Miller, K.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1191">Chang, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1192">Cuatracasas (1978) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    enkephalin in rat brain and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1193">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1194">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1195">Neurol. 182:17-38.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1196">Sastry, B.R. (1978) Effects of substance P, 
    acetylcholine and stimulation of habenula on rat interpeduncular 
    neuronal activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1197">Brain Res. 144:404410.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1198">Sastry, B.R., S.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1199">Zialkowski, L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1200">Hansen, J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1201">Kavanagh, and E.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1202">Envoy (1979) Acetylcholine release in interpeduncular 
    nucleus following stimulation of habenula.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1203">Brain Res. 164:334-337.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1204">Shibata, H., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1205">Suzuki (1984) Efferent projections of the 
    interpeduncular complex in the rat, with special reference to its 
    subnuclei: A retrograde horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1206">Brain Res. 296t345-349.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1207">Shinoda, K., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1208">Inagaki, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1209">Shiosaka, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1210">Kohuo, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1211">Tohyama (1984) Experimental immunohis&amp;hemical 
    studies on the substance system in the lateral habnular nucleus of 
    the rat: Distribution origins.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1212">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1213">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1214">Neurol. 222:578-588.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1215">Simantov, R., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1216">Kuhar, G.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1217">Uhl, and S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1218">Snyder (1977) Opioid peptide enkephalin: 
    Immunohistochemical mapping in rat central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1219">Proc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1220">Natl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1221">Acad.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1222">Sci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1223">U.S.A. 74t2167-2171.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1224">Smaha, L.A., and W.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1225">Kaelber (1973) Efferent fiber projections of the 
    habenula and the interpeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1226">An experimental study in the opossum and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1227">EXP.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1228">Brain Res. 16291-308.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1229">Sofroniew, M.V., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1230">Eckenstein, and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1231">Cuello (1983) Immunohistochemistry of cholinergic 
    neurons in the rat brain and spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1232">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1233">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1234">Suppl. 14:348 (Abstract).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1235">Sofroniew, M.V., F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1236">Eckenstein, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1237">Thoenen, and A.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1238">Cue110 (1982) ToPography of choline 
    acetyltransferasecontaining neurons in the forebrain of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1239">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1240">Lett. 33:7-12.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1241">Sorimachi, M., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1242">Kataoka (1974) Choline uptake by nerve terminals: A 
    sensitive and a specific marker of cholinergic innervation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1243">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1244">72350-353.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1245">Steinbusch, H.W.M. (1981) Distribution of 
    serotonin-immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the 
    rat-Cell bodies and terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1246">Neuroscience 6:557-618.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1247">Steinbusch, H.W.M. (1984) Serotonin-irnmunoreactive 
    neurons and their projections in the CNS.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1248">In A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1249">Bjorklund, T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1250">Hokfelt, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1251">Kuhar (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1252">Amsterdam: Elsevier, Vol. 3, Part 11, pp. 68-125.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1253">Sternberger, L.A. (1979) Immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1254">New York: Wiley.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1255">Stofer, D.W., and S.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1256">Edwards (1978) Organization and efferent projection of 
    the interpeduncular complex in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1257">SOC. f.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1258">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1259">Abstr. 4:228.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1260">Sutherland, R.J. (198%) The dorsal diencephalic 
    conduction system: A review of the anatomy and functions of the 
    habenular complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1261">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1262">Biobehav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1263">Rev. 6rl-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1264">Uhl, G.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1265">,R.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1266">Goodman, M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1267">Kuhar, S.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1268">Childers, and S.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1269">Snyder (1979) Immunohistochemical mapping of enkephalin 
    containing cell bodies, fibers and nerve terminals in the brain 
    stem of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1270">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1271">166:75-94.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1272">Villani, L., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1273">Contestabile, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1274">Fonnum (1983) Autoradiographic labeling of the 
    cholinergic habenulo-interpeduncular projection.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1275">Neurosci.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1276">Lett. 42:261-267.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1277">Velayos, J.L., and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1278">Reinoso-Suarez (1982) Topographic organization of the 
    brain stem afferents to the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1279">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1280">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1281">Neurol. 206:17-27.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1282">Wainer, B.H., A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1283">Levey, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1284">Mufson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1285">-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1286">Mesulam (1984) Cholinergic systems in mammalian brain 
    identified with antibodies against choline acetyltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1287">Rev.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1288">Neurochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1289">Int. 6:163-182.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1290">Wamsley, J.K., W.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1291">Yong, and M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1292">Kuhar (1980) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    enkephalin in rat forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1293">Brain Res. 190:153-174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1294">Wang, R.Y., and G.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1295">Aghajanian (1977) Physiological evidence for habenula 
    as major link between forebrain and midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1296">Science 197:89-91.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1297">Watson, S.J., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1298">Akil, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1299">Sullivan, and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1300">Barchas (1977) Immunohistochemical localization of 
    methionine enkephalin: Preliminary observations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1301">Life Sci. 21:733-738.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1302">Wilson, P.M., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1303">Watson (1980) Acetylcholinesterase staining in an 
    interpedunculotegmental pathway in four species: PTocuuia cupensis 
    (dassief, Cuuia procellus (guinea pig), Trichosurus vulpecula 
    (brushtail possum) and Rattus rattus (hooded rat).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1304">Brain Res. 2Ulr418-422.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1305">Wyss, J.M., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1306">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1307">Cowan (1979) A study of subcortical afferents to the 
    hippocampal formation in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1308">Neuroscience 4t463476.</S>
  </References>

</File>

