<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Connections of the Subthalamic Nucleus With Ventral 
  Striatopallidal Parts of the Basal Ganglia in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>HENK J. GROENEWEGEN AND HENK W. BERENDSE</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The present study was undertaken to establish the precise 
    anatomical relationship of the subthalamic nucleus (STh) with 
    limbic lobe-afferented parts of the basal ganglia in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The anterograde tracer Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L), injected in the STh, the globus pallidus, the ventral 
    pallidum, the ventral striatum, and the parafascicular thalamic 
    nucleus, and the retrograde tracers Fluoro-Gold (FG) and cholera 
    toxin B (CTb), injected in the globus pallidus, the ventral 
    pallidum, the ventral striatum, and the ventral mesencephalon, were 
    used for this purpose.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The results of these tracing experiments confirm the 
    general notion of reciprocal connections between the STh and 
    pallidal areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Thus the dorsomedial part of the STh is connected with the 
    subcommisural ventral pallidum, whereas a more ventral and lateral 
    part of the medial STh is related to the medial globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The lateral hypothalamic area, directly adjacent to the 
    STh, containing neurons with a morphology quite similar to those in 
    the STh, projects to parts of the ventral pallidum related to the 
    olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The reciprocal projection from this pallidal area to 
    subthalamic regions appears to be very sparse.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">The medial STh sends strong projections to the medial part 
    of the entopeduncular nucleus and the adjacent lateral hypothalamic 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Sparser projections from the medial STh reach the rostra1 
    and medial part of the caudate-putamen and the nucleus 
    accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">The nucleus accumbens sends a very sparse projection back 
    to the medial STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The projections of the medial STh to the ventral 
    mesencephalon appear also to be topographically organized.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The lateral hypothalamus and a few cells in the most 
    medial part of the STh project to the ventral tegmental area, 
    whereas progressively more lateral parts of the ventral 
    mesencephalon, in particular the substantia nigra, receive input 
    from successively more lateral and caudal parts of the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">In addition, a number of STh fibers reach the midbrain 
    extrapyramidal area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">The lateral part of the parafascicular thalamic nucleus 
    projects to the lateral part of the STh, whereas parafascicular 
    neurons medial to the fasciculus retroflexus project to the 
    dorsomedial portion of the STh.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">The medial part of the STh and the adjacent lateral 
    hypothalamus are intimately connected with limbic parts of the 
    basal ganglia in a way similar and parallel to the connections of 
    the lateral STh with motor-related parts of the basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">These findings suggest a role for the STh in nonmotor 
    functions of the basal ganglia.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">The subthalamic nucleus (STh), a small nuclear mass 
    located just dorsal to the cerebral peduncle in the caudal part of 
    the diencephalon, is generally considered to be part of the motor 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Dysfunctioning of this nucleus can lead to a hyperkinetic 
    syndrome that is known as (hemi)ballism.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Although there are some species differences, in all 
    mammals studied the main projections from the STh reach the 
    external and internal (entopeduncular nucleus in cats and rodents) 
    segments of the globus pallidus, the substantia nigra, and the 
    pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus (Nauta and Cole, &apos;78; 
    Ricardo, &apos;80; Carpenter et al., &apos;81; Jackson and 
    Crossman, &apos;81, &apos;83; Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">In turn, the STh receives fibers predominantly from the 
    external segment of the globus pallidus and the motor cortex 
    (Kunzle and Akert, &apos;77; Kunzle, &apos;78; Hartmann-Von Monakow 
    et al., &apos;79; Carpenter et al., &apos;81; Afsharpour, &apos;85) 
    and to a lesser degree from the parafascicular thalamic nucleus 
    (Sugimoto et al., &apos;83; Sugimot0 and Hattori, &apos;83) and the 
    pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus (Graybiel, &apos;77; Nomura et 
    al., &apos;80; Carpenter et al., &apos;81; Hammond et al., 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">In the 1980s it became increasingly clear that extensive 
    parts of the basal ganglia are involved in the processing of 
    information from limbic structures, in particular the hippocampus 
    and the amygdala (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The connectional organization of these limbic 
    lobe-afferented parts of the basal ganglia largely parallels the 
    circuitry of the rest of the basal ganglia (Haber et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">In the rat, it has been shown that the limbic striatum 
    encompasses the nucleus accumbens, the striatal elements of the 
    olfactory tubercle, and the ventromedial and caudal parts of the 
    caudate-putamen.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">This designation is primarily based on the distribution 
    in the ventral striatum of inputs from the hippocampus, the 
    amygdala, and limbic diencephalic and mesencephalic structures 
    (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75; Groenewegen et al., &apos;82, 
    &apos;87; Nauta, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The efferent connections of the ventral striatum are 
    distributed to pallidal structures that occupy the medial region of 
    the main body of the globus pallidus and an adjacent area 
    underneath the anterior commissure that has been designated as the 
    ventral pallidum (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75; Nauta et al., 
    &apos;78; Haber and Nauta, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">The latter area encompasses a region directly ventral to 
    the anterior commissure, i.e., the subcommissural part of the 
    ventral pallidum, and fingerlike rostra1 extensions of this region 
    into the deep layers of the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Like its dorsal, nonlimbic counterpart, the ventral 
    pallidum sends fibers to the thalamus, the ventral mesencephalon, 
    and the STh (Haber et al., &apos;85; Nauta, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The projection from the ventral part of the pallidal 
    complex to the STh has been considered as a route by which ventral 
    striatopallidal pathways reach the motor system (Nauta, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Apart from the ventral pallidal input to the STh, very 
    little is known about any further relations of this nucleus with 
    the limbic lobe-innervated parts of the basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Recently, it has been shown that the primate STh is a 
    rather differentiated structure with respect to its afferent and 
    efferent connections and that functionally different subsectors may 
    exist (e.g., Parent and Smith, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">The main purpose of the present study in the rat was to 
    establish the exact anatomical relationship of the STh with limbic 
    lobe-related parts of the basal ganglia and the midbrain 
    tegmentum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Therefore, injections of anterograde tracers were placed 
    in the STh, the ventral striatum, the globus pallidus, and the 
    ventral pallidum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Retrograde tracers were injected in the ventral tegmental 
    area and the adjacent substantia nigra and in the globus pallidus, 
    the ventral pallidum, and the ventral striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Additional data were obtained from injections of 
    anterograde tracers in the caudal thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The results of our experiments show that the medial 
    portion of the STh and the directly adjacent region of the lateral 
    hypothalamus are intricately connected with parts of the basal 
    ganglia that project to and receive inputs from limbic structures, 
    i.e., the ventral pallidum, the olfactory tubercle, and the ventral 
    tegmental area.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">This may imply that, apart from its prevalent motor role, 
    the STh is also involved in the processing of limbic 
    information.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">All experiments were done with female Wistar rats (180220 
    g body wt.).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Prior to surgery the animals were anesthetized by an 
    intramuscular injection of a mixture of Ketamine and Rompun (4:3, 1 
    ml/kg).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">After the appropriate survival time, the rats were deeply 
    re-anesthetized with an intraperitoneal injection of pentobarbital 
    (NembutalR) and transcardially perfused to fix the brain.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Stereotaxic coordinates for the injections in the 
    subthalamic nucleus (STh; n = 2), the ventral pallidum, the medial 
    part of the globus pallidus, the olfactory tubercle (n = 13), the 
    ventral striatum (n = lo), and the parafascicular thalamic nucleus 
    (n = 4) were determined by using the atlas of Paxinos and Watson 
    (&apos;86) as a reference.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Injections of 2.5 % Phaseolus uulgaris-leucoagglutinin 
    (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; PHA-L; Vector Laboratories), 
    dissolved in 0.05 M Tris buffer at pH 7.4, were made by applying a 
    5 PA positive pulsed current (7 sec on/7 sec off CCS-3 constant 
    current source Midgard) to the PHA-L solution in a glass 
    micropipette (internal diameter 10-20 pm) for 15-30 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">The animals were allowed to survive for 7-14 days and 
    perfused transcardially with 200 ml saline, followed by 500 ml 
    fixative containing 4% paraformaldehyde and 0.05% glutaraldehyde in 
    0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4) over a 15-30-minute period.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Following 2-4 hours postfixation, in this fixative, the 
    brains were stored overnight at 4째C in 30% phosphate-buffered 
    sucrose, subsequently cut at 40 pm on a freezing microtome, and 
    collected in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">Sections to be immunoprocessed with anti-PHA-L were first 
    prerinsed three times (15 min) in 0.05 M Tris-buffered saline (pH 
    8.6) with 0.5% Triton X-100 (TBS-T).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Incubation in rabbit-anti-PHA-L (1:2,000; E-Y Labs) in 
    TBS-T lasted for 36-60 hours at 4째C.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">To visualize the PHA-L, the peroxidase-antiperoxidase 
    (PAP) method according to Sternberger ( 79) was used.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Prior to the incubation with the second antibody, the 
    sections were rinsed 3 x 15 minutes in TBS-T.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">The sections were then incubated in swineantirabbit whole 
    serum ( ~ 4 0 Nordic ; Immunochemicals, Tilburg, The Netherlands) 
    for 60 minutes (20째C) in TBS-T and subsequently transferred to 
    rabbit peroxidase-antiperoxidase (1:800; Nordic Immunochemicals) in 
    TBS-T for 60 minutes at room temperature.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">After rinsing 3 x 15 minutes in Tris/HCl, pH 7.6, the 
    sections were processed with diaminobenzidine (DAB; 50 mg in 100 ml 
    Tris/HCl, pH 7.6).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">The DAB solution contained 35 fil 30% H,0,/100 ml, and 
    the incubation lasted 15-45 minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">After a thorough rinse the sections were mounted.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Half of the sections were counterstained with Cresyl 
    violet, whereas the remaining sections were left unstained.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Labeled fibers and terminals were plotted by using a 
    drawing tube on a standard Zeiss microscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s54">Retrograde tracing with 
    Fluoro-Gold (FG)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">In a separate set of experiments, injections of the 
    fluorescent tracer Fluoro-Gold (Schmued and Fallon, 86; FG; 2% in 
    acetate buffer; Fluorochrome Inc.) were placed in different 
    pallidal areas of six rats and in the ventral tegmental area of 
    another six rats.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">The injections were made iontophoretically through glass 
    micropipettes (25-40 fim internal tip diameter) by using a 
    positive-pulsed 10 @A current (7 sec on/ sec off) for 5-15 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Following a survival period of 7-17 days, the animals 
    were perfused with 100 ml saline, followed by 750 ml 4% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">The brains were postfixed for 30 minutes to 2 hours in 
    the same fixative, stored overnight at 4째C either in 30% 
    phosphate-buffered sucrose or in a mixture of 20% glycerine and 2% 
    dimethyl sulfoxide in distilled water, and cut on a freezing 
    microtome at 40 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">Sections were then mounted, air dried, xylene cleared, 
    coverslipped with Entallan, and examined under a Zeiss IV F 
    fluorescence miroscope, using filter-mirror system 01 (365 nm).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s60">Retrograde tracing of 
    cholera toxin B (CTb)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">In 10 rats injections of the tracer choleratoxin B 
    (Ericson and Blomqvist, 88; CTb; List Biochemical Laboratories) 
    were placed in the ventral striatum and in 10 rats in the ventral 
    tegmental area and the substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">The tracer, in a 1 % solution containing 1 M Tris, 4 M 
    NaCl, 0.02 M Na, EDTA and 0.06 M NaN,, pH 7.5, was injected by 
    means of air pressure through glass micropipettes (external tip 
    diameter 10-25 pm; injection volume 0.2-0.5 pl per injection).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">The animals were allowed to survive for 6-11 days and 
    were then perfused with 150 ml saline and 500 ml of a fixative 
    containing 4% paraformaldehyde, 15 % picric acid and 0.05 % 
    glutaraldehyde in phosphate buffer (pH 7.4).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Following one to two hours postfixation in the same 
    fixative, the brains were stored overnight at 4OC in a mixture of 
    20% glycerol and 2 % dimethylsulfoxide in distilled water.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Sections were cut at 40 pm on a freezing microtome and 
    collected in 0.05 M Tris-buffered saline (pH 7.6).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Every second section was incubated in a sequence of goat 
    anti-CTb (18 hrs; 1:5,000, List Biochemical Laboratories), donkey 
    antigoat whole serum (60 min; 150, Nordic Immunology, The 
    Netherlands), and goat peroxidase-antiperoxidase (60 min; PAP, 
    1:400, Nordic Immunology, The Netherlands).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">All antisera were dissolved in TBS-T (see above).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Prior to incubation, the sections were rinsed three times 
    (15 min) in TBS-T.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Following incubation, the sections were rinsed and 
    subsequently processed with Ni-enhanced diaminobenzidine (DAB, 12.5 
    mg in 25 mlO.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4 with 1 ml 15% 
    ammonium-Ni-sulfate).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">The rest of the incubation procedure was similar to that 
    described for PHA-L tracing.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Half of the incubated sections were counterstained with 
    Cresyl violet prior to coverslipping.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s72">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s73">Pallidosubthalamic 
    connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> in 
    pallidal structures .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> were placed in eight rats in 
    <injectionLocation>various parts of the ventral 
    pallidum</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , in three rats in 
    <injectionLocation>the olfactory tubercle</injectionLocation> , and 
    in two rats medially in <injectionLocation>the rostral part of the 
    globus pallidus</injectionLocation> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s76">Following 
    the injection in <injectionLocation>the ventral 
    pallidum</injectionLocation> in rat RP - 83415 ( Fig . lA ) , 
    <labelingDescription>an area of dense 
    termination</labelingDescription> can be observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the subthalamic nucleus ( 
    STh</labelingLocation> ; Fig . 1B ) throughout its rostrocaudal 
    extent .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s77"><labelingDescription>Terminal 
    fibers</labelingDescription> are also present in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamus in an 
    area</labelingLocation> immediately medial to the STh ( Fig 
    .IB).</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">After <exptLabel>an injection of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> medially in <injectionLocation>the globus 
    pallidus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RP - 84114 ; Fig .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">IC ) , <labelingDescription>the 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    STh</labelingLocation> occupy a more lateral and ventral position 
    in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s81">ID) when 
    compared with the previous case.</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s82">There are 
    only <labelingDescription>very few fibers and 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    hypothalamus medial to the STh</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the olfactory 
    tubercle</injectionLocation></exptLabel> do not result in 
    <labelingDescription>any anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> , even in cases in 
    which at the injection site both medium - size , striatallike , and 
    larger pallidallike neurons were labeled ( RP - 85050 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">In such cases , anterogradely <labelingDescription>PHA - 
    L - labeled axons</labelingDescription> can be followed through the 
    medial forebrain bundle to terminate in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> at the level of the rostral 
    part of the STh ( Fig . 1E ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s85">Compared to the density of 
    <labelingDescription>termination</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> in cases of injections 
    in <injectionLocation>the ventral pallidum and the globus 
    pallidus</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>the 
    termination</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> following injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the olfactory tubercle</injectionLocation> is 
    <labelingDescription>rather sparse</labelingDescription> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s86">Subthalamopallidal 
    connections</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the subthalamic 
      nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">In two rats an injection of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> was placed in <injectionLocation>the medial 
      part of the STh</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">In both cases densely stained , 
      <labelingDescription>small neurons</labelingDescription> are 
      present in the center of the injection site in 
      <injectionLocation>the STh</injectionLocation> , but there are 
      also <labelingDescription>a small number of labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> along the injection tract in 
      <labelingLocation>the area immediately dorsal to the STh , i . e 
      . , the zona incerta</labelingLocation> ( e . g . , RP - 84149 ; 
      Fig . 2A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90">In case RP - 84149 <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> ascend through <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral hypothalamic area</labelingLocation> , giving off 
      <labelingDescription>sparse branches with varicosities and 
      terminal boutons</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">At the level of the entopeduncular nucleus 
      <labelingDescription>a dense terminal field</labelingDescription> 
      is observed just medial to this internal segment of the globus 
      pallidus in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">The field extends into <labelingLocation>the medial 
      part of the entopeduncular nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2D 
      ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">Farther rostrally in <labelingLocation>the basal 
      forebrain</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>an extremely 
      dense fiber and terminal field</labelingDescription> is present 
      in <labelingLocation>the subcommissural part of the ventral 
      pallidum</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2B , C ) and in continuity 
      with it , in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the main body 
      of the globus pallidus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94">In <labelingLocation>the ventral 
      pallidum</labelingLocation> , the density of terminations rapidly 
      decreases in rostral and ventral directions , and 
      <labelingDescription>no fibers or terminals</labelingDescription> 
      are found in <labelingLocation>the pallidal regions of the 
      olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95">Above the anterior commissure , <labelingDescription>a 
      dense accumulation of terminals</labelingDescription> is found 
      not only in <labelingLocation>the medial globus pallidus but also 
      medial to it between the fiber bundles of the internal 
      capsule</labelingLocation> ( Fig .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96">ZC,E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">In dorsal and lateral directions, the density of 
      terminals rapidly diminishes.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98">However , in particular in <labelingLocation>more 
      caudal regions of the globus pallidus</labelingLocation> , 
      <labelingDescription>a large contingent of 
      fibers</labelingDescription> courses laterally and apparently 
      terminates in <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the globus 
      pallidus where it borders the caudate - putamen 
      complex</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">Such lateral terminations are most prominent ventrally 
      in <labelingLocation>the globus pallidus</labelingLocation> ( Fig 
      . 2E ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100"><labelingDescription>The fiber and terminal 
      density</labelingDescription> in pallidal regions is 
      <labelingDescription>considerably less</labelingDescription> in 
      the second case with an injection of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> in <labelingLocation>the medial part of the 
      STh ( RP - 84173 )</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">The distribution of <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers and terminals</labelingDescription> , however , is 
      essentially rather similar to that described for the previous 
      case .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">In both cases of injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
      STh</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>a considerable 
      number of retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> are 
      present in <labelingLocation>dorsal and ventral pallidal 
      regions</labelingLocation> where they lie intermingled with 
      <labelingDescription>the terminal fiber plexus of anterogradely 
      labeled subthalamic afferents</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">In numerous occasions , <labelingDescription>labeled 
      fibers carrying varicosities</labelingDescription> are seen in 
      close apposition with the perikarya or the proximal dendrites of 
      <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 3 ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">Injections of Fluoro-Gold in pallidal regions.</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105">In case RF - 87219 <exptLabel>an iontophoretic 
      injection of <tracerChemical>FG</tracerChemical> was placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the subcommissural part of the ventral 
      pallidum</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">The center of the injection site , as identified by a 
      small locus of intense fluorescence , is located just beneath 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior limb of the anterior 
      commissure</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">The periphery of the injection site , which has a 
      diameter of about 2 - 3 mm , is characterized by strongly 
      fluorescent neuronal and glial cells against 
      <labelingDescription>a diffuse fluorescent background 
      labeling</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108">In <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingDescription>a large number of retrogradely labeled , 
      intensely fluorescent neurons</labelingDescription> are present 
      in its medial one - third .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">In <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial part of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>virtually all 
      cells are strongly fluorescent</labelingDescription> , whereas 
      laterally and ventrally the labeled neurons rapidly diminish in 
      number ( Fig . 4B , C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110"><labelingDescription>Scattered labeled 
      cells</labelingDescription> are found between the fascicles of 
      the cerebral peduncle ( Fig . 4C ) ventral to the STh and in 
      <labelingLocation>the medially adjacent lateral hypothalamic 
      region</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s111">An injection of <tracerChemical>FG</tracerChemical> , 
      placed more ventrally and rostrally in <labelingLocation>the 
      basal forebrain</labelingLocation> , includes 
      <labelingLocation>the deep layers of the caudal part of the 
      olfactory tubercle</labelingLocation> ( RF - 87157 ).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">Following this injection , 
      <labelingDescription>relatively few retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> are found in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial part of the STh</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113">Most of <labelingDescription>the fluorescent 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in the nucleus are seen in the 
      dorsomedial corner , whereas more ventrally and laterally cells 
      are more dispersed and less intensely fluorescent ( Fig . 4E , F 
      ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114">Immediately medial to the STh , 
      <labelingDescription>labeled neurons</labelingDescription> are 
      present in <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamic 
      area</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">As can be appreciated from Figure 4F , 
      <labelingDescription>the labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in 
      this area are less densely packed , but regarding their size and 
      morphology clearly resemble the labeled neurons in the STh .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116">In rat RF - 87450 an injection of 
      <tracerChemical>FG</tracerChemical> was placed in 
      <injectionLocation>the medial part of the globus 
      pallidus</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">The injection site does not extend into 
      <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the ventral pallidum</injectionSpread> 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labeled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      STh</labelingLocation> are present in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial half of the nucleus</labelingLocation> , but are located 
      more ventrally and laterally than in the previous cases .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">Moreover , <labelingLocation>the extreme dorsomedial 
      part of the nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      <labelingDescription>remains free of retrograde 
      labeling</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 4D ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s120">Reciprocal 
    subthalamostriatal connections</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the subthalamic 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s122">In both 
    cases of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the STh</injectionLocation> ( RP - 84149, RP - 
    84170 ) , <labelingDescription>sparse labeling of fibers and 
    terminals</labelingDescription> could be observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the striatum</labelingLocation> , in particular 
    in <labelingLocation>rostra1 and medial parts of the caudate - 
    putamen complex</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral two - thirds of the nucleus accumbens</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 5A , B ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123"><exptLabel>Injections of 
    <tracerChemical>cholera</tracerChemical> toxin B ( CTb ) in 
    <injectionLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s124">The 
    injections of CTb in <labelingLocation>the ventral striatum 
    cover</labelingLocation> in most cases a relatively large area ( 1 
    - 2 mm in diameter ) , such that either <labelingLocation>the 
    medial or the lateral half of the nucleus 
    accumbens</labelingLocation> is included in the injection site .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">Following all injections 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> are observed in <labelingLocation>the 
    STh</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s126">For example , in rat RC - 
    89149 with an injection of <tracerChemical>CTb</tracerChemical> 
    laterally in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5C ) , <labelingDescription>a 
    small number of granularly labeled neurons</labelingDescription> is 
    present in <labelingLocation>the medial one - third of the 
    STh</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5D ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s127">It must 
    be noted that these neurons contain <labelingDescription>only 
    perikaryal labeling and that the dendrites remain free of 
    label</labelingDescription>.</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s128">This is in contrast to 
    <labelingDescription>the extensive dendritic labeling of 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in other parts of the brain following 
    <tracerChemical>CTb</tracerChemical> injections ( present 
    observations ; Ericson and Blomqvist , &apos; 88 ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s129">Apart 
    from <labelingDescription>the retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    STh</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>anterograde fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> is present in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , just ventromedial to the 
    STh ( Fig . 5D ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s130"><labelingDescription>A few of 
    these fibers</labelingDescription> appear to enter 
    <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> , indicating the 
    existence of projections from <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</labelingLocation> to this nucleus .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131"><exptLabel>Injections of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the ventral 
    striaturn</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s132">Of a 
    large collection of experiments with <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections in <injectionLocation>the ventral 
    striatum</injectionLocation> , only <labelingDescription>a small 
    number of cases showed anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s133">The 
    fibers from the ventral striatum descend through 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">At the level of <labelingLocation>the posterior 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , they course just medial to the 
    cerebral peduncle skirting the most ventromedial part of the STh 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">In a number of cases , <labelingDescription>a few 
    individual fibers</labelingDescription> are found in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial part of the STh</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 5E , F ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s136">Relationship of the 
    subthalamic nucleus with the mesencephalon</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137"><exptLabel>Following the injection of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
    medial part of the STh</injectionLocation></exptLabel> in rat RP - 
    84149, <labelingDescription>a dense terminal 
    field</labelingDescription> is found in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial two - thirds of the pars reticulata</labelingLocation> , 
    whereas <labelingLocation>the pars compacta of the substantia 
    nigra</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>less densely 
    labeled</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 6A , B ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><labelingDescription>Terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> is <labelingDescription>relatively 
    sparse</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    tegmental area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6C ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">Furthermore , <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> 
    <labelingModifier>traverse</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
    retrorubral and central tegmental fields of the 
    mesencephalon</labelingLocation> in a lateral and caudal curve .</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">As judged from the relatively smooth appearance of the 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L labeled fibers</labelingDescription> , 
    there are <labelingDescription>only few 
    terminations</labelingDescription> along the course of these fibers 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">More caudally <labelingDescription>a sparsely labeled 
    terminal field</labelingDescription> can be observed that is 
    located just dorsal to <labelingLocation>the superior cerebellar 
    peduncle</labelingLocation> at the level of the trochlear nucleus ( 
    Fig . 6D ) .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s142">This area coincides with the 
    midbrain extrapyramidal area as recently described by Rye et al. 
    (&apos;87).</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s143"><labelingDescription>A few 
    fibers</labelingDescription> extend medially and terminate in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of the central grey 
    substance</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">In order to study a possible topographical organization 
    in the projections from the STh to the ventral mesencephalon , a 
    number of experiments with <exptLabel>injections of 
    <tracerChemical>FG</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>CTb</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
    ventral tegmental area and the substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation></exptLabel>  were carried out .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Following <exptLabel>injections of 
    <tracerChemical>CTb</tracerChemical> that involve 
    <injectionLocation>the ventral tegmental 
    area</injectionLocation></exptLabel> with only minor inclusion of 
    <injectionSpread>the medial part of the substantia 
    nigra</injectionSpread> , <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    STh</labelingLocation> are located in <labelingLocation>its medial 
    part</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6E ) .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s146">It must 
    be noted that the density of <labelingDescription>anterograde and 
    retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    adjacent lateral hypothalamic area far</labelingLocation> exceeds 
    that of the labeling in <labelingLocation>the 
    STh</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6E ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147"><exptLabel>Injections that were placed more laterally in 
    <injectionLocation>the substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation></exptLabel> result in 
    <labelingDescription>retrograde labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>most of the STh</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6F ) 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Following such injections , there is in addition 
    <labelingDescription>extensive anterograde and retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the dorsally 
    adjacent zona incerta</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s149">Thalamosubthalamic 
    connections</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">In experiments with <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections in <injectionLocation>the midline and 
    the intralaminar nuclei of the 
    thalamus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , which were placed in the 
    course of a parallel study ( Berendse et al . , &apos; 88 ; 
    Berendse and Groenewegen , &apos; 90a ) , <labelingDescription>the 
    projections</labelingDescription> from the thalamus to the STh 
    could be examined .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">In particular , <exptLabel>injections of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the 
    parafascicular nucleus result</injectionLocation></exptLabel> in 
    <labelingDescription>anterograde labeling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="21"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Injections that involve <injectionLocation>the portion 
    of the parafascicular nucleus</injectionLocation> located lateral 
    to the fasciculus retroflexus give rise to labeling in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the STh</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . 7A , B ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153"><exptLabel>Injections placed medial to the fasciculus 
    retroflexus that involve , among others , <injectionLocation>the 
    medial part of the parafascicular 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , result in 
    <labelingDescription>labeled fibers and 
    terminals</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsomedial part of the STh</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 7C , D ) 
    .</S><S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154"><labelingDescription>Anterograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was absent from 
    <labelingLocation>the STh</labelingLocation> following 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injections in the same 
    caudal thalamic area that did not involve the medial part of the 
    parafascicular nucleus .</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s155">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">The main data of the present study are summarized in 
    Figure 8.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">Combining the results of the anterograde and retrograde 
    tracing experiments, it can be concluded that the dorsomedial part 
    of the STh has strong reciprocal connections with the 
    subcommissural part of the ventral pallidum.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">The same part of the STh sends weaker projections to the 
    ventral tegmental area and adjacent parts of the substantia nigra 
    and to a more caudal midbrain region, i.e., the midbrain 
    extrapyramidal area (Rye et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">It further receives thalamic inputs from the medial part 
    of the parafascicular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">The region of the medial STh, directly ventral and 
    lateral to the above-mentioned dorsomedial portion of the STh, is 
    reciprocally connected with the medial part of the main body of the 
    glohus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">Projections from more lateral parts of the STh terminate 
    more laterally and ventrally in the substantia nigra than those 
    from the medial part and, like the latter, also extend into the 
    midbrain extrapyramidal area (Fig. 8).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">The results of the PHA-L anterograde tracing experiments 
    show that the medial STh has additional projections to the medial 
    part of the entopeduncular nucleus and the directly adjacent region 
    of the lateral hypothalamic area and to a lateral and ventral zone 
    of the globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">The present experiments do not allow conclusions with 
    respect to a topography in these projections.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Finally, the lateral hypothalamic region medially 
    adjacent to the STh has connections, albeit weak, with the pallidal 
    elements of the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">Before dealing in more detail with the connections of 
    the medial STh, the tracing methods used by us in this study are 
    briefly discussed.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s166">Methodological 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">The advantages and limitations of the use of Phaseolus 
    uulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) have been amply discussed in the 
    literature (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84; Groenewegen and 
    Wouterlood, &apos;90).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">Choleratoxin subunit B (CTb) has been introduced only 
    recently as a retrograde neuroanatomical tracer (Ericson and 
    Blomqvist, &apos;88) and therefore deserves some discussion.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">Choleratoxin B is transported both anterogradely and 
    retrogradely, but the anterograde transport is generally weaker and 
    in its quality of labeling neuronal structures is not comparable 
    with PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">The main advantage of CTb as a retrograde tracer is its 
    superior sensitivity and the excellent retrograde filling of the 
    dendritic arborizations (Ericson and Rlomqvist, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">In the present study the very weak projections from the 
    STh to the striatum could indeed be shown with CTh.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">The main disadvantages of the CTb technique are that the 
    dimensions of the injection site are difficult to control and that 
    the tracer is taken up by passing fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">However, both problems do not affect the interpretation 
    of the results of the present experiments in which CTb was used.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s174">Pallidal connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">The results of previous studies have shown that the most 
    prominent fiber connections of the STh are established with 
    pallidal structures (e.g., Nauta and Cole, &apos;78; Ricardo, 
    &apos;80; Carpenter et al., &apos;81; Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">In concurrence with these studies, the present data 
    indicate that the densest projections from the medial STh reach the 
    ventral pallidum and the medial part of the entopeduncular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Furthermore, the lateral hypothalamic area medially 
    adjacent to the entopeduncular nucleus receives an even denser 
    termination from the medial STh than the entopeduncular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">This finding underscores the previously expressed notion 
    that this area is continuous with and, in its connectivity, very 
    similar to the entopeduncular nucleus (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Heimer et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">Like the entopeduncular nucleus, neurons in this region 
    of the lateral hypothalamus project to the lateral habenula 
    (Herkenham and Nauta, &apos;77).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">The same hypothalamic region receives input also from 
    the ventral striatum and has immunohistochemical characteristics 
    comparable to those of the entopeduncular nucleus (Nauta et al., 
    &apos;78; Groenewegen and Russchen, &apos;84; Haber et al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">The present findings of a projection from the medial STh 
    to the lateral hypothalamus adjacent to the entopeduncular nucleus 
    further confirms the internal pallidal nature of this area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">Whether the latter region indeed represents the internal 
    segment of the limbic-related ventral pallidum cannot be concluded 
    only from the existing evidence.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Physiological and behavioral data are needed to further 
    explore this possibility.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">It is also important to note here that the 
    subcommissural ventral or limbic pallidum has a number of 
    characteristics that resemble those of both the internal and 
    external segments of the globus pallidus (cf.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Heimer et al., 85; Nauta, 86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Therefore, it is unclear whether a separation in 
    internal and external segments can be made within the 
    limbic-related parts of the pallidal complex, as in the dorsally 
    located globus pallidus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">The present results indicate that there is a rather 
    strict topography in the reciprocal pallidosubthalamic connections 
    involving the medial STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">In particular, the results of the anterograde (PHA-L) 
    and retrograde tracer injections in the subcommissural part of the 
    ventral pallidum and of those in the medial sector of the globus 
    pallidus show that these distinct parts of the pallidal complex 
    communicate with distinct parts of the medial STh (Fig. 8).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">As a result of the circumstance that following the 
    injections of PHA-L in the STh pallidal neurons are retrogradely 
    labeled, it was observed that anterogradely labeled 
    subthalamopallidal fibers make close contact with these 
    retrogradely labeled pallidal cells or with their dendrites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">This emphasizes the reciprocity of the connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">The fact that injections of PHA-L in the olfactory 
    tubercle, in which large pallidal neurons are included, give rise 
    to anterograde labeling of fibers and terminals in the lateral 
    hypothalamic area adjacent to the STh and that injections of 
    retrograde tracers in the olfactory tubercle result in labeled 
    neurons in the same hypothalamic region, concurs with the 
    reciprocity in the pallidosubthalamic connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">This implies that a population of neurons outside the 
    borders of the STh have connectional characteristics comparable to 
    those of subthalamic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194">An argument in favor of the notion that neurons lying 
    outside the STh proper belong to the same neuronal system is the 
    similarity in morphology of the retrogradely labeled neurons in the 
    lateral hypothalamus at the level of the STh following olfactory 
    tubercle injections and the retrogradely labeled cells in the STh 
    after injections in the ventral pallidum (cf. also Kita et al., 
    83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">A difference is that in the STh the neurons are more 
    closely packed.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">Furthermore, it is of interest to note that a small 
    number of subthalamic cells projecting to the globus pallidus are 
    situated amidst the fiber bundles of the cerebral peduncle, and 
    therefore also lie outside the borders of the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Whether the lateral hypothalamic neurons close to the 
    STh may indeed be considered subthalamic neurons awaits further 
    knowledge of the synaptology and the physiological characteristics 
    of these cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Seemingly in contrast with the above-discussed 
    topography in the pallidosubthalamic connections is the finding 
    that PHA-L injections in the medial STh result in a rather 
    widespread anterograde labeling in the pallidal complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">However, this is probably due to the fact that even when 
    PHA-L is used as the tracer, the injection sites in a small nucleus 
    such as the STh are relatively large.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Another observation that bears discussion is the 
    presently observed projection from the medial part of the STh to a 
    strip in the ventral and lateral parts of the globus pallidus at 
    the border with the caudate-putamen complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">A lateral strip of subthalamic terminals in the globus 
    pallidus has also been reported by Kita and Kitai (&apos;87) 
    following lateral injections in STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">As suggested by these authors, inputs from all parts of 
    the STh might converge in this lateral band of the globus pallidus, 
    whereas the subthalamopallidal fibers to more medial parts of the 
    pallidal complex are topographically organized (as discussed 
    above).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">The striatopallidal projection system has also been 
    shown, on the one hand, to be highly topographically organized and, 
    on the other, to contain a nontopographical component, such that 
    divergent areas of the striatum project in an overlapping manner to 
    a lateral strip of the globus pallidus bordering the caudateputamen 
    complex (Chang et al., &apos;81; Wilson and Phelan, &apos;82; 
    Gerfen, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Presumably, the lateral strip of subthalamic projections 
    in the globus pallidus overlaps with these nontopographically 
    organized striatopallidal projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Not only in the rat, but also in the primate a banded 
    organization of the subthalamopallidal projections has been 
    described (Nauta and Cole, &apos;78; Parent et al., &apos;89).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s206">Striatal connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">The present PHA-L antrograde tracing experiments 
    demonstrate, in agreement with the observations of Kita and Kitai 
    (&apos;87), the existence of a projection from the STh to the 
    striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">The fibers originate in the medial part of the STh and 
    terminate predominantly in the rostral and medial parts of the 
    caudate-putamen complex and in the lateral part of the nucleus 
    accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">The projection to the ventral striatum is confirmed by 
    the results of injections of the sensitive tracer CTb.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Apparently, it is modest in volume since following 
    injections of this tracer in the ventral striatum the number of 
    retrogradely neurons in the STh is very small and the cells are 
    only weakly labeled even though the injections are relatively 
    large.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">The results obtained from a large collection of PHA-L 
    tracing experiments with injections of the tracer in the ventral 
    striatum indicate that the connection from the STh to this part of 
    the striatum is reciprocated.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">As judged from the number of fibers that enter the STh 
    following PHA-L injections in the ventral striatum, this return 
    pathway is also not extensive in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">It may therefore be concluded that, although a 
    reciprocal connection between the STh and the striatum does exist 
    in the rat, this pathway is much less prevalent than in cats and 
    monkeys (rat: Kita and Kitai, &apos;87; present study; cat: 
    Beckstead, &apos;83; Royce and Laine, &apos;84; monkey: Nauta and 
    Cole, &apos;78; Parent and Smith, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s214">Connections with the 
    thalamus</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">Inputs from the thalamus to the STh have been shown 
    previously in the rat and the cat with anterograde autoradiographic 
    tracing techniques (Sugimoto et al., &apos;83; Sugimoto and 
    Hattori, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">The results of the present PHA-L tracing experiments 
    confirm that these projections to the STh originate in the 
    parafascicular nucleus of the caudal thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">In none of our cases with PHA-L injections in more 
    rostral parts of the midline and intralaminar thalamic nuclei could 
    anterograde labeling be observed in the STh (unpublished 
    observations).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Our data demonstrate that, like the pallidosubthalamic 
    connections, the thalamosubthalamic pathway is topographically 
    organized.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">The most medial part of the parafascicular nucleus, 
    located medially to the fasciculus retroflexus, projects to the 
    dorsomedial part of the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">This part of the parafascicular thalamic nucleus also 
    sends fibers to the nucleus accumhens (Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90a), which, via a pathway leading through the subcommissural 
    ventral pallidum, is related to the medial STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">The largest part of the parafascicular nucleus, located 
    lateral to the fasciculus retroflexus projects to the more lateral 
    regions of the STh and to extensive areas of the dorsal striatum 
    (Beckstead, &apos;84; Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;90a), which, 
    in turn, indirectly via the globus pallidus, can influence the 
    lateral STh.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s222">Connections with the 
    brainstem</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">In agreement with previous studies, the results of our 
    anterograde tracing experiments with injections of PHA-L in the STh 
    show that the main descending projections of this nucleus are 
    directed to the pars reticulata of the substantia nigra (Nauta and 
    Cole, &apos;78; Ricardo, &apos;80; Carpenter et al., &apos;81; 
    Gerfen et al., &apos;82; Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">Whereas Ricardo (&apos;80) showed that injections of 
    tritiated amino acids in lateral parts of the STh give rise to 
    anterograde labeling ventrally in the pars reticulata, close to the 
    cerebral peduncle, the present results show that the projections 
    from the medial STh reach more dorsal strata of the pars 
    reticulata, close to the pars compacta.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">It thus appears that in these projections a mediolateral 
    axis in the STh corresponds to a dorsoventral axis in the 
    substantia nigra (cf. also Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">As has previously been demonstrated by other authors 
    (Ricardo, &apos;80; Mintz et al., &apos;86; Kita and Kitai, 
    &apos;87), our results also show that the pars compacta of the 
    substantia nigra receives an input from the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">In line with the above-discussed involvement of the 
    medial STh in limbicrelated circuits, additional projections from 
    this part of the nucleus are directed to the limbic-related ventral 
    tegmental area.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">It is therefore possible that the medial part of the 
    STh, through its projections to the dopaminergic cells in the 
    ventral tegmental area and the adjacent pars compacta of the 
    substantia nigra influences the ascending mesolimbic dopamine 
    pathways, which, among others, distribute to the ventral 
    striatum.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">Projections from the STh to more caudal midbrain 
    regions, in particular to the region of the pedunculopontine 
    tegmental nucleus, have also been described previously (Nauta and 
    Cole, &apos;78; Hammond et al., &apos;83; Jackson and Crossman, 
    &apos;81, &apos;83; Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">In our present description, we have followed the more 
    recent subdivision and nomenclature of the midbrain tegmentum by 
    Rye et al. (&apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">According to this scheme, the relatively sparse 
    projections from the medial part of the STh terminate in the 
    midbrain extrapyramidal area dorsal and lateral to the superior 
    cerebellar peduncle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">It has recently been shown by Lee et al. (&apos;88) that 
    the return fibers from the midbrain tegmentum to the STli also 
    originate for the most part in the midbrain extrapyramidal area and 
    only a very small percentage from cholinergic cells in the 
    pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s233">The subthalamic nucleus 
    and the circuitry of the basal ganglia</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">It has long been recognized that the connections between 
    the striatum, the pallidal complex, and substantia nigra are 
    topographically organized.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">The results of the present and other recent studies 
    provide evidence that the connections of the STh also fit into this 
    topographical pattern.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">For instance, the nucleus accumbens of the ventral 
    striatum projects to the subcommissural part of the ventral 
    pallidum and to the lateral hypothalamic area adjacent to the 
    entopeduncular nucleus (Nauta et al., &apos;78; Groenewegen and 
    Russchen, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">These two pallidal regions are in turn connected with a 
    small dorsomedial portion of the STh (present study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">It was observed by us that there is also a direct 
    pathway from the nucleus accumbens to the medial STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">A second system of striatopallidosubthalamic connections 
    is formed by the projections from the ventromedial part of the 
    caudato-putamen to the medial parts of the globus pallidus (Gerfen, 
    &apos;85) and the entopeduncular nucleus (unpublished observations) 
    and the reciprocal connections between these regions and lateral 
    and ventral parts of the medial STh (present results).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">Thirdly, as demonstrated by Gerfen (&apos;85) and 
    Fink-Jensen and Mikkelsen (&apos;89), the more lateral and dorsal 
    parts of the caudato-putamen project to lateral and dorsal parts of 
    the globus pallidus and to the lateral part of the entopeduncular 
    nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">The area in the STh that maintains reciprocal 
    connections with the latter two regions comprises the lateral 
    two-thirds of the nucleus (Ricardo, &apos;80; Kita and Kitai, 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">As first documented by Nauta and Domesick (&apos;79) and 
    Domesick (&apos;81)&apos; the organization in the projections from 
    the striatum to the substantia nigra is such that ventral regions 
    of the striatum, including the nucleus accumhens, project to dorsal 
    zones of the substantia nigra, whereas dorsal regions of the 
    striatum project to ventral zones of the substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">In the present study it was found that the projections 
    from medial-to-lateral STh are also arranged along a dorsoventral 
    axis in the substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Because, as discussed above, the medial and lateral 
    parts of the STh are related to ventral and dorsal regions of the 
    striatum, respectively, this means that the topography in the 
    subthalamonigral fibers is in register with that in the 
    striatonigral projections (see also Kita and Kitai, &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">A further interesting feature is that the projections of 
    the lateral and medial parts of the thalamic parafascicular nucleus 
    to the striatum and STh terminate in areas that are mutually 
    interconnected, either directly or by way of the pallidal 
    complex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The areas that are targeted by the fibers from the 
    lateral parts of the parafascicular nucleus are the dorsolateral 
    region of the caudate-putamen and the lateral STh, whereas the 
    medial part of the parafascicular nucleus distributes its fibers to 
    the medial region of the caudateputamen, the lateral part of the 
    nucleus accumbens, and the medial STh (Berendse and Groenewegen, 
    &apos;90a).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Both in rats (Afsharpour, &apos;85) and in monkeys 
    (Kunzle and Akert, &apos;77; Kunzle, &apos;78; Hartmann-Von Monakow 
    et al., &apos;79)&apos; it has been demonstrated that the motor and 
    premotor cortices have projections to the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Afsharpour (&apos;85), using anterograde tracing of 
    tritiated amino acids in the rat, described a topographical 
    organization in the projections of the frontal agranular cortex and 
    the zone of overlap of the motor and the sensory cortical areas to 
    the STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">The rostra1 part of the medial agranular cortex projects 
    to the ventral two-thirds of the medial STh.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">The dorsomedial part of the STh remains free of labeling 
    following the cortical injections placed by Afsharpour 
    (&apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">This may indicate that the dorsomedial STh is innervated 
    by frontal cortical regions that were not studied by Afsharpour, 
    i.e., the medial and lateral prefrontal cortical areas.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Preliminary results of experiments with PHA-L injections 
    in these parts of the prefrontal cortex indeed show that the 
    dorsomedial part of the STh is innervated by the prefrontal cortex 
    (Berendse and Groenewegen, &apos;gob).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">These same cortical areas, additionally, have indirect 
    access to the medial STh through the ventral striatopallidal 
    system.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s254">Functional interpret a 
    tions</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">The role of the subthalamic nucleus (STh) in behavior is 
    thought to be primarily in the realm of the motor system.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">This suggestion is based on the intimate anatomical 
    relationship of the STh with primarily motor-related parts of the 
    basal ganglia and with the motor cortex, and concurs with 
    experimental and clinical observations that lesions or 
    pharmacological manipulations of the STh result in pronounced motor 
    disturbances, i.e., (hemi)ballistic symptoms (Martin, &apos;27; 
    Whittier and Mettler, &apos;49; Carpenter et al., &apos;50; 
    Crossman, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">However, the present and previous (Ricardo, &apos;80; 
    Haber et al., &apos;85; Kita and Kitai, &apos;87) anatomical 
    tracing studies have provided evidence that the STh also has 
    connections with the ventral pallidum, which through projections 
    from the ventral striatum is under the influence of limbic 
    structures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">Moreover, it could presently be shown that the medial 
    STh has additional connections with other limbic-innervated parts 
    of the basal ganglia, such as the ventral tegmental area, the 
    lateral hypothalamus at the level of the entopeduncular nucleus, 
    and the ventral striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s259">Our results further indicate that the connections of the 
    lateral hypothalamus directly medial to the STh has characteristics 
    very similar to those of the STh itself.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">The conclusion that the medial STh is intricately 
    connected with the ventral striatopallidal parts of the basal 
    ganglia is important since, contrary to earlier reports that the 
    subthalamic output is inhibitory and GABAergic (Rouzaire-Dubois et 
    al., &apos;83), it has now been demonstrated that the projections 
    of the STh to the pallidal complex and the substantia nigra are 
    excitatory and presumably use glutamate as neurotransmitter (Kitai 
    and Kita, &apos;87; Smith and Parent, &apos;88; Albin et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">The subthalamic input to the ventral pallidum might 
    therefore be an important driving force of this part of the 
    pallidal complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">The present findings and the results of previous studies 
    on the connections of the STh with the caudate nucleus of the 
    primate (Parent and Smith, &apos;87) indicate that functions of the 
    STh are probably not restricted to the motor system, but also 
    include the limbic and cognitive spheres of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">The rather precise topographical arrangements in the 
    connections of the STh with other parts of the basal ganglia might 
    imply that the influence of a certain part of the STh remains 
    restricted to those subdivisions of the striatopallidal system from 
    which it receives its inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">Thus, judged purely on the basis of its connections, the 
    involvement of the STh in limbic-motor integration is rather 
    limited.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">However, the projections from the medial STh to a 
    lateral band of the globus pallidus may yet provide a way for 
    limbic influences to reach the somatomotor system through the 
    subthalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">In addition, the STh projections to the medial part of 
    the globus pallidus and the medially adjacent region of the 
    internal capsule may contact the numerous cholinergic neurons in 
    this region (Mesulam, &apos;83) that project to the prefrontal and 
    motor cortices (Saper, &apos;84; Luiten et al., &apos;87).</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="27" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s267">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s268">The authors express their 
    gratitude to Drs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s269">Anthony Lohman and Menno 
    Witter for critically reading the manuscript, and to Yvonne 
    Galis-de Graaf and Dirk de Jong for excellent technical 
    assistence.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s270">This work was supported in 
    part by Medigon-NWO Program Grant #900-550-093.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="27" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s271">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Afsharpour, S. (1985) Topographical projections of the 
    cerebral cortex to the subthalamic nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Neurol. 236:14-28.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Alhin, R.L., J.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Aldridge, A.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Young, and S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Gilman (1989) Feline subthalamic nucleus neurons contain 
    glutamate-like hut not GABA-like or glycine-like 
    immunoreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Brain Res. 491:185-188.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Beckstead, R.M. (1983) A reciprocal axonal connection 
    between the subthalamic nucleus and the neostriatum in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Brain Res. 275:137-142.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Beckstead, R.M. (1984) The thalamostriatal projection in 
    the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Neur ol.223:3 13-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Groenewegen (1990a) The organization of the 
    thalamostriatal projections in the rat, with special emphasis on 
    the ventral striatum (submitted).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Berendse, H.W., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Groenewegen (1990b) The connections of the medial part 
    of the subthalamic nucleus in the rat: Evidence for a parallel 
    organization.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Bernardi, M.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Carpenter, and G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">DiChiara (eds): Basal Ganglia, 111.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">New York Plenum Press (in press).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Berendse, H.W., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Voorn, A. te Kortschot, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Groenewegen (1988) Nuclear origin of thalamic afferents 
    of the ventral striatum determines their relation to patch/matrix 
    configurations in enkephalin-immunoreactivity in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">,J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Chem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Neuroanat. 1 :310.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Carpenter, M.B., J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Whittier, and F.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Mettler (1950) Analysis of choreoid hyperkinesia in the 
    rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Surgical and pharmacological analysis of hyperkinesia 
    resulting from lesions in the subthalamic nucleus of Luys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Neurol. 92:293-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Carpenter, M.B., S.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Carleton, J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Keller, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Conte (1981) Connections of the subthalamic nucleus in 
    the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Brain Res. 224:l-29.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Chang, H.T., C.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Wilson, and S.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Kitai (1981) Single neostriatal efferent axons in the 
    globus pallidus: A light and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Science 213t915-918.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Crossman, A.R. (1987) Primate models of dyskinesia: The 
    experimental approach to the study of basal ganglia-related 
    involuntary movement disorders.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Neuroscience 21 :140.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Domesick, V.B. (1981) Further observations on the 
    anatomy of the nucleus accumbens and caudate-putamen in the rat: 
    similarities and contrasts.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">In R.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Chronister and J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">DeFrance (eds): The Neurobiology of the Nucleus 
    Accumbens.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Brunswick, M E Haer Institute, pp. 7-39.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Ericson, H., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Blomqvist (1988).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Tracing of neuronal connections with cholera toxin 
    subunit B: light and electron microscopic immunohistochemistry 
    using monoclonal antibodies.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Meth. 24:225-235.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Fink-Jensen, A,, and J.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Mikkelsen (1989).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">The striato-entopeduncular pathway in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">A retrograde transport study with 
    wheatgermagglutinin-horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Brain Res. 476t19.5198.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Gerfen, C.R. (1985) The neostriatal mosaic.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Compartmental organization of projections from the 
    striatum to the substantia nigra in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Neurol. 236:454467.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Gerfen, C.R., and Sawchenko, P.E. (1984) An anterograde 
    neuroanatomical tracing method that shows the detailed morphology 
    of neurons, their axons and terminals: Immunohistochemical 
    localization of an axonally transported plant lectin, Phaseolus 
    oulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Gerfen, C.R., W.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Staines, G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Arbuthnott, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Fibiger (1982) Crossed connections of the substantia 
    nigra in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Neurol. 207:283-303.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Graybiel, A.M. (1977) Direct and indirect preoculomotor 
    pathways of the brainstem: an autoradiographic study of the pontine 
    reticular formation in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">I75:37-78.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Groenewegen, H.J., and F.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Russchen (1984), Organization of the efferent 
    projections of the nucleus accumhens to pallidal, hypothalamic, and 
    mesencephalic structures: A tracing and immunohistochemical study 
    in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Neurol. 223:347-367.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Groenewegen, H.J., and Wouterlood, F.G. (1990) Light and 
    electron microscopic tracing of neuronal connections with Phaseolus 
    oulgarisleucoagglutinin (PHA-L), and combinations with other 
    neuroanatomical techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">In F.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Wouterlood, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Van den Pol, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Bjorklund, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy, Vol. 
    8.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 47-124.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Groenewegen, H.J., P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Room, M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Witter, and A.H.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Lohman (1982) Cortical afferents of the nucleus 
    accumbens in the cat, studied with anterograde and retrograde 
    transport techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Neuroscience 7:977996.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Croenewegen, H.J., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Vermeulenvan der Zee, A. te Kortachot, and M.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Witter (1987) Organization of the projections from the 
    subiculum to the ventral striatum in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">A study using anterograde transport of Phaseolus 
    vulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Neuroscience 23:103-120.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Haber, S.N., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Nauta (1983) Ramifications of the globus pallidus in the 
    rat as indicated by patterns of immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Neuroscience 9:245-260.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Haber, S.N., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Groenewegen, E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Grove, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Nauta (1985) Efferent connections of the ventral 
    pallidum: Evidence of a dual striato pallidofugal pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Neurol. 235:322-335.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Haber, S.N., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Lynd, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Klein, and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Groenewegen (1990) Topographic organization of the 
    ventral striatal efferent projections in the Rhesus monkey: an 
    anterograde tracing study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">(in press).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Hammond, C., B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Rouzaire-Dubois, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">FBger, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Jackson, and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Crossman (1983) Anatomical and electrophysiological 
    studies on the reciprocal projections between the subthalamatic 
    nucleus and nucleus tegmenti pedunculopontinus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Neuroscience 9.4-52.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Hartmann-Von Monakow, K.?</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Akert, and H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Kunzle (1979) Projections of precentral and premotor 
    cortex to the red nucleus and other midbrain areas in Macaca 
    fasciccularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Brain Res. 34:91-105.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Heimer, L., and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Wilson (1975) The subcortical projections of the 
    allwortex: similarities in the neural associations of the 
    hippocampus, the piriform cortex, and the neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Santini (ed): Golgi Centennial Symposium.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">New York Raven Press, pp. 177-193.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Heimer, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Zaborszky (1985) Basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">In G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Australia: Academic Press, pp. 37-86.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Herkenham, M., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Nauta (1977) Afferent connections of the habenular 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">A horseradish peroxidase study, with a note on the 
    fiber-of-passage problem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Neurol. 173:123-146.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Jackson, A., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Crossman (1981) Basal ganglia and other afferent 
    projections to the peribrachial region in the rat: A study using 
    retrograde and anterograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Neuroscience 6:15371549.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Jackson, A., and A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Crossman (1983) Nucleus tegmenti pedunculopontinus: 
    efferent connections with special reference to the basal ganglia, 
    studied in the rat by anterograde and retrograde transport of 
    horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Neuroscience 10:725-765.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Kita, H., and S.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Kitai (1987) Efferent projections of the subthalamic 
    nucleus in the rat: Light and electron microscopic analysis with 
    the PHA-L method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Neurol. 260t435-452.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Kita, H., H.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Chang, and S.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Kitai (1983) The morphology of intracellularly labeled 
    rat subthalamic neurons: A light microscopic analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Neurol. 215:245-257.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Kunzle, H. (1978) An autoradiographic analysis of the 
    efferent connections from premotor and adjacent prefrontal regions 
    (areas 6 and 9) in MUCUCQ fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Brain Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Evol. 35135-234.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Kunzle, H., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Akert (1977) Efferent connections of cortical area 8 
    (frontal eye field) in Macaca fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">A reinvestigation using the autoradiographic 
    technique.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Neurol. 173147-164.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Lee, H.J., D.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Rye, A.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Hallanger, A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Levey, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Wainer (1988) Cholinergic Vs. noncholinergic efferents 
    from the mesopontine tegmentum to the extrapyramidal motor system 
    nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Neurol. 275469-492.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Luiten, P.G.M., R.P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Gaykema, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Traber, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Spencer Jr. (1987) Cortical projection of magnocellular 
    basol nucleus subdivision by anterogradely transported Phaseolus 
    uulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Brain Res. 413: 229-250.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Martin, J.P. (1927) Hemichorea resulting from a focal 
    lesion of the (The syndrome of the hody of Luys.)</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Brain 5Ot637-651.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">-hL, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Mufson, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Wainer, and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Levey (1983) Central cholinergic pathways in the rat: an 
    overview based on an alternative nomenclature (Chl-Ch6).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Neuroscience 30:1185-1202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Mintz, I., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Hammond, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Guihert, and V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Leviel (1986) Stimulation of the subthalamic nucleus 
    enhances the release of dopamine in the rat substantia nigra.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Brain Res. 376t406-408.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Nauta, H.J.W.., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Cole (1978) Efferent projections of the subthalamic 
    nucleus: An autoradiographic study in monkey and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Neurol. 180:1-16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Nauta, W.J.H. (1986).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Circuitous connections linking cerebral cortex, limbic 
    system, and corpus striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">In B.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Doane and K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Livingston (eds): The Limbic System: Functional 
    Organization and Clinical Disorders.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">New York: Raven Press, pp. 43-54.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Nauta, W.J.H., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Domesick (1979) The anatomy of the extrapyramidal 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">In K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Fuxe and D.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Calne (eds): Dopaminergic Ergot Derivates and Motor 
    Function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Oxford Pergamon Press, pp. 3-22.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Nauta, W.J.H., G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Smith, R.L.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Faull, andV.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Domesick (1978) Efferent connections and nigra afferents 
    of the nucleus accumbens septi in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Neuroscience 3:385401.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Nomura, S., N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Mizuno, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Sugimoto (1980) Direct projections from the 
    pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus to the subthalamic nucleus in 
    the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Brain Res. 196:223-227.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Parent, A,, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">-N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Hazrati, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Smith (1989) The subthalamic nucleus in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">A neuroanatomical and immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">In A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Crossman and M.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Sambrook (eds): Neural Mechanisms in Disorders of 
    Movement.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">London: John Libbey, pp. 29-35.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Parent, A,, and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Smith (1987) Organization of efferent projections of the 
    subthalamic nucleus in the squirrel monkey as revealed by 
    retrograde labeling methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Brain Res. 436.296-310.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Paxinos, G.W., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates, 
    2nd ed.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Ricardo, J.A. (1980) Efferent connections of the 
    subthalamic region in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">The subthalamic nucleus of Luys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Brain Res. 202257-271.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Rouzaire-Dubois, B., E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Scarnati, C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Hammond, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Crossman, and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Shibazaki (1983) Microiontophoretic studies on the 
    nature of the neurotransmitter in the subthalamo-entopeduncular 
    pathway of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Brain Res. 27Z:ll-20.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Royce, G.J., and E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Laine (1984) Efferent connections of the caudate 
    nucleus, including cortical projections of the striatum and other 
    basal ganglia: An autoradiographic and horseradish peroxidase 
    investigation in the cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Neurol. 226:28-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Rye, D.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Saper, H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Lee, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Wainer (1987) Pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus of the 
    rat: Cytoarchitecture, cytochemistry, and some extrapyramidal 
    connections of the Neurol. 259:483-528.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Saper, C.B. (1984) Organization of cerebral cortical 
    afferent systems in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Magnocellular basal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">J. a m p .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Neurol. 222313-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Schmued, L.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Fallon (1986) Fluoro-Gold a new fluorescent retrograde 
    axonal tracer with numerous unique properties.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Brain Res. 377:147-154.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Smith, Y., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Parent (1988) Neurons of the subthalamic nucleus in 
    primates display glutamate but not GABA immunoreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Brain Res. 453:353-356.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Sternherger, L.A. (1979) Immunocytochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">New York Wiley.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Sugimoto, T., and T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Hattori (1983) Confirmation of thalamosubthalamic 
    projections by electron microscopic autoradiography.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Brain Res. 267:335339.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Sugimoto, T., T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Hattori, N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Mizuno, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Itoh, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Sat0 (1983) Direct projections from the centre 
    median-parafascicular complex to the subthalamic nucleus in the cat 
    and rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Neurol. 214:209-216.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Whittier, J.P., and F.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Mettler (1949) Studies on the subthalamus of the rhesus 
    monkey. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Hyperkinesia and other physiological effects of 
    subthalamic lesions, with special reference to the subthalamic 
    nucleus of Luys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Neurol. 90:319-372.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Wilson, C.J., and K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Phelan (1982) Dual topographic representation 
    neostriatum in the globus pallidus of rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Brain Res. 243456459.</S>
  </References>

</File>

