<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Neural Associations of the Substantia Innominata in the Rat: 
  Afferent Connections</Title>

  <Authors>ELIZABETH A. GROVE</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The afferent connections of the substantia innominata (SI) 
    in the rat were determined employing the anterograde axonal 
    transport of Phaseobs vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) and the 
    retrograde transport of wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to 
    horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRP), in combination with histochemical 
    procedures to characterize the neuropil of the SI and identify 
    cholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Both neurochemical and connectional data establish that 
    the SI is organized into a dorsal and a ventral division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Each of these divisions is strongly affiliated with a 
    different region of the amygdala, and, together with its amygdalar 
    affiliate, forms part of one of two largely distinct constellations 
    of interconnected forebrain and brainstem cell groups.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">The dorsal SI receives selective innervation from the 
    lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, the 
    central and basolateral nuclei of the amygdala, the fundus of the 
    striatum, distinctive perifornical and caudolatera1 zones of the 
    lateral hypothalamus, and caudal brainstem structures including the 
    dorsal raphe nucleus, parabrachial nucleus, and nucleus of the 
    solitary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Projections preferentially directed to the ventral SI 
    arise from the medial part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis, the rostra1 twothirds of the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala, a large region of the rat amygdala that lies ventral to 
    the central nucleus, the medial preoptic area, anterior 
    hypothalamus, medialmost lateral hypothalamus, and the ventromedial 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Both SI divisions appear to receive afferents from the 
    dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus, supramammillary region, 
    ventral tegmental area, and the peripeduncular area of the 
    midbrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Projections to the SI whose selectivity was not determined 
    originate from medial prefrontal, insular, perirhinal, and 
    entorhinal cortex and from midline thalamic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Findings from both PHA-L and WGA-HRP experiments 
    additionally indicate that cell groups preferentially innervating a 
    single SI division maintain numerous projections to one another, 
    thus forming a tightly linked assembly of structures.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">In the rat, cholinergic neurons that are scattered 
    throughout the SI and in parts of the globus pallidus make up a 
    cell population equivalent to the primate basal nucleus of Meynert 
    (Mesulam et al.: Neuroscience 10:11851201, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">PHA-L-filled axons, labelled from lectin deposits in the 
    dorsal raphe nucleus, peripeduncular area, ventral tegmental area, 
    or caudomedial hypothalamus were occasionally seen to approach 
    individual cholinergic neurons in the SI, and to contact the 
    surface of such cells with axonal varicosities (putative synaptic 
    boutons).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">Pending confirmation in an electron microscopic study, 
    such findings suggest that several sources of innervation of the SI 
    may provide afferents to the cholinergic cells in the region.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">The term &quot;substantia innominata&quot; (SI) has 
    historically referred to an irregularly shaped region that reaches 
    the ventral surface of the mammalian brain and stretches beneath 
    the corpus striatum for most of the latter&apos;s rostrocaudal 
    extent (Konig and Klippel, &apos;63; Nauta and Haymaker, 
    &apos;69).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">It is now well established, however, that a ventral 
    extension of the globus pallidus (GP), the ventral pallidum WP) of 
    Heimer and Wilson (&apos;751, accounts for roughly the rostra1 
    third of the region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">Like the GP, the VP receives a heavy innervation from the 
    striatum (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75), which is reflected by the 
    presence in the entire VP-GP continuum of dense axon plexuses 
    immunoreactive for Lglutamate-1-decarboxylase and met-enkephalin 
    (Switzer et al., &apos;82; Zaborszky et al., &apos;82; Haber and 
    Nauta, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">The efferent connections of the VP, as well, appear to 
    parallel those of the overlying GP (Groenewegen and van Dijk, 
    &apos;84; Young et al., &apos;84; Haber et al., &apos;85; Zahm et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Strong evidence that the VP is a component of the basal 
    ganglia has led many investigators to reserve the term 
    &quot;substantia innominata&apos;&apos; for the comparatively 
    poorly characterized area caudal to the VP (de Olmos et al., 
    &apos;85; Heimer et al., &apos;85; Paxinos and Watson, &apos;82, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Reported here is the first of two companion studies 
    investigating the afferent and efferent connections of this region, 
    also referred to as the &quot;sublenticular substantia 
    innominata&quot; (de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Heimer et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Although there has been no single comprehensive study of 
    the efferents of the SI, it is evident the region maintains an 
    influence over structures in many of the major subdivisions of the 
    brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Recent attention has focused on projections to the 
    amygdala and cerebral cortex from the prominent group of 
    cholinergic cells that form the basal nucleus of Meynert in the 
    primate, as well as from noncholinergic SI neurons (Lehmann et al., 
    &apos;80; Big1 et al., &apos;82; Woolf and Butcher, &apos;82; Grove 
    et al., &apos;83; McKinney et al., &apos;83; Mesulam et al., 
    &apos;83a,b; Rye et al., &apos;84b; Saper, &apos;84; Carlsen et 
    al., &apos;85; Fisher et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">The SI also sends efferents as far caudal in the neural 
    axis as the medulla, and to cell groups in the pons, midbrain and 
    diencephalon (Jones et al., &apos;76; Phillipson, &apos;79; 
    Schwaber et al., &apos;82; Swanson et al., &apos;84; Young et al., 
    &apos;84; Holstege et al., &apos;85; Mogenson et al., &apos;85; 
    Levey et al., &apos;87; Russchen et al., &apos;87; Grove, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">Afferents to the SI appear to arise from similarly 
    widespread cortical and subcortical structures that fit within the 
    broad category of the &quot;limbic system&quot; (Jones et al., 
    &apos;76; Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Saper et al., &apos;79a,b; 
    Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; Mesulam and Mufson, &apos;84; Russchen 
    et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">A systematic determination of the afferent connections of 
    a region is particularly helpful when its anatomical and functional 
    character is unclear, as in the case of the SI, since the cell 
    groups that provide input may be themselves better understood.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">However, investigation of the afferents of the SI is 
    especially challenging because of its strikingly fibrous nature.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Axons traversing the SI in the ansa peduncularis and 
    medial forebrain bundle establish numerous links between forebrain 
    and brainstem cell groups.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Which of these fiber contingents also distribute 
    terminals in the SI?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">A problem in interpreting the results of retrograde 
    tracer injections in such a region is that uptake and 
    transportation by fibers that pass through the injection site 
    without terminating cannot be discounted.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Fibers of passage have been found to take up horseradish 
    peroxidase (HRP) and, at least when damaged, wheat germ agglutinin 
    conjugated to HRP (WGA-HRP) (unpublished observations).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Injections of these retrograde tracers into the SI can, 
    however, provide a survey of possible afferent sources, each of 
    which can be further investigated with anterograde axonal a 
    transport methods.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">The Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) method 1 
    (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84) is an ideal anterograde circuit by 
    tracing technique for determining the afferent and efferent 
    connections of fibrous areas such as the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Under specified ing delivery conditions (Gerfen and 
    Sawchenko, &apos;84), PHA-L is not taken up by axons passing 
    through the injection site, an advantage it shares with the 
    autoradiographic antero50 grade tracing technique.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Unlike the latter, however, the PHA-L method allows, at 
    the light microscope level, a reliable distinction of labelled axon 
    terminals from nonterminating axon segments (Gerfen and Sawchenko, 
    &apos;84; Wouterlood and Groenewegen, &apos;85; Grove and Ingham, 
    &apos;86), even at in regions where the terminals are sparse or are 
    IooseIy scattered among labelled fibers of passage.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">The present study in the rat examines the afferent conin 
    nections of the SI, employing the anterograde axonal transport of 
    PHA-L and retrograde transport of WGA-HRP, in as combination with 
    histochemical procedures to characterize of the neuropil of the SI 
    and identify cholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">In brief, both histochemical and connectional data 
    obtained in the 40 present study indicate that the SI is organized 
    into a dorsal and a ventral division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">The afferent connections of the SI, as well as its 
    efferent projections, which are the subject of a subsequent paper 
    (Grove, &apos;88), indicate each SI division is strongly affiliated 
    with a different part of the amygdala, and, together with its 
    amygdalar affiliate, forms part of one ing of two distinct 
    constellations of interconnected forebrain and brainstem cell 
    groups.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s35">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s36">For all experiments in 
    the present study, adult, female, albino rats (CD strain) were 
    obtained from Charles River Laboratories.</S>
    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s37">During surgical 
    procedures, and before transcardial perfusion of fixatives, the 
    animals were deeply anesthetized with Chloropent, a veterinary 
    anesthetic containing chloral hydrate and pentobarbital (obtained 
    for these experiments from Ft.</S>
    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s38">Dodge Labs, but no longer 
    available from this source). and Retrograde tracing experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to horseradish 
    peroxidase (WGA-HRP) (Sigma) was dissolved in Tris-buffered saline, 
    pH 7.6, to a 5-10% solution.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Deposits of WGA-HRP were placed in the basal forebrain of 
    sixteen rats.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Small tracer injections with little or no spread along 
    the pipette track were consistently obtained by applying 2 pA of 
    direct current (Midgard constant-current source), for 2-5 minutes, 
    through a glass pipette with a tip diameter of 10-15 pm.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Passing current for 10-15 minutes produced larger but 
    less well-confined injections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Twenty-four to 72 hours after surgery animals were 
    perfused transcardially with 50 ml saline, followed by 500 ml of 2% 
    glutaraldehyde and 0.5% paraformaldehyde, or 2% paraformaldehyde 
    and 0.1% glutaraldehyde, in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4, and a 
    final rinse of 100 ml 3% sucrose in the same buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">After overnight rinsing in 30% sucrose in phosphate 
    buffer, the brains were cut on a freezing microtome in the 
    transverse plane at 50 pm into six series.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Two standard procedures were employed to demonstrate HRP 
    with tetramethylbenzidine (TMB) as the chromagen (Mesulam, 
    &apos;78; de Olmos et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Tissue sections were counterstained with Neutral Red.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s47">Anterograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">PHA-L, obtained from Vector Labs, was reconstituted as 2% 
    solution in 0.05 M Tris-buffered saline (TBS), pH 7:6.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Glass pipettes, tip diameter 5-10 pm, were filled with 
    about p1 of this solution, and PHA-L was deposited in the brain 
    passing through the solution a pulsed current (5 FA, 7 seconds on, 
    7 seconds off) for 10-60 minutes, varying accordto the area of the 
    brain injected.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">In all, PHA-L injections were made in 65 animals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">After 4-8 days, the rats were perfused transeardially 
    with ml of saline, followed by fixative (up to 500 ml in 15-20 
    minutes) consisting of either 4% paraformaldehyde or 2% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.1% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, 
    pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">The brains were stored in phosphate buffer, and, after a 
    standard delay of 2-16 hours, sectioned 30-50 pm into six series 
    using an Oxford Vibratome.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">PHA-L was localized with a peroxidase-antiperoxidase 
    (PAP) procedure.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Sections were first rinsed for 60 minutes Tris-buffered 
    saline (TBS), pH 7.6, 0.5 M, containing 1% Triton-X.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">The tissue was then washed for 30-60 minutes, after each 
    subsequent incubation step, in three changes plain TBS, and 
    transferred to TBS plus primary antiserum, goat anti-PHA-L (Vector 
    Laboratories) (MOO), for hours at 4°C.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">Sections were next incubated in TBS plus rabbit antigoat 
    IgG (1:40) (Antibodies Inc.), followed by TBS plus 
    peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP), raised in goat (1:lOO) 
    (Sternberger-Meyer Immunochemicals, Inc.).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Both steps were carried out at room temperature for 60 
    minutes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Sections were presoaked for 15 minutes in a solution 
    contain0.05% diaminobenzidine (DAB) in Tris buffer, pH 7.6, 0.05 M, 
    then hydrogen peroxidase was added to a final concentration of 
    0.01%.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The chromagen reaction was allowed to proceed for 10-30 
    minutes, and stopped by transferring the sections to phosphate 
    buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">An adequate Nissl counterstain of these tissue sections 
    could be obtained with Cresyl Violet.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">When&apos; PHA-L and choline acetyltransferase (ChAT) 
    immunoreactivity was to be localized in the same tissue sections, 
    rat anti-ChAT (Boehringer Mannheim) (1:500) was added to the 
    primary incubation medium, rabbit anti-rat IgG (Antibodies 
    Incorporated) was added to the secondary, PAP, raised in rat 
    (Sternberger-Meyer), was added to the PAP incubation step.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Control sections were incubated through the whole 
    procedure, omitting either the ChAT or PHA-L primary antibodies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Although the same chromagen, DAB, marked both forms of 
    immunoreactivity, examination of control sections showed that the 
    two could be distinguished by features described below.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Additional control sections were processed to reveal ChAT 
    immunoreactivity alone by including in the protocol only anti-ChAT 
    primary antiserum and the appropriate secondary antiserum and PAP 
    complex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s65">Additional histochemical 
    procedures</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">From each brain in which PHA-L deposits were placed, one 
    series of tissue sections was processed to locate 
    metenkephalin-like immunoreactivity (ENK-IR) instead of PHA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">A PAP technique similar in outline to that described 
    above was employed, with the exceptions that 0.5% Triton-X was 
    added to all incubation media to optimize staining, the primary 
    antiserum was rabbit anti-ENK (donated by Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Elde), the secondary antiserum was goat antirabbit IgG 
    (Antibodies Incorporated), and the PAP complex was raised in rabbit 
    (Sternberger-Meyer).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Three additional brains were used to determine the extent 
    and some histochemical features of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">These were perfused as above and sectioned in the 
    transverse plane at 30 pm into six series.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Complete series of tissue sections through the basal 
    forebrain were stained to reveal Nissl substance (Cresyl Violet), 
    or acetylcholinesterase activity (Geneser-Jensen and Blackstad, 
    &apos;71), or were processed immunohistochemically to reveal 
    enkephalin, choline acetyltransferase, or tyrosine hydroxylase (TH) 
    immunoreactivities.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">The PAP procedure used to reveal TH immunoreactivity was 
    identical to that employed to localize enkephalin except that the 
    primary antiserum was rabbit antityrosine hydroxylase (Eugene Tech 
    International).</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s74">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s75">The substantia innominata 
    : topographic relations and some histochemical features</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">The SI appears in Nisslor myelin-stained material to be 
    an amorphous region with few clear boundaries.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">However, two striking anatomical features are 
    characteristic of the SI and these were used to determine its 
    extent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">In the rat the SI 1 ) contains scattered cholinergic 
    perikarya and 2 ) caudal to the ventral pallidum , is densely 
    traversed by axons of the ansa peduncularis , a fiber system 
    linking the diencephalon with the amygdala and certain ventral 
    cortices ( Nauta and Haymaker , &apos; 69 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">In keeping with standard terminology in the rat , the 
    nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal band ( NHDB ) is not 
    included under the term SI ( Konig and Klippel , &apos; 63 ; 
    Paxinos and Watson , &apos; 82, &apos; 86 ) , even though it meets 
    the two criteria .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Supporting such a convention, in several histochemical 
    and connectional respects the NHDB differs from the overlying SI 
    (Ottersen &apos;80; de Olmos et al., &apos;85; and see below).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">For example, in Timm-stained preparations the SI displays 
    modest, even staining, but the NHDB is almost free of reaction 
    product (Ottersen, &apos;80; de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Figure 1 shows the extent of the SI according to the two 
    criteiia given above.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">Cholinergic perikarya were identified by ChAT 
    immunoreactivity , and the course of the ansa peduncularis was 
    determined from cases described below in which deposits of the 
    anterograde tracer <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> were 
    placed in <injectionLocation>amygdalar and hypothalamic 
    sites</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">Rostromedially , the SI merges with <labelingLocation>the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis ( BNS )</labelingLocation>( Fig 
    . 1B , C ) , which contains <labelingDescription>sparse cholinergic 
    cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">Caudal to the VP , as the NHDB dwindles , the SI broadens 
    dorsoventrally ( Fig . 1D - F ) to its widest extent and its dorsal 
    half fades without a clear boundary into the medial division of the 
    rostral central nucleus of the amygdala ( Ace ) ( Fig . lE , F ) , 
    which , likewise , contains several cholinergic cells .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86">The ventral half of the SI blends laterally into the 
    anterior amygdaloid area ( AAA ) ( Fig . 1D , E ) and curves down 
    between the caudal NHDB and the nucleus of the lateral olfactory 
    tract ( NLOT ) ( Fig . 1E ) into an ill - defined region that is 
    replaced caudally by the medial nucleus of the amygdala ( AM ) ( 
    Fig . 1F ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">Medially , the SI extends into the cellular interstices 
    of the inferior thalamic peduncle ( ITP ) and this fiber tract, 
    together with the medial fore , - bundle ( Fig . lE ) , separates 
    the SI from <labelingLocation>the lateral preoptic area and lateral 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">At more caudal levels still , the SI dwindles , to give 
    space to <labelingLocation>the laterally expanding optic tract ( OT 
    )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . lG , H ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Drawn according to <labelingLocation>the two criteria 
    given above , the dorsal boundary of the SI</labelingLocation> is 
    similar to that shown by Paxinos and Watson ( &apos; 86 ) in their 
    atlas of the rat brain .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">However, the SI illustrated here appears slightly more 
    extensive ventrally.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">(Compare, e.g., Paxinos and Watson, &apos;86, Fig. 23, 
    and Fig. 1D,E from the present study.)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">Although the GP is distinguished from the SI by lying 
    dorsal to the dense fiber traffic of the ansa peduncularis, the 
    ventromedial and caudal GP resemble the SI in containing many 
    cholinergic perikarya (Fig. 1D-G).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">These cells <labelingDescription>are particularly 
    numerous</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the cellular 
    interstices of the internal capsule</labelingLocation> , most of 
    which display connectional and neurochemical features of pallidal 
    tissue ( Haber et al . , &apos; 85 ; Grove et al . , &apos; 861, 
    including the presence of a terminal configuration characteristic 
    of the VP and GP ( Haber and Nauta , &apos; 83, the enkephalin - 
    immunoreactive ( ENK - IRI &quot; woolly fiber &quot; ( Fig . 1D - 
    F ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingDescription>ENK - IR woolly 
    fibers</labelingDescription> not only 
    <labelingModifier>fill</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the VP 
    and GP</labelingLocation> but also invade <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral BNS</labelingLocation> ( Haber and Nauta , &apos; 83 ) and 
    the dorsalmost SI ( Fig . 1B - F ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">The continuity of the ENK - IR plexus is , however , 
    broken by an inlet , <labelingDescription>free of ENK - IR woolly 
    fibers</labelingDescription> , and filled by <labelingDescription>a 
    dense grouping of cholinergic cells</labelingDescription> , first 
    oriented vertically ( Fig . 1B , C , arrowheads ) , then near - 
    horizontally ( Fig . lD , arrowhead ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">This peculiar feature , reminiscent of the cholinergic 
    cell clusters of the primate basal nucleus of Meynert ( BNM ) , 
    intervenes between the continuous mass of the lateral BNS and 
    rostromedial SI on one side and the VP and GP on the other ( Fig . 
    1B - D ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s97"><labelingDescription>A different ENK - IR axon terminal 
    configuration</labelingDescription> , namely a field of dotlike 
    immunoreactive &quot; puncta , &quot; pervades the rest of the SI ( 
    not shown ) and emphasizes the continuity of the SI with parts of 
    <labelingLocation>the adjacent hypothalamus and 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> , which exhibit a similar feature .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">By contrast , at least most of <labelingLocation>the 
    nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal 
    band</labelingLocation> is conspicuously pale in ENK - stained 
    material , further indicating that the NHDB and overlying SI can be 
    distinguished on neurochemical and connectional grounds .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">The extent of <labelingDescription>a terminal field of 
    tyrosine hydroxylaseimmunoreactive ( TH - IR ) 
    fibers</labelingDescription> , illustrated in Figure 2, reveals 
    several features of the SI and adjacent structures .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">At rostral levels ( Fig . 2A , B ) , 
    <labelingDescription>a loose - woven plexus of TH - IR fibers 
    displaying axon terminals</labelingDescription> , representing 
    <labelingDescription>a light to moderately dense 
    innervation</labelingDescription> , pervades <labelingLocation>
    lateral and ventral parts of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis</labelingLocation> , intruding only minimally into 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral pallidum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">Slightly more caudally , <labelingDescription>the TH - 
    IR plexus</labelingDescription> reaches into <labelingLocation>the 
    most rostromedial SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C ) and 
    <labelingDescription>a second patch of TH - IR varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> appears in <labelingLocation>the 
    rostral part of the central nucleus of the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102"><labelingLocation>The ventral 
    pallidum</labelingLocation> intervenes , containing 
    <labelingDescription>only small islands of labelled varicose 
    axons</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 2C ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">Caudal to the VP , <labelingDescription>the TH - IR 
    fiber plexus</labelingDescription> sweeps across <labelingLocation>
    the SI</labelingLocation> , com pleting the lateral BNS - SI - Ace 
    continuum ( Fig . 2D ) and defining a <labelingLocation>dorsal 
    division of the SI</labelingLocation> , including but not limited 
    to <labelingLocation>the dorsalmost strip of the 
    SI</labelingLocation> that is <labelingDescription>pervaded by ENK 
    - IR woolly fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104"><labelingLocation>The GP , like the 
    VP</labelingLocation> , is 
    <labelingModifier>filled</labelingModifier> with 
    <labelingDescription>thick , smooth , presumably nonterminating ,TH 
    - IR fibers</labelingDescription> en route to <injectionLocation>
    the striatum</injectionLocation> ( not shown ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">Only along <labelingLocation>the lateral face of the 
    internal capsule</labelingLocation> do <labelingDescription>small 
    patches of slender , varicose TH - IR fibers</labelingDescription> 
    appear , loosely continuous with <labelingDescription>the light 
    terminal field</labelingDescription> that 
    <labelingModifier>fills</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C - E ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">comment The TH - IR terminal field described above 
    distinguishes a dorsal from a ventral division in the SI and 
    emphasizes the continuity of the lateral BNS , dorsal SI , and 
    central nucleus of the amygdala .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">Further , the TH - IR terminal plexus generally 
    distinguishes the dorsal SI from the ventral pallidum and overlying 
    GP yet also reveals a similarity between the SI and at least a 
    limited part of the cholinergic cell - rich region of the GP .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">The presence of ENK - IR woolly fibers , a feature 
    typical of pallidal tissue , might suggest that the dorsalmost 
    strip of the SI ( as drawn by Paxinos and Watson , &apos; 82, 
    &apos; 86 ; de Olmos and his colleagues , &apos; 85 ; and the 
    present author ) is best considered an extension of the globus 
    pallidus , similar to the VP .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">In the monkey, ENK-IR woolly fibers similarly extend 
    into the intermediate and caudal parts of the BNM (Russchen et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">However , before identifying a region as pallidal it 
    should perhaps also be found to display such characteristic 
    features as a reciprocal connection with the striatum , which 
    provides the ENK - IR axonal component of the woolly fiber in the 
    VP and GP ( Haber and Elde , &apos; 81 ; Zaborszky et al . , &apos; 
    82 ; Haber and Nauta , &apos; 83 ) , the presence of a typically 
    pallidal cell population described by Fox et al . ( &apos; 74 ) , 
    and , possibly , a second reciprocal connection with the 
    subthalamic nucleus ( Graybiel and Ragsdale , &apos; 79 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">The question of whether the dorsalmost strip of the SI 
    meets these criteria is discussed further below, but a conclusive 
    characterization of this district is beyond the scope of the 
    present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">Instead, the afferent connections of the entire SI will 
    be investigated, without prejudice as to whether the dorsalmost SI 
    should ultimately be viewed as, or as mixed with, pallidal 
    tissue.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">The feature of the dorsalmost SI that is of greatest 
    interest here - and defines it as part of the SI distinct from the 
    overlying GP - is the passage of the dorsal third of a dense band 
    of fibers composing the ansa peduncularis .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">Findings presented below, and in a companion study 
    (Grove, 88), indicate that this feature determines several of the 
    afferent and efferent connections of the dorsalmost SI; thus the 
    Iatter bears a strong connectional similarity to the rest of the 
    SI, traversed by the ventral two-thirds of the ansa 
    peduncularis.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s115">Afferents to 
    <connxTermination>the substantia innominata and the cholinergic 
    cell - rich region of the globus pallidus</connxTermination> 
    surveyed with the retrograde transport of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical></S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">Deposits of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    were placed in several sites within <injectionLocation>the basal 
    forebrain</injectionLocation> ( Fig . 3 ) to survey possible 
    afferents to three regions : <labelingLocation>the ventral and 
    dorsal divisions of the SI , distinguished above on neurochemical 
    grounds , and the cholinergic cell - rich portion of the 
    GP</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">All three regions can be characterized by shared 
    projections to the cortex and amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">Case RHSZl.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">In case RHSIl <exptLabel>an injection of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> was centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the dorsal SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
      , with some spillage of the tracer along the pipette track in 
      <injectionSpread>the medial GP</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120"><labelingDescription>Retrogradely labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were found in <labelingLocation>
      numerous structures</labelingLocation> , almost all of which were 
      noted to lie along either <labelingLocation>the ansa peduncularis 
      or medial forebrain bundle</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><labelingDescription>Cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> at rostral levels in this brain 
      appeared in <labelingLocation>the SI , the fundus of the 
      striatum</labelingLocation> , and in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4A , B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">A little more caudally , 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> were labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>the central nucleus of the amygdala , 
      particularly its medial segment</labelingLocation> , and in 
      <labelingLocation>the basolateral nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 4B - D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">Additionally , <labelingDescription>a few WGA - HRP - 
      filled cells</labelingDescription> appeared in a region ventral 
      to <labelingLocation>the central nucleus and dorsal to the 
      cortical nuclei of the amygdala</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4C ) 
      .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">In the present study , no subnuclear boundaries have 
      been drawn in the part of the amygdala just mentioned , except 
      for those marking <labelingLocation>the intercalated 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">Such boundaries were identified with reference to 
      tissue sections stained to reveal Nissl substance, 
      acetylcholinesterase activity, or enkephalin or tyrosine 
      hydroxylase immunoreactivities.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126">None of these stains revealed clear subnuclear borders 
      in <labelingLocation>the region ventral to the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127">In comparison , however , it should be noted that 
      several authors have successfully identified <labelingLocation>a 
      rostral portion of the basomedial nucleus ( ABM 
      )</labelingLocation> in part of this region ( Krettek and Price , 
      78b ; de Olmos et al . , 85 ; Paxinos and Watson , 86 ) , and 
      Paxinos and Watson ( 86 ) indicate that much of the rest of this 
      amygdaloid district may be occupied by <labelingLocation>an intra 
      - amygdaloid division of the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> ( see their Figs . 28 - 32 ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128">In <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>marked 
      concentrations of WGAHRP - filled cells</labelingDescription> 
      appeared in <labelingLocation>a distinctive perifornical region 
      of the lateral hypothalamus ( LH )</labelingLocation> that also 
      contains<labelingDescription>enkephalin - immunoreactive woolly 
      fibers</labelingDescription> streaming medially from 
      <labelingLocation>the entopeduncular nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 40, and in <labelingLocation>a triangular , caudolateral 
      zone of the LH , just medial to the subthalamic nucleus ( STH 
      )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4D , E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129">(Note that the perifornical nucleus identified by 
      other authors (Paxinos and Watson, 86) seems to be caudal to the 
      perifornical zone indicated here.)</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130"><labelingDescription>Cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      STH</labelingLocation> itself may have been due to the spread of 
      the injection site into <labelingLocation>the medial 
      GP</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131"><labelingDescription>A modest concentration of 
      labelled cells</labelingDescription> could also be seen in 
      <labelingLocation>the LH just ventral to the 
      fornix</labelingLocation> at relatively caudal levels ( Fig . 4D 
      , E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132"><labelingDescription>A few 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the lateralmost part of the lateral preoptic area ( LPO ) , 
      dorsomedial hypothalamus ( DMH )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4D ) 
      , <labelingLocation>posterior hypothalamus ( PH 
      )</labelingLocation>( Fig . 4E ) , and <labelingLocation>
      supramammillary region ( SUM )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4F ) 
      .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133"><labelingLocation>The perifornical and caudolateral 
      zones of the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> that 
      contained <labelingDescription>labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> in this case are marked out 
      connectionally in other ways , to be described in more detail 
      below .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134">For example , <labelingDescription>dense clusters of 
      retrogradely labelled cells</labelingDescription> filled 
      <labelingLocation>the two districts</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5 
      ) after <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
      injection in <injectionLocation>the dorsomedial 
      medulla</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( case RHM1, Grove , 
      &apos; 88 ) that involved <injectionLocation>the nucleus of the 
      solitary tract and dorsal motor nucleus of the 
      vagus</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">Similarly striking <labelingDescription>cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in these small subregions of 
      <labelingLocation>the LH</labelingLocation> followed deposits of 
      the tracer in <injectionLocation>the central nucleus of the 
      amygdala</injectionLocation> ( <exptLabel>case RHCEB</exptLabel> 
      ) or <injectionLocation>parabrachial nucleus</injectionLocation> 
      ( <exptLabel>RHPBG</exptLabel> , Grove , &apos; 88 ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136">In the thalamus of case RHSI1, 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> were labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>the parafascicular nucleus ( PF 
      )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4D ) , and medial to PF where the 
      midline thalamus merges with the central gray of the midbrain 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137">Since no other case with a <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> deposit involving <injectionLocation>the 
      SI</injectionLocation> contained <labelingDescription>back - 
      filled cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      parafascicular nucleus</labelingLocation> , such labelling in 
      RHSIl may have been due , again , to a spread of the 
      <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> deposit into 
      <injectionSpread>the GP</injectionSpread> , or to uptake by 
      fibers passing through the injection site .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138"><labelingDescription>A continuum of labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> stretched caudolaterally from 
      <labelingLocation>the parvocellular part of the subparafascicular 
      nucleus of the thalamus ( SPF , arrowheads , Fig . 4D - F ) , 
      into the peripeduncular area ( PPA ) of the midbrain ( Fig . 4G 
      )</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139">Caudal to the diencephalon , labelled perikarya 
      appeared within cell groups organized along two trajectories in 
      <labelingLocation>the midbrain and pons</labelingLocation> , 
      dividing in <labelingLocation>the rostral midbrain and 
      rejoining</labelingLocation> at more caudal levels , 
      corresponding closely to the bifurcating course of the medial 
      forebrain bundle ( Nauta and Domesick , &apos; 82 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140">Thus , 
      <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> were labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental area ( VTA 
      )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4F , G ) , <labelingLocation>
      substantia nigra pars compacta ( SNpc )</labelingLocation> Pig . 
      4G ) , <labelingLocation>the region of cell group 
      A8</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4H ) , <labelingLocation>nucleus 
      linearis of the raphe</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 4G ) , 
      <labelingLocation>dorsal raphe nucleus ( DR )</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 4H ) , <labelingLocation>central gray</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 4H ) , <labelingLocation>locus 
      coeruleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 41 ) , and <labelingLocation>
      both medial and lateral subdivisions of the parabrachial nucleus 
      ( PB )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 41 , J ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">Case RHCHS.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142">In case RHCHS , <exptLabel>the <tracerChemical>WGA - 
      HRP</tracerChemical> deposit was centered in <injectionLocation>
      the ventral SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , spreading into 
      <injectionSpread>the caudal portion of the nucleus of the 
      horizontal limb of the diagonal band</injectionSpread> ( NHDB ) ( 
      Fig . 3B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143">In the caudal brainstem , 
      <labelingDescription>labelled neurons</labelingDescription> were 
      distributed in a pattern similar to that in case RHSIl but were 
      markedly fewer .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s144">Further , a strikingly different and complementary 
      pattern of <labelingDescription>cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      basal forebrain</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s145"><labelingLocation>The central and basolateral nuclei 
      of the amygdala</labelingLocation> contained 
      <labelingDescription>few WGA - HRP - filled 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> , but such cells were numerous in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral and medial 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> , including <labelingLocation>the 
      medial nucleus , the cortical nuclei , the region ventral to ACe 
      ( Fig . 6A , B ) , and the anterior amygdaloid 
      area</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s146">Only <labelingDescription>a few 
      cells</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the lateral part of the BNS</labelingLocation> , and many more 
      were evident in <labelingLocation>medial and posterior portions 
      of the nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s147">Additionally , perikarya were labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>piriform cortex ( Fig . 6A , B 
      )</labelingLocation> , and in <injectionLocation>the most ventral 
      part of insular cortex</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s148">In <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>WGA - HRP 
      - filled neurons</labelingDescription> were distributed in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial ( MPO ) and lateral preoptic areas 
      and anterior hypothalamic area ( AH )</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149">More caudally ( Fig . 6A , B ) , 
      <labelingDescription>cell labelling</labelingDescription> was 
      loosely dispersed in <labelingLocation>the LH</labelingLocation> 
      , <labelingDescription>with several labelled 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the most 
      medial LH</labelingLocation> but no evident concentration in the 
      perifornical or caudolateral zones strikingly marked out in case 
      RHSI1.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150">Similar to that case , however , a small cluster of 
      <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> - filled cells 
      appeared just ventral to <labelingLocation>the 
      fornix</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151"><labelingDescription>Additional 
      cells</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the dorsomedial hypothalamus , posterior hypothalamus and 
      supramammillary region</labelingLocation> , but , unlike the 
      previous case , <labelingLocation>the ventromedial and arcuate 
      nuclei ( Fig . 6A )</labelingLocation> as well as 
      <labelingLocation>the premammillary area</labelingLocation> also 
      contained <labelingDescription>a few labelled 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">Case RHBNl.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153">In case RHBN1, <exptLabel>a large <tracerChemical>WGA 
      - HRP</tracerChemical> injection involved <injectionLocation>the 
      ventral and dorsal SI and part of the rostral 
      amygdala</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , but not 
      <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the NHDB</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 3C 
      ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s154"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> appeared in all the hypothalamic , 
      amygdaloid , and brainstem sites that contained 
      <labelingDescription>such cells</labelingDescription> in RHSIl 
      and RHCHS .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155">Apparently because of the large volume of tracer 
      injected , <labelingDescription>cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was in all these areas more 
      profuse than in cases RHSIl or RHCHS .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156"><labelingLocation>The SPF - PPA 
      continuum</labelingLocation> , in particular , was marked by 
      <labelingDescription>numerous WGA - HRP - filled 
      neurons</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157"><labelingDescription>Further cell labelling appeared , 
      sparsely</labelingDescription> , in <labelingLocation>the 
      paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus ( PVH ) and the 
      midline thalamus</labelingLocation> , including <labelingLocation>
      the paratenial , paraventricular , central medial , rhomboid , 
      and reuniens nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">In <labelingLocation>the lower 
      brainstem</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>a few 
      labelled perikarya</labelingDescription> were identified in 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus subcoeruleus and nucleus of the 
      solitary tract</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159">Figure 7 illustrates the distribution of 
      <labelingDescription>WGA - HRP - filled 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> observed in <labelingLocation>the 
      cortex</labelingLocation> in cases RHBNl and RHCH9.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">Both cases were marked by large injection sites and by 
      abundant <labelingDescription>cortical cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161">Nonetheless , all such labelling taken together marked 
      out only selected areas of <labelingLocation>the cortical 
      mantle</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">Thus , <labelingDescription>many labelled 
      cells</labelingDescription> were identified in <labelingLocation>
      medial prefrontal , insular , perirhinal , piriform and 
      entorhinal cortices</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 7 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">By contrast , <labelingDescription>very few 
      neurons</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      areas on the lateral convexity of the cortex</labelingLocation> 
      or along <labelingLocation>the medial face of the hemisphere 
      caudal to the genu of the corpus callosum ( divisions in medial 
      prefrontal cortex</labelingLocation> , Fig . 7, according to 
      Beckstead , 79 ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">Cases RHCE2 and RHBMl.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">The subcortical distribution of cells labelled following 
    <exptLabel>injections of <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    into <injectionLocation>the SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    strongly resembled that reported to result from retrograde tracer 
    injections into the amygdala Weening , &apos; 78 ; Ottersen and Ben 
    - Ari , &apos; 79 ; Aggleton et al . , &apos; 80 ; Mehler , &apos; 
    80 ; Norita and Kawamura , &apos; 80 ; Ottersen , &apos; 80 ; 
    Mehler et al . , &apos; 81 ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s166">Several cases available to 
    the present study allowed direct comparisons.</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">Following an injection of <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> centered at <injectionLocation>a midcaudal 
    level of the central nucleus of the amygdala</injectionLocation> ( 
    RHCEZ ) ( Fig . 3D ) , not spreading into 
    <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the SI</injectionSpread> , 
    <labelingDescription>labelled cells</labelingDescription> were 
    distributed in a pattern almost exactly matching that noted in case 
    RHSIl with a dorsal SI injection ( Fig . 4 ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s168">A few 
    differences included <labelingDescription>the absence of labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the subthalamic 
    nucleus and the parafascicular nucleus of the 
    thalamus</labelingLocation> ( possibly due in RHSIl to tracer 
    uptake by fibers passing through or terminating in <injectionSpread>
    the medial globus pallidus</injectionSpread> , which was minimally 
    invaded by the <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> deposit ) 
    .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">In similar fashion , <exptLabel>an injectj . on of 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>
    a ventromedial region of the 
    amygdala</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , immediately caudal to , 
    and contiguous with , the ventral SI ( case RHBM1 ) ( Fig . 3D ) , 
    <labelingDescription>labelled perikarya</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus and 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> that were distributed almost 
    exactly like those bac , llled from the ventral SI ( case RHCHg ) 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170">cases RHcH2 and RHCH3Finally , to Survey the POSsible 
      sources of fibers afferent selectively to the cholinergic cell - 
      rich region of the GP , <exptLabel>tracer injections were 
      centered in <injectionLocation>the medial ( RHCHZ , Fig . 3C ) or 
      lateral GP ( RHCH3, Fig .3B; and RHCH4, not 
      shown)</injectionLocation></exptLabel>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s172"><labelingDescription>Cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> seen only when the injection site 
      involved <injectionLocation>the medial cholinergic cell - rich GP 
      district</injectionLocation> was distributed in just a few sites 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">In case RHCHZ , <labelingDescription>a small number of 
      WGA - HRP - filled neurons</labelingDescription> appeared in 
      <labelingLocation>the central nucleus of the amygdala , lateral 
      and dorsomedial hypothalamus , and lateral parabrachial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174">Such <labelingDescription>cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> , strongly resembling the pattern 
      in case RHSIl ( with a dorsal SI injection ) , but sparser , is 
      difficult to interpret because it could result from a small 
      spread of the injection site into <injectionSpread>the dorsal 
      substantia innominata</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175">By contrast , <labelingDescription>many more WGA - HRP 
      - filled neurons</labelingDescription> were identified in 
      <labelingLocation>the peripeduncular area</labelingLocation> than 
      in case RHSI1.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s176">Contrary to the findings of Haring and Wang ( &apos; 
      861, who report finding <labelingDescription>retrogradely 
      labelled perikarya</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      cortex</labelingLocation> after WGAHRP injections into 
      <labelingLocation>the medial but not lateral globus 
      pallidus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>labelled 
      cortical neurons</labelingDescription> were found after 
      injections involving either GP region .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s177">However , <labelingDescription>anomalous cell 
      labelling</labelingDescription> also appeared in parts of 
      thalamus unlikely to project to the GP , namely the ventrobasal 
      nuclei .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Thus WGA-HFtP was almost certainly taken up and 
    transported by corticopetal fibers, and therefore possibly also by 
    corticofugal axons, that pass through the GP without 
    terminating.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s179">Afferents to 
    <connxTermination>the substantia innominata and the cholinergic 
    cell - rich region of the globus pallidus</connxTermination> 
    determined with the anterograde transport of Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">The <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> survey 
    described above suggested several possible sources of input to 
    <connxTermination>the SI and the adjacent cholinergic cell - rich 
    region of the GP</connxTermination> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">These afferent connections were further investigated by 
    placing <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> into most of the 
    candidate sites .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">Findings from the PHA - L cases described below provide 
    confirmation of SI innervation from many candidate sources , 
    support a division of the SI into a dorsal and a ventral subregion 
    , and demonstrate a strong similarity between the afferent 
    connections of the SI and those of the amygdala .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">In addition , <labelingDescription>a high 
    degree</labelingDescription> of interconnectivity is indicated 
    among structures that preferentially innervate <connxTermination>a 
    single SI division</connxTermination>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Further information regarding the last point was 
    obtained from cases in which <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> was injected into <injectionLocation>the 
    amygdala ( Fig . 3 ) , parabrachial nucleus , or dorsomedial 
    medulla ( Grove , &apos; 88, cases RHPBG and RHM1, Fig . 3 
    )</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Observations made in cases of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections of <injectionLocation>the 
    cortex</injectionLocation> are the subject of a separate report 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Cases with subcortical <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections are grouped into two classes in the 
    following description .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">First , <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> deposits in <injectionLocation>the amygdala , 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis , parts of the hypothalamus , 
    dorsal raphe , or parabrachial 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> 
    <labelingDescription>preferentially labelled 
    axons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>one or the other 
    of the two SI divisions</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">In the second group of cases , <labelingDescription>PHA 
    - L - labelled fibers</labelingDescription> arising from injection 
    sites in <injectionLocation>other regions of the hypothalamus , the 
    ventral tegmental area , and peripeduncular 
    area</injectionLocation> <labelingDescription>formed terminal 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    SI</labelingLocation> without discriminating between the dorsal and 
    ventral subregions .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">Afferents from <connxOrigin>the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s190">In case RPGP4, <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> deposit was confined to <injectionLocation>the 
      most lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s191">In RPBNS2, the injection site was more medially placed 
      (Fig. 8C,D).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s192">Figure 8 shows the distribution of 
      <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled axons</labelingDescription> 
      in these two complementary cases , not only in <labelingLocation>
      the SI</labelingLocation> , where the ventral and dorsal 
      divisions are differentially labelled , but also in 
      <labelingLocation>amygdaloid and hypothalamic 
      sites</labelingLocation> that also appear from the WGA - mP cases 
      described above , as well as PHA - L cases discussed below , to 
      innervate selectively one or the other of the two divisions .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s193">Rostra1 to the injection sites in both RPGP4 and 
      RPBNS2 ( Fig . 8A , B ) , <labelingDescription>labelled fibers 
      displaying terminal varicosities</labelingDescription> appeared 
      in <labelingLocation>the lateral septum ( LS ) , rostral BNS , 
      lateral preoptic area</labelingLocation> , and sparsely in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral pallidum</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s194">In case RPGP4 only , several <labelingDescription>PHA 
      - L - filled fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in 
      <labelingLocation>the medial and ventral 
      striatum</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s195">Caudal to the injection site in case RPGP4, 
      <labelingDescription>a continuum of labelled , varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> spread caudolaterally from 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral BNS</labelingLocation> , through 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal SI , into the medial segment of the 
      central nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8C , E 
      , G , I , K ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s196">Some PHA - L - filled <labelingDescription>varicose 
      axons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral and basolateral nuclei</labelingLocation> and in 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdaloid region ventral to 
      Ace</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8G , I , K ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s197"><labelingDescription>Labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      SI</labelingLocation> extended well into <labelingLocation>the 
      dorsalmost portion of the SI</labelingLocation> , which like the 
      GP , is marked by <labelingDescription>ENK - IR woolly 
      fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s198"><labelingDescription>A small number of stray PHA - L - 
      filled fibers</labelingDescription> could be followed still 
      further dorsally into <labelingLocation>the cellular interstices 
      of the internal capsule</labelingLocation> , that is , into 
      <labelingLocation>the cholinergic cell - rich region of the 
      GP</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s199">In RPBNS2, <labelingDescription>a complementary 
      continuum of PHA - L - filled axons</labelingDescription> spread 
      from <labelingLocation>the medial BNS</labelingLocation> through 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8B , 
      D , F ) , into <labelingLocation>the ventromedial 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> , prominently including 
      <labelingLocation>the region ventral to Ace</labelingLocation> 
      and <labelingLocation>the rostral two - thirds of the medial 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8H , J , L ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s200">In <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , likewise , two strikingly 
      complementary patterns of <labelingDescription>fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> were evident .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s201">In case RPGP4, <labelingDescription>moderate varicose 
      axon labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      rostral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , mainly laterally ( Fig 
      . 8 0 , contrasts with <labelingDescription>dense varicose fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> in case RPBNSB in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral and , especially , medial preoptic 
      areas , and anterior hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8D , 
      F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s202">More caudally , in case RPGP4 
      <labelingDescription>many axons</labelingDescription> were 
      labelled in <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus and 
      lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8G , I , K ) , 
      notably in <labelingLocation>the perifornical zone invaded by ENK 
      - IR fibers</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 81 ) and the caudolateral 
      zone medial to <labelingLocation>the subthalamic 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8K ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s203"><labelingDescription>A few 
      fibers</labelingDescription> extended into <labelingLocation>a 
      region of LH</labelingLocation> beneath the fornix and into 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial and posterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s204">In case RPBNSB , <labelingDescription>dense fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was found around but only 
      sparsely within <labelingLocation>the PVH</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 8H ) , in <labelingLocation>the most medial LH , 
      subfornical LH , DMH , and PH</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8H , J , 
      L ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s205">There was <labelingDescription>no evident 
      concentration of labelled fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the perifornical zone of the 
      LH</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 84 and <labelingDescription>very 
      little axon labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>
      the caudolateral region</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8L ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s206">In both cases <labelingDescription>smooth and varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> extended through midline thalamic 
      structures , including <labelingLocation>the reuniens ( RE ) , 
      paraventricular ( PW , and paratenial nuclei ( PT 
      )</labelingLocation> , to <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal 
      nucleus and lateral habenula</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 8E - L ) 
      .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">Some general features of <labelingDescription>labelled 
    fibers and their varicosities</labelingDescription> appeared 
    similar in these cases and in others in which <exptLabel>deposits 
    of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> were placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the amygdala, hypothalamus , or parabrachial 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">In single coronal sections , 
    <labelingDescription>individual labelled 
    axons</labelingDescription> could often be followed across the 
    rough boundaries between <labelingLocation>the BNS , SI , and 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> and be observed <labelingDescription>to 
    display terminal varicosities</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>more than one region</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">The majority of <labelingDescription>labelled varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    SI</labelingLocation> in all cases described in the present study 
    appeared to form <labelingDescription>en passant 
    terminals</labelingDescription>, although axonal branches 
    displaying single swellings were also seen .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">Occasionally , following <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation>the BNS , 
    amygdala , or parabrachial nucleus</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>several labelled 
    terminals</labelingDescription> appeared to outline a single cell 
    body or dendrite in <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Atrerents from <connxOrigin>the 
    amygdala</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s212">In case RPAA1 ,<exptLabel>the 
      <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> injection site was confined 
      to <injectionLocation>the rostra1 part of the central 
      nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , centered in 
      <labelingLocation>its lateral segment</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      9C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s213">A profusion of <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      varicose fibers</labelingDescription> swept across 
      <labelingLocation>the medial segment of the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> , through <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
      SI</labelingLocation> , intruding well into <labelingLocation>the 
      ENK - IR fiber mass that fills part of this 
      subdivision</labelingLocation> , and into <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral BNS</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s214">( Since , in <labelingLocation>the GP and 
      VP</labelingLocation> , the source of <labelingDescription>the 
      ENK - IR axons</labelingDescription> that make up this plexus 
      appears to be <connxOrigin>the striatum</connxOrigin> ( Zaborszky 
      et al . , &apos; 82 ; Haber and Nauta , &apos; 83 ) , and since 
      <labelingLocation>the border between the striatum and the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> is not always clear - cut , it should 
      be emphasized that the <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
      injection site in case RPAAl did not encroach on striatal 
      neuropil , as defined by intense staining for AChE and high 
      levels of TH immunoreactivity . )</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s215"><labelingDescription>Many fewer varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> reached ventral to the injection 
      site into <labelingLocation>the anterior amyg daloid area and 
      ventral SI</labelingLocation> (Fig. 9C).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s216">More caudally in <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial part of the central nucleus</labelingLocation> and , 
      <labelingDescription>more sparsely</labelingDescription> , in 
      <labelingLocation>the district ventral to Ace and 
      ABL</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9E ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s217">In <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>varicose 
      fiber labelling was sparse</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral preoptic area</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 9A ) but <labelingDescription>moderately 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the perifornical 
      ( Fig . 9E ) and caudolateral ( Fig . 9G ) districts of the 
      lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s218"><labelingDescription>Light axon 
      labelling</labelingDescription> also appeared in <labelingLocation>
      the dorsomedial ( Fig . 9E ) , and posterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9G ) and in 
      <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal nucleus of the 
      thalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9E , G ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219"><exptLabel>The somewhat larger <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> deposit in case RPACE8 ( Fig . 9, bottom ) was 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the medial division of the central 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> caudal to the injection 
    site in RPAA1.</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s220">The distribution of 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled axons</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the forebrain</labelingLocation> was almost 
    identical to the pattern seen in case RPAA1, except that 
    <labelingDescription>labelled fibers</labelingDescription> spread 
    through <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> in a slightly 
    more ventral position .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s221"><labelingDescription>A few 
    PHA - L - filled fibers</labelingDescription> were additionally 
    seen in <labelingLocation>the paraventricular hypothalamic 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
    deposits placed in <injectionLocation>the basolateral 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> also label 
    <labelingDescription>fibers that traverse and 
    terminate</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
    continuum formed by the medial Ace , dorsal SI , and lateral 
    BNS</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s223">Numerous 
    <labelingDescription>labelled axons</labelingDescription> appeared 
    in this continuum following a <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injection confined to <injectionLocation>the 
    basolateral nucleus at a mid - rostrocaudal 
    level</injectionLocation> ( RPBLZ ) ( Fig . 9, bottom ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">In contrast to cases with tracer deposits in 
    <injectionLocation>the central nucleus</injectionLocation> , many 
    of <labelingDescription>the fibers</labelingDescription> labelled 
    in <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> in this case 
    appeared <labelingDescription>smooth or displayed only sparse 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> ; only <labelingDescription>a 
    few were richly varicose</labelingDescription> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s225">It is 
    possible , of course , that tracer injections in a different part 
    of the basolateral nuclew might have labelled 
    <labelingDescription>a denser terminal field</labelingDescription> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">The pattern of fiber labelling in case RPBM3 was 
    strikingly different from that seen in RPAAl and RPACE8.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">In this brain , <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> deposit was placed ventral to <injectionLocation>
    the central nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , spreading 
    into the region in which other authors have discerned 
    <injectionSpread>a basomedial nucleus</injectionSpread> in the rat 
    ( Krettek and Price , &apos; 78b ; de Olmos et al . , &apos; 85 ; 
    Paxinos and Watson , &apos; 86 ) ( Fig . 9H ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s228">Many 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> streamed rostrally across 
    <labelingLocation>the medial nucleus , anterior amygdaloid area , 
    and ventral SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9D , F ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> 
    traversing the SI joined <labelingDescription>a more massive 
    contingent of stria terminalis axons 
    terminating</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the medial 
    BNS and medial preoptic area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 9B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">At more caudal levels , <labelingDescription>labelled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> spread out widely across 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral amygdala</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
    9H ) and into <labelingLocation>the piriform 
    cortex</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s231"><labelingDescription>Only 
    sparse fibers</labelingDescription> could be seen within 
    <labelingLocation>the central , lateral , and basolateral 
    nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232"><labelingDescription>Dense varicose fiber 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    SI</labelingLocation> also followed <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA 
    - L</tracerChemical> injections in <injectionLocation>the region 
    ventral to Ace</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , dorsal and rostral 
    to the injection site in RPBM3 ( RPBMl ) , or in <injectionLocation>
    the rostral part of the medial nucleus</injectionLocation> ( RPAB1 
    ) ( Fig . 9, bottom ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Both cases differed from RPBM3 in displaying 
    <labelingDescription>many labelled varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>ventral and 
    medial parts of the lateral hypothalamus and the ventromedial 
    hypothalamus in addition to the rostral 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">In cases RPACo2a and ACo2b <exptLabel>the 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injection sites involved , 
    respectively , <injectionLocation>the caudal half of the medial 
    nucleus and the posteromedial cortical 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig . 9, bottom ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">In both cases , only <labelingDescription>a small number 
    of labelled fibers</labelingDescription> extended through 
    <labelingLocation>the SI , confined to the ventral 
    division</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s236">Far more numerous were 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled axons</labelingDescription> 
    in <labelingLocation>the stria terminalis and its target 
    regions</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Afferents from <connxOrigin>the 
    hypothalamus</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238"><labelingDescription>Varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>the 
    SI</labelingLocation> following <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injections in <injectionLocation>the lateral 
    preoptic area</injectionLocation> ( RPLPOZ ) , <injectionLocation>
    lateral hypothalamus</injectionLocation> ( RPLH5 ) , 
    <injectionLocation>caudomedial hypothalamus</injectionLocation> ( 
    RPVMH3 ) and <injectionLocation>supramammillary 
    region</injectionLocation> ( RPSUM2 ) , but 
    <labelingModifier>not</labelingModifier> <injectionLocation>zona 
    incerta</injectionLocation> ( RPLH2 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">The location of these injections is indicated in Figure 
    12.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">The <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> deposit in 
    case RPSUM2 filled numerous <labelingDescription>varicose 
    axons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>both divisions of 
    the SI and in regions of the amygdala and 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> associated with each subregion .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">However , in cases RPLH5 and RPVMW3 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - Llabelled fibers</labelingDescription> 
    were distributed in forebrain structures in a complementary pattern 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242"><exptLabel>An injection of <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> in <injectionLocation>the caudolateral zone of 
    the lateral hypothalamus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RPLH5 ) 
    labelled <labelingDescription>a moderate number of labelled 
    varicose fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis</labelingLocation> ( Fig . lOA ) , <labelingLocation>
    dorsal SI ( with a few straying into the cholinergic cell - rich 
    region of the GP ) , and the medial segment of the central 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10C , E ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">Elsewhere in <labelingLocation>the 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsomedial and rostra1 lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( 
    Fig . lOE ) , <labelingLocation>lateral preoptic 
    area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10A , C ) , and <labelingLocation>
    paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10E ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">In a complementary case , RPVMHB , <exptLabel>a deposit 
    of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> was placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the caudomedial 
    hypothalamus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , including parts of 
    <injectionSpread>the dorsomedial and ventromedial hypothalamic 
    nuclei</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 12 ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245"><labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral SI , medial nucleus , anterior amygdaloid 
    area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10D , F ) , and <labelingLocation>
    dorsomedial part of the BNS</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10B ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246"><labelingDescription>Additional labelled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> spread into <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal hypothalamus , medial LH , preoptic area , and anterior 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 10B , D , F ) .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">Afferent5 from <connxOrigin>the dorsal raphe 
    nuclem</connxOrigin>.</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248"><exptLabel>A <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
    deposit centered at a <injectionLocation>mid - rostrocaudal level 
    of the dorsal raphe nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig . 
    12 ) <labelingDescription>labelled many 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the SI , 
    VP</labelingLocation> , Merents from <connxOrigin>the purabrachiul 
    nucleus</connxOrigin> .</S></TTE>

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s249">Following <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> injection into <injectionLocation>the lateral 
      segment of the parabrachial 
      nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RPPBG , Fig . 121, 
      <labelingDescription>varicose fibers</labelingDescription> were 
      evident throughout <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> 
      but were markedly <labelingDescription>more 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
      division</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s250">Fiber labelling was <labelingDescription>moderate to 
      dense</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      BNS</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11A ) <labelingLocation>and 
      central nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation> and 
      considerably sparser in <labelingLocation>the medial nucleus and 
      the region ventral to the central nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 11C , D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s251"><labelingDescription>Moderate to dense , smooth and 
      varicose fiber labelling</labelingDescription> appeared in 
      <labelingLocation>the posterior , dorsomedial , and ventromedial 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11C , D ) , 
      <labelingLocation>the caudolateral ( Fig . 11D ) and perifornical 
      zones of the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11C 
      ) , <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus , and the 
      lateral preoptic area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11A , B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s252"><labelingDescription>Only modest numbers of 
      axons</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the medial preoptic area and anterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11A , B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s253">A feature common to all cases in which numerous 
      <labelingDescription>PHAL - filled axons</labelingDescription> 
      spread through <labelingLocation>the dorsal SI</labelingLocation> 
      was most striking in this brain .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s254">That is , <labelingDescription>a small contingent of 
      labelled , smooth and sparsely varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> coursed dorsally from and NHDB , but 
      most were either smooth or sparsely varicose .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s255">However , <labelingDescription>a few richly varicose 
      labelled fibers</labelingDescription> could be identified .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s256">These appeared slightly ( but not dramatically ) more 
      numerous in <labelingLocation>the dorsal SI , lateral bed nucleus 
      of the stria terminalis , and central nucleus of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> than in the ventrally contiguous 
      continuum that passes through the ventral SI .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s257">Labelled , <labelingDescription>beaded 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appeared profusely in the 
      ventromedial caudo - putamen and more modestly in the GP ; they 
      were evident especially along <labelingLocation>the lateral face 
      of the internal capsule</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s258"><labelingLocation>the SI along the lateral and medial 
      margins of the globus pallidus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 11B , C 
      ) , some penetrating <labelingLocation>the cellular interstices 
      of the internal capsule</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s259">These fibers appeared to form slender bridges between 
      the dorsal amygdalopetal pathway-the stria terminalis-and the 
      ventral pathway which traverses the SI.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260"><exptLabel>The injection sites in cases RPPB8 and 9 were 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the medial segment of the 
    parabrachial nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( Fig . 12 ) 
    <labelingDescription>Labelled varicose fibers</labelingDescription> 
    were distributed in <labelingLocation>the LH , PVH , Ace , dorsal 
    SI , NHDB , and lateral BNS</labelingLocation> but were 
    considerably <labelingDescription>more sparse</labelingDescription> 
    than in case RPPBG , especially <labelingLocation>in 
    PVH</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">Ascending projections of <connxOrigin>the peripeduncular 
    area</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">Following injections of <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the SI and rostra1 
    amygdala</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RHBN1 ) or medial GP ( 
    RHCHB ) , <labelingDescription>many labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>a 
    triangular region of the midbrain abutting the dorsal end of the 
    cerebral peduncle</labelingLocation> ( see also Mehler , &apos; 80 
    ; Mehler et al . , &apos; 81 ; LeDoux et al . , &apos; 85 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">This triangular region is referred to in the present 
    study as <neuroanatomicalLocation>the &quot; peripeduncular 
    area</neuroanatomicalLocation> &quot; but it should be noted that 
    it is composed not only of <labelingLocation>the peripeduncular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> but also , according to the parcellation 
    of Ledoux et al . ( &apos; 85 ) and Paxinos and Watson ( &apos; 86 
    ) , of several caudal components of the thalamus .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s264">Figure 13 illustrates the distribution of 
      <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> - filled fibers 
      following <exptLabel>an injection of the lectin centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the peripeduncular 
      area</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RPPNG ) , spreading only 
      slightly into <injectionSpread>the lateralmost substantia 
      nigra</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s265"><labelingDescription>Scattered tyrosine hydroxylase 
      immunoreactive neurons</labelingDescription> extend dorsally from 
      <labelingLocation>the substantia nigra , pars lateralis , into 
      the PPA</labelingLocation>  of the rat ( unpublished observations 
      ) , and such cells may also have been unavoidably involved in the 
      injection site .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s266">Since the efferents of <connxOrigin>the 
      PPA</connxOrigin> have not been examined previously in the rat 
      with either the autoradiographic or <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> anterograde tracing techniques , a greater 
      rostrocaudal extent of brain RPPNG is represented in Figure 13 
      than is illustrated in other cases .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s267">From the injection site, <labelingDescription>numerous 
      smooth and varicose PHA-L-filled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      appeared along the bifurcating course taken by the medial 
      forebrain bundle through the midbrain (Fig. 13H).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s268">Becoming more evident farther rostrally was another 
      contingent of <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> coursing dorsal to <labelingLocation>
      the medial lemniscus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13Gk apparently 
      through <labelingLocation>the Parvocellular part of the 
      subparafascicular nucleus ( Paxinos and Watson , &apos; 86 
      )</labelingLocation> , to a position ( Fig . 13F ) just ventral 
      to <labelingLocation>the gustatory nucleus of the 
      thalamus</labelingLocation>  and dorsal to <labelingLocation>the 
      trimgular magnocellular part of the SPF</labelingLocation>( 
      labelled &quot; spf &quot; in Fig . 13F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s269">Of these ascending pathways through the midbrain, only 
      the medial forebrain bundle appears to be Joined by fibers from 
      the substantia nigra (Beckstead et al., &apos;7% and see 
      below).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s270">Thus , the fiber contingent that Passes through the 
      subparafascicular nucleus can be more readily identified as 
      arising specifically from <injectionLocation>the 
      PPA</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s271">Elsewhere in the diencephalon , 
      <labelingDescription>labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      midline thalamus ( Fig . 13B - E ) , zona incerta ( Fig . 13E - G 
      ) , posterior , ventromedial , and dorsomedial 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> !</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s272"><labelingLocation>Fig . 13D - F ) , lateral 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , including the caudolateral zone 
      ( Fig . 13E , F ) , <labelingLocation>lateral and medial preoptic 
      areas , and anterior hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13A 
      , B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s273"><labelingLocation>The paraventricular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( not shown ) was 
      <labelingDescription>not notably invaded by labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> , although one or two were found 
      within <labelingLocation>the nucleus</labelingLocation> , and 
      some surrounded its lateral boundary .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s274">Numerous <labelingDescription>ascending 
      fibers</labelingDescription> penetrated <labelingLocation>the 
      cerebral peduncle or traveled rostrally over the supraoptic 
      decussation ( SOX )</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13D - F ) to enter 
      the caudo - putamen ( CP ) , caudal GP , and amygdala .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s275"><labelingLocation>The cholinergic cell - rich caudal 
      GP</labelingLocation> was filled with richly 
      <labelingDescription>varicose labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 13C , D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s276">Some coursed beneath <labelingLocation>the cerebral 
      peduncle</labelingLocation> , where additional cholinergic cells 
      are found , and continued medially into <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s277">Further rostrally , also , the distribution of 
      <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> - filled 
      <labelingDescription>varicose fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the GP</labelingLocation> appeared roughly 
      coextensive with ChAT - IR perikarya ( Fig . 13B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s278">Ventral to the GP , both divisions of the SI contained 
      <labelingDescription>a modest number of labelled 
      axons</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 13B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s279">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> , 
      <labelingDescription>numerous labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral ( AL ) and medial nuclei and</labelingLocation> , most 
      prominently , in the region ventral to <labelingLocation>the 
      central nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13C - E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s280">Some also reached the medial part of <labelingLocation>
      the central nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13B - D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s281">Throughout, the basolateral nucleus and lateral Ace 
      were free of varicose fiber labelling (Fig. 13C-E).</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s282"><labelingLocation>The nucleus of the lateral olfactory 
      tract</labelingLocation> also contained <labelingDescription>no 
      labelled axons</labelingDescription> , but 
      <labelingDescription>varicose fibers</labelingDescription> 
      surrounded this nucleus in <labelingLocation>the anterior 
      amygdaloid area</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s283"><labelingDescription>Sparse varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the lateral and medial+BNS (Fig. 13A)</labelingLocation>.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s285"><labelingDescription>Numerous smooth and varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were also evident spreading through 
      the striatum , terminating in <labelingLocation>central and 
      medial parts of the caudal CP</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13C - E 
      ) , <labelingLocation>a ventral zone adjacent to 
      Ace</labelingLocation> ( area X of Hall , &apos; 72 ) , 
      considered a transition region between the CP and Ace ( Paxinos 
      and Watson , &apos; 86 ) ( Fig . 13C , D ) , and <labelingLocation>
      the fundus of the striatum</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13A , B ) 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s286"><labelingDescription>A few labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> penetrated <labelingLocation>the 
      external capsule</labelingLocation> to enter 
      <labelingLocation>the cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 13C - E ) 
      .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287"><labelingLocation>The peripeduncular 
    area</labelingLocation> is a complex region ( Le Doux et al . , 
    &apos; 85 ) invaded , for example , by cells typical of the 
    substantia nigra ( see above ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">To distinguish the characteristic efferents of the PPA 
    from those of adjacent or even intrusive components of the medial 
    geniculate body and substantia nigra , deposits of 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> were placed in these 
    neighboring structures .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">Of particular interest in the present study is 
    <labelingDescription>the source of varicose fiber 
    labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the globus 
    pallidus , SI , and related parts of the amygdala , striatum and 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> seen in case RPPNG .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">In cases RPPN5 ( Fig . 13 ) and 15,<exptLabel> 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injections were confined 
    to <injectionLocation>the lateral 
    SN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s291">From 
    these injection sites , <labelingDescription>labelled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> ascended in <labelingLocation>the 
    medial forebrain bundle</labelingLocation> , through 
    <labelingLocation>the subthalamic region</labelingLocation> , or in 
    <labelingLocation>the cerebral peduncle</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292"><labelingDescription>Fibers</labelingDescription> were 
    <labelingModifier>not labelled</labelingModifier> along 
    <labelingLocation>the PPA - SPF</labelingLocation> route or in 
    <labelingLocation>the supraoptic decussation</labelingLocation> 
    .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">In <labelingLocation>pallidal areas</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>varicose fibers</labelingDescription> were 
    distributed in <labelingLocation>the entopeduncular 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , but only <labelingDescription>smooth 
    fibers</labelingDescription> traversed <labelingLocation>the 
    GP</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s294">These entered 
    <labelingLocation>the caudoputamen</labelingLocation> and displayed 
    <labelingDescription>profuse terminal 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>its lateral 
    part</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s295">Fibers ascending in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial forebrain bundle</labelingLocation> 
    spread into <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental 
    area</labelingLocation> , but not further rostrally into 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296"><labelingDescription>No labelled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    cortex , amygdala , or SI</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297"><exptLabel>The injection in RPPNll was placed in an 
    intermediate position , involving part of <injectionLocation>the 
    lateral SN</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , but extending up into 
    <injectionSpread>the ventral part of the triangular peripeduncular 
    area</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 13 ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s298">In 
    addition to fiber labelling typical of injections in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral SN</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were found throughout <labelingLocation>
    the peripeduncular area - subparafascicular nucleus continuum and 
    in the GP , amygdala , and hypothalamus</labelingLocation> - more 
    sparsely than in RPPNG , but with a similar pattern of distribution 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Finally , in case RPPNS <exptLabel>a small injection was 
    confined to <injectionLocation>a medial part of the medial 
    geniculate body</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , and in RPPN14, a 
    larger injection spread additionally into <injectionSpread>a more 
    central part of the nucleus</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 13 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">In both , <labelingDescription>numerous 
    fibers</labelingDescription> ascended in <labelingLocation>the 
    cerebral peduncle</labelingLocation> and through <labelingLocation>
    the reticular nucleus of the thalamus</labelingLocation> , but none 
    was labelled along <labelingLocation>the PPA - SPF 
    continuum</labelingLocation> , nor <labelingDescription>did 
    fibers</labelingDescription> ascend by way of the supraoptic 
    decussation .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s301">Smooth fibers traversed the 
    GP to enter <labelingLocation>the striatum</labelingLocation> , 
    where they terminated within <labelingLocation>a central part of 
    the nucleus at mid</labelingLocation> and caudal levels .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302"><labelingDescription>Some varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> also appeared in <labelingLocation>a 
    dorsal part of the lateral nucleus of the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> , but not in other amygdaloid nuclei or 
    in <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Many penetrated the external capsule to terminate 
    profusely, often in a columnar pattern, in a large region of the 
    cortex dorsal to the rhinal sulcus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">In summary , in the case described first , RPPNG , 
    <labelingDescription>fiber labelling</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral ahd central parts of the 
    striatum</labelingLocation> may have been due to tracer uptake by 
    components of <injectionSpread>the substantia nigra and medial 
    geniculate nucleus</injectionSpread> , respectively ; and part , or 
    all , of the axon labelling in <labelingLocation>the 
    cortex</labelingLocation> and <injectionSpread>lateral amygdaloid 
    nucleus</injectionSpread> to <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> transport from <labelingLocation>the medial 
    geniculate nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Afferents from <connxOrigin>the ventral tegmental 
    area</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Following <exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> deposits into either <injectionLocation>the 
    medial or lateral VTA</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( cases RPVTG 
    and RPVT7, Fig . 121, <labelingDescription>a modest number of 
    varicose and smooth fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled in 
    <labelingLocation>both divisions of the SI , the VP , and the 
    ventromedial GP</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">More lateral placements centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the substantia nigra</injectionLocation> ( such 
    as case RPSNM2 ) resulted in only <labelingDescription>very sparse 
    fiber labelling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>any of 
    these areas</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Light microscopic evidence of sgnaptic relations : 
    apparent contacts between <labelingDescription>PHA - Glabelled 
    axonal swellings and identified cholinergic 
    neurons</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Two series of sections from each brain were processed to 
    reveal ChAT and <labelingDescription>PHA - L immunoreactivities 
    simultaneously</labelingDescription> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Although the same chromagen marked both , ChAT and 
    <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> immunoreactivities could 
    be distinguished in the SI and GP because they appeared in 
    different neural elements .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Under the conditions of fixation and immunohistochemical 
    processing employed in the present study , <labelingDescription>no 
    varicose axons</labelingDescription> were labelled in either the GP 
    or SI when sections were reacted to reveal ChAT alone .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">C U T immunoreactivity in the SI and GP was represented 
    by a light to midbrown reaction product that filled cell bodies and 
    their proximal dendrites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">By contrast , outside the <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> injection site , <tracerChemical>PHA - 
    L</tracerChemical> immunoreactivity appeared only in axons and was 
    marked by a dense immunoprecipitate that produced a dark brown to 
    black color .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Tissue sections from each case were searched for 
    juxtapositions between <labelingDescription>PHA - L labelled axonal 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> and ChAT - IR cells , which 
    might represent innervation of the cholinergic cell group .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Such juxtapositions were rare.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">However , instances in which several 
    <labelingDescription>PHA - L - labelled axonal 
    varicosities</labelingDescription> were observed in apparently 
    direct apposition to single ChAT - IR neurons followed tracer 
    injections into <injectionLocation>the peripeduncular 
    area</injectionLocation> ( RPPNG ) , caudomedial hypothalamus ( 
    RVMH3 ) ( Fig . 14 ) , <labelingLocation>dorsal raphe nucleus ( 
    RPDR3 ) , and ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> ( RPVT6 ) 
    .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Each of these apparent contacts was judged using a Leitz 
    100 x oil immersion objective.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Merents Rom <connxOrigin>the caudoputamen and 
    subthalamic nucleus</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Following <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation>the SI ( 
    RHSI1 ) or central nucleus of the amygdala ( RHCEB 
    )</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , <labelingDescription>a few 
    labelled neurons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>
    the fundus of the striatum</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s320">In one of the autoradiographic cases included in a 
      previous study by Nauta and his colleagues ( &apos; 781, 
      <exptLabel>a small deposit of <tracerChemical>tritiated amino 
      acids</tracerChemical> was placed medially in <injectionLocation>
      this ventral pocket of the 
      striatum</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( case RRHSI27 ) ( Fig . 
      15A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s321">This case was reexamined by the present author.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s322">Judged by the presence of heavy silver grain labelling 
      over cell bodies , the injection site in RRHSI27 did not spread 
      out of <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the striatum into the rostra1 
      amygdala or other adjacent structures</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s323"><labelingDescription>Labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> streamed ventrally and caudally from 
      the injection site , through <labelingLocation>the most dorsal 
      part of the SI</labelingLocation> into <labelingLocation>the 
      central nucleus of the amygdala</labelingLocation> , crossing the 
      nucleus toward its lateral segment ( Fig . 15B , C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s324">Since this contingent of <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> could not be followed beyond 
      <labelingLocation>the SI and central nucleus</labelingLocation> , 
      it may be concluded that <labelingDescription>the axons 
      terminated</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>these 
      two regions</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s325">If so, the dorsalmost SI is like the overlying GP in 
      receiving striatal innervation.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">The second major source of afferents to 
    <connxTermination>the GP</connxTermination> is <connxOrigin>the 
    subthalamic nucleus</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
    deposits in <injectionLocation>the 
    STH</injectionLocation></exptLabel> <labelingDescription>labelled a 
    characteristically dense mass of richly varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    pallidum and globus pallidus</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s328">Of a 
    range of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injection sites 
    in <injectionLocation>medial , mid , or lateral parts of the 
    nucleus</injectionLocation> , those placed far medially in the STH 
    , intruding into <injectionSpread>the lateral 
    hypothalamus</injectionSpread> ( such as in RPSTH13, Fig . 121, 
    produced <labelingDescription>dense axon 
    labelling</labelingDescription> farthest ventrally in 
    <labelingLocation>the GP - VP continuum</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">In no case , however , was <labelingDescription>profuse 
    fiber labelling</labelingDescription> observed in <labelingLocation>
    the dorsal SI or in the most ventral part of the 
    VP</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s330">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Two features characteristic of the SI can be used to 
    define the extent of the region: the presence of dispersed 
    cholinergic cells and the passage of numerous fibers belonging to 
    the ansa peduncularis (AP).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">The AP is a voluminous fiber system that includes the 
    ventral amygdalofugal pathway and the inferior thalamic 
    peduncle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">It is largely composed of axons coursing between the 
    diencephalon and the amygdala and ventral cortical areas but is 
    joined by fibers from more caudal sites, for example, the 
    parabrachial nucleus, en route to the amygdala and cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Findings from the present PHA-L study show that the AP 
    not only traverses the SI but also terminates densely within the 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Thus, just as the nucleus of the diagonal band receives 
    its name from the diagonal band of Broca, so could the SI aptly be 
    termed an interstitial nucleus of the AP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Although some Ap fibers distribute over the ventral 
    pallidum, for the most part they appear to course around this 
    component of the basal ganglia (Figs. 2, 8-11), further 
    distinguishing the VP from the caudally adjacent region for which 
    the term SI is now commonly reserved (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;82, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">In addition to AP fibers, axons originating from several 
    cell groups along the medial forebrain bundle as well as fibers 
    from the internal capsule and diagonal band of Broca distribute 
    over the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Observations from WGA-HRP experiments, confirmed with 
    the anterograde PHA-L circuit tracing technique, indicate that the 
    SI is thus innervated by cell groups in many of the major 
    subdivisions of the brain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Specifically, in close agreement with a previous WGA-HRP 
    study in the monkey (Russchen et al., &apos;85), retrograde tracer 
    experiments suggested fibers afferent to the rat SI arise from 
    prefrontal, insular, and temporal cortices, the fundus of the 
    striatum, widespread regions of the amygdala and hypothalamus, 
    midline thalamic nuclei, the peripeduncular area, ventral tegmental 
    area, substantia nigra, dorsal raphe, central gray, parabrachial 
    nucleus, locus coeruleus, subcoeruleus, and the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Most of these projections were confirmed with 
    anterograde tracing methods.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">(Notably, however, a significant innervation from the 
    substantia nigra could not be labelled by PHA-L deposits in that 
    site.)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Surprisingly, given the uniform appearance of the SI in 
    Nisslor myelin-stained material, two lines of evidence, 
    neurochemical and connectional, indicate the region is organized 
    into two divisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Dorsal and ventral subregions are distinguished by the 
    selective termination of fibers immunoreactive for tyrosine 
    hydroxylase, and, in retrospect, it appears likely that the same 
    divisions were revealed by differential staining in cupric-silver 
    preparations from normal brains (de Olmos, &apos;72) and by the 
    distribution of angiotensin-11-containing fibers (Lind et al., 
    &apos;85, Plates 8-17).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">PHA-L experiments disclosed that axons from severa1 
    sources selectively terminate in one or the other of the two 
    neurochemically distinct divisions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">In the present study such selective afferents were shown 
    with the PHA-L method to arise from different Parts ofthe amYgdala 
    and hYPotha1amus and from the caudal brainstem.&apos;</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Findings from WGAHRP experiments and from studies in 
    other laboratories summarized below suggest that additional 
    brainstem and cortical sites may also project preferentially to one 
    of the two SI subregions.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Immediately dorsal to the main pathway of the AP, and 
    thus outside the SI as it is defined in the present study, a third 
    region composed of the ventromedial and caudal GP also contains 
    numerous cholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Part of this cholinergic cell-rich region, which extends 
    into the cellular interstices of the internal capsule, has been 
    referred to as the basal nucleus of Meynert in the rat (Big1 et 
    al., &apos;82; Paxinos and Watson, &apos;861, a term which, 
    however, neglects the additionally pallidal nature of the area 
    (Haber et al., &apos;85; Grove et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Findings from the present series of PHAL experiments 
    indicate that the cholinergic cell-rich region of the GP shows some 
    additional similarity to the SI by sharing, sparsely, afferents 
    from several sources that do not innervate the dorsolateral GP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">The purpose of the present study was not only to uncover 
    further detail regarding the afferent connections of the SI but 
    also to determine general features of its neural associations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">From the foregoing account two principal findings 
    emerge, both of which provide a context for further consideration 
    of the afferent connections of the dorsal and ventral SI divisions 
    and the cholinergic cell-rich region of the globus pallidus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s352">Afferents ofthe SI 
    strongly resemble those of the amygdala</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Moderate or heavy projections to the SI arise from most 
    subdivisions of the rostra1 two-thirds of the amygdala (present 
    study; Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Russchen et al., &apos;85), 
    which also receives a widespread return innervation from the SI 
    (Russchen, &apos;82; Aggleton et al., &apos;87; Grove, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Indicating a still closer affiliation with the amygdala, 
    findings from both WGA-HRP and PHA-L experiments demonstrate a 
    strong similarity between the afferent connections of the amygdala 
    and those of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Specifically, the lateral part of the bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis, dorsal SI, and central nucleus of the amygdala 
    share numerous afferents from elsewhere in the amygdala, the 
    diencephalon, and caudal brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">A second tissue continuum marked by common subcortical 
    innervation is formed by a ventromedial region of the amygdala, the 
    ventral SI, and the medial BNS.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">These findings, together with those described in a 
    companion report (Grove, &apos;881, provide substantial 
    documentation to support an emerging view of a forebrain continuum 
    composed of elements of the BNS, SI, and amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">It has long been recognized that the amygdala and BNS 
    may form a single anatomical entity (Johnston, &apos;23), and 
    several more recent reports have suggested that they are continuous 
    through the SI (for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">In particular, an affiliation between the lateral part 
    of the BNS and the central nucleus of the amygdaIa has been well 
    documented.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">The two structures contain neurons with similar 
    morphological features (McDonald, &apos;831, as well as several of 
    the same types of peptidergic cell groups (Woodhams et al., 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Some of the latter contribute to common descending 
    projections to the brainstem (Gray and Magnuson, &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">A tissue continuum stretching from the lateral BNS, 
    through the SI, into the central nucleus of the amygdala has been 
    previously identified in cupric-silver preparations from normal 
    brains (de Olmos, &apos;72) and shown to be marked by connections 
    with the basolateral nucleus of the amygdala (de Olmos, &apos;72; 
    Krettek and Price, &apos;78a) and several brainstem structures 
    (Ricardo and Koh, &apos;78; Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; Schwaber et 
    al., &apos;82; Holstege et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">An analogous affiliation between the medial segment of 
    the BNS and the medial nucleus of the amygdala has also been 
    proposed (de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Holstege et al., &apos;85) and 
    supported by observations that both maintain connections with the 
    accessory olfactory system and medial hypothalamus (for review, see 
    de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">A priori, the marked connectional distinctions between 
    the lateral BNS and central nucleus of the amygdala on the one 
    hand, and the medial BNS and medial amygdaloid nucleus on the 
    other, would suggest that the two pairs are likely to be continuous 
    through distinguishable parts of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Indeed, de Olmos and his colleagues (&apos;85) have 
    previously proposed a parcellation of the SI into posteroventral 
    and anterodorsal sectors, citing unpublished observations by de 
    Olmos and Beltramino.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">No rostrocaudal differences were noted in the SI in the 
    present study, but the same affiliation is proposed between dorsal 
    and ventral parts of the SI and, respectively, the central 
    amygdala-lateral BNS and the medial amygdaloid nucleus-medial 
    BNS.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">The present study has focused primarily on the 
    subcortical afferents of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">However, cortical projections to the SI may also 
    resemble afferent connections of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Following large deposits of WGA-HRP into the SI, 
    labelled cells appeared in medial prefrontal, piriform, insular, 
    perirhinal, and entorhinal cortices, which also project to the 
    amygdala in the rat (for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">The results of a small number of PHA-L injections into 
    the cortex, to be described in greater detail in a separate report, 
    confirmed projections to the SI from at least the rostromedial 
    prefrontal, insular, and entorhinal cortex, all of which send 
    efferents through ventral parts of the internal capsule (IC) andor 
    the ansa peduncularis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">By contrast, fibers labelled from PHA-L deposits in 
    cingulate cortex caudal to the genu of the corpus callosum, or in 
    motor cortex, coursed through more dorsal parts of the IC and did 
    not appear to form terminal structures within the SI or 
    amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">A comparison of previous studies reveals that large 
    injections of retrograde tracers into the SI or amygdala in the 
    monkey label cells of apparently similar distribution in 
    subcortical structures (Aggleton et al., &apos;80; Mehler, 
    &apos;80; Norita and Kawamura, &apos;80; Mehler et al., &apos;81; 
    Russchen et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Additionally, Russchen and her colleagues (&apos;85) 
    have noted that those cortical areas demonstrated with the 
    autoradiographic technique to project to the SI in the monkey 
    (Mesulam and Mufson, &apos;84; Russchen et al., &apos;85) are also 
    strongly interconnected with the amygdala (Aggleton et al., 
    &apos;80; Turner et al., &apos;80; Mufson et al., &apos;81; Amaral 
    and Price, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Both groups of investigators (Mesulam and Mufson, 
    &apos;84; Russchen et al., &apos;85) concur that orbital, insular, 
    and rostra1 temporal cortices project to the SI but that there is 
    little direct innervation of the SI from the rest of the corticaI 
    mantle, including sensory and motor cortex and several association 
    areas.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s375">The dorsal and ventral 
    divisions of the SI are associated with two largely distinct 
    constellations of interconnected forebrain and brainstem cell 
    groups</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">The dorsal and ventral SI are not only interconnected 
    with different parts of the amygdala, with which they share 
    numerous afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Additionally, as illustrated in Figure 16, each 
    division, together with affiliated parts of the amygdala, belongs 
    to one of two sets of systematically interconnected cell groups 
    lying along the ansa peducularis and medial forebrain bundle.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Previous studies, cited below, have shown connections 
    among elements of each set that were confirmed in the present study 
    with the PHA-L method.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">New information was obtained from cases with injections 
    of anterograde or retrograde tracers in the ventral and dorsal SI, 
    lateral and medial BNS, and regions such as the caudolateral zone 
    of the lateral hypothalamus that were selected specifically for 
    their apparent association with one or the other SI division (see 
    also Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Neural associates of the dorsal SZ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Present findings from PHA-L and WGA-HRP experiments, 
    summarized in Figure 16, demonstrate that subcortical forebrain 
    afferents preferentially directed to the dorsal division of the SI 
    arise from the lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis, both medial and lateral subdivisions of the central 
    nucleus, the basolateral nucleus, and the lateralmost parts of the 
    preoptic area and lateral hypothalamus, including the distinctive 
    perifornical and caudolateral zones.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Multiple, selective interconnections associate the 
    lateral BNS, dorsal SI, medial central nucleus, and perifornical 
    and caudolateral zones of the lateral hypothalamus (present study, 
    Krettek and Price, &apos;78; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;79; Price and 
    Amaral, &apos;81; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">The dorsomedial hypothalamus is one of a few regions 
    that innervate both SI divisions, and it is (or appears likely to 
    be) additionally interconnected with each region just named, as 
    well as with the forebrain associates of the ventral SI (present 
    study; Saper et al., &apos;79a; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;79; Luiten 
    and Room, &apos;80; Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Price and 
    Amaral, &apos;81; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">The paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus may also 
    innervate the SI and certainly receives a projection from the SI 
    (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Although no information was obtained to confirm a 
    preferential connection with the dorsal division, PHA-L experiments 
    did demonstrate projections to the PVH from the lateral BNS, 
    central nucleus of the amygdala, and caudolateral LH, but not from 
    comparable forebrain associates of the ventral SI (present study, 
    Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Retrograde tracer experiments suggest a heavier 
    innervation of the dorsal rather than ventral SI from the caudal 
    brainstem, and the results of PHA-L injections confirm such 
    preferential projections from the dorsal raphe (for which, however, 
    only a weak selectivity is evident) and parabrachial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">(The lateral PB appears to provide a strikingly heavier 
    projection to the SI than does the medial segment.&apos;)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">The distribution of axons anterogradely labelled from an 
    injection of WGA-HRP into the dorsomedial medulla, together with 
    previously reported observations (Ricardo and Koh, &apos;78, see 
    their Fig. 2E-G), suggests a similarly preferential innervation of 
    the dorsal SI by at least the caudal part of the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Projections directed preferentially toward all the 
    forebrain associates of the dorsal SI-except the basolateral 
    nucleus-rather than those of the ventral SI (Fig. 16), arise from 
    lateral subnuclei of the parabrachial nucleus and less densely from 
    the latter&apos;s medial segment (present study; Norgren, &apos;76; 
    Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; Fulwiler and Saper, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Observations following PHA-L deposits in the bed nucleus 
    of the stria terminalis, amygdala, and hypothalamus, or WGA-HRP 
    injections in the pons, confirmed earlier reports that the 
    parabrachial nucleus receives similarly weighted return projections 
    from the same structures (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Saper et 
    al., &apos;79a; Holstege et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">In the rat, the nucleus of the solitary tract caudal to 
    the obex projects heavily to the lateral parabrachial nucleus well 
    as to the forebrain associates of the dorsal SI (again apparently 
    excluding the basolateral nucleus of the amygdala) (Ricardo and 
    Koh, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">These forebrain structures, in turn, project back to the 
    complex formed by the NTS and dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus 
    (present study; Saper et al., &apos;76b; Price and Amaral, 
    &apos;81; Schwaber et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Saper and his colleagues (&apos;76b) report projections 
    terminating still further caudally, in the intermediolateral column 
    of the thoracic spinal cord, arising from the paraventricular 
    nucleus, dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus, and the 
    &quot;perifornical&quot; LH, adding that the distribution of 
    labelled cells in the hypothalamus is identical following HRP 
    injections into the parabrachial nucleus, medulla, or thoracic 
    spinal cord.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">The nucleus of the solitary tract receives general 
    visceral afferents from the periphery that terminate most heavily 
    caudal to the obex, and gustatory afferents that primarily 
    innervate its rostral portion.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">The dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus contains 
    preganglionic motor neurons of the parasympathetic nervous system, 
    and preganglionic sympathetic neurons are found in the 
    intermediolateral column of the thoracic spinal cord.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Thus, the set of highly interconnected cell groups 
    associated with the dorsal SI includes structures that relay 
    primary visceral sensory afferents or directly control autonomic 
    function.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Some forebrain associates of the dorsal SI, illustrated 
    in Figure 16, maintain a more limited set of connections with other 
    members of the group.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">For example, the basolateral nucleus of the amygdala and 
    the lateral segment of the central nucleus project into the 
    continuum formed by the medial part of the central nucleus, dorsal 
    SI, and lateral BNS (present study, de Olmos, &apos;72; Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Cells within the continuum return the projection to the 
    basolateral nucleus but not to the lateral part of the central 
    nucleus (present study, Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">As noted above, the basolateral nucleus is not 
    prominently connected with the hypothalamic or caudal brainstem 
    associates of the dorsal SI, but the lateral segment of the central 
    nucleus receives notable projections from the parabrachial nucleus 
    and NTS (present study; Norgren, &apos;76; Ricardo and Koh, 
    &apos;78; Saper and Loewy, &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Finally, the fundus of the striatum innervates both the 
    dorsalmost SI and the lateral part of the central nucleus (present 
    study) and receives slight to moderate projections from at least 
    the lateral BNS, lateral hypothalamus, SI, and basolateral and 
    basomedial nuclei of the amygdala (present study; Kelley et al., 
    &apos;82; Zaborszky et al., &apos;85; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Figure 16 illustrates only those structures whose 
    selective associations with one or the other SI division have been 
    demonstrated in the present study.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Other cell groups in the thalamus or caudal brainstem 
    that appear to innervate the SI may, of course, also be 
    preferentially connected with a single division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">For example, amygdalopetal efferents of the thalamic 
    paraventricular and central medial nuclei selectively innervate the 
    central and basolateral nuclei (Turner and Herkenham, &apos;81) and 
    are thus likely to traverse, and perhaps terminate in, the dorsal 
    division of the SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="23" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldItalicMT" id="s405">Possible 
    selectivity of cortical projections to the</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">SZ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Injections of WGA-HRP centered in the ventral SI 
    labelled cells primarily in piriform and entorhinal cortex with 
    only a cell or two in the most ventral insular cortex, whereas 
    tracer deposits involving both SI divisions labelled additional 
    perikarya in infralimbic, prelimbic, anterior cingulate, insular, 
    and perirhinal cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">IR cases to be described in a separate report, PHA-L 
    deposits in medial prefrontal, insular, and entorhinal cortices 
    filled smooth and varicose axons in the SI, but none produced fiber 
    labelling that was notably selective for either SI division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">However, the organization of corticofugal fibers may 
    simply not have been revealed by the limited series of available 
    PHAL cases.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">Suggestive of this, Saper (&apos;82a) indicates that 
    caudal insular cortex projects preferentially to the lateral BNS, 
    dorsal amygdala, and a region in between that may correspond to the 
    dorsal SI (see Saper, &apos;82a, Fig. 2).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">In the rat, several subcortical cell groups associated 
    with the dorsal SI maintain connections with cortices that 
    innervate the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Infralimbic, prelimbic, anterior cingulate, insular, 
    piriform, and entorhinal cortex project to and receive projections 
    from the basolateral nucleus of the amygdala, and all but anterior 
    cingulate cortex have also been reported to innervate the central 
    nucleus (for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Additionally, the caudolateral zone of the lateral 
    hypothalamus innervates medial prefrontal and insular cortex 
    (Saper, &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">The medial parabrachial nucleus is reciprocally 
    connected with the most ventral infralimbic cortex and a large 
    rostrocaudal extent of insular cortex (Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; 
    Saper, &apos;82b; Fulwiler and Saper, &apos;84) that includes areas 
    identified as containing gustatory and visceral sensory 
    representations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Insular and ventral infralimbic cortex also project to 
    the nucleus of the solitary tract (Ross et al., &apos;81; Saper, 
    &apos;82a; Shipley, &apos;82; Van der Kooy et al., &apos;82; 
    Terrebeny and Neafsey, &apos;831, and possibly to the 
    intermediolateral column of the spinal cord (Shipley, &apos;82; 
    Shimada et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Neural associates of the ventral SZ.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">As illustrated in Figure 16, structures preferentially 
    interconnected with the ventral SI form a complementary set to the 
    forebrain associates of the dorsal division.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Present findings indicate only a modest innervation of 
    the dorsal SI from the anterior amygdaloid area and the region 
    ventral to the central nucleus that may include part of the 
    basomedial nucleus as delineated by Krettek and Price 
    (&apos;78b).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">These ventral regions of the amygdala instead project 
    heavily to the ventral SI, which also receives selective 
    innervation from the rostral two-thirds of the medial nucleus, 
    medial BNS, medial preoptic area, anterior hypothalamus, the most 
    medial part of the lateral hypothalamus, and the ventromedial 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">The medial BNS, ventral SI, and ventromedial amygdala 
    maintain reciprocal connections with one another (present study, 
    Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Grove, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Further, the medial BNS, ventral SI, and rostral parts 
    of both the medial nucleus and the amygdaloid area beneath the 
    central nucleus all project to the anterior hypothalamus, medial 
    portions of the preoptic area and lateral hypothalamus, and the 
    dorsomedial and ventromedial hypothalamus (present study; Krettek 
    and Price, &apos;78a; Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81; Price, 
    &apos;81; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Present findings from PHA-L and WGA-HRP experiments 
    indicate the same hypothalamic regions return projections to the 
    ventromedial amygdala and ventral SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">At least the caudomedial hypothalamus innervates the 
    medial BNS as well (present study; Saper et al., &apos;76a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Finally, these hypothalamic areas may maintain 
    connections among themselves (present study; Conrad and Pfaff, 
    &apos;76a,b; Saper et al., &apos;76a, &apos;79a,b; Swanson, 
    &apos;76; Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">In the rodent, the rostral part of the medial nucleus, 
    anterior amygdaloid area, and medial BNS lie along conduction lines 
    leading from the main olfactory bulb (OB) or accessory olfactory 
    bulb (AOB), which relay chemosensory information from, 
    respectively, the olfactory epithelium and vomeronasal organ (a 
    second chemosensory organ found in the nasal cavity of many 
    nonprimate mammals.)</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">The two pathways may overlap in the rostral medial 
    nucleus (for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Switzer et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Projections back to the AOB arise from the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala, medial BNS, and the ventral SI (de Olmos 
    et al., &apos;85; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">The OB is innervated, in turn, by at least the SI 
    (Grove, &apos;88) and anterior amygdaloid area (for review of the 
    return projections to OB and AOB, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85; 
    Switzer et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Possible nonselective afferents to the SZ.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Several structures that project preferentially to one SI 
    division innervate the other subregion at least sparsely (Figs. 4, 
    8-11).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">In particular, WGA-HRP deposits involving either SI 
    division labelled several cells in the dorsomedial hypothalamus, an 
    area of the lateral hypothalamus just ventral to the fornix, the 
    posterior hypothalamus, the supramammillary region, the ventral 
    tegmental area, and the peripeduncular area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">PHA-L deposits centered in the last three regions 
    confirmed projections to the SI that appeared nonselective.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">(Small subregions within these areas may, of course, 
    maintain preferential, separate projections to each SI division, 
    but the present study provided no evidence of such a 
    parcellation.)</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Findings from both WGA-HRP and PHA-L experiments further 
    suggested that the dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus, 
    supramammillary region, and peripeduncular area project to at least 
    some of the amygdaloid and hypothalamic associates of both SI 
    divisions.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">At least in the case of the peripeduncular area, 
    however, projections do not appear to reach all forebrain 
    associates of the dorsal SI, avoiding the paraventricular nucleus 
    of the hypothalamus and the basolateral nucleus of the amygdala and 
    distributing only modestly in the central nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s436">Of the globus that 
    selectively</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s437">innervate the 
    cholinergic cell-rich region</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">The present study additionally revealed several 
    afferents to the cholinergic cell-rich region of the GP that bring 
    their target cells into the general circuitries described above.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">In the following, three categories of afferents are 
    described in relation to the routes of access they take.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">PHA-L experiments revealed that a few axons of both the 
    stria terminalis and AP become detached from these main fiber 
    bundles and form slender bridges between the two pathways by 
    running along the lateral face of the internal capsule, or lateral 
    margin of the GP.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">At least a few sparsely varicose axons arising from the 
    central nucleus of the amygdala, dorsal SI (Grove, &apos;881, 
    lateral bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, lateral hypothalamus, 
    and parabrachial nucleus follow this route.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Fibers from the ventral tegmental area and dorsal raphe 
    also spread along the lateral face of the internal capsule, 
    although varicose axons from at least the dorsal raphe appear in 
    the main mass of the globus pallidus as well.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Finally, although their source was not determined, some 
    of these &quot;bridging&quot; axons have been the identified as 
    immunoreactive for tyrosine hydroxylase (Fig.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">21, or angiotensin I1 (Lind et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">In the monkey, too, a few axons from the central nucleus 
    of the amygdala course along the fiber laminae that surround the 
    GP, and are distributed among the large cells that extend into 
    these regions from the basal nucleus of Meynert (Price and Amaral, 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">In both rat and monkey, this category of afferents to 
    areas in and around the GP strays from fiber contingents that more 
    densely innervate the SI (specifically the dorsal SI in the 
    rat).</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Such sparse fibers appear likely to provide a 
    significant innervation only to cells that receive relatively few 
    inputs from any other source.</S>
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">It is therefore interesting that intrapallidal 
    cholinergic cells are of this sparsely afferented type (Ingham et 
    al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">A greater volume of more richly varicose fibers courses 
    over a second route into the ventromedial and caudal GP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Efferents from the peripeduncular area penetrate the 
    cerebral peduncle and pass rostrally over the supraoptic 
    decussation to be distributed selectively in the cholinergic 
    cellrich region of the GP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Just as the peripeduncular nucleus in the monkey 
    projects more heavily to the caudal cell islands of the basal 
    nucleus of Meynert (Jones et al., &apos;76), the PPA in the rat 
    innervates the comparatively caudal cholinergic cell-rich GP more 
    densely than it does the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">However, afferents to the SI and amygdala arise not only 
    from the PPA proper but from a continuum extending rolitrally from 
    the PPA to incorporate the parvocellular part of the 
    subparafascicular nucleus (present study; Mehler, &apos;80; Mehler 
    et al., &apos;81; LeDoux et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">The continuum is identified 1) by the finding that cells 
    throughout its extent are labelled by retrograde tracers placed in 
    the SI or amygdala (present study; Mehler, &apos;80; Mehler et al., 
    &apos;81; LeDoux et al., &apos;85) and 2) by the somatostatin 
    (Graybiel and Elde, &apos;83) and enkephalin-immunoreactive fibers 
    (unpublished observation) that permeate it.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">It may be that rostral parts of the continuum (not 
    injected with PHA-L in the present study) may project more densely 
    to more rostral parts of the cholinergic basal forebrain. including 
    the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Saper (&apos;84) has proposed that a third route, the 
    internal capsule, may supply the region with a variety of cortical 
    inputs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Further, Haring and Wang (&apos;86) have reported 
    evidence from retrograde axonal transport experiments that cortical 
    innervatibn is not typical of the GP as a whole but is directed 
    selectively toward its medial part.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Findings from a few PHA-L cases available to the present 
    studv revealed that axons from at least the rostral-medial 
    prefiontal and insular cortex do display terminal varicosities in 
    the internal capsule and medial GP, as well as in the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">However, not all cortical areas may give rise to 
    efferents that innervate the GP and the intracapsular gray as they 
    traverse the region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">PHA-L deposits in cingulate cortex caudal to the genu of 
    the corpus callosum, for example, filled only smooth, 
    nonterminating fibers in the GP and IC.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Additionally, and surprisingly, the medial GP is not the 
    only target of corticopallidal afferents: a few axons labelled from 
    PHAL injections into motor cortex displayed terminal swelling:; in 
    the lateral, but not medial, part of the GP (Grove, in 
    preparation).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">In summary, a variety of afferents to the SI, in 
    particulaito its dorsal division, are shared at least sparsely by 
    neurons within the cholinergic cell-rich region of the GP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Since projections from this area to the cortex are well 
    documented, it appears that the cholinergic cell-rich region of GP 
    shares a kinship with the SI in both afferent and efferent 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Pallidal features of the dorsalmost part of the SI The 
    separation of cell populations typical of the GP or SI may also be 
    incomplete in the dorsalmost part of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">This region is marked by enkephalin-immunoreactive 
    &quot;woolly fibers,&quot; a terminal configuration that is 
    characteristic of the projection from the striatum to the GP and 
    ventral pallidum (Haber and Elde, &apos;81; Switzer et al., 
    &apos;82; Zaborszky et al., &apos;82; Haber and Nauta, 
    &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Further, the dorsalmost SI does receive a projection 
    from the striatum (Fig. 151, and appears to project back to the 
    striatum as well (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Such observations suggest the dorsalmost S[ should be 
    viewed as, or as mixed with, pallidal tissue.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">However, in receiving innervation from the striatum and 
    from ENK-IR woolly fibers, the SI resembles not only the GP and VP 
    but also certain parts of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Both features are shared by the lateral segment of the 
    central nucleus and the most lateral part of the bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis (present study, Nauta et al., &apos;78; Haber and 
    Nauta, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Moreover, the striatum has not been directly established 
    as an origin of enkephalinergic innervation in any of these areas, 
    and other sources are possible.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">For example, PHA-L-filled axon terminals, labelled from 
    deposits in the central nucleus of the amygdala, bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis, or parabrachial nucleus were occasionally seen to 
    outline a single cell body or dendrite in the SI in &quot;woolly 
    fiber&quot; fashion (see Results).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Each of these nuclei contains enkephalinergic neurons 
    (Mantyh and Hunt, &apos;84; Veening et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Indeed, the central nucleus has been shown by lesion 
    experiments to provide enkephalinergic afferents to the bed nucleus 
    of the stria terminalis, some of which traverse the SI (Rao et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Only a similar study can finally determine the origin of 
    ENK-IR woolly fibers, in particular, in the SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">The dorsalmost strip of the SI also differs from the 
    adjacent GP and VP in several respects, resembling instead the rest 
    of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">First, present findings do not indicate a heavy 
    innervation by the subthalamic nucleus, the second major source of 
    input to the GP-VP continuum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Second, the dorsalmost SI is the target not of just a 
    few AP fibers, like the cholinergic cell-rich region of the GP, but 
    of many.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">These fibers include afferents from regions that 
    themselves display &quot;pallidal&quot; features-the lateral 
    segment of the central nucleus of the amygdala, lateral part of the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, and the perifornical zone of 
    the lateral hypothalamus-but also from the basolateral nucleus of 
    the amygdala, caudolateral zone of the lateral hypothalamus, 
    parabrachial nucleus, and possibly nucleus of the solitary 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Third, the dorsalmost SI, like the rest of the dorsal 
    division, can be distinguished from most of the GP and VP in 
    material stained to reveal tyrosine hydroxylase-immunoreactive axon 
    terminals (Fig. 2), or a cupric-silver reaction product (de Olmos, 
    &apos;72; de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Finally, the entire SI displays modest, even staining in 
    Timm preparations, whereas the VP and GP appear patchy (Ottersen, 
    &apos;80; de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">At present, perhaps the only possible conclusion 
    regarding the dorsalmost strip of the SI is that the region appears 
    to combine certain histochemical and connectional features of both 
    the overlying GP and the rest of the SI, forming a more complex 
    tissue than either one.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s481">Innervation of the 
    cholinergc neurons within the globus pallidus and substantia 
    innominata</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">The most striking constituent of the SI in the primate 
    is the basal nucleus of Meynert (BNM), which provides most of the 
    cholinergic innervation of the neocortex and amygdala (Mesulam et 
    al., &apos;83a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">In the rat, too, although there is no infrapallidal cell 
    mass comparable to the BNM, the SI contains a characteristic 
    scattering of cholinergic neurons that also project to neocortical 
    and amygdaloid targets (Lehmann et al., &apos;80; Big1 et al., 
    &apos;82; Woolf and Butcher, &apos;82; Grove et al., &apos;83; 
    McKinney et al., &apos;83; Mesulam et al., &apos;83a,b; Rye et al., 
    &apos;84b; Saper, &apos;84; Carlsen et al., &apos;85; Fisher et 
    al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">This dispersed cell population is helpful in determining 
    the rough boundaries that can be drawn around the SI (see 
    Results).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Cholinergic neurons in the SI, however, are only part of 
    a loosely continuous mass of cholinergic cells in the basal 
    forebrain that extends from the medial septum and the nucleus of 
    the diagonal band to the caudal GP, and it has been proposed that 
    this cell population may form a single anatomical and functional 
    entity (Schwaber et al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">It is thus plausible that cholinergic cells that invade 
    the SI maintain their own characteristic afferent and efferent 
    connections, related to those of other basal forebrain cholinergic 
    neurons, but wholly unrelated to those of neighboring, 
    noncholinergic SI cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Alternatively, cholinergic cells may take a strategic 
    advantage from their wide scattering in different parts of the 
    basal forebrain, participating in the distinctive circuitry of 
    these different regions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Resolving this issue requires considerable further 
    investigation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">However, some observations from the present study bear 
    on one important question-namely, what are the afferent connections 
    of the cholinergic neurons, and how do they compare to those of 
    neighboring noncholinergic cells?</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">The cell bodies and proximal dendrites of cholinergic 
    cells in the GP and SI are typically contacted only sparsely by 
    synaptic axonal boutons (Ingham et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Probably for this reason, in tissue sections processed 
    to show both forms of immunoreactivity, juxtapositions between 
    PHA-L-labelled axonal varicosities and ChAT-IR neurons were seen 
    only rarely.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Synaptic relations can be identified conclusively only 
    in the electron microscope, since a physical contact between a 
    labelled axon terminal and an identified cell seen in the light 
    microscope may well be coincidental: the bouton in reality makes 
    synaptic contact with an adjacent, unlabelled element, or forms no 
    synapse at all.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">For this reason, only contacts by several PHA-L-labelled 
    varicosities on the same CUT-IR cell were taken as providing strong 
    light microscopic evidence of innervation.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Such terminal configurations were particularly difficult 
    to find but were noted in the SI or GP following PHA-L injections 
    into the ventral tegmental area, dorsal raphe, peripeduncular 
    nucleus, and caudomedial hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Pending confirmation in an ultrastructural study, such 
    findings suggest that several sources of innervation to the SI may 
    provide afferents to the cholinergic cells in the region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Electron microscopic observations following knife cuts 
    at the mesodiencephalic border provide supportive evidence of 
    synaptic inputs to cholinergic SI cells from caudal brainstem 
    structures (Zaborszky et aI., &apos;86b).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">In the present study, fibers originating from the 
    amygdala and some cortical areas were observed to form terminal 
    varicosities, sometimes in profusion, in regions containing 
    cholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Nonetheless, only occasional single contacts were 
    observed between PHA-L-labelled axanal swellings and CMT-IR 
    elements.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Inputs selective for distal Darts of the cholinermc 
    cells&apos; dendrites would be missed; however, since the reuaction 
    product marking ChAT rarely filled that part of the cell densely 
    enough to be identifiable in the light microscope.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Indeed, electron microscopic studies employing WGA-HRP 
    as an anterograde axonal tracer have suggested synaptic input from 
    the cortex to cortically projecting basal forebrain neurons 
    (Lehmann and Saper, &apos;85) and from the basolateral nucleus of 
    the amygdala to amygdala-projecting or ChAT-immunoreactive cells 
    (Zaborszky et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Studies in the monkey provide additional evidence for a 
    variety of afferents to cholinergic cells in the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">In primates, most cholinergic neurons in the SI cluster 
    to form the cell islands of the basal nucleus of Meynert.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Even when seen in exclusively light microscopic 
    examination, anterograde axonal labelling over these clusters thus 
    strongly suggests innervation of the cholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Such labelling has been reported in autoradiographic 
    studies of the efferents of the peripeduncular nucleus and 
    ventromedial hypothalamus (Jones et al., &apos;761, central nucleus 
    of the amygdala (Price and Amaral, &apos;81), other sites in the 
    amygdala (Russchen et al., &apos;851, and orbital, insular, and 
    anterior et temporal cortex (Mesulam and Mufson, &apos;84; Russchen 
    al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Several lines of evidence suggest a general conclusion: 
    cholinergic neurons do not form an entirely separate, intruding 
    cell group in the SI and GP but participate to some extent in the 
    afferent circuitry of local neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">In the monkey, axons arising from the peripeduncular 
    nucleus, ventromedial hypothalamus, amygdala, and cortex not only 
    appear to terminate over the BNM cell clusters but also distribute 
    over other parts of the SI where comparatively few cholinergic 
    cells are dispersed (Jones et al., &apos;76; Price and Amaral, 
    &apos;81; Russchen et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">In the rat, the moderate-to-high density of axon 
    terminal labelling in the SI and cholinergic cell-rich GP that 
    follows PHA-L injections into the peripeduncular area or amygdala 
    of the rat, and sometimes locally appears as &quot;empty 
    basket&quot; formations of labelled terminals, suggests that a 
    sparsely innervated cell type such as the cholinergic neuron cannot 
    be the only target.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Finally, both lightand electron-microscopic evidence 
    indicates that at least some intrapallidal cholinergic cells 
    receive innervation from the striatum (Grove et al., &apos;86; 
    Grove and Ingham, &apos;861, a source of input they share with 
    noncholinergic, typically pallidal cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s509">FUNCTIONAL 
    CONSIDERATIONS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Three observations, based on the present anatomical 
    findings, could be useful in guiding physiological and behavioral 
    studies of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">First, the SI is likely to be functionally 
    heterogeneous: the dorsal and ventral divisions receive afferent 
    input from largely different sets of struttures and maintain 
    similarly distinct efferent connections (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Second, the cholinergic cell GOUP, whose functional role 
    is of great current interest, is distributed in both divisions and 
    appears likely to Participate in the afferent circuitry of 
    neighboring, noncholinergic cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Third7 and perhaps most important, in designing 
    functional studies of the SI, investigators might take a cue from 
    its strong neuroanatomical affiliation with the amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">More detailed anatomical studies are needed, but it 
    seems likely that these generalizations are also applicable to the 
    primate.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">The organisation of the SI into two divisions, 
    demonstrated here in the rat, reflects the relative position of 
    axons that compose the AP in its traverse of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">To the extent that different contingents of fibers in 
    the AP have a comparable organisation in other species, SI 
    divisions defined by differential afferentation should be 
    identifiable.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Further, heavy projections between the amYgdala and the 
    SI in the monkey have been demonstrated (Russchen et al., &apos;85; 
    Aggleton et al., &apos;87), and as noted above, a comparison of 
    retrograde tracer studies suggests that the afferent connections of 
    the SI and amygdala in the monkey are highly similar (Aggleton et 
    al., &apos;80; Mehler, &apos;80; Norita and Kawamura, &apos;80; 
    Mehler et al., &apos;81; Russchen et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s518">Possible functional 
    associations of the dorsal SI</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Several of the interconnected forebrain and brainstem 
    structures associated with the dorsal SI appear to form a 
    functional assembly concerned at least in part with monitoring and 
    influencing autonomic and visceral functions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Changes in blood pressure and heart rate are induced by 
    ablation or stimulation in the posterior insular cortex, ventral 
    infralimbic cortex, bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, central 
    nucleus of the amygdala, dorsomedial nucleus of the hypothalamus, 
    dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus, and nucleus of the solitary 
    tract.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Respiratory function is modified by stimulation or 
    ablation of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, central 
    nucleus, or medial parabrachial nucleus, and changes in GI motility 
    or secretory activity are elicited by stimulation of the central 
    nucleus (for review, see Kaada, &apos;72; Ricardo and Koh, 
    &apos;78; Price and Amaral, &apos;81; Ruggiero et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Stimulation in or ablation of the amygdaloid affiliates 
    of the dorsal SI can additionally evoke or disrupt coordinated 
    behaviors that prominently include autonomic components.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">The central and basolateral nuclei of the amygdala are 
    effective stimulation sites for eliciting the defense reaction, an 
    integrated set of autonomic, endocrine, and somatic motor responses 
    (for review, see Kaada, &apos;721, and ablation of the central 
    nucleus has been reported to suppress autonomic and behavioral 
    components of a conditioned fear response (Iwata et al., 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s524">Possible functional 
    associations of the ventral S%</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Indicating that the circuitries associated with the two 
    SI divisions are functionally as well as anatomically distinct, 
    cell groups connected with the ventral SI have been implicated in 
    quite different species-specific behaviors.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Stimulation in the corticomedial nuclei of the amygdala 
    in the monkey is comparatively ineffective in eliciting defense and 
    flight responses, and instead modifies feeding and sexual behaviors 
    (for review, see Kaada, &apos;72).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">In the rodent, lesions in the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala, medial preoptic area, or caudomedial hypothalamus 
    suppress mi2ting and investigatory behaviors (Heimer and Larsson, 
    &apos;67; paxinos and ~ i ~ &apos;73; &amp; ~ Lehman , et al., 
    &apos;80) apparent,ly due, at least in the of amygdaloid lesions, 
    to disrupted processing of chemosensory input from the olfactory 
    and vomeronasa~ organs (Lehman et al., &apos;80).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">It might be noted that lesions in the peripeduncular 
    area, which innervates both ventral and dorsal divisions ofthe SI 
    and at least of their forebrain associates, have been reported to 
    disrupt aspects of sexual behavior in the female rat (see Arnault 
    and Roger, &apos;87, for review), as well as autonomic responses 
    and emotional behavior conditioned to acoustic stimuli (LeDoux et 
    al., &apos;84; Jarrell et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Although experiments have indicated functional 
    heterogeneity in the amygdala, an view of the role of this 
    structure has proved useful in guiding behavioral studies and may 
    be applicable to the SI as well.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">This view, that the amygdala is a route through which 
    complex sensory stimuli elicit appropriate affective re.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">sponses ( ~ l i &apos;72; ~ ~ ~ , l &apos;78; Mishkin ~ 
    ~ and ~ Aggleton, , &apos;81)&apos; appears to be supported by the 
    anatomical position of the amygdala (shared by the SI), receiving 
    afferents that can be presumed to relay sensory information from 
    insular alld temporal polysensory association cortices and 
    maintainirlg widespread descending projections to the hypothalamus 
    arld caudal brainstem. price and Amaral(&apos;81) hypothesize that 
    the central nucleus may, thus, mediate between the perception of a 
    fear-evoking situation and the mobilization of an appropriate 
    autonomic and behavioral response.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">It can be conjectured that the medial nucleus might play 
    an analogous role in the initiation of sexual and investigatory 
    behavior in response to complex chemosensory stimuli.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s533">Memory function</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Consistent with the general view of amygdala function 
    expressed above, lesions in that structure in the monkey disrupt a 
    specific type of learning, the association of stimulus and reward 
    (Jones and Mishkin, &apos;72; Mishkin and Aggleton, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Further observations, however, indicate a wider 
    involvement by the amygdala in memory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Ablation of the amygdala impairs a monkey&apos;s ability 
    to form cross-modal associations, that is, to recognize by vision 
    an object it has previously examined by touch (Murray and Mishkin, 
    &apos;851, and combined lesions of the amygdala and hippocampus 
    produce an analog of human global amnesia (Mishkin, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Against this background, the suggestion that the 
    affXated SI may also be involved in memory is particularly 
    noteworthy.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Such a proposal has previously focused on the 
    cholinergic cell population in the SI, deriving from observations 
    that cholinergic drugs affect performance in tests of memory (for 
    review, see Aigner and Mishkin, &apos;861, and that, in 
    Alzheimer&apos;s disease (AD), degenerative changes that occur in 
    the pathway from the cholinergic basal nucleus of Meynert to cortex 
    appear correlated with the degree of memory loss (for review, see 
    Corkin, &apos;81; Bartus et al., &apos;82; Rossor et al., 
    &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">However, in both cases, memory could be influenced by 
    altered function in brain structures other than the SI (Davies, 
    &apos;83; Hyman et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Several studies have further investigated the role of 
    the cholinergic SI cell population in memory with experimental 
    lesions confined to the basal forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Lesions that deplete cortical cholinergic markers in the 
    rat have been observed to impair performance in several tasks that 
    involve a memory component, although in many such studies the 
    possibility that this is caused by the disruption of some 
    nonmnemonic process has not been discounted (for review, see 
    Salamone, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">In the monkey, Aigner and colleagues (&apos;84) have 
    shown that combined ablation of the septum, diagonal band, and 
    basal nucleus disrupts recognition memory; they propose that the 
    impairment results from compromised function in both the 
    hippocampus and amygdala, targets of cholinergic projections from, 
    respectively, the medial septum and basal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">However, although the excitotoxic lesions made by Aigner 
    and colleagues would spare fibers passing through the lesion sites, 
    they would also destroy noncholinergic cells in the SI and disrupt 
    conduction pathways that incorporate such neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">New information from the present study and from a 
    cornpanion investigation provides a firm neuroanatomical basis a 
    role for the SI in memory and suggests a for novel view.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Such a functional contribution, in the new view, may go 
    beyond the cholinergic modulation of activity in other 
    memory-related structures.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">The complete set of afferent and efferent connections 
    maintained by the SI appears highly similar, if not identical, to 
    that of the amygdala, and in the case of the latter structure, 
    these associations support a well-documented role in memory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Thus, neuroanatomical evidence suggests the SI may 
    contribute to normal memory function in strong affiliation with the 
    amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Shifting attention to the neuroanatomical character of 
    the SI as a whole, rather than focusing only on its cholinergic 
    projections elsewhere, also suggests a new emphasis for functional 
    studies.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">A specific illustration can be offered in conclusion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">A recent study (Richardson and DeLong, &apos;86) of the 
    response properties of neurons in the basal nucleus of Meynert was 
    motivated by a focus on its cholinergic projection to cortex, 
    specifically its innervation of dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in 
    the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Ablation or cooling of this part of the cortex disrupts 
    performance in a delayed response task (Fuster and Alexander, 
    &apos;70; Goldman and Rosvold, &apos;70), as do cholinergic 
    antagonists (Bartus, &apos;78).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Neurons in dorsolateral prefrontal cortex display 
    altered firing rates during the delay period of the task (Fuster, 
    &apos;73; Kojima and Goldman-Rakic, &apos;82), and if BNM neurons 
    influence response properties in such cells they might exhibit 
    similar firing rate changes themselves.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">However, Richardson and DeLong (&apos;86) found that few 
    neurons in the basal nucleus of Meynert change their rate of 
    discharge during the delay period of a task in which a monkey is 
    required to discriminate between two spatial locations for 
    reward.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Instead, these authors observed that most recorded cells 
    altered their firing rate as the monkey selected, reached for, or 
    received its reward (Richardson and DeLong, &apos;86), consistent 
    with similar previous observations (DeLong, &apos;71; Burton et 
    al., &apos;75; Rolls et al., &apos;79, &apos;80; Rigdon and Pirch, 
    &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">These results provide little evidence for a direct 
    involvement of BNM in the memory component of the task but support 
    a relation to aspects of reward acquisition.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">An emphasis on the connectional similarity between the 
    SI and the amygdala, however, suggests the type of task described 
    by Richardson and DeLong may not be best suited to revealing the 
    particular contribution of the SI to memory.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Ablation studies have not implicated the amygdala in 
    memory for spatial location (Jones and Mishkin, &apos;72; Mishkin 
    and Aggleton, &apos;811, and lesions must be placed in both the 
    amygdala and hippocampus to disrupt performance in several object 
    discrimination tasks involving a delay (Mishkin, &apos;78; Mishkin 
    and Aggleton, &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">However, ablation of the amygdala alone dramatically 
    impairs an animal&apos;s ability to form associations between 
    particular objects and reward conditions.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Thus, the strong affiliation between the SI and the 
    amygdala, especially in light of the apparent involvement of SI 
    neurons with reward acquisition, suggests that a focus on memory 
    for object-reward associations might prove fruitful in both 
    ablation and single-unit recording studies of the SI.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="25" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s560">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s561">I take great pleasure in 
    thanking Doctor J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s562">Nauta for his encouragement 
    and -;dance throughout the course of this study and for his 
    critical reading of the manuscript.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s563">This study was K d e Possible 
    by NSF grant BNS 8306284, pHs grants RO1 NS 19945 and MH 311549 and 
    a predoctoral fellowship from the Scottish Rite Schizophrenia 
    Research Program (N.M.J., U.S.A.).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="25" class="references.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Aggleton, J.P., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Burton, and R.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Passingham (1980) Cortical and subcortical afferents to 
    the amygdala of the rhesus monkey (Macaca mulatta).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">I90;347-368.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Aggleton, J.P., D.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Friedman, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Mishkin (1987) A comparison between the connections of 
    the amygdala and hippocampus with the basal forebrain of the 
    macaque.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Brain Res. 67t556-568.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Aigner, T.G., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Mishkin (1986) The effects of physostigmine and 
    scopolamine on recognition memory in monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Behav.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Neural Biol. 4531-87.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Aigner, T., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Mitchel, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Aggleton, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">DeLong, R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Struble, G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Wenk, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Price, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Mishkin (1984) Recognition deficit in monkeys following 
    neurotoxic lesions of the basal forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Abstr. 10:386.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Amaral, D.G., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Price (1984) Amygdalo-cortical projections in the 
    monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Neurol. 23Ot465-496.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Arnault, P., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Roger (1987) The connections of the peripeduncular area 
    studied by retrograde and anterograde transport in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Neurol. 258:463-476.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Bartus, R.T. (1978) Evidence for a direct cholinergic 
    involvement in the scopolamine-induced amnesia in monkeys: Effects 
    of concurrent administration of pbysostigmine and methylphenidate 
    with scopolamine.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Pharmacol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Biochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Behav. 9t833-836.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Bartus, R.T., R.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Dean, B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Beer, and A.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Lippa (1982) The cholinergic hypothesis of geriatric 
    memory dysfunction.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Science 217t408-417.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Beckstead, R.M. (19791 An autoradiographic examination 
    of cortico-cortical and subcortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal-projection (prefrontal) cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Neurol. 184t43-62.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Beckstead, R.M., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Nauta (1979) Efferent connections of the substantia 
    nigra and ventral tegmental area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Brain Res. 175:191-217.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Finkelstein (1981) Afferent projections to the preoptic 
    area and hypothalamic regions in rat brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Neuroscience 6t1601-1624.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Bigl, V., N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Woolf, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Butcher (1982) Cholinergic projections from the basal 
    forebrain to frontal, parietal, temporal, occipital and cingulate 
    cortices: A combined fluorescent tracer and acetylcholinesterase 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Bull. 8t727-749.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Burton, ML, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Mora, and E.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Rolls (1975) Visual and taste neurones in the lateral 
    hypothalamus and substantia innominata: Modulation of 
    responsiveness by hunger.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Physiol. 252:50-51P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Carlsen, J., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Zaborszky, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Heimer (1985) Cholinergic projections from the basal 
    forebrain to the basolateral amygdaloid complex: A combined 
    retrograde fluorescent and immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Neurol. 234:155-167.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Conrad, L.C.A., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Pfaff (1976a) Efferents from medial basal forebrain and 
    hypothalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">An autoradiographic study of the medial preoptic 
    area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Neurol. 169:185-220.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Conrad, L.C.A., and D.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Pfaff (1976h) Efferents from medial basal forebrain and 
    hypothalamus in the rat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">An autoradiographic study of the anterior 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Neurol. 169:221-262.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Corkin, S. (1981) Acetylcholine, aging and Alzheimer s 
    disease.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Implications for treatment.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Trends Neurosci. 4.287-290.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">Davies, P. (1983) Neurotransmitters and neuropeptides in 
    Alzheimer s disease.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">In R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Katzman (ed): Banbury Report 15.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Biological Aspects of Alzheimer s Disease.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">Cold Spring Harbor NY: Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, 
    pp. 255-265.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Olmos, J.S. (1972) The amygdaloid projection field in 
    the rat as studied with the cupric-silver method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">In B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Eleftheriou (ed): The Neurobiology of the Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 145-204.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Olmos, J.S., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Hardy, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Heimer (1978) The afferent connections of the main and 
    accessory olfactory bulb formations in the rat: An experimental HRP 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">I81:213-244.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Olmos, J.S., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Beltramino (1985) Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Vol. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Australia: Academic Press, pp. 223-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">DeLong, M.R. (19711 Activity Neurophysiol. 
    34:414-427.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Fisher, R.S., J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Asai, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Wainer, N.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Buchwald, andM.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Levine (1986) Cholinergic and gahaergic projections from 
    pallidal and peripallidal regions to the neocortex of the cat: 
    Demonstration by double peroxidase labeling of their neurons of 
    origin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Abstr. 12:1467.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Fox, C.A., A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Andrade, I.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">LuQui, and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Rafols (1974) The primate globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">A Golgi and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Hirnforsch. 15:75-93.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Fulwiler, C.E., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Saper (1984) Subnuclear organization of the efferent 
    connections of the parabrachial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Rev. 7229-259, Fuster, J.M. (1973) Unit activity in 
    prefrontal cortex during delayed-response performance: Neuronal 
    correlates of transient memory.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Neurophysiol. 36:61-78.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Fuster, J.M., and G.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Alexander (1970) Delayed response ogenic depression of 
    frontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Brain Res. 20:85-90.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Geneser-Jensen, F.A., and J.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Blackstad (1971) Distribution of acetylcholinesterase in 
    the hippocampal region of the guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Entorhinal area, parasubiculuni and presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Zellforsch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Mikrosk.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Anat. 114:460-481.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morpholoby of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Brain Res. 29Ot219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Gloor, P. (1978) Inputs and outputs of the amygdala: 
    What the amygdala is trying to tell the rest ofthe brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">In K.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Livingston and 0.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Hornykiewicz (eds): Limbic Mechanisms.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 189-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Goldman, P.S., and H.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Rosvold (1970) Localization of function within the 
    dorsolateral prefrontal cortex of the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Neurol. 27:291304.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">Gray, T.S., and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Magnuson (1987) Neuropeptide neuronal efferents from the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and central amygdaloid nucleus 
    to the dorsal vagal complex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Neurol. 262.365-374.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">Graybiel, A.M., and R.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">Elde (1983) Somatostatin-like immunoreactivity 
    characterizes neurons of the nucleus reticularis thalami in the cat 
    and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s729">Neurosci. 3t1308-1321.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s730">Graybiel, A.M., and C.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s731">Ragsdale (1979) Fiber connections of the ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s732">Prog.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s733">Brain Res. 51239-283.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s734">Groenewegen, H.J., and C.A. van Dijk (1984) Efferent 
    projections of the ventral pallidum in the rat as studied with the 
    anterograde transport of Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s735">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s736">Lett.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s737">[Suppl.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s738">I S58.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s739">Grove, E.A. (1988) Efferent connections of the 
    substantia rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s740">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s741">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s742">Neurol. 277t347-364.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s743">Grove, E.A., and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s744">Ingham (1986) Electron microscopic evidence of striatal 
    input to intrapallidal neurons of cholinergic cell group Ch4 in 
    t,he rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s745">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s746">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s747">Abstr. 12:1328.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s748">Grove, E.A., S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s749">Haber, V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s750">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s751">Nauta (1983) Differential projections from AChE-positive 
    and AChE-negative ventral pallidum cells in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s752">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s753">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s754">Abstr. 1Ot16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s755">Grove, E.A., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s756">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s757">Nauta (1986) Light microscopic evidence of striatal 
    input to intrapallidal neurons of cholinergic cell group Ch4 in the 
    rat: A study employing the anterograde tracer Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s758">Brain Res. 367:379-384.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s759">Haber, S., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s760">Elde (1981) Correlation between met-enkephalin and 
    substance P immunoreactivity in the primate globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s761">Neuroscience 6t1291-1297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s762">Haber, S.N., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s763">Nauta (1983) Ramifications of the globus pallidus in the 
    rat as indicated by patterns of immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s764">Neuroscience 9.245-260.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s765">Haber, S.N., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s766">Groenewegen, E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s767">Grove, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s768">Nauta (1985) Efferent connections of the ventral 
    pallidum: Evidence of a dual striatopallidofugal pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s769">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s770">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s771">Neurol. 235322-335.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s772">Hall, E. (1972) Some aspects of the structural 
    organization of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s773">B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s774">Eleftheriou (ed): The Neurobiology of the Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s775">New York Plenum Press, pp. 95-121.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s776">Haring, J.H., and R.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s777">Wang (1986) The identification of some sources of 
    afferent input to the rat nucleus basalis magnocellularis by 
    retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s778">Brain Res. 366t152-158.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s779">Heimer, L., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s780">Larsson (1967) Mating behavior of male olfactory bulb 
    lesions.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s781">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s782">Behav. 2t207-209.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s783">Heimer, L., and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s784">Wilson (1975) The subcortical projections of the 
    allocortex: Similarities in the neural associations of the 
    hippocampus, the piriform cortex, and the neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s785">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s786">Santini (ed): Golgi Centennial Symposium.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s787">New York: Raven Press, pp. 177-193.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s788">Heimer, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s789">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s790">Zaborszky (1985) Basal ganglia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s791">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s792">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s793">Vol. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s794">Australia: Academic Press, pp. 37-86.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s795">Holstege, G., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s796">Meiners, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s797">Tan (1985) Projections of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis to the mesencephalon, pons, and medulla oblongata in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s798">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s799">Brain Res. 58t379-391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s800">Hyman, B.T., G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s801">Van Hoesen, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s802">Damasio, and C.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s803">Barnes (1984) Alzheimer s disease: Cell specific 
    pathology isolates the hippocampal formation.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s804">Science 225t1168-1170.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s805">Ingham, C.A., J.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s806">Bolam, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s807">Wainer, and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s808">Smith (1985) A correlated light and electron microscopic 
    study of identified cholinergic basal forebrain neurons that 
    project to the cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s809">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s810">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s811">Neurol. 239:176-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s812">Iwata, J., J.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s813">LeDoux, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s814">Reis (1986) Different efferent projections of the 
    geniculo-amygdala pathway mediate autonomic and behavioral 
    concomitants of conditioned fear: Possible completion of the 
    conditioned response circuits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s815">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s816">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s817">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s818">I2:977.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s819">Jarrell, T.W., C.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s820">Gentile, P.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s821">McCabe, and N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s822">Schneiderman (1986) The role of one medial geniculate 
    region in differential Pavlovian conditioning of bradycardia in 
    rabbits.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s823">Brain Res. 374~126-136.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s824">Johnston, J.B. (1923) Further contributions to the study 
    of the the forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s825">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s826">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s827">Neurol. 36:143-192.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s828">Jones, B.E., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s829">Beaudet (1987) Distribution of acetylcholine and 
    catecholamine neurons in the cat brainstem: A choline 
    acetyltransferase and tyrosine hydroxylase immunohistochemical 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s830">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s831">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s832">Neurol. 261 :15-32.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s833">Jones, B., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s834">Mishkin (1972) Limbic lesions and the problem of 
    stimulus reinforcement associations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s835">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s836">Neuroi. 36t362-377.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s837">Jones, E.G., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s838">Burton, C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s839">Saper, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s840">Swanson (1976) Midbrain, diencephalic and cortical 
    relationships of the basal nucleus of Meynert and associated 
    structures in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s841">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s842">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s843">Neurol. 167t385-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s844">Kaada, B.R. (1972) Stimulation and regional ablation of 
    the amygdaloid complex with reference to functional 
    representations.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s845">In B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s846">Eleftheriou (ed): The Neurobiology of the Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s847">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 205-282.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s848">Kelley, A.E., V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s849">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s850">Nauta projection in the rat-an study by anterograde 
    grade tracing methods.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s851">Neuroscience 7:615-630.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s852">Kling, A. (1972) Effects of amygdalectomy on 
    social-affective behavior in nonhuman primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s853">In B&apos;E&apos; (ed): The Neurobiology Of the 
    Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s854">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 511-536.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s855">Kojima, S., and P.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s856">Goldman-Rakic (1982) Delay-related activity of 
    prefrontal in rhesus monkeys performing response.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s857">Brain 248r43-49.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s858">Konig, J.F.R., and R.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s859">Klippel (1963) The Rat Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s860">A Stereotaxic Atlas ofthe Forebrain and Lower Parts 
    ofthe Brainstem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s861">Baltimore: Williams and Wilkins.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s862">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s863">Price (1978a) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s864">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s865">Neurol. 178r225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s866">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s867">Price (1978b) A description of the amygdaloid complex in 
    the rat and cat, with observations on intra.amygdaloid axonal 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s868">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s869">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s870">Neurol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s871">I78r255-280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s872">LeDoux, J.E., A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s873">Sakaguchi, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s874">Reis (1984) Subcortical efferent projections of the 
    medial geniculate nucleus mediate emotional responses conditioned 
    to acoustic stimuli.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s875">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s876">Neurosci. 41683-698.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s877">LeDoux, J.E., D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s878">Ruggiero, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s879">Reis (1985) Projections to the subcortical forebrain 
    from anatomically defined regions of the medial geniculate body in 
    the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s880">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s881">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s882">Neurol. 242.182-213.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s883">Lehman, M.N., S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s884">Winans, and J.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s885">Powers (1980) Medial nucleus of the amygdala mediates 
    chemosensory control of male hamster sexual behavior.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s886">Science 210557-560.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s887">Lehmann, w,, and c.3, Saper (1985) Evidence for a 
    cortical projection to the magnocellular basal nucleus in the rat: 
    An electron microscopic axonal transport study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s888">Brain Res. 334r344-348.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s889">Lehmann, J,, J,I, Nagy, s, Atmadja, and H,C, Fibiger 
    (1980) The nucleus basalis magnocellularis: The origin of a 
    cholinergic projection to the neocortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s890">Neuroscience 51161-1174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s891">Levey, A.I,, A.E, Hallanger, and B,H, Wainer (1987) 
    Cholinergic nucleus basalis may influence the cortex via the 
    thalamus, Neurosci, Lett. 74:7-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s892">Lind, R,W,, L.w, Swanson, and D, Ganten (1985) 
    Organization of angiotensin I1 immunoreactive cells and fibers in 
    the rat central nervous system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s893">Neuroendocrinology 4Ot2-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s894">Lindvall, O., and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s895">Bjorklund (1983) Dopamine and norepinephrine-containing 
    systems: Their in the rat brain. p,c, E~~~~ (ed): Chemical 
    Neuroanatomy.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s896">New York: Raven Press, pp. 229-255.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s897">Luiten, P.G.M., and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s898">Room (1980) Interrelations between lateral, dorsomedial, 
    and ventromedial hypothalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s899">~~~i~ R ~ 190:321-332.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s900">Mantyh, P.W., and S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s901">Hunt (1984) Neuropeptides are present in projection 
    neurones at all levels in visceral and taste pathways: From 
    periphery to sensory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s902">Brain Res. 2991297-311.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s903">McDonald, A.J. (1983) Neurons of the bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis: Golgi study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s904">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s905">Bull. 10:111-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s906">McKinney, M,, J,T, Coyle, and J,c, Hedreen (1983) 
    Topographical analysis of the innervation of the rat neocortex and 
    hippocampus by the basal forebrain cholinergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s907">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s908">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s909">Neurol. 217:103-121.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s910">Mehler, W.R. (1980) Subcortical afferent connections 
    ofthe monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s911">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s912">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s913">Neurol. 1901733-762.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s914">Mehler, W.R., J.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s915">Pretorius, K.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s916">Phelan, and P.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s917">Mantyh (1981) Diencephalic afferent connections ofthe 
    amygdala in the squirrel monkey with observations and comments on 
    the cat and rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s918">In y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s919">Ben.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s920">~ri (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s921">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 105-120.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s922">Mesulam, M,.M,, E, J, ~ ~ A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s923">L f ~ and ~ ~ B.H. wainer ~ ~ ~ (1983a) ~ , Choljn, 
    ergic innervation of cortex by the basal forebrain: Cytochemistry 
    and cortical connections of the septa1 area, diagonal band nuclei, 
    nucleus basalis (substantia innominata), and hypothalamus in the 
    rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s924">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s925">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s926">Neurol. 21411&apos;70-197.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s927">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s928">-M., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s929">Mufson, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s930">Wainer, and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s931">Levey (1983b) Central cholinergic pathways in the rat: 
    An overview based on an alternative nomenclature (Chl-ChG).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s932">Neuroscience 1O:1185-1201.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s933">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s934">-M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for horseradish 
    peroxidase neurochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue reaction product 
    with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural afferents and 
    efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s935">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s936">Histachem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s937">Cytochem. 26:106-117 Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s938">-M., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s939">Mufson (1984) Neural inputs into the nucleus basalis of 
    the substantia innominata (Ch4) in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s940">Brain 107:253-274.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s941">Mishkin, M. (1978) Memory in monkeys severely impaired 
    by combined but not by separate removal of amygdala and 
    hippocampus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s942">Nature 273:297298.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s943">Mishkin, M., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s944">Aggleton (1981) Multiple functional contributions ofthe 
    amygdala in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s945">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s946">Ben-Ari (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s947">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 409-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s948">Mogenson, G, J,, L,W, Swanson, and M, Wu (1985) Evidence 
    that projections from substantia innominata to zona incerta and 
    mesencephalic locomotor region contribute to locomotor activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s949">Brain Res. 334:65-76.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s950">Mufson, E, J,, M,.M, Mesulam, and D.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s951">Pandya (1981) Insular interconnec.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s952">tions with the amygdala in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s953">Neuroscience 6t12311248.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s954">Murray, E,A., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s955">Mishkin (1985) Amygdalectomy association in monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s956">Science 228r604-606.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s957">Nauta, W.J.H., and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s958">Domesick (1981) Ramifications of the limbic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s959">In: Psychiatry and the Biology of the Human Brain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s960">(A Symposium Dedicated to Seymour S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s961">Kety).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s962">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 165-188.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s963">nuclei and fiber Nauta, W.J.H., and w.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s964">Haymaker (1969) connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s965">In W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s966">Haymaker, E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s967">Anderson, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s968">Nauta (eds): The Hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s969">Springfield, Illinois: Charles C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s970">Thomas, pp. 136209, Nauta, W.J.H., G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s971">Smith, R.L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s972">Faull, andV.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s973">Domesick (1978) Efferent connections and nigral 
    afferents of the nucleus accumbens septi in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s974">~~~~~~~i~~~~ 3:385-401, Norgren, R. (1976) Taste 
    pathways to hypothalamus Neural. 166: 17-30.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s975">Norita, M., and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s976">Kawamura (1980) Subcortical amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s977">Brain Res. 190r225-230.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s978">Ottersen, o.p., and y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s979">Ben-Ari (1979) Afferent connections to the amygdaloid 
    complex of the rat and cat. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s980">Projections from the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s981">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s982">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s983">Neurol. 187t401-424.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s984">Otterson, O.P. (1980) Afferent connections to the 
    amygdaloid complex of the rat and cat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s985">Afferents from the hypothalamus and the basal 
    telencephalon.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s986">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s987">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s988">Neurol. 194t267-289.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s989">Paxinos, G., and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s990">Bindra (1973) Hypothalamic and midbrain neural pathways 
    involved in eating, drinking, irritability, aggression and 
    copulation in rats.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s991">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s992">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s993">Physiol.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s994">Psychol. 82t1-14.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s995">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s996">Watson (1982) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s997">Ist edition.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s998">Academic Press&apos; Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s999">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates. 
    2nd edition.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1000">Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1001">Phillipson, O.T. (1979) Afferent projections to the 
    ventral tegmental area of Tsai and interfascicular nucleus: A 
    horseradish peroxidase study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1002">J&apos; Neurol&apos; 187:117-144.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1003">~ .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1004">J.L. (1981) The efferent projections of the arnygdaloid 
    complex in the rat, cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1005">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1006">Ben-Ari (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1007">Amsterdam: pp&apos; 121-132&apos; Price, JL and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1008">A m a d (1981) An autoradiographic study ofthe 
    Projections of the central nucleus of the monkey amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1009">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1010">Neurosci. 1 r1242-1259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1011">Rao, Z.R., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1012">Yamano, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1013">Shiosaka, A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1014">Shinohara, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1015">Tohyama (1987) Origin of leucine-enkephalin fibers and 
    their two main afferent pathways in the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1016">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1017">Brain Res. 65r411-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1018">Ricardo, J., and E.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1019">Koh (1978) Anatomical evidence of direct projections 
    from the nucleus of the solitary tract to the hypothalamus, 
    amygdala and other forebrain structures in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1020">Brain Res. 153r1-26.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1021">Richardson, R.T., and M.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1022">DeLong (1986) Nucleus basalis of Meynert neurenal 
    activity during a delayed response task in monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1023">Brain Res. 399r364-368.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1024">Rigdon, G.C., and J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1025">Pirch (1986) Nucleus basalis involvement in conditioned 
    neuronal responses in the rat frontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1026">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1027">Neurosci. 6t2535 2542.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1028">Rolls, E.T., M.K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1029">Sanghera, and A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1030">Roper-Hall (1979) The latency of activation of neurones 
    in the lateral hypothalamus and substantia innominata during 
    feeding in the monkey&apos; Brain 164&apos;121-135.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1031">Rolls, E.T., M.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1032">Burton, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1033">Mora (1980) Neurophysiological analysis of 
    brain-stimulation reward in the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1034">Brain Res. 194r339-357.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1035">Ross, C.A., D.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1036">Ruggiero, and D.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1037">Reis (1981) Afferent projections to cardiovascular 
    portions of the nucleus of the tractus solitarius in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1038">Brain Res. 223.402-408.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1039">Rossor, M.N., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1040">Svendsen, S.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1041">Hunt, C.Q.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1042">Mountjoy, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1043">Roth, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1044">Iversen (1982) The substantia innominata in 
    Alzheimer&apos;s disease: A histochemical and biochemical study of 
    cholinergic marker enzymes.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1045">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1046">Lett. 28217-222.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1047">Ruggiero, D.A, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1048">Mraovitch, A.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1049">Granata, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1050">Anwar, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1051">Reis (1987) A role of insular cortex in cardiovascular 
    function.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1052">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1053">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1054">Neurol. 257:189-207.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1055">Russchen, F.T. (1982) Amygdalopetal projections in the 
    cat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1056">Subcortical afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1057">A study with retrograde tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1058">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1059">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1060">Neurol. 207:157-176.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1061">Russchen, F.T., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1062">Amaral, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1063">Price (1985) The afferent connections of the suhstantia 
    innominata in the monkey, macaca fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1064">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1065">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1066">Neural. 242-27.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1067">Russchen, F.T., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1068">Amaral, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1069">Price (1987) The afferent input to the magnocellular 
    division of the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus in the monkey, macaca 
    fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1070">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1071">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1072">Neurol. 256:175-210.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1073">Rye, D.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1074">Saper, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1075">Wainer (1984a) Stabilization of the 
    tetramethylhenzidine (TMB) reaction product: Application for 
    retrograde and anterograde tracing, and combination with 
    immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1076">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1077">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1078">Cytochem. 321145-1153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1079">Rye, D.B., B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1080">Wainer, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1081">-M., Mesulam, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1082">Mufson, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1083">Saper (198415) Cortical projections arising from the 
    basal forebrain: A study of cholinergic and non-chol inergic 
    components employing combined retrograde tracing and 
    immunohistochemical localization of choline acetyltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1084">Neuroscience 13:627-644.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1085">Salamone, J.D. (1986) Behavioural functions of nucleus 
    hasalis magnocellularis and its relationship to dementia.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1086">Trends Neurosci. 9,256-258.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1087">Saper, C.B. (1984) Organization of cerebral cortical 
    afferent systems in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1088">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1089">Magnocellular basal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1090">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1091">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1092">Neurol. 222,313-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1093">Saper, C.B. (1985) Organization of cerebral cortical 
    afferent systems in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1094">Hypothalamocortical projections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1095">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1096">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1097">Neurol. 237.9-46.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1098">Saper, C.B. (1982a) Convergence of autonomic and limbic 
    connections in the insular cortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1099">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1100">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1101">Neurol. 210:163-173.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1102">Saper, C.B. (198213) Reciprocal parahrachial-cortical 
    connections in the Brain Res. 24233-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1103">Saper, C.B., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1104">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections of the parabrachial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1105">Brain Res. 197:291-317.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1106">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1107">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1108">Cowan (1976a) The efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1109">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1110">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1111">Neurol. 169:409-442.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1112">Saper, C.B., A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1113">Loewy, L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1114">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1115">Cowan, (1976h) Direct hypothalamo-autonomic 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1116">Brain Res. 117:305-312.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1117">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1118">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1119">Cowan (1979a) An autoradiographic study of the efferent 
    connections of the lateral hypothalamic area in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1120">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1121">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1122">Neurol. 183~689-706.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1123">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1124">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1125">Cowan (1979b) Some efferent connections of the rostral 
    hypothalamus in the squirrel monkey (Saimiri sciureus) and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1126">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1127">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1128">Neurol. 184.205-242.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1129">Schwaber, J.S., B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1130">Kapp, G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1131">Higgins, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1132">Rapp (1982) Amygdaloid and basal forebrain direct 
    connections with the nucleus of the solitary tract and the dorsal 
    motor nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1133">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1134">Neurosci. 21424-1438.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1135">Schwaber J.S., W.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1136">Rogers, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1137">Satoh, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1138">Fibiger (1987) Distribution and organization of 
    cholinergic neurons in the rat forebrain demonstrated by 
    computer-aided data acquisition and three-dimensional 
    reconstruction.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1139">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1140">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1141">Neurol. 263:309-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1142">Shimada, S., S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1143">Shiosaka, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1144">Takami, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1145">Yamano, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1146">Tohyama (1985) Somatostatinergic neurons in the insular 
    cortex project to the spinal cord: Combined retrograde axonal 
    transport and immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1147">Brain Res. 326:197-200.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1148">Shipley, M.T. (1982) Insular cortex projection to the 
    nucleus of the solitary tract and brainstem visceromotor regions in 
    the mouse.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1149">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1150">Bull. 8:138-148.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1151">Swanson, L.W. (1976) An autoradiographic study of the 
    efferent connections of the preoptic region in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1152">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1153">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1154">Neurol. 167:227-256.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1155">Swanson, L.W., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1156">Mogenson, C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1157">Gerfen, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1158">Robinson (1984) Evidence for a projection from the 
    lateral preoptic area and substantia innominata to the Res. 
    295:161-178.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1159">Switzer, R.C., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1160">Hill, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1161">Heimer (1982) The globus pallidus and its rostroventral 
    extension into the olfactory tubercle ofthe rat: A cytoa.nd 
    chemoarchitectural study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1162">Neuroscience 7:1891-1904.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1163">Switzer, R.C., J. de Olmos, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1164">Heimer (1985) Olfactory system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1165">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1166">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1167">Vol. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1168">Australia: Academic Press, pp. 1-36.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1169">Terreherry, R.R., and E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1170">Neafsey (1983) Rat medial frontal cortex: A visceral 
    motor region with a direct projection to the solitary nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1171">Brain Res. 278245-249.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1172">Turner, B., and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1173">Herkenham (1981) An autoradiographic study of 
    thalanioamygdaloid connections in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1174">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1175">Rec. 199;260A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1176">Turner, B.H., M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1177">Mishkin, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1178">Knapp (1980) Organization of the amygdalopetal 
    projections from modality-specific cortical association areas in 
    the monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1179">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1180">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1181">Neurol. 191:515-543.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1182">Van der Kooy, D., J.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1183">McGinty, L.Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1184">Koda, C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1185">Gerfen, and F.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1186">Bloom (1982) Visceral cortex: Direct projections from 
    prefrontal cortex to the solitary nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1187">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1188">Rec. 202195A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1189">Veening, J.G. (1978) Suhcortical afferents of the 
    amygdaloid complex in the rat: An HRP study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1190">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1191">Lett. 8:197-202.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1192">Veening, J.G., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1193">Swanson, and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1194">Sawchenko (1984) The organization of projections from 
    the central nucleus of the amygdala to brainstem sites involved in 
    central autonomic regulation: A combined retrograde 
    transport-immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1195">Brain Res. 303;337-357.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1196">Woodhams, P.L., G.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1197">Roberts, J.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1198">Polak, and T.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1199">Crow (1983) Distribution of neuropeptides in the limbic 
    system of the rat: The bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, septum 
    and preoptic area.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1200">Neuroscience 8:677-703.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1201">Woolf, N.J. and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1202">Butcher (1982) Cholinergic projections to the 
    basolatera1 amygdala: A combined Evans Blue and 
    acetylcholinesterase analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1203">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1204">Bull. 8:751-763.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1205">Wouterlood, F.G., and H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1206">Groenwegen (1985) Neuroanatomical tracing by use of 
    Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L): Electron microscopy of 
    PHA-L filled neuronal somata, dendrites, axons and axon 
    terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1207">Brain Res. 326: 188-191.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1208">Young, W.S., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1209">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1210">Heimer (1984) The ventral pallidal projection to the 
    mediodorsal thalamus: A study with fluorescent retrograde tracers 
    and immunohistofluorescence.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1211">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1212">Neurosci. 4:1626-1638.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1213">Zaborszky, L., C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1214">Leranth, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1215">Heimer (1984) Ultrastructural evidence of amygdalofugal 
    axons terminating on cholinergic cells of the rostral forebrain.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1216">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1217">Lett. 52219-225.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1218">Zaborszky, L., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1219">Heimer, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1220">Eckenstein, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1221">Leranth (1986a) GABAergic input to cholinergic 
    forebrain neurons: An ultrastructural study using retrograde 
    tracing of HRP and double immunolabelling.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1222">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1223">Camp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1224">Neilrol. 250;282-295.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1225">Zaborszky, L., V.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1226">Luine, D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1227">Allen, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1228">Snavel, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1229">Heimer (198611) Biochemical changes in the cholinergic 
    forebrain system following trarisection of ascending brainstem 
    fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1230">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1231">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1232">Abstr. 12:571.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1233">Zaborszky, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1234">Alheid, V.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1235">Alones, W.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1236">Oertel, D.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1237">Schmeckel, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1238">Heimer (1982) Afferents of the ventral pallidum studied 
    with a combined immunohistochemical-anterograde degeneration 
    method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1239">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1240">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1241">Abstr. 8,218.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1242">Zahorszky, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1243">Alheid, M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1244">Beinfeld, L.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1245">Eiden, L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1246">Heimer, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1247">Palkovits (1985) Cholecystokinin innervation of the 
    ventral striatum: I\ morphological and radioimmunological study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1248">Neuroscience 14:427-453.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1249">Zahm, D.S., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1250">Zaborszky, G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1251">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1252">Heimer (1987) The ventral striatopallidothalamic 
    projection: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1253">The ventral pallidothalamic link, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1254">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1255">Neural. 255t592-605.</S>
  </References>

</File>

