<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE File PUBLIC "NeuroScholar.DTD" "NeuroScholar.DTD">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="NeuroScholar.css"?>
<File>

  <Title>Efferent Connections of the Substantia Innominata in the 
  Rat</Title>

  <Authors>ELIZABETH A. GROVE</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The efferent connections of the substantia innominata (SI) 
    were investigated employing the anterograde axonal transport of 
    Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) and the retrograde 
    transport of wheat germ agglutinin conjugated to horseradish 
    peroxidase (WGA-HRP).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">The projections of the SI largely reciprocate the afferent 
    connections described by Grove (J Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">NeuroL 277:315-346, &apos;88) and thus further distinguish 
    a dorsal and a ventral division in the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Efferents from both the dorsal and ventral divisions of 
    the SI descend as far caudal as the ventral tegmental area, 
    substantia nigra, and peripeduncular area, but projections to 
    pontine and medullary structures appear to originate mainly from 
    the dorsal SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Within the amygdala and hypothalamus, which receive 
    widespread innervation from the SI, the dorsal SI projects 
    preferentially to the lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis; the lateral, basolateral, and central nuclei of the 
    amygdala; the lateral preoptic area; paraventricular nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus; and certain parts of the lateral hypothalamus, 
    prominently including the perifornical and caudolateral zones 
    described previously.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The ventral SI projects more heavily to the medial part of 
    the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis; the anterior amygdaloid 
    area; a ventromedial amygdaloid region that includes but is not 
    limited to the medial nucleus; the lateral and medial preoptic 
    areas; and the anterior hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Modest projections reach the lateral hypothalamus, with at 
    least a slight preference for the medial part of the region, and 
    the ventromedial and arcuate hypothalamic nuclei.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Both SI divisions appear to innervate the dorsomedial and 
    posterior hypothalamus and the supramammillary region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">In the thalamus, the subparafascicular, gustatory, and 
    midline nuclei receive a light innervation from the SI, which 
    projects more densely to the medial part of the mediodorsal nucleus 
    and the reticular nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">Cortical efferents from at least the midrostrocaudal part 
    of the SI are distributed primarily in piriform, infralimbic, 
    prelimbic, anterior cingulate, granular and agranular insular, 
    perirhinal, and entorhinal cortices as well as in the main and 
    accessory olfactory bulbs.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The cells of origin for many projections arising from the 
    SI were identified as cholinergic or noncholinergic by combining 
    the retrograde transport of WGA-HRP with histochemical and 
    immunohistochemical procedures to demonstrate acetylcholinesterase 
    activity or choline acetyltransferase immunoreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Most of the descending efferents of the SI appear to 
    arise primarily or exclusively from noncholinergic cells.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Overall, the subcortical projections of the dorsal 
    division of the SI were found to be strikingly reminiscent of those 
    reported previously for two adjoining structures: the lateral part 
    of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and the central nucleus 
    of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">A second tissue continuum with common subcortical 
    efferents appears to be formed by the medial part of the bed 
    nucleus, ventral SI, and the rostra1 parts of both the medial 
    nucleus of the amygdala and an amygdaloid region that lies ventral 
    to the central nucleus and dorsal to the cortical nuclei (Krettek 
    and Price: J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">Neurol. 178:225-254, &apos;78; Price and Amaral: J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">Neurosci. 1:1242-1359, &apos;81; Holstege et al.: Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s18">Brain Res. 58:379-391, &apos;85; Grove: J.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s19">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">Neurol. 277:315-346, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The substantia innominata (SI) is an amorphous region of 
    the mammalian basal forebrain that stretches along the ventral 
    aspect of the corpus striatum.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">An extension of the globus pallidus (GP), the ventral 
    pallidum (VP) of Heirner and Wilson (&apos;754 has been shown to 
    occupy roughly the rostra1 third of the region as historically 
    defined (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75; Switzer et al., &apos;82; 
    Haber and Nauta, &apos;83), and the term &quot;substantia 
    innominata&quot; is now generally reserved for the area caudal to 
    the VP (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;82, &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The connectivity of this comparatively poorly 
    characterized basal forebrain district is the subject of the 
    present pair of companion studies.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The first of these two studies showed that the afferent 
    connections of the SI strongly resemble those of the amygdala and 
    that innervation is provided by widespread cell groups in many of 
    the main subdivisions of the brain (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">Further, the distribution of fibers afferent to the SI 
    (de Olmos, &apos;72; de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Grove, &apos;88) 
    and of certain neurochemical and histochemical markers (de Olmos, 
    &apos;72; de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Lind et al., &apos;85; Grove, 
    &apos;88) indicates that the SI, which appears uniform in material 
    stained to reveal Nissl substance or myelin, is in fact organized 
    into a dorsal and a ventral division.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">To date, the efferent connections of the SI have not been 
    examined in a single comprehensive study, nor have previous 
    investigations noted whether projections with different targets 
    arise from different subregions within the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">Of the known projections of the SI, those to the amygdala 
    and cerebral cortex, originating from both cholinergic and 
    noncholinergic neurons, have received the greatest recent attention 
    (Lehmann et al., &apos;80; Big1 et al., &apos;82; Woolf and 
    Butcher, &apos;82; Grove et al., &apos;83; McKinney et al., 
    &apos;83; Mesulam et al., &apos;83a,b; Rye et al., &apos;84b; 
    Saper, &apos;84; Carlsen et al., &apos;85; Luiten et al., &apos;85, 
    &apos;87; Fisher et al., &apos;86; Woolf et al., &apos;86).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">Subcortical projections from the SI have been suggested 
    in retrograde tracing studies of the afferent connections of 
    several structures. including the thalamus (Young et al., &apos;84; 
    Levey et al., &apos;87; Russchen et al., &apos;871, ventra&apos;i 
    tegmental area Phillipson, &apos;79), and dorsomedial medulla 
    (Schwaber et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">Finally, efferents from the VP and adjacent SI to the 
    hypothalamus, midbrain, and pons have been identified with both 
    electrophysiological and anterograde tracing techniques (Swanson et 
    al., &apos;84; Haber et al., &apos;85; Mogenson et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">Because much information regarding the efferent 
    connections of the SI is still lacking, it is unclear how, or 
    whether, the well-known cholinergic and noncholinergic projections 
    from the SI to the cortex and amygdala are integrated into a more 
    comprehensive set of the region&apos;s efferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Indeed, it might be suggested that the cholinergic cells 
    in the SI represent an invading cell population, also distributed 
    in the GP, nucleus of the diagonal band, and medial septum, a 
    population whose connections could be unrelated to those of the SI 
    as a whole.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">However, some evidence suggests that the cholinergic cell 
    group may participate in the afferent circuitry of other neurons in 
    the SI (for review see Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Thus, the direct and indirect involvement of this cell 
    group in the other efferent connections of the SI is worth further 
    investigation.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">In the present study, both the cortical and subcortical 
    projections of the SI were investigated, employing the anterograde 
    axonal transport of PHA-L (Gerfen and Sawchenko, &apos;84) and the 
    retrograde transport of WGA-HRP.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The cells of origin for many projections arising from the 
    SI were further identified as cholinergic or noncholinergic by 
    combining the retrograde transport of WGA-HRP with histochemical 
    and immunohistochemical procedures to locate acetylcholinesterase 
    activity or choline acetyltransferase immunoreactivity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Findings from the present study suggested three main 
    generalizations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">First, the projections of the SI generally reciprocate 
    the afferent connections described by Grove (&apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">As a consequence, a dorsal and a ventral division can be 
    distinguished within the SI on the basis of both afferent and 
    efferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s39">Second, the efferent projections of the SI, like its 
    afferent connections, strongly resemble those of neighboring 
    components of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">This similarity embraces not only efferents to caudal 
    brainstem sites as previously reported (Schwaber et al., &apos;82; 
    Holstege et al., &apos;85) but appears to incorporate virtually the 
    entire set of SI projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Third, cholinergic cells in the SI do not seem to 
    contribute significantly to most of the descending efferents of the 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">Nonetheless, several observations indicate that the 
    cholinergic cell group in the SI may play an integral part in the 
    overall efferent circuitry of the region rather than maintaining a 
    wholly distinct set of projections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">For example, findings described below suggest that 
    several noncholinergic projections from the SI lead indirectly over 
    their subcortical targets to the cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">If so, the region&apos;s cholinergic corticopetal 
    efferents may be viewed as part of a set of direct and indirect 
    pathways leading - to the cortical mantle.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s45">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">For all experiments in the present study, adult female 
    albino rats (CD strain) were obtained from Charles River 
    Laboratories.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">During surgical procedures and before transcardial 
    perfusion of fixatives the animals were deeply anesthetized with 
    Chloropent, a veterinary anesthetic containing chloral hydrate and 
    pentobarbital (obtained previously from Ft.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Dodge Labs, but no longer available from this source).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s49">Anterograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">In nine rats, PHA-L deposits were placed either in the 91 
    or in the nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal band 
    (NHDB) (cases RPSI1-3 and RPDB1-6).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Additionally available for comparison were eight cases 
    described in a previous report (Grove, &apos;88) in which PHA-L 
    deposits had been made adjacent to the SI in the bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis (cases RPBNS2, RPGP4) and amygdala (cases RPAA1, 
    RPAB1, RPACE8, RPBLS, RPBM1, RPBM3) (Grove, &apos;88, Figs. 8, 
    9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">PHA-L, obtained from Vector Labs, was reconstituted and 
    injected into the brain as previously described (Grove, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">After 4-8 days, the rats were perfused transcardially 
    with 50 ml of saline, followed by fixative (up to 500 ml in 15-20 
    minutes) consisting of 2% paraformaldehyde and 0.1% glutaraldehyde 
    in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">The brains were stored in phosphate buffer, and sectioned 
    at 50 pm into six series with an Oxford Vibratome.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">PHA-L was then localized in two series of sections from 
    each brain with a peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) procedure (Grove, 
    &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">One of the two series stained for PHA-L was 
    counterstained with Cresyl Violet.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">A third series from each brain was processed to reveal 
    both PHA-L and choline acetyltransferase (ChAT) in the same 
    sections, and a fourth was processed to locate met-enkephalin 
    immunoreactivity (ENK-IR) (see Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Rabbit anti-ENK antiserum was donated by Dr.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">R.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Elde.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s61">Retrograde tracing 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">In a total of 30 animals, injections of wheat germ 
    agglutinin conjugated to horseradish peroxidase (WGA-HRP) were 
    centered in the nucleus accumbens, amygdala, lateral hypothalamus, 
    mediodorsal nucleus of the thalamus, habenular nucleus, substantia 
    nigra, ventral tegmental area, peripeduncular area, dorsal raphe, 
    parabrachial nucleus, dorsomedial medulla, or neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">Several of these injection sites are illustrated in 
    Figure 7.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">WGA-HRP (Sigma) was prepared and injected into the brain 
    as described previously (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Twenty-four to 72 hours after surgery the animals were 
    perfused transcardially with 50 ml saline, followed by 500 ml of 2% 
    paraformaldehyde and 0.1% glutaraldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, 
    pH 7.4, and a final rinse of 100 ml3% sucrose in the same 
    buffer.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">After rinsing overnight in a 30% sucrose solution made up 
    in phosphate buffer, the brains were cut on a freezing microtome 
    into six series of 50-pm-thick transverse sections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">Two standard procedures were employed to demonstrate HRP 
    with tetramethylbemidine (TMB) as the chromagen (Mesulam, &apos;78; 
    de Olmos et al., &apos;78).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">At least two of the six series of sections from each 
    brain were processed to locate both WGA-HRP and a cholinergic 
    marker: acetylcholinesterase (AChE) activity in one series and 
    choline acetyltransferase (ChAT) immunoreactivity in the other.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">Intense AChE reactivity seen after pretreating animals 
    with diisopropylfluorophosphate (DFP) is considered a reliable 
    marker of cholinergic neurons in the GP, SI, and diagonal 
    band-medial septum continuum (Levey et al., &apos;83; Eckenstein 
    and Sofroniew, &apos;83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Accordingly, 4-6 hours before perfusion, the rats were 
    injected intramuscularly with DFP (1 mgkg) (Calbiochem) dissolved 
    in peanut oil.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Sections to be double-labelled were processed to locate 
    WGA-HRP with the TMB technique of de Olmos et al. (&apos;781, and 
    the TMB reaction product was stabilized to prevent fading (Rye et 
    al., &apos;84a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Next, tissue sections were treated to reveal either AChE 
    activity (Geneser-Jensen and Blackstad, &apos;71) or ChAT 
    immunoreactivity (following the same PAP procedure described by 
    Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">From each brain, control sections were prepared to 
    demonstrate AChE activity or ChAT immunoreactivity alone.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">Tissue sections processed only for WGA-HRP were 
    counterstained with Neutral Red.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Two additional, unoperated rats were perfused 
    transcardially, following the fixation procedure described by 
    Baughman, Eckenstein, and their colleagues (see Graybiel et al., 
    &apos;86) to optimize staining for ChAT-IR fibers and their 
    terminals within the basal forebrain.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="27" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s76">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s77">Cortical and subcortical 
    projections of the substantia innominata</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Case RPSI3.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s79">In case RPSI3, <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> deposit was centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      dorsal SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> but intruded into 
      <injectionSpread>the ventral division</injectionSpread> as well ( 
      Fig .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s80">I).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s81">The injection site did not spread into 
      <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the amygdala</injectionSpread> , which 
      is laterally contiguous with the SI .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s82">About half of the <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> deposit lay in <injectionLocation>the most 
      dorsal part of the SI</injectionLocation> , which , like the 
      overlying GP , is marked by the presence of an enkephalin 
      immunoreactive &quot; woolly fiber &quot; plexus ( Grove , &apos; 
      88 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s83">However , PHA - L did not appear to have been taken up 
      by cells lying dorsal to the SI in <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the 
      GP</injectionSpread> itself or by neurons in 
      <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the VP</injectionSpread> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s84">Criteria used to delineate <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      SI</neuroanatomicalLocation> from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
      adjacent GP and VP</neuroanatomicalLocation> are discussed more 
      fully in Grove ( &apos; 88 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s85">Briefly , <neuroanatomicalLocation>the border between 
      the SI and GP</neuroanatomicalLocation> , marked by a dotted line 
      in Figure 1, was drawn with reference to the dorsalmost extent of 
      <labelingDescription>a dense band of ansa peduncularis 
      fibers</labelingDescription>  , whose passage characterizes 
      <neuroanatomicalLocation>the SI</neuroanatomicalLocation> ( Grove 
      , &apos; 88 ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s86">Figure 1 illustrates the distribution of 
      <labelingDescription>PHA - L - labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> in this case .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s87"><labelingDescription>Labelled axons displaying en 
      passant and terminal varicosities</labelingDescription> ( 
      putative synaptic boutons ) were found in numerous structures 
      whose common characteristic is their position along 
      <labelingLocation>the course of the ansa peduncularis ( AP ) or 
      medial forebrain bundle ( MFB )</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s88">To reach <labelingLocation>the 
      cortex</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> followed the AP or traveled in 
      <labelingLocation>the internal capsule</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s89">Most <labelingDescription>cortical fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was confined to areas surrounding 
      or ventral to the rhinal sulcus : <labelingLocation>piriform 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1B - F ) , 
      <labelingLocation>agranular and granular insular 
      cortices</labelingLocation> ( divisions according to Paxinos and 
      Watson , &apos; 86 ) ( Fig . 1A - C ) , and 
      <labelingLocation>perirhinal and entorhinal 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1D - G ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s90">However , at levels rostral to the genu of the corpus 
      callosum ( Fig . lA ) , <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> also appeared along the 
      medial face of the hemisphere <labelingLocation>in prelimbic , 
      infralimbic , and rostral cingulate cortex</labelingLocation> ( 
      divisions according to Beckstead , &apos; 79 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s91">Farther rostrally still , such 
      <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> extended into 
      <labelingLocation>the olfactory bulb</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s92">In the amygdala , <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> spread out widely .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s93">From the injection site , <labelingDescription>labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>streamed 
      through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the dorsal and 
      ventral SI</labelingLocation> into <labelingLocation>the rostral 
      portion of the central nucleus ( Ace ) and the anterior 
      amygdaloid area</labelingLocation> , only 
      <labelingModifier>avoiding</labelingModifier>  <labelingLocation>
      the nucleus of the lateral olfactory tract</labelingLocation> ( 
      NLOT ) ( Fig . 1C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s94"><labelingDescription>Numerous labelled varicose 
      axons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial segment of the central nucleus</labelingLocation> and 
      in<labelingLocation> a region ventral to Ace</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . lD , E ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s95"><labelingDescription>Additional 
      fibers</labelingDescription> 
      <labelingModifier>crossed</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral Ace</labelingLocation> , displaying 
      <labelingDescription>few terminal 
      varicosities</labelingDescription> , to reach <labelingLocation>
      the basolateral nucleus ( ABL ) and lateral nucleus ( AL 
      )</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>where moderate to 
      dense terminal fields</labelingDescription> were apparent ( Fig . 
      1D - F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s96"><labelingLocation>The medial and cortical 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> contained <labelingDescription>only 
      sparse fiber labelling</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 1D - F ) 
      .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s97">Rostromedially directed fibers spread into 
      <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis ( BNS 
      )</labelingLocation> , distributing almost entirely in its 
      lateral sector ( divisions according to Paxinos and Watson , 
      &apos; 82 ) ( Fig . 1B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s98"><labelingDescription>A few axons</labelingDescription> 
      reaching more laterally <labelingDescription>traversed and 
      terminated</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral pallidum and ventralmost striatum</labelingLocation> or 
      coursed in and around <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the 
      horizontal limb of the diagonal band</labelingLocation> ( Fig 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s99">lB,C).</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s100">In <labelingLocation>the 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , fibers spread into 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral preoptic area</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . lB ) , <labelingLocation>anterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1C , D ) , 
      <labelingLocation>paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . lD ) , and <labelingLocation>lateral ( Fig . lC - F ) , 
      dorsal , and posterior hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1F 
      ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s101">Although <labelingDescription>fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was widespread in 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , 
      concentrations of <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled varicose 
      axons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>a 
      perifornical zone of the lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . lE ) , largely lateral and dorsal to the fornix ; in 
      <labelingLocation>a triangular , caudolateral zone adjacent to 
      the subthalamic nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1F ) ; and in 
      <labelingLocation>a district ventral to the 
      fornix</labelingLocation> ( Fig . lE , F ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s102">Some <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> followed the ansa peduncularis 
      dorsally from the hypothalamus into thalamic structures close to 
      the midline .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s103">Thus , at least <labelingDescription>sparse varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled 
      <labelingModifier>traversing</labelingModifier> 
      <labelingLocation>the reuniens , rhomboid , and centromedial 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> ( Fig . lD , E ) , and 
      <labelingDescription>a denser terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> was evident in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial part of the mediodorsal nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      1D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s104">In <labelingDescription>the lateral habenula labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> formed small puffs in both 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral and medial parts of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s105"><labelingDescription>Several 
      axons</labelingDescription> were also labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>a region transitional between the midline 
      thalamus and the central gray of the midbrain</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 1F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s106">Elsewhere in the thalamus , PHA - L - filled 
      <labelingDescription>varicose axons</labelingDescription> 
      appeared in <labelingLocation>the reticular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 1C - E ) , in the region 
      termed the gustatory nucleus by Paxinos and Watson ( 86 ) , and 
      just ventral to that in what may be <labelingLocation>the rostra1 
      tip of the parvocellular portion of the subparafascicular 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Grove , 88 ) ( Fig . 1F ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s107">(The structure labelled %pf in Fig. 1F is the 
      magnocellular part of the same nucleus.)</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s108"><labelingDescription>A moderate number of both smooth 
      and varicose PHA - Lfilled fibers</labelingDescription> could be 
      traced along <labelingLocation>the bifurcating route of the 
      medial forebrain bundle through the midbrain and 
      pons</labelingLocation> , appearing in <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral tegmental area , linear nucleus of the raphe , substantia 
      nigra pars compacta , peripeduncular area ( Fig . lG ) , pontine 
      tegmentum</labelingLocation>  ( including 
      <labelingDescription>sparse varicose fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> within <labelingLocation>
      cholinergic cell group Ch5 of Mesulam and his colleagues , 83b ) 
      , central gray , and dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 1H ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s109">More caudally , <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> were evident in 
      <labelingLocation>both the medial and lateral segments of the 
      parabrachial nucleus</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>
      the locus coeruleus and subcoeruleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      11 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s110">Perhaps because of a relatively short postinjection 
      survival time , <labelingDescription>few labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> could be followed caudal to the pons 
      in this case : only <labelingDescription>one or two labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      region of the nucleus of the solitary tract and dorsal motor 
      nucleus of the vagus</labelingLocation> .</S>
    </TTE>

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">Case RPSI2.</S>
    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s112">In a contrasting case , RPSIZ , <exptLabel>an 
      injection of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> was 
      centered in <injectionLocation>the ventral division of the SI , 
      intruding into the dorsal SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , 
      but not into the dorsalmost portion that is pervaded by ENK - IR 
      woolly fibers and not spreading ventrally into 
      <injectionSpread yesNo="0">the nucleus of the horizontal limb of 
      the diagonal band</injectionSpread> ( Fig . 1, bottom panel ) 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s113"><labelingDescription>Axon 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was evident in <labelingLocation>
      the same caudal brainstem regions</labelingLocation> as in case 
      RPSI3 but appeared <labelingDescription>only very 
      sparsely</labelingDescription> caudal to <labelingLocation>the 
      ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s114"><labelingDescription>In cortical structures fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was primarily confined to 
      <labelingLocation>the entorhinal and piriform 
      cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig .</S>
      <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s115">ZB-IS).</S>
      <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s116"><labelingDescription>Sparse 
      labelling</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      main olfactory bulb</labelingLocation> , and , unlike case RPSIS 
      , <labelingDescription>a few PHA - L - filled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> could also be traced to 
      <labelingLocation>the accessory olfactory bulb ( AOB 
      )</labelingLocation> , where <labelingDescription>varicose 
      axons</labelingDescription> were identified in <labelingLocation>
      the granule cell layer</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2A ) .</S>
      <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s117">The last finding appears consistent with previous 
      observations by de Olmos and Beltramino (cited in de Olmos et 
      al., 851.</S>
      <S avgH="20" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s118">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> , 
      by contrast with case RPSIS , <labelingDescription>very little 
      fiber labelling</labelingDescription> was found in 
      <labelingLocation>the basolateral or lateral 
      nu</labelingLocation> de Olmos and Beltramino noted that neurons 
      retrogradely labelled from <labelingLocation>the AOB did not fill 
      the entire SI</labelingLocation> but were confined to 
      <labelingLocation>a band of tissue linking the medial nucleus of 
      the amygdala with the medial part of the BNS</labelingLocation> 
      .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s119">clei.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s120">In <labelingLocation>the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>significant 
      numbers of PHA - Lfilled axons</labelingDescription> appeared 
      only at its outer rim ( Fig . 2C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s121"><labelingDescription>Varicose fiber labelling was far 
      more profuse</labelingDescription> , however , in 
      <labelingLocation>a large ventromedial sector of the 
      amygdala</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s122">Numerous <labelingDescription>labelled 
      axons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      anterior amygdaloid area</labelingLocation> and in a region that 
      lies ventral to <labelingLocation>the central nucleus , lateral 
      to the medial nucleus and dorsal to the cortical 
      nuclei</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s123">Most of this latter region has been left unlabelled in 
      the present pair of studies (see Grove, 88).</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s124">It appears to include a district designated 
      <labelingLocation>the intraamygdaloid division of the bed nucleus 
      of the stria terminalis by Paxinos and Watson ( 86 ) , and the 
      anterior part of the basomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> as 
      identified in the rat by other authors ( Krettek and Price , 78b 
      ; de Olmos et al . , 85 ; Paxinos and Watson , 86 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s125">More caudally , varicose axon labelling continued into 
      <labelingLocation>the amygdalohippocampal area and the posterior 
      part of the basomedial nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2D ) 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s126"><labelingDescription>Additional moderately dense fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> could be seen in <labelingLocation>
      the rostral part of the medial nucleus</labelingLocation> , 
      diminishing caudally ( Fig . 2C ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s127"><labelingDescription>A small number of PHA - L - 
      filled varicose axons</labelingDescription> entered 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the lateral olfactory tract and 
      the cortical amygdaloid nuclei</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C , D 
      ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s128">A further marked contrast with case RPSIS was evident 
      in <labelingLocation>the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s129"><labelingDescription>Many PHA - Lfilled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>medial 
      and intermediate districts of the BNS</labelingLocation> , but 
      few in <labelingLocation>the most lateral part of the 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s130"><labelingDescription>Additional 
      fibers</labelingDescription> reached dorsal to the BNS into 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral septum</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      2B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s131">In <labelingLocation>the rostral SI</labelingLocation> 
      , <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      axons</labelingDescription> occupied <labelingLocation>a 
      relatively ventral position</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s132">As in case RPSIS , however , only 
      <labelingDescription>a few labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> spread into <labelingLocation>the 
      horizontal limb of the diagonal band</labelingLocation> , and 
      still fewer in <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the vertical 
      limb</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s133">Rather more <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> coursed around <labelingLocation>the 
      NHDB</labelingLocation> , particularly ventrally , close to the 
      base of the brain ( Fig . 2B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s134"><tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> deposits in 
      <injectionLocation>the NHDB</injectionLocation> itself ( for 
      example , cases RPDBl and RPDB5, Fig . 1 ) filled cell bodies and 
      dendrites within <labelingLocation>this 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> and disclosed that the dendrites of 
      NHDB neurons may sometimes extend almost to the ventral surface 
      of the brain .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s135">Thus, axon terminals ventral to the NHDB proper could, 
      nonetheless, potentially provide innervation to cells within that 
      nucleus.</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s136"><labelingDescription>Denser axon 
      labelling</labelingDescription> than in case RPSIS was evident in 
      <labelingLocation>several parts of the medial 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s137">This was most prominent in <labelingLocation>the 
      medial preoptic area and anterior hypothalamus</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 2B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s138">However , <labelingDescription>a few PHA - L - filled 
      sons</labelingDescription> entered <labelingLocation>the 
      ventromedial and arcuate nuclei</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C , D 
      ) , which were unlabelled in case RPSIS .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s139"><labelingDescription>Denser fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> than was seen in the previous 
      case was also evident in <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s140">By contrast , several hypothalamic regions that 
      contained <labelingDescription>many PHA - L - filled 
      axons</labelingDescription> in case RPSI3 were comparatively 
      <labelingDescription>sparsely labelled here</labelingDescription> 
      .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s141"><labelingDescription>Only sporadic labelled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> could be identified in 
      <labelingLocation>the paraventricular nucleus</labelingLocation> 
      , although axon labelling appeared around and especially dorsal 
      to this nucleus .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s142">In <labelingLocation>the lateral preoptic area and 
      lateral hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , 
      <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> spread out diffusely , 
      <labelingModifier>without apparent 
      concentrations</labelingModifier> in <labelingLocation>the 
      perifornical or caudolateral zones</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2B 
      - D ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s143">As in case RPSI3, however , <labelingDescription>PHA - 
      L - filled fibers</labelingDescription> reached through 
      <labelingLocation>the dorsal and posterior 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C , D ) , to course 
      along <labelingLocation>the midline thalamus</labelingLocation> 
      into <labelingLocation>the medial part of the mediodorsal 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 2C , D ) .</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">Cases RPDBI and RPDBS.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Like the region referred to here as the SI , 
    <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the horizontal limb of the 
    diagonal band contains cholinergic perikarya</labelingLocation> and 
    is traversed by fibers of the ansa peduncularis .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">Nonetheless , the NHDB is not conventionally included as 
    part of the SI in the rat ( Paxinos and Watson , &apos; 82, &apos; 
    86 ) .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">A thorough determination of the efferent connections of 
    the NHDB was not attempted in the present study, since the nucleus 
    is composed of several subdivisions (Zaborszky et al., &apos;86a), 
    not all of which were injected with PaA-L.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">Available cases ( RPDB1 - RPDBG ) allowed , however , 
    some comparisons of the efferent connections of <connxOrigin>the 
    NHDB and the overlying SI amygdala , hypothalamus , and cauda . 1 
    with the cortex , brainstem</connxOrigin> .</S>
    <BR />

    <TTE>

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s149">In the case that displayed the most dense and 
      widespread fiber labelling ( RPDBl ) , <exptLabel>a large deposit 
      of <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> was centered in 
      <injectionLocation>the NHDB but spread into parts of the VP and 
      rostra1 SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> as well ( Fig . 1, 
      bottom panel ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s150">Several marked differences between RPDBl and previous 
      cases appear, however, to be attributable to the involvement of 
      the NHDH in the injection site.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s151">The general distribution of 
      <labelingDescription>labelled fibers</labelingDescription> in 
      case RPDBl accorded quite well with that reported by Domesick ( 
      &apos; 76 ) following <tracerChemical>tritiated amino 
      acid</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation>the 
      NHDB</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s152">In <labelingLocation>the amygdala</labelingLocation> , 
      by contrast with cases RPSI2 and RPSI3, <labelingDescription>a 
      profusion of PHA - L - filled fibers</labelingDescription> 
      distinguished the nucleus of <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      olfactory tract</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3A ) and 
      <labelingLocation>the posterolateral cortical 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s153"><labelingDescription>More modest fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
      anterior amygdaloid area , the anterior cortical , posteromedial 
      cortical , and medial nuclei</labelingLocation> , and in  
      <labelingLocation>the amygdaloid region that lies dorsal to the 
      cortical nuclei and ventral to the central 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3A , B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s154">In addition , <labelingDescription>a patch of richly 
      varicose fibers</labelingDescription> was labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventromedial portion of the basolateral 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s155">However , such labelling may have been due to the 
      spread of the <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> deposit 
      into <injectionLocation>the rostral SI and ventral 
      pallidum</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s156">Consistent with this possibility , retrograde tracer 
      injections confined to <injectionLocation>the basolateral 
      nucleus</injectionLocation> fail to fill many cells in 
      <labelingLocation>the NHDB</labelingLocation> ( Carlsen et al . , 
      85, and see below ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s157">Further , no <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled 
      axons</labelingDescription> appeared in the basolateral nucleus 
      when a small PHA - L deposit was confined to the NHDB ( case 
      RPDB5, Fig . 1, bottom panel ) .</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s158">Suggesting a possible topographical organization in 
      the projection from the SI to the basolateral nucleus , it is 
      worth noting that a <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
      deposit in <injectionLocation>the midcaudal 
      SI</injectionLocation> ( case RPSI3, above ) 
      <labelingDescription>labelled axons most 
      densely</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      part of the basolateral nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s159"><labelingDescription>Sparse to moderate axon 
      labelling</labelingDescription> appeared in both <labelingLocation>
      the lateral and medial segments of the bed nucleus of the stria 
      terminalis</labelingLocation> and in <labelingLocation>the 
      lateral , dorsal , and posterior hypothalamus</labelingLocation> 
      ( Fig . 3A , B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s160">Within <labelingLocation>the lateral 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>PHA - L - 
      filled axons</labelingDescription> , both smooth and varicose , 
      filled a triangular region medial to the zone marked in case 
      RPSI3 ( compare Figs . 1F and 3B ) .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s161"><labelingDescription>A much larger labelled fiber 
      contingent</labelingDescription> than in case RPSI2 ( ventral SI 
      ) reached caudal to the diencephalon .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s162">Many <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled smooth and 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> were evident in 
      <labelingLocation>the ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> ( 
      Fig . 3C ) and elsewhere along <labelingLocation>the route of the 
      medial forebrain bundle through the midbrain and 
      pons</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s163">It cannot be discounted that some of this labelling - 
      for example , part or all of that seen in <labelingLocation>the 
      substantia nigra , pars compacta</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      3Cbwas due to the involvement of <injectionSpread>the ventral 
      pallidum or rostral SI</injectionSpread> in the 
      <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> injection site .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s164">In <labelingLocation>the pons</labelingLocation> , 
      however , the distribution of <labelingDescription>fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was strikingly different from 
      that seen in previous cases and seems likely to have resulted 
      from PHAL transport from the NHDB .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s165"><labelingDescription>Varicose 
      axons</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>
      the median , as well as dorsal , raphe</labelingLocation> , and 
      in <labelingLocation>the laterodorsal tegmental 
      nucleus</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3D ) , but 
      <labelingModifier>none were labelled</labelingModifier> in 
      <labelingLocation>the parabrachial nucleus or locus 
      coeruleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s166">Finally , <labelingDescription>cortical 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was observed in <labelingLocation>
      the olfactory bulb and piriform cortex</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 
      3A , B ) , which contained <labelingDescription>numerous labelled 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> , and in <labelingLocation>
      infralimbic and entorhinal cortex</labelingLocation> where 
      <labelingDescription>lighter fiber 
      labelling</labelingDescription> was evident .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
       format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s167">Local connections 
      within <neuroanatomicalLocation>the SI</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
      and with <neuroanatomicalLocation>other parts of the cholinergic 
      basal forebrain</neuroanatomicalLocation></S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s168">The neuropil immediately surrounding any PHA - L 
      injection site in <injectionLocation>the SI</injectionLocation> 
      contained numerous <labelingDescription>PHA - L - filled axonal 
      swellings</labelingDescription> , indicating 
      <labelingDescription>a moderately dense local terminal 
      field</labelingDescription> ( Fig . 4A , B ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s169">Occasionally , juxtapositions could be seen between 
      such varicosities and the <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> - filled dendrite of a neuron that had taken 
      up the lectin ( Fig . 4B ) , perhaps reflecting axodendritic 
      synaptic contacts .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s170"><labelingDescription>Axon 
      terminals</labelingDescription> were also labelled in 
      <labelingLocation>more distant parts of the SI</labelingLocation> 
      ; indeed , wherever <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
      deposits were placed in <injectionLocation>the 
      SI</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>lectin - filled 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> stretched throughout its 
      rostrocaudal extent .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s171"><labelingDescription>Most labelled axon 
      swellings</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      SI</labelingLocation> appeared to represent 
      <labelingDescription>en passant terminals</labelingDescription> , 
      often lying along fibers that crossed into <labelingLocation>the 
      amygdala , bed nucleus of the stria terminalis , or 
      hypothalamus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s172"><connxOrigin>The nucleus of the horizontal limb of the 
      diagonal band on one side of the brain</connxOrigin> is known to 
      project to <connxTermination>its contralatera1 
      counterpart</connxTermination> ( Fuller et al . , 86 ) .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s173">Consequently, <labelingLocation>the 
      SI</labelingLocation> contralateral to that injected in cases 
      RPSI1-3 was carefully examined.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s174"><labelingDescription>Only a few labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were found , suggesting , 
      nonetheless , at least some interconnection between the SI on 
      each side of the brain .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s175">Larger or differently placed injections might well 
      have revealed <labelingDescription>a denser 
      projection</labelingDescription> .</S>
      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s176"><neuroanatomicalLocation>The 
      SI</neuroanatomicalLocation> shares a striking feature , the 
      presence of <labelingDescription>cholinergic 
      perikarya</labelingDescription> , with <labelingLocation>the 
      medial septum , nucleus of the diagonal band , and parts of the 
      globus pallidus</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s177">To what extent is the SI affiliated by direct 
      connections with other components of the cholinergic basal 
      forebrain?</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s178">From <tracerChemical>PHAL</tracerChemical> deposits in 
      <injectionLocation>the SI</injectionLocation> , at least 
      <labelingDescription>a few labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> could be traced dorsally along 
      <labelingLocation>the lateral face of the internal 
      capsule</labelingLocation> where many intrapallidal cholinergic 
      cells are found ( Fig . lC , D ) or followed ventrally into 
      <labelingLocation>the nucleus of the horizontal limb of the 
      diagonal band</labelingLocation> ( Figs . 1B , 2B ) .</S>
      <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s179">In turn , the <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> 
      deposit in case RPDB1, centered in <injectionLocation>the 
      NHDB</injectionLocation> , filled <labelingDescription>several 
      varicose axons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
      SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 3A ) , although such labelling may 
      have resulted in part from the involvement of 
      <injectionSpread>the rostral SI</injectionSpread> in the 
      injection site .</S></TTE>

      <BR />

      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s180">By contrast , there may be only a minor direct 
      communication between <connxOrigin>the medial septum and nucleus 
      of the vertical limb of the diagonal band</connxOrigin> on the 
      one hand , and <connxTermination>the SI</connxTermination> on the 
      other .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s181">As noted above , <tracerChemical>PHA - 
      L</tracerChemical> injections into <injectionLocation>the 
      SI</injectionLocation> labelled  <labelingDescription>almost no 
      axons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the nucleus of 
      the ventral limb of the diagonal band or the medial 
      septum</labelingLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s182">Similarly , <labelingDescription>no PHA - L - filled 
      fibers</labelingDescription> were evident in 
      <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> following an 
      injection ( not shown ) involving these structures in turn .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s183"><connxOrigin>The NHDB</connxOrigin>, however, does 
      maintain a heavy projection to <connxTermination>the rest of the 
      diagonal band-medial septum continuum</connxTermination>.</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s184"><labelingDescription>A profusion of labelled varicose 
      fibers</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>swept 
      through</labelingModifier> <labelingLocation>the vertical limb of 
      the diagonal band</labelingLocation> into <labelingLocation>the 
      medial septum</labelingLocation> after injections of 
      <tracerChemical>PHA - L</tracerChemical> into 
      <injectionLocation>the NHDB</injectionLocation> .</S>
      <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
       id="s185">This projection appears to be reciprocated : a deposit 
      involving <injectionLocation>parts of the medial septum and 
      ventral limb of the diagonal band</injectionLocation> filled 
      <labelingDescription>many varicose axons</labelingDescription> in 
      <labelingLocation>the most medial portion of the 
      NHDB</labelingLocation>  , and <labelingDescription>a 
      few</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>more lateral parts 
      of the nucleus</labelingLocation>.</S>
    </TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s186">The cells of origin for 
    SI projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">Brains with <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> deposits in <injectionLocation>the efferent 
    targets of the SI</injectionLocation></exptLabel> provided 
    additional evidence regarding the subdivision of the region .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">For example , after <exptLabel>tracer deposits in 
    <injectionLocation>the central or basolateral nuclei ( RHBL2, 
    RHCE2, Fig . 7 ) of the amygdala</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal SI</labelingLocation> contained 
    <labelingDescription> numerous retrogradely filled 
    cells</labelingDescription> embedded in <labelingDescription>a 
    dense band of axons</labelingDescription> that appeared to have 
    transported <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> in the 
    anterograde direction from  <labelingLocation>the 
    amygdala</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5A ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189"><labelingDescription>Far fewer perikarya or 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were labelled in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral SI</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s190">A modest number of 
    <labelingDescription>WGA - HRP - filled cells</labelingDescription> 
    were also found in <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    pallidum</labelingLocation> in cases RHBL2 and RHCE2, but 
    <labelingDescription>both labelled cells and fibers were 
    sparse</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the nucleus of 
    the horizontal limb of the diagonal band</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191"><exptLabel>By contrast , <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injections that mainly involved 
    <injectionLocation>the medial nucleus of the amygdala ( RHBM1, Fig 
    . 7 ) , or a large amygdaloid region ventral to the central 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RHBMB , not shown ) , 
    <labelingDescription>labelled many cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral SI</labelingLocation> but only 
    <labelingDescription>a few</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal division</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Again , <labelingDescription>WGA - HRP - filled 
    perikarya lay among numerous anterogradely labelled 
    axons</labelingDescription> that , in these cases , 
    <labelingModifier>streamed through</labelingModifier> 
    <labelingLocation>the anterior amygdaloid area and ventral 
    SI</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 5B ) .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Additional <labelingDescription>labelled 
    cells</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
    nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal 
    band</labelingLocation> , particularly in the caudal part of that 
    structure .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    injections placed in <injectionLocation>progressively more caudal 
    sites in the brainstem</injectionLocation></exptLabel> labelled  
    <labelingDescription>an increasing proportion of 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    SI</labelingLocation> as compared with <labelingLocation>the 
    ventral division</labelingLocation> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s195">Thus , a 
    large <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> deposit in 
    <injectionLocation>the ventral tegmental area</injectionLocation> , 
    spreading into <injectionSpread>the supramammillary 
    area</injectionSpread> ( RHVT2, Fig . 7 ) , 
    <labelingDescription>labelled cells</labelingDescription> 
    throughout <labelingLocation>the SI ( Fig . 6A )</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196"><exptLabel>A tracer deposit involving <injectionLocation>
    the dorsal raphe nucleus and central 
    gray</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RHDR1, Fig . 7 ) 
    <labelingDescription>labelled cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> that appeared slightly 
    more numerous in <labelingLocation>the dorsal 
    division</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6B ) .</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Finally , when <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> injections were centered either in 
    <injectionLocation>the parabrachial nucleus</injectionLocation> 
    CRHPB6, Fig . 7 ) or in <injectionLocation>the dorsomedial medulla 
    , involving the nucleus of the solitary tract and the dorsal motor 
    nucleus of the vagus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RHM1, Fig . 
    7 ) , the majority of labelled perikarya in the SI appeared in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal division</labelingLocation> ( Fig . 6C 
    ) .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Interestingly , <labelingDescription>a few such 
    cells</labelingDescription> were evident even in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsalmost strip of the SI</labelingLocation> 
    that is marked by enkephalin - immunoreactive woolly fibers .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">No backfilled 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> could be 
    identified , however , in <labelingLocation>the GP or VP 
    themselves</labelingLocation> , or in <labelingLocation>the nucleus 
    of the horizontal limb of the diagonal band</labelingLocation> 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s200">Participation of 
    cholinergic cells in SI projections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">The double - labelling procedure employed to reveal both 
    <tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> and choline 
    acetyltransferase immunoreactivity slightly reduced the number of 
    ChAT - immunoreactive cells that could be identified in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the basal 
    forebrain</neuroanatomicalLocation> compared with control sections 
    stained for ChAT alone .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">By contrast, the technique used to demonstrate both 
    WGAHRP and acetylcholinesterase activity did not appear to decrease 
    the number of cells staining strongly for AChE.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">In both instances , <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> was marked by a granular reaction product ( 
    Fig . 4C , D ) that was blue - black in color .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">ChAT immunoreactivity or strong AChE reactivity was 
    evident as a smooth, midbrown background stain filling the cell
    soma and proximal dendrites (Fig. 4D).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">The double - labelling procedures employed were 
    sufficiently sensitive to reveal a major involvement of cholinergic 
    cells in a given projection .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">For example , after<exptLabel> 
    <tracerChemical>WGAHRP</tracerChemical> injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the cortex or the basolateral nucleus of the 
    amygdala</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , at least 
    <labelingDescription>one - half to almost all of the retrogradely 
    labelled cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    SI</labelingLocation> could be identified as immunoreactive for 
    ChAT or as strongly AChE positive .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s207">( In the 
    case of <labelingLocation>the basolateral 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>a few additional 
    double labelled neurons</labelingDescription> were observed in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis and the medial segment of the central nucleus of the 
    amygdala .</labelingLocation> )</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">One or two doublelabelled cells were also found in each 
    50 - pm tissue section through <labelingLocation>the 
    SI</labelingLocation> following <exptLabel>tracer injections 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala</injectionLocation> ( RHBMl , Figs . 5, 7 ) or in 
    <injectionLocation>the amygdaloid region ventral to the central 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( case RHBMB , not shown ) 
    , without spread into <injectionSpread>the basolateral 
    nucleus</injectionSpread> .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209"><exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> 
    deposits involving <injectionLocation>the lateral hypothalamus , 
    habenular nuclei , ventral tegmental area , peripeduncular area , 
    dorsal raphe , central gray , or parabrachial 
    nucleus</injectionLocation></exptLabel> backfilled many cells in 
    <labelingLocation>the SI and / or adjacent basal forebrain 
    regions</labelingLocation> , but none were strongly AChE positive 
    or immunoreactive for ChAT .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s210">Thus, no evidence was 
    obtained that cholinergic cells contribute significantly to 
    projections to the former sites from the SI, ventral pallidum, or 
    diagonal band-septa1 continuum.</S></TTE>

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Ventral pallidal cells , unlike neurons in 
    <labelingLocation>the SI</labelingLocation> , were also labelled 
    after <exptLabel>tracer injections in <injectionLocation>the 
    nucleus accumbens</injectionLocation></exptLabel> .</S><S avgH="22"
     class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s212">None of 
    these was seen to contain cholinergic markers.</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">In two cases , RHMDl and RHPN3, with 
    <exptLabel><tracerChemical>WGA - HRP</tracerChemical> injections 
    centered , respectively , in <injectionLocation>the mediodorsal 
    nucleus of the thalamus , and in the substantia 
    nigra</injectionLocation></exptLabel> , <labelingDescription>a few 
    doublelabelled cells</labelingDescription> could be identified in 
    <labelingLocation>the basal forebrain</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">In case RHMDZ , one or two such cells appeared in 
    <labelingLocation>the nuclei of the vertical</labelingLocation> and 
    horizontal limbs of the diagonal band in each 5O - wm section 
    through these structures .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s215">In RHPN3, a comparable small 
    number of cells staining for both WGAHRP and ChAT appeared in 
    <labelingLocation>the globus pallidus and SI</labelingLocation> 
    .</S><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">In both cases , <labelingLocation>the basal forebrain 
    structures</labelingLocation> in question contained 
    <labelingDescription>numerous WGA - HRP - labelled 
    perikarya</labelingDescription> that were negative for ChAT 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Levey and Hallanger and their colleagues ( Levey et al . 
    , &apos; 87 ; Hallanger et al . , &apos; 87 ) have reported 
    significant cholinergic projections to <connxTermination>the 
    reticular nucleus of the thalamus from basal forebrain districts 
    that include the cholinergic cell - rich region of the 
    GP</connxTermination> .</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">It is possible that the injection site in case RHPN3 
    intruded upon <injectionSpread>the most caudal part of the 
    reticular nucleus or some other caudal thalamic 
    structure</injectionSpread> and that this accounts for the handful 
    of double - labelled basal forebrain cells seen in this brain .</S>
    <TTE><S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">However , <exptLabel>a <tracerChemical>WGA - 
    HRP</tracerChemical> deposit of comparable size centered in 
    <injectionLocation>the peripeduncular 
    area</injectionLocation></exptLabel> ( RHPNZ ) should have involved 
    the same caudal thalamic structures , if anything , to a greater 
    extent ; yet none of <labelingDescription>the WGA - HRP - filled 
    cells</labelingDescription> observed in <labelingLocation>the SI or 
    GP</labelingLocation> in this case was also immunoreactive for ChAT 
    .</S></TTE>

    <BR />

  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s220">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s221">projections of the SI 
    reciprocate its afferent connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">A principal finding of the present study is that the 
    efferent projections of the SI largely reciprocate its afferent 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">A second observation follows from the first, namely, 
    that ventral and dorsal divisions can be distinguished in the SI on 
    the basis of its efferent as well as afferent connections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">In no case was a PHA-L injection entirely confined to 
    either the dorsal or the ventral SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">However, a comparison of available PHA-L cases, together 
    with findings from WGAHRP experiments, established that descending 
    efferents that reach caudal to the mesodiencephalic border, 
    including projections to the parabrachial nucleus and medulla 
    (Schwaber et al., &apos;82), arise primarily from the dorsal SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">Among these target cell groups, the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract, parabrachial nucleus, and dorsal raphe have been 
    shown previously to innervate more heavily the dorsal division of 
    the SI (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">Findings from both PHA-L and WGA-HRP experiments further 
    indicate that the efferents of the dorsal and ventral SI are 
    distributed preferentially in different regions of the hypothalamus 
    and amygdala, reciprocating equally selective afferentation from 
    these areas (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">In summary, the dorsal SI projects heavily to the 
    lateral part of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis and to the 
    lateral: basolateral, and central nuclei of the amygdala; it 
    projects more sparsely to an amygdaloid region that lies ventral to 
    the central nucleus and dorsal to the cortical nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">This ventral amygdaloid district, however, which may 
    include at least parts of the intraamygdaloid division of the bed 
    nucleus of the stria terminalis (Paxinos and Watson, &apos;86) and 
    the basomedial nucleus (Krettek and Price, &apos;78b; de Olmos et 
    al., &apos;85; Paxinos and Watson, &apos;861, receives a heavy 
    innervation from the ventral SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">The ventral division of the SI also projects in at least 
    moderate density to the medial nucleus, anterior amygdaloid area, 
    and medial portions of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">In the hypothalamus, efferents from the dorsal SI are 
    distributed most heavily over the lateral preoptic area, 
    paraventricular nucleus, and certain parts of the lateral 
    hypothalamus, prominently including the perifornical and 
    caudolateral zones described previously (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Projections from the ventral SI terminate most densely 
    in the medial preoptic area and anterior hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">At least light projections to the lateral preoptic area, 
    lateral hypothalamus (including its most medial district), and the 
    ventromedial and arcuate hypothalamic nuclei also arise from the 
    ventral SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">The dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus seem to be 
    innervated by both divisions of the SI but perhaps more heavily by 
    the ventral SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">Widespread projections from the SI to the hypothalamus, 
    with a similar overall pattern to that reported here, were 
    previously noted by Mogenson et al. (&apos;851, who, however, did 
    not describe differences between the projections of dorsal and 
    ventral parts of the SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Within the thalamus, some divergence from the principle 
    of reciprocal connections is apparent.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Findings described in a previous report (Grove, 
    &apos;88) suggest that the SI receives innervation from the 
    paratenial, paraventricular, central medial, rhomboid and reuniens 
    nuclei of the thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Present observations indicate that the SI also projects 
    to this group of midline thalamic nuclei.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">However, the SI additionally innervates the medial part 
    of the mediodorsal nucleus and the reticular nucleus of the 
    thalamus, neither of which appears to send efferents to the SI 
    (Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">In its connection with the mediodorsal nucleus the SI 
    resembles the amygdala, which also maintains a projection to the 
    mediodorsal nucleus that is not reciprocated (Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78a; Ottersen and Ben-Ari, &apos;79).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">The projection to the reticular nucleus of the thalamus 
    represents part of a cholinergic and noncholinergic innervation of 
    that nucleus reported to arise from several basal forebrain 
    regions, including the SI (Hallanger et al., &apos;87; Levey et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">The present PHA-L experiments provided no evidence that 
    the projection to the SI and the cholinergic cell-rich region of 
    the globus pallidus that arises from a continuum of cells in the 
    parvocellular part of the subparafascicular nucleus of the thalamus 
    and peripeduncular area (Jones et al., &apos;76; Grove, &apos;88) 
    is returned in comparably high volume.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">A WGA-HRP injection involving the PPA and adjacent 
    substantia nigra (case RHPN2) labelled a few cells in the 2Note, 
    however, that no evidence was obtained in a previous WGA-HRP study 
    (Grove, &apos;88) that the lateral nucleus of the amyg dala 
    innervates the SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">globus pallidus, SI, and the medial part of the central 
    nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">However, many more cells were labelled, particularly in 
    the GP and central nucleus, after an injection of comparable size 
    restricted to the lateral third of the substantia nigra (case 
    RHPN3), suggesting that this nucleus may be the primary target.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The central nucleus of the amygdala has been reported 
    previously to project to both the lateral part of the substantia 
    nigra and the peripeduncular nucleus (Krettek and Price, 78a; Price 
    and Amaral, 81).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">The cortical projections of the SI, however, again 
    appear to reciprocate closely the afferent connections of the 
    region.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Findings described elsewhere (Grove, 88) indicate that 
    prominent cortical afferents to the SI arise from medial 
    prefrontal, insular, perirhinal and entorhinal cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Efferents from at least the mid-rostrocaudal part of the 
    SI that was injected with PHA-L in cases RPSI2 and RPSI3 terminate 
    most heavily in the same cortical areas as well as innervating 
    piriform cortex and the main and accessory olfactory bulbs.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Projections to the cortex from the SI also display some 
    dorsal to ventral organization.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">That is, efferents from the ventral SI that were 
    labelled in the present study appeared to be distributed 
    preferentially in the most ventrally placed cortices, namely, 
    piriform and entorhinal cortex.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s252">The rough 
    dorsal-to-ventral organization of cortical projections from the SI 
    also appears to apply to some extent to efferents from the 
    ventrally contiguous nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal 
    band and the dorsally adjacent, cholinergic cell-rich region of the 
    globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s253">Further, the 
    organization may have the effect of associating these regions with 
    cortices that are connectionally and functionally appropriate.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s254">Thus, the PHA-L deposit 
    in NHDB in case RPDBl produced heavy varicose fiber labelling in 
    the amygdaloid nuclei defined by Scalia and Winans ( 75) as 
    components of the olfactory amygdala, as well as in the olfactory 
    bulb and primary olfactory cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s255">The PHA-L injection in 
    case RPSI3 densely labelled fibers in widespread areas of the 
    amygdala, prominently including the basolateral and lateral nuclei, 
    and, as will be discussed further below, in cortical areas that are 
    themselves in direct contact with the basolateral amygdaloid group 
    in the rat (Krettek and Price, 77b; Turner and Zimmer, 84; and for 
    review, see de Olmos et al., 85).</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s256">Finally, the cholinergic 
    cell-rich region of the globus pallidus contains relatively few 
    cells that innervate the amygdala, and is invaded by only sparse 
    amygdalofugal fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s257">Several studies in which 
    anterograde tracers have been placed in this region, dorsal to the 
    SI injection sites described in the present study, have indicated 
    substantial projections to cortices on the convexity of the 
    hemisphere (Saper, 84; Haber et al., 85; Luiten et al., 85, 87) 
    that have not been reported in the rat to be heavily connected with 
    the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s258">(For a review of 
    corticoamygdaloid relations in the rat, see de Olmos et al., 
    85.)</S>
    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s259">Pallidal-type cells may 
    contribute to projections from the SI</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s260">Tissue with features that are characteristic of the 
    neuropi1 of the ventral pallidum and globus pallidus appears to 
    overflow into part, though not all, of the adjacent dorsal division 
    of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s261">That is, the dorsalmost portion of the region that can 
    be defined as substantia innominata by the passage of a high volume 
    of fibers belonging to the ansa peduncularis is also invaded by 
    enkephalin-immunoreactive woolly fibers (Grove, 88), a 
    configuration of axon terminals characteristic of the 
    striatopallidal projection (Haber and Elde, 81; Switzer et al., 82; 
    Haber and Nauta, 83).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s262">In addition, this part of the SI maintains reciprocal 
    connections with the fundus of the striatum (present study; Grove, 
    These observations raise questions that are pertinent to any 
    account of the SI and its connections, although it is important to 
    emphasize that they do not concern the entire dorsal division of 
    the SI as defined here-only the most dorsal strip that displays 
    pallidal features.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s263">Should this strip of the SI properly be viewed as an 
    extension of the globus pallidus, or, at least, as mixed with 
    pallidal tissue?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s264">If so, which of the efferents of the SI demonstrated in 
    the present study might be expected to represent the projections of 
    pallidal cells?</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">At present the answers to these questions are 
    unclear.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">The dorsalmost part of the SI is a complex tissue that 
    displays both pallidal and nonpallidal attributes.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Considering these in turn: 1.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">The ENK-IR woolly fiber configuration appears when 
    nonimmunoreactive dendrites or cell bodies are densely invested 
    with ENK-IR axon terminals.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Thus, their presence in the dorsalmost SI strongly 
    suggests the presence of a category of cell that is common in the 
    ventral pallidum and globus pallidus, whose dendritic and somatic 
    surface is studded with numerous striatofugal axon terminals (Fox 
    et al., 74; Heimer and Wilson, 75; Heimer et al., 87; Zahm et al., 
    87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">It should be noted that such cells appear to be 
    projection neurons in the ventral pallidum (Zahm et al., 87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">However, the ENK-IR axons that compose the woolly fibers 
    in the SI have not been directly shown to originate from the 
    striatum as they have in the VP and GP (Zaborszky et al., 82; Haber 
    and Nauta, 83), and such axons could originate from other 
    structures (see Grove, 88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Ultimately, whether pallidal-type cells are present in 
    the dorsal SI and what their connections may be will be determined 
    only by studies similar to those of the VP cited above in which the 
    source of ENK-IR axons was determined (Zaborszky et al., 82; Haber 
    and Nauta, 83) and the connections and morphological features of 
    cells were examined in the light and electron microscope (Fox et 
    al., 74; Heimer and Wilson, 75; Heimer et al., 87; Zahm et al., 
    87).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">2.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">The tissue that makes up the dorsalmost strip of the SI 
    can also be differentiated histochemically from the adjacent 
    ventral pallidum and globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Whereas the VP and GP display a patchy appearance in 
    Timm-stained material, the whole of the SI is characterized by 
    modest, even staining (de Olmos et al., 85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Further, the entire dorsal division of the SI is 
    distinguished by the selective termination of fibers immunoreactive 
    for tyrosine hydroxylase (Grove, 88) and by the argyrophilia it 
    exhibits in cupric-silver preparations (de Olmos, 72; de Olmos et 
    al., 85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">At present it seems most likely that the dorsalmost part 
    of the SI is a heterogeneous tissue, containing several 
    intermingled cell populations.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Such cell groups would appear to include not only 
    cholinergic and noncholinergic cells that innervate the cortex and 
    amygdala but also other cell types characteristic of the SI as a 
    whole.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">For example, WGA-HRP deposits involving the parabrachial 
    nucleus or the nucleus of the solitary tract and dorsal motor 
    nucleus of the vagus backfill many cells in the dorsal SI, 
    including a few in the part invaded by ENK-IR woolly fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Given the visceroceptive and visceromotor associations 
    of the parabrachial nucleus and dorsomedial medulla, these 
    structures appear improbable targets of pallidal cells, at least 
    given our present conception of the role of the globus pallidus in 
    somatomotor function.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">It is tempting to assume that the projections from the 
    dorsal SI to the amygdala, diencephalon, midbrain, and pons, 
    because they appear to be part of a general system of 
    topographically organized connections linking the two subdivisions 
    of the SI to a diversity of cell groups lying along the ansa 
    peduncularis and medial forebrain bundle, must also arise entirely 
    from cells characteristic of the SI as a whole.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Certainly, both WGA-HRP and PHA-L experiments indicate 
    that such projections arise fiom cells in that part of the dorsal 
    SI division that exhibits no pallidal features, and thus, at least 
    in that region, from cells typical of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">However, the ansa peduncularis and medial forebrain 
    bundle are common routes for efferents from several basal forebrain 
    structures, including the nucleus accumbens (Nauta et al., 
    &apos;78) and the region here called ventral pallidum (Swanson et 
    al., &apos;84; Haber et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">All of these distribute efferents over an apparently 
    similar set of hypothalamic and midbrain targets.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Fibers from the ventral pallidum continue into the pons, 
    innervating the pedunculopontine nucleus (Swanson et al., &apos;84; 
    Haber et al., &apos;85), which lies just rostral to the 
    parabrachial nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Thus, some fiber contingents arising from the dorsalmost 
    SI may receive contributions from both pallidal-type cells and 
    neurons more characteristic of the entire SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Further work will be needed to determine if this is so 
    and whether efferents arising from different cell types might 
    distribute over slightly different targets along the route of the 
    AP and MFB.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s288">The efferent projections 
    of the SI resemble those of the amygdala</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">The subcortical projections of the dorsal SI determined 
    in the present study are reminiscent of those previously reported 
    for the central nucleus of the amygdala and the lateral part of the 
    bed nucleus of the stria terminalis (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; 
    Price, &apos;81; Price and Amaral, &apos;81; Holstege et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Similarly, the efferent connections of the ventral SI 
    resemble those of the medial amygdaloid nucleus (Krettek and Price, 
    &apos;78a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Available for direct comparison with the cases described 
    in the present study were several others, previously described 
    (Grove, &apos;88) in which PHA-L had been deposited adjacent to the 
    SI in the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis or amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Examination of these cases demonstrated that the 
    distribution of PHA-L-filled fibers in subcortical structures is 
    indeed strikingly similar whether the lectin injection is placed in 
    a division of the SI itself or in contiguous parts of the BNS or 
    amygdala.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Specifically, PHA-L injections involving the lateral BNS 
    (RPGP4, RPBNSB), dorsal SI (RPSI1 and RPSI3), or central nucleus of 
    the amygdala (RPAA1, RPACe8) (see Fig. 1 and Grove, &apos;88, Figs. 
    8,9) label axons in the same set of subcortical forebrain 
    structures: the lateral BNS, dorsal SI, central nucleus of the 
    amygdala, lateral preoptic area, paraventricular nucleus of the 
    hypothalamus, perifornical and caudolateral zones of the lateral 
    hypothalamus, dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus, and midline 
    thalamic cell groups, prominently including the medial part of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">The lateral nucleus of the amygdala is also innervated 
    by the lateral BNS as well as by the dorsal SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Observations from WGA-HRP experiments additionally 
    indicate that projections to the basolateral nucleus of the 
    amygdala arise not only from the dorsal SI but also from a few 
    cholinergic and noncholinergic cells in the lateral BNS and medial 
    part of the central nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Similarly, when PHA-L injection sites involve the medial 
    portion of the bed nucleus of the stria terminalis (RPBNSB), 
    ventral SI (RPSI1 and 2), rostral part of the medial nucleus of the 
    amygdala (RPABl), or rostral part of the amygdaloid region ventral 
    to the central nucleus (RPBMl), axons are labelled in each of the 
    other regions, as well as in the medial and lateral preoptic areas, 
    anterior hypothalamus, medialmost district of the lateral 
    hypothalamus, dorsomedial and posterior hypothalamus, and 
    mediodorsal nucleus of the thalamus (see Grove, &apos;88, Figs. 8, 
    9, and text).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">The ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus, which 
    receives a prominent projection from the medial nucleus (Krettek 
    and Price, &apos;78a, Price, &apos;811, is also at least lightly 
    innervated by the ventral SI.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Finally, moderately dense fiber labelling appears caudal 
    to the diencephalon in a distribution similar to that shown in 
    Figure 1G-I (case RPSI3) whenever the lateral BNS, dorsal SI, or 
    central nucleus of the amygdala are involved in the PHA-L injection 
    site (cases RPSI1, RPGP4, RPBNSB, RPAA1, and RPACe8).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Some differences appear in the density and topography of 
    subcortical projections from different parts of the two 
    BNSSI-amygdala continua.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">For example, as PHA-L injections are placed more 
    rostromedially in the two continua, progressively denser fiber 
    labelling appears in many parts of the hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Heavier and more widespread axon labelling appears in 
    the amygdala when PHA-L deposits are placed in the SI than when 
    deposits are made in the BNS or in the central nucleus of the 
    amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">A few differences appear also in projections to the 
    brainstem, reflecting a rostrocaudal ordering of efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">For example, the lateral BNS projects most heavily to a 
    more rostral part of the parabrachial nucleus than does the dorsal 
    SI, although the same parabrachial subnuclei (Fulwiler and Saper, 
    &apos;84) appear to be involved.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Previous studies have established two distinctive 
    efferent pathways leading to a different set of subcortical 
    structures from the central nucleus on one hand, and a ventromedial 
    region of the amygdala, prominently including the medial nucleus, 
    on the other (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Price, &apos;81; Price 
    and Amaral, &apos;81; de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Although other amygdaloid nuclei, including the 
    basolateral and basomedial nuclei, maintain at least modest 
    projections to the hypothalamus and other subcortical sites, the 
    central and medial nuclei appear to represent output 
    &quot;staging&quot; areas of the amygdala, receiving projections 
    from other amygdaloid nuclei (Krettek and Price, &apos;78b; 
    Aggleton, &apos;85) and projecting heavily to diencephalic and 
    caudal brainstem structures (Krettek and Price, &apos;78a; Price, 
    &apos;81).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Earlier investigations have demonstrated strong 
    similarities between the lateral part of the bed nucleus of the 
    stria terminalis and the medial part of the central amygdaloid 
    nucleus in their projections to brainstem structures (Schwaber et 
    al., &apos;82; Holstege et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Further, a continuum of cells stretching between these 
    two structures through the SI has been labelled by retrograde 
    tracer injections involving the parabrachial nucleus, the nucleus 
    of the solitary tract and dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus, or the 
    nucleus raphe magnus and adjoining midline reticular formation 
    (Schwaber et al., &apos;82; Holstege et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Findings from the present study augment these 
    observations and establish that the two &quot;staging areas&quot; 
    of the amygdala extend from the medial and central nuclei into, 
    respectively, the ventral and dorsal SI and medial and lateral 
    BNS.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">The most striking difference between the efferent 
    connections of the SI and immediately adjacent parts of the 
    amygdala and BNS is that the SI projects widely to the cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Only sparse fibers were labelled in piriform and insular 
    cortices in case RPSI1, which contained a PHA-L deposit in the 
    transitional area between the SI and bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">No cortical labelling followed injections into the BNS 
    itself or the central nucleus of the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">PHA-L deposits in the rostroventromedial amygdala 
    labelled fibers only in piriform cortex (Grove, &apos;88, Fig. 
    9).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">However, consistent with previous reports (Krettek and 
    Price, &apos;77b; for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;851, a 
    PHA-L injection into the basolateral nucleus (case RPBL2, Grove, 
    &apos;88, Fig. 9), which is interconnected with the central 
    nucleus, dorsal SI, and lateral BNS, labelled varicose fibers in 
    the medial prefrontal, agranular insular, piriform, perirhinal, and 
    entorhinal cortices.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Of those cortical areas that contained PHA-L-filled 
    varicose axons in case RPSI3, only granular insular cortex appeared 
    free of labelled fibers.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Thus, the cortical projections of at least the midcaudal 
    portion of the SI also closely resemble those of a neighboring 
    amygdaloid nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s316">Cholinergic projections 
    to the amygdala and cortex may be integrated into the efferent 
    circuitry of the SI</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">It has been proposed that the population of cholinergic 
    cells that reaches from the medial septum and the nucleus of the 
    diagonal band through the SI and into the caudal globus pallidus 
    may form a single anatomical and functional entity (Schwaber et 
    al., &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Thus, it is plausible that cholinergic neurons invade 
    the SI but are not part of it, maintaining afferent and efferent 
    connections that are typical of the cholinergic cell continuum but 
    wholly unrelated to those of other SI cells.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Several observations from the present pair of studies 
    appear pertinent to this issue.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Findings reported by Grove (&apos;88) suggested that the 
    cholinergic cell group in the SI (like other cells in the region) 
    may receive some innervation from the hypothalamus, peripeduncular 
    area, ventral tegmental area, and dorsal raphe nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Nonetheless, the present study provides no evidence that 
    the cholinergic cells of the SI innervate these areas in return or 
    contribute significantly to any extrinsic projections of the SI 
    other than those previously described to the cortex, basolateral 
    nucleus of the amygdala, and reticular nucleus of the thalamus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Some intrinsic connections within the SI may arise, 
    however, from local cholinergic neurons.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">A procedure developed for labelling cholinergic fibers 
    has demonstrated ChATimmunoreactive axonal varicosities, probably 
    representing synaptic terminals, in the SI and ventromedial globus 
    pallidus (this study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">ChAT-IR synaptic boutons have previously been observed 
    in the electron microscope in the ventral pallidum (Zaborszky et 
    al., &apos;86b) and globus pallidus (Ingham, personal 
    communication).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Both Ingham (personal communication) and Zaborszky et 
    al. (&apos;86b) noted that synaptic contacts were formed between 
    ChAT-IR boutons and nonimmunoreactive elements.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">If noncholinergic projection neurons are among those 
    innervated, cholinergic cells in the SI could have a significant 
    influence over a range of subcortical SI projections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">A more fundamental observation is that the cholinergic 
    projections that arise from cells within the SI appear to fit with 
    the overall character of SI connections.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Both the afferents and efferents of the region associate 
    it strongly with much of the amygdala and with structures that are 
    themselves directly connected with the amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Thus, the cholinergic (and non-cholinergic) projection 
    from the SI to the basolateral amygdaloid nucleus is only part of a 
    voluminous system of SI efferents that distributes over most of the 
    amygdala (present study; Russchen, &apos;82; Aggleton et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">It is notable, too, that the cholinergic cells 
    innervating the basolateral nucleus are mainly confined to the 
    dorsal division of the SI, obeying the general topography of 
    SI-amygdala connections.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">The projections from cholinergic cells in the SI to the 
    cortex may also conform to the pattern.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Medial prefrontal, insular, perirhinal, entorhinal, and 
    piriform cortices seem to receive a preferentially heavy 
    innervation from the SI, most of which is likely to be cholinergic 
    (Rye et al., &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">The same cortical areas have been reported to be 
    directly interconnected with the &quot;basolateral&quot; amygdaloid 
    group in the rat (Krettek and Price, &apos;77b; Turner and Zimmer, 
    &apos;84; and for review, see de Olmos et al., &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">More generally, cholinergic corticopetal projections may 
    be only one element of a set of direct and indirect pathwa;ys 
    leading from the SI to the cortical mantle, which appear to 
    converge upon similar cortical sites.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Saper (&apos;85) has d.escribed projections to the 
    cortex arising from scattered cel Is in the lateral 
    hypothalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">In particular, cells in the caudolateral zone of the LH, 
    which is reciprocally connected with the dorsal SI, innervate 
    insular and medial prefrontal cortex.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">The medial part of the mediodorsal nucleus, which 
    receives a projection from noncholinergic SI neurons, innervates 
    rostra1 insular cortex (Krettek and Price, &apos;77a).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Finally, the medial division of the parabrachial 
    nucleus, also reciprocally connected with the SI, projects to 
    ventral infralimbic cortex and both anterior and posterior granular 
    and agranular insular cortex (Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; Saper, %2; 
    Fulwiler and Saper, &apos;84).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Further study is needed to answer questions about the 
    circuitry that might coordinate these cortical infiuences-whether, 
    for example, SI efferents synapse directly on cortically projecting 
    neurons in the amyg dala, lateral hypothalamus, thalamus, or 
    parabrachial nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">In summary, the findings of the present study support 
    three generalizations that may be of use in designing behavioral 
    and physiological studies of the SI.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">First, the SI appears to be strongly affiliated with the 
    amygdala (see also de Olmos, &apos;72; Schwaber et al., &apos;82; 
    de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Grove, &apos;88).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Second, the SI is organized into a ventral and a dorsal 
    division, suggesting functional heterogeneity.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Swh an organization is indicated by both the afferent 
    and efferent connections of the SI, as well as by histochemical 
    features (de Olmos, &apos;72; de Olmos et al., &apos;85; Grove, 
    &apos;88; present study).</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Finally, although the cholinergic neurons in the SI 
    belong to a cell type that is dispersed rather widely in the basal 
    forebrain, those within the SI may be integrated into the overall 
    afferent and efferent circuitry of the region, and thus into 
    whatever functional roles the SI may subserve.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s345">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s346">I am indebted to Doctor Walle 
    J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s347">Nauta for his encouragement 
    and guidance throughout the course of this study, In addition, I 
    wish to thank Cliff Ragsdale for his constructive criticism of the 
    manuscripts.</S>
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s348">This study was made possible 
    by NSF grant BNS 8306284, PHS grants 1 R01 NS 19945 and 5 PO1 MH 
    31154, and a predoctoral fellowship from the Scottish Rite 
    Schizophrenia Research Progr&amp; (N.M.J., U.S.A.).</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s349">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Aggleton, J.P. (1985) A description of intra-amygdaloid 
    world monkeys.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Brain Res. 57:390-399.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">Aggleton, J.P, D.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Friedman, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Mishkin (1987) A comparison between the connections of 
    the amygdala and hippocampus with the basal forebrain of the 
    macaque.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Brain Res. 67356-568.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Beckstead, R.M. (1979) An autoradiographic examination 
    of cortico-cortical and subcortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal-projection (prefrontal) cortex in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">J Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Neurol. 184:43-62.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Bigl, V., N.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Woolf, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Butcher (1982) Cholinergic projections from the basal 
    forebrain to frontal, parietal, temporal, occipital and cingulate 
    cortices: A combined fluorescent tracer and acetylcholinesterase 
    analysis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Bull. 8.727-749.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Carlsen, J., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Zaborszky, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Heimer (1985) Cholinergic projections from the basal 
    forebrain to the basolateral amygdaloid complex: A combined 
    retrograde fluorescent and immunohistochemical study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Neurol. 234t155-167.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Olmos, J.S. (1972) The amygdaloid projection field in 
    the rat as studied with the cupric-silver method.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">In B.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Eleftheriou (ed): The Neurobiology of the Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 145-204.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Olmos, J., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Hardy, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Heimer (1978) The afferent connections of the main and 
    accessory olfactory bulb formations in the rat: An experimental HRP 
    study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Neurol. 181:213-244.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Olmos, J., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Beltramino (1985) Amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">In G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Paxinos (ed): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Vol. 1.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">Australia: Academic Press, pp. 223-334.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Domesick, V.B. (1976) Projections of the nucleus Broca 
    in rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Anat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Rec. 184:391-392.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Eckenstein, F., and M.V.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Sofroniew (1983) Identification of central cholinergic 
    neurons containing both choline acetyltransferase and 
    acetylcholinesterase and of central neurons containing only 
    acetylcholinesterase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Neurosci. 3:2286-2291.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Fisher, R.S., J.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Asai, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Wainer, N.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Buchwald, and M.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Levine(1986) Cholinergic and gabaergic projections from 
    pallidal and peripallidal regions to the neocortex of the cat: 
    Demonstration by double peroxidase labeling of their neurons of 
    origin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Abstr: 12:1467.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Fox, C.A., A.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Andrade.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">I.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">LuQui. and J.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Rafols (1974) The primate globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">A Golgi and electron microscopic study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Hirnforsch. 15:75-93.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Fuller, T.A., K.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Carnes, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Price (1986) Afferents to the diagonal band of rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">SOC.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Abstr.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">I2r351.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Fulwiler, C.E., and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Saper (1984) Subnuclear organization of the efferent 
    connections of the parabrachial nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Rev.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">7t229-259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Geneser-Jensen, F.A., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Blackstad (1971) Distribution of acetylcholinesterase in 
    the hippocampal region of the guinea pig.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Entorhinal area, parasubiculum and presubiculum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Z.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">Zellforsch.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Mikrosk.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Anat.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">114:460-481.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Brain Res. 29Ot219-238.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Graybiel, A.M., R.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Baughman, and F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Eckenstein (1986) Cholinergic neuropil of the striatum 
    observes striosomal boundaries.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Nature 323:625-627.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Grove, E.A. (1988) Neural associations of the substantia 
    innominata rat: Afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Neurol. 277:315-346.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Grove, E.A., S.N.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Haber, V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Domesick, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Nauta (1983) Differential projections from AChE-positive 
    and AChE-negative ventral pallidum cells in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Soc.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Abstr. lOr16.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Haber, S., and R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Elde (1981) Correlation between met-enkephalin and 
    substance P immunoreactivity in the primate globus pallidus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Neuroscience 6r1291-1297.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Haber, S.N., and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Nauta (19831 Ramifications of the globus pallidus in the 
    rat as indicated by patterns of immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Neuroscience 9t245-260.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Haber, S.N., H.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Groenewegen, E.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Grove, and W.J.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Nauta (1985) Efferent connections of the ventral 
    pallidum: Evidence of a dual striatopallidofugal pathway.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Neurol. 235:322-335.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Hallanger, A.E., A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Levey, H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Lee, D.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Rye, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Wainer (1987) The origins of cholinergic and other 
    subcortical afferents to the thalamus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Neurol. 262:105-124.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Heimer, L., and R.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Wilson (1975) The subcortical projections of the 
    allocortex: Similarities in the neural associations of the 
    hippocampus, the piriform cortex, and the neocortex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">In M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Santini (ed): Golgi Centennial Symposium.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">New York Raven Press, pp. 177-193.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Heimer, L., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Zaborszky, D.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Zahm, and G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Alheid (1987) The ventral striatopallidothalamic 
    projection: I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">The striatopallidal link originating in the striatal 
    parts of the olfactory tubercle.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Neurol. 255:571591.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Holstege, G., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Meiners, and K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Tan (1985) Projections of the bed nucleus of the stria 
    terminalis to the mesencephalon, pons, and medulla oblongata in the 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Exp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Brain Res. 58:379-391.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Jones, E.G., H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Burton, C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Saper, and L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Swanson (1976) Midbrain, diencephalic and cortical 
    relationships of the basal nucleus of Meynert and associated 
    structures in primates.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Neurol. 167:385-420.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Price (1977a) The cortical projections of the 
    mediodorsal nucleus and adjacent thalamic nuclei in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Neurol.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s504">171: 157-192.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Price (1977b) Projections from the amygdaloid complex to 
    the cerebral cortex and thalamus in the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Neurol. 172~687-722.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Price (1978a) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the basal forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Neurol. 178:225-254.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Krettek, J.E., and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Price (1978b) A description of the amygdaloid complex in 
    the rat and cat, with observations on intra-amygdaloid axonal 
    connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Neurol. 178t255-280.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Lehmann, J., J.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Nagy, S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Atmadja, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Fibiger (1980) The nucleus basalis magnocellularis: The 
    origin of a cholinergic projection to the neocortex of the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Neuroscience 51161-1174.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Levey, A.L, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Wainer, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Mufson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Mesuiam (1983) Colocalization of acetylcholinesterase 
    and choline acetyltransferase in the rat cerebrum.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Neuroscience 9:9-22.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Levey, A.I., A.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Hallanger, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Wainer (1987) Cholinergic nucleus basalis neurons may 
    influence the cortex via the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Lett: 74:7-13.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Lind, R.W., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Swanson, and D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Ganten (1985) Organization of angiotensin I1 
    immunoreactive cells and fibers in the rat central nervous 
    system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Neuroendocrinology 4Ut2-24.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Luiten, P.G.M., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Spencer, Jr., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Traber, and R.P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Gaykema (1985) The pattern of cortical projections from 
    the intermediate parts of the magnocellular nucleus basalis in the 
    rat demonstrated by tracing with Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Lett. 57:137-142.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Luiten, P.G.M., R.P.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Gaykema, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Traber, and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Spencer, Jr. (1987) Cortical projection patterns of 
    magnocellular basal nucleus subdivisions as revealed by 
    anterogradely transported Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Brain Res. 413:229-250.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">McKinney, M., J.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Coyle, and J.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Hedreen (1983) Topographical analysis of the innervation 
    of the rat neocortex and hippocampus by the basal forebrain 
    cholinergic system.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Neurol. 217:103-121.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">-M. (1978) Tetramethyl benzidine for horseradish 
    peroxidase neurohistochemistry: A non-carcinogenic blue reaction 
    product with superior sensitivity for visualizing neural afferents 
    and efferents.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Cytochem. 26t106-117.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">-M., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Mufson, A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Levey, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Wainer (1983a) Cholinergic innervation of cortex by the 
    basal forebrain: Cytochemistry and cortical connections of the 
    septa1 area, diagonal hand nuclei, nucleus basalis (substantia 
    innominata), and hypothalamus in the rhesus monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Neurol. 214t170-197.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Mesulam, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">-M., E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Mufson, B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Wainer, and A.I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Levey (1983b) Central cholinergic pathways in the rat: 
    An overview based on an alternative nomenclature (Chl-Ch6).</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Neuroscience 1Ot1185-1201.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Mogenson, G.J., L.W.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Swanson, and M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Wu (1985) Evidence that projections from substantia 
    innominata to zona incerta and mesencephalic locomotor region 
    contribute to locomotor activity.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Brain Res. 334:65-76.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Nauta, W.J.H., G.P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Smith, R.L.M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Faull, and V.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Domesick (1978) Efferent connections and nigral 
    afferents of the nucleus accumbens in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Neuroscience 3t385-401.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Ottersen, O.P., and Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Ben-Ari (1979) Afferent connections to the amygdaloid 
    complex of the rat and cat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Projections from the thalamus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Neurol. 187t401-424.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Watson (1982) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates: 
    1st edition Australia: Academic Press.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates. 
    2nd edition Australia: Academic Press.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Phillipson, O.T. (1979) Afferent projections to the 
    ventral tegmental area of Tsai and interfascicular nucleus: A 
    horseradish peroxidase study in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Neurol. 187:117-144.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Price, J.L. (1981) The efferent projections of the 
    amygdaloid complex in the rat, cat and monkey.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">In Y.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Ben-Ari (ed): The Amygdaloid Complex.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Elsevier, Amsterdam: pp. 13-18.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Rice, J.L., and D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Amaral(1981) An autoradiographic study of the 
    projections of the central nucleus of the monkey amygdala.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Neurosci.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">1:1242-1259.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Russchen, F.T. (1982) Amygdalopetal projections in the 
    cat: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Subcortical afferent connections.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">A study with retrograde tracing techniques.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Neurol. 207:157-176.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Russchen, F.T., D.G.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Amaral, and J.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Price (1987) The afferent input to the magnocellular 
    division of the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus in the mankey, macaca 
    fascicularis.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Neurol. 256:175-210.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">Rye, D.B., C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">Saper, and B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Wainer (1984a) Stabilization of the tetramethylbenzidine 
    (TMB) reaction product: Application for retrograde and anterograde 
    tracing, and combination with immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Histochem.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Cytochem. 321145-1153.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Rye, D.B., B.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Wainer, M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">-M.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Mesulam, E.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Mufson, and C.B.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Saper (1984b) Cortical projections arising from the 
    basal forebrain: A study of cholinergic and non-cholinergic 
    components employing combined retrograde tracing and 
    immunohistochemical localization of choline acetYltransferase.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Neuroscience f3:627-644.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">Saper, C.B. (1982) Reciprocal parabrachial-cortical 
    Brain Res. 24233-40.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Saper, C.B. (1984) Organization of cerebral cortical 
    afferent systems in the rat, I.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Magnocellular basal nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Neurol. 221:313-342.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Saper, C.B. (1985) Organization of cerebral cortical 
    afferent systems in the rat. 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Hypothalamocortical projections. 3.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Neurol. 2372-46.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">Sapcr, C.B., and A.D.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections ofthe parabracllial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Brain Res. 197:291-317.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Scalia, F., and S.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Winans (1975) The differential projections of the 
    olfactory bulb and accessory hulh in mammals.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Neurol. 161:31-56.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Schwaber, J.S..</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">Kapp, G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Higgins, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">RaPP (1982) AmYgdaIoid and basal forebrain direct 
    connections with the nucleus ofthe solitary tract and the dorsal 
    motor nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Neurosci. 2.1424-1438.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Schwaher *J.S., W.T.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Rogers, K.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Satoh, and H.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Fibiger (1987) Distribution and organization of 
    cholinergic neurons in the rat forebrain demonstrated hy 
    computer-aided data acquisition and three dimensional 
    reconstruction.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Neurol. 2fi3:309-325.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">Swanson, L.W., G.J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Mogenson, C.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Gerfen, and P.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Robinson (1984) Evidence for a projection from the 
    lateral preoptic area and substantia innominata to the 
    &apos;mesencephalic locomotor region&apos; in the rat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Brain Res. 295161-178.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Schwaber, J.S., B.S.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Kapp, G.A.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Higgins, and P.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Rapp (1982) Amygdalciid and basal forebrain direct 
    connections with the nucleus of the solitary tract and the dorsal 
    motor nucleus.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Neurosci. 21424-1438, Switzer, R.C., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Hill, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Heimer (1982) The globus pallidus and its rostroventral 
    extension into the olfactory tubercle ofthe rat: A cyto. and 
    chemoarchitectural study.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Neuroscience 7: 1891-1904.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">Turner, B.H., and J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Zimmer (1984) The architecture and some of the 
    interconnections of the rat&apos;s amygdala and lateral 
    periallocortex, J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Neurol. 227:540-557.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">WOOlf, N.J., and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Butcher (1982) Cholinergic projections to the 
    basolat.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">era1 amygdala: A combined Evans Blue and 
    acetylcholinesterase anal.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">ysis: Brain Res.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">Bull. 8:751-763.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Woolf, N.J., M.C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Hernit, and L.L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Butcher (1986) Cholinergic and noncholinergic 
    projections from the rat basal forebrain revealed by con&quot;.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">bind choline acetyltransferase and Phaseolus vulgaris 
    leucoagglutinjn immunohistochemistry.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Neurosci.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Lett. 66281-286.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Young, W.S., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">Heimer (1984) The ventral pallidal projec.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">tion to the medicdorsal thalamus: A study with 
    fluorescent retrograde tracers and immunohistofluorescence.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Neurosci. 4:1626-1638.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Zaborszky, L., J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Carlsen, H.R.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Brashear, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Heimer (1986a) Cholinergic and GABAergic afferent$ to 
    the olfactory bulb in the rat with special emphasis on the 
    projection neurons in the nucleus of the horizontal limb Of the 
    hand.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Ncurol. 24&apos;3&apos;488-509.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">ZahorszkY, L., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Hcimer, F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Eckenstein, and C.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Leranth (1986b) GABAergic input to cholinergic forebrain 
    neurons: An Ultrastructural study using retrob&apos;ade tracing of 
    HRP and double immunolabelling.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">J.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Neu.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">rol. 250282-295.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Zaborsky, L., G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Alheid, V.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Alone% W.H.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">Oertel, D.E.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Schmeckel, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Heimer (1982) AfYerents of the ventral pallidum studied 
    with i( combined immunohistochcmical-anteroaade degeneration 
    method. sot.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s721">N ~ ~ ~ Abstr. . ~ 8:218, ~ ~ , .</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s722">Zahm, D.S., L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s723">Zaborszky, G.F.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s724">Alheid, and L.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s725">Heimer (1987) The ventral striatopallidothalamic 
    projection: 11.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s726">The ventral pallidothalamic link.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s727">J: Comp.</S>
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s728">Neurol. 255.592-605.</S>
  </References>

</File>

