<?xml version='1.0'?>
<File>

  <Title>The Ventral Striatopallidothalamic Projection: I. The 
  Striatopallidal Link Originating in the Striatal Parts of the 
  Olfactory Tubercle</Title>

  <Authors>L. HEIMER, L. ZABORSZKY, D.S. ZAHM, AND G.F. ALHEID</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The projections from the striatal part of the olfactory 
    tubercle were examined in rats, both with the aid of experimental 
    silver impregnation methods following superficial laminar heat 
    lesions of the tubercle and by the use of anterograde transport of 
    Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHAL) following injections of 
    the lectin in the dense cell layer of the tubercle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">Retrograde transport of fluorescent substances following 
    injections of the tracer in the multiform layer of the tubercle 
    were used to corroborate the results obtained by the anterograde 
    transport and degeneration methods.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">The main and apparently only significant termination from 
    the striatal cells in the olfactory tubercle is located immediately 
    deep to the dense cell layer in areas that could be identified as 
    part of the ventral pallidum on the basis of either the Nissl 
    method or glutamate decarboxylase immunocytochemistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Whereas a mediolateral topography is generally maintained 
    by the ventral striatopallidal pathway originating in the dense 
    cell layer, there is a considerable spread of the projection in the 
    rostrocaudal direction.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">The dense projection field of the olfactory tubercle 
    component of the ventral striatopallidal pathway permeates the 
    ventrolateral part of the ventral pallidum, thereby complementing 
    the termination of the accumbens projection to the more mediodorsal 
    parts of the ventral pallidum.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">The rodent olfactory tubercle (Tu) is a complex 
    structure.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">Its cells encompass a broad spectrum of sizes and shapes 
    with medium and large neurons as the predominant forms.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">In addition, there are striking aggregates of tightly 
    packed small cells in the islands of Calleja and in the cap-regions 
    of the dense cell layer (e.g., Fallon et al., 83; Millhouse and 
    Heimer, 84; Heimer et al., 85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s9">Because Nissl-stained 
    sections of the Tu give the impression of a laminated structure and 
    because the Tu, like the neighboring primary olfactory (piriform) 
    cortex, receives olfactory bulb projections, the Tu has generally 
    been considered part of the olfactory cortex (e.g., Crosby and 
    Humphrey, 41; Heimer, 68; Haberly and Price, 78).</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s10">A major input to the Tu, 
    furthermore, consists of fibers from the olfactory cortex (Haberly 
    and Price, 78).</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s11">However, the apparent 
    lack of a reciprocal pathway from the Tu back to primary olfactory 
    cortex is not in harmony with the notion that the Tu represents a 
    cortical structure (Heimer and van Hoesen, 79).</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s12">Furthermore, 
    acetylcholinesterase histochemAccepted July 24, 1986.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s13">Address reprint requests 
    to Lennart Heimer, M.D., University of Virginia School of Medicine, 
    Department of Otolaryngology, Box 430, Charlottesville, VA 
    22908.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s14">L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s15">Heimer s present address 
    is the Department of Otolaryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, 
    University of Virginia Medical School, Charlottesville, VA 
    22908.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s16">L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s17">Zaborszky is on leave of 
    absence from Semmelweis University, Hungary.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s18">D.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s19">Zahm s present address is 
    the Department of Anatomy, St.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s20">Louis University School 
    of Medicine, 1402 S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s21">Grand Blvd., St.</S>
     
    <S avgH="20" class="introduction.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s22">Louis, MO 63104.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">istry (Switzer et al., &apos;821, immunocytochemistry 
    (Haber and Nauta, &apos;81, &apos;83; Zaborszky et al., &apos;821, 
    and Golgi studies (Millhouse and Heimer, &apos;84) have provided 
    evidence favoring expansion of the boundaries of the corpus 
    striatum to encompass the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">Specifically, we have proposed that the medium-sized cell 
    territories of the Tu represent a ventral part of the striatum 
    (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75; Heimer, &apos;78; Heimer and van 
    Hoesen, &apos; 7 9 Heimer et al., &apos;82; Heimer et al., 
    &apos;85).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">In terms of connectivity, pathways from the allocortex 
    (Heimer, &apos;72), the intralaminar thalamic nuclei (Newman and 
    Winans, &apos;80; Beckstead, &apos;84; Zaborszky et al., &apos;85), 
    the amygdaloid body (Krettek and Price, &apos;781, and the 
    dopaminergic cell groups of the ventral tegmental area (Fuxe, 
    &apos;65; Ungerstedt, &apos;71; Hedreen and Chalmers, &apos;72), 
    which converge on the Tu, are more consistent with a striatal than 
    cortical system of afTerents.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Fibers reported to originate in the superficial dense 
    cell layer of Tu, and that terminate in a rostroventral part of the 
    globus pallidus (i.e., the &quot;ventral pallidum,&quot; Heimer and 
    Wilson, &quot;75), also argue in favor of considering the 
    superficial medium-sized cell territories as part of striatum 
    (Heimer et al., &apos;75; GoldSchmidt and Heimer, &apos;80; 
    Zaborszky et al., &apos;82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The following report is a comprehensive description of 
    the ventral striatopallidal pathway originating in the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">The results produced by reduced silver impregnation 
    techniques following superficial, laminar heat lesions of the Tu 
    have been supplemented by a description of the anterograde 
    transport of the plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin 
    (PHA-L), from neurons in the superficial laminae of the Tu.</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s29">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s30">General</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">All surgery was performed under general anesthesia using 
    either sodium pentobarbital (50 mgkg) or Chloropent@ (3.3 mlkg).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">Male Sprague-Dawley albino rats were used for all 
    experiments and were housed in a temperature-controlled vivarium 
    (21°C) with a 12/12 hour light-dark cycle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">For lesion experiments 100-150 gm rats were used, while 
    for experiments using anterograde or retrograde transport, the rats 
    weighed 175-200 gm.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s34">Superficial laminar heat 
    lesions</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">The olfactory tubercle (Tu) was exposed from the lateral 
    side by removing the superficial muscle and bone tissue in the 
    subtemporal region of the head.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">If a large enough opening is made, a heated silver plate, 
    attached to a soldering iron, can easily be slipped underneath the 
    Tu and a superficial lesion produced by leaving the silver plate in 
    contact with the surface of the Tu for 2-5 seconds.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">By keeping the temperature of the silver plate at about 
    70°C, the blood vessels in the area are usually not severely 
    damaged, which in turn minimizes the risk for bleedings and 
    necroses deep to the superficial lesion.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Another advantage of the laminar coagulation technique is 
    that the size and depth of the lesion can be reasonably well 
    controlled.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s39">Silver impregnation of 
    degeneration</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Forty rats were given laminar heat lesions of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">Following 1-7 days survival time, the animals were 
    perfused and their brains processed for subsequent impregnation 
    with the Fink and Heimer (&apos;67), the cupric silver (de Olmos, 
    &apos;691, or the Gallyas et al. (&apos;80) methods for visualizing 
    degenerating axons and terminals.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s42">Electron microscopy of 
    axonal degeneration</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">Thirty-three rats were prepared for electron microscopic 
    investigation of degeneration.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">Of these, 5 cases were eliminated due to poor 
    preservation and an additional 11 were not analyzed for this 
    experiment because the lesion extended beyond the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">Following the laminar heat lesions in the Tu, the animals 
    were allowed to survive for periods that ranged from 16-72 
    hours.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Under general anesthesia, the rats were perfused through 
    the ascending aorta with a mixture of 1% paraformaldehyde and 1.25% 
    glutaraldehyde in a 0.12 M sodium phosphate buffer (modified from 
    Karnovsky, &apos;65).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">After the perfusion, the brains were exposed and left 
    overnight at 4°C in fresh fixative.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Tissue slabs containing the ventral pallidum (VP) were 
    cut by hand or with the vibratome (40 pm) in the frontal plane.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">The tissue was rinsed in 5% sucrose buffer, postfixed for 
    one hour in 2% osmium tetroxide in sucrose buffer, dehydrated in 
    graded ethanols, and embedded in araldite or a mixture of 
    epon-araldite.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">For light microscopic orientation, 5 pm semithin sections 
    were cut from the blocks and stained either with methylent?</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">blue-azure I1 (Richardson et al., &apos;60) or with 
    silver for the demonstration of degenerating boutons (Heimer, 
    &apos;70).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">Thin sections were cut from areas where degenerating 
    boutons were impregnated.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="25" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s53">Lectin injections and 
    immunocytochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Nine rats received iontophoretic injections of phaseolus 
    vulgaris-leuco agglutinin (PHA-L; Vector Labs) at various 
    rostrocaudal levels of the dense cell layer of the Tu and in 
    adjacent loci in the basal forebrain.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">Glass micropipettes with tip diameters of 10-20 pm 
    (O.D.)</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">were pulled from one millimeter (O.D.) glass tubing 
    containing a glass fiber.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">PHA-L (2.5% in 0.1 M sodium phosphate buffered saline; pH 
    7.4; NaPBS) was drawn into the tip of the pipette with suction 
    until the pipette was filled to its shank.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">A fine silver wire was immersed in the PHA-L solution in 
    the pipette and attached to the output of a constant voltage 
    stimulator.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">The filled pipettes were held in an electrode carrier 
    mounted on a David Kopf micromanipulator.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Under general anesthesia, the scalps of the rats were 
    opened and the return lead for the stimulator was attached to one 
    flap of the wounds.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Electrode placements were made through burr holes in the 
    skull with the aid of the atlas of Paxinos and Watson 
    (&apos;82).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Coordinates in the following ranges were used 0.7-2.2 mm 
    in front of the bregma, 1.0-2.2 mm lateral to the midline, and 
    7.2-8.6 mm beneath the dura.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s63">When the pipette tips were positioned satisfactorily, 
    iontophoretic injections were made with a pulsed 4-5 pA positive 
    current for 15-20 minutes (50% duty cycle and 1 pulse/7 sec).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">The current was monitored using a microammeter and held 
    relatively constant by adjusting the output voltage of the 
    stimulator.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">After 10 days survival, injected rats were reanesthetized 
    and perfused through the heart, first briefly with a rinse of NaPBS 
    containing 2.5% sucrose and 0.5% procaine hydrochloride, and then 
    with 0.07 M Sorenson s phosphate buffer (SPB) containing 4% 
    paraformaldehyde, 0.1% glutaraldehyde, and 2.5% sucrose.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">Following 15-20 minutes of fixation, unbound aldehydes 
    were washed out by perfusing a second time with the rinse 
    solution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">The brains were removed immediately and stored overnight 
    in NaPBS containing 30% sucrose.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">The following day, 4 series of 40 pm frozen sections were 
    collected in NaPBS at the sliding microtome.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">These were treated with antiserum against (1) PHA-L, (2) 
    glutamate decarboxylase (GAD), or (3) both GAD and PHA-L.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Immunofluorescence microscopy was used to make a rapid 
    assessment of the injection site and transport of the lectin.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Sections prepared for immunofluorescence were incubated 
    for 1 hour in NaPBS containing 0.25% lambda-carrageenan (Sigma), 
    0.25% Triton X-100 (Sigma), and PHA-L antiserum diluted 1:750 
    (Vector Labs).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">After three quick rinses for a total of 10-15 minutes, 
    the sections were incubated for 1 hour in the same carrier solution 
    containing a 1:lOO dilution of antigoat IgG antiserum conjugated to 
    fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Another quick series of rinses preceded mounting of the 
    sections on pig-gelled glass slides.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The sections were then coverslipped with a 1:3 solution 
    of glycerol and 0.1 M lithium carbonate (pH 11) and immediately 
    viewed using the epifluorescence microscope filtered appropriately 
    for FITC.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">In cases where the injection site and transport were 
    judged suitable by immunofluorescence, the rest of the sections 
    were placed in NaPBS containing 0.25% lambda-carrageenan, 0.125% 
    Triton X-100, and either anti-PHA-L (1:2,000) or anti-GAD 
    (1:8,000), or both anti-PHA-L (1:2,000) and anti-GAD (1:8,000) 
    overnight at 4°C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s76">The following morning, the sections were washed 3 times 
    in NaPBS over at least 1 hour and then placed in the same carrier 
    solution containing biotinylated antigoat IgG diluted 1:200 for 1 
    hour at room temperature.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">After another series of 3 rinses over at least 1 hour, 
    the sections were incubated for 1 hour in the same carrier solution 
    containing avidin and biotinylated horseradish peroxidase (KRP), 
    each at a 1:200 dilution.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">Another series of rinses preceded a 1-hour incubation at 
    room temperature in a solution of NaPBS (100 ml) containing 50 mg 
    of diaminobenzidine, 40 mg of NH4Cl, 200 mg of P-D-glucose, and 0.4 
    mg of glucose oxidase (modified from Itoh et al., 79).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s79">Sections were then rinsed again, mounted on slides, and 
    air-dried on a slide warmer.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s80">Immunostaining was intensified by sequential incubations 
    in 0.005% aqueous Os04 for 20-30 minutes, thiocarbohydrazide (0.1 
    g/lOO ml, 10 minutes), and 0.005% Os04 (10 minutes) with brief 
    intervening rinses in running tap water (C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Gerfen, personal communication).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">Sections were then dehydrated in a graded series of 
    alcohols and lightly counterstained by incubating them in absolute 
    alcohol containing 0.025% toluidine blue for 20-30 minutes, 
    followed by 2 quick dips in absolute alcohol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">They were then cleared in xylene and coverslipped with 
    Permount.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">In both this and the following experiment, incubation in 
    the absence of anti-PHA-L, or in the presence of both antiPHA-L and 
    50 pgiml PHA-L, did not produce staining of cells, axons, or 
    terminals.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">The GAD antibody has already been extensively 
    characterized (Oertel et al., 81, 82).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s86">Electron microscopy of 
    anterogradely transported PHA-L</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">PHA-L was injected into the Tu of 4 rats as described in 
    the preceding paragraph.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">Following perfusion with the solutions specified above, 
    the brains were removed immediately and small blocks containing the 
    Tu were sunk in 15% sucrose, frozen in liquid nitrogen, thawed and 
    cut on the Oxford vibratome into 50 pm sections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">Three series of sections were cut.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">The first series was subjected to immunofluorescence 
    using PHA-L antiserum as described above to evaluate the success of 
    uptake and transport.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91">When successful transport was detected, the remaining 
    sections were pooled and placed overnight at 4°C in a 1:2,000 
    dilution of anti-PHA-L in NaPBS containing 0.25% lambda-carrageenan 
    without triton.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">The following day the sections were rinsed 3 times in 
    NaPBS over a period of 45 minutes, and placed in buffer containing 
    biotinylated antigoat antibodies (MOO), again rinsed, and placed in 
    buffer containing the avidin-biotin-peroxidase complex (1:200) for 
    2 hours at room temperature.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">The peroxidase was reacted using a modification of the 
    Itoh et al. ( 79) glucose oxidase reaction, and the sections were 
    rinsed, osmicated, and embedded in Araldite 6005 (EMS) on plastic 
    slides with plastic coverslips.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94">Following polymerization, sections were viewed and 
    photographed with transmitted light.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">Areas selected for EM were centered and fastened with 
    Epoxy adhesive to the top of a blank plastic stub.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96">Thin sections were cut and viewed in a Zeiss 109 electron 
    microscope.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s97">Retrograde labeling with 
    a fluorescent tracer</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">Under general anesthesia, 6 rats received small 
    injections of the retrograde fluorescent tracer fast blue (Dr.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99">Illing, West Germany; 10% in 2% dimethyl sulfoxide) aimed 
    at the multiform layer of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100">In order to avoid labeling of the cannula tract, 
    micropipettes with 40-100 pm O.D. were chronically implanted 
    (Alheid and Carlsen, 82) and the tracer allowed to diffuse out.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">After 10-14 days survival time, the animals were 
    reanesthetized, and perfused through the ascending aorta.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Following a brief rinse, a twostage fixation was used 
    consisting of 250 ml of a solution containing 1% tannic acid, 4% 
    formaldehyde, and 0.1 M MgS04, followed by 250 ml of an identical 
    fixative but without the tannic acid.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">The brains were removed, cryoprotected in 30% sucrose 
    until they sank, and subsequently frozen sectioned on a cryostat at 
    30 pm.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">Two series were saved from every 5 sections and 
    thaw-mounted on gelatinized slides.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s105">One series was coverslipped with DPX (BDH Ltd., England) 
    without further staining or clearing, and the second, adjacent 
    series was counterstained with cresylviolet.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="26" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s106">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s107"><labelingLocation>the 
    extent of the ventral pallidum ( vp</labelingLocation> )</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108">intense gad immunoreactivity ( gad - ir ) is coextensive 
    in <neuroanatomicalLocation>the forebrain with globus 
    pallidus</neuroanatomicalLocation>  ( ribak et al . , 79 ) and 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>vp</neuroanatomicalLocation> ( zaborszky 
    et al . , 82 young et al . , 84 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">parasagittal sections , which pass approximately through 
    the middle of the tu ( fig . l ) , display the maximal extent of 
    the gad - ir continuum and thus serve to illustrate 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the vp and its continuity with the globus 
    pallidus</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">the most ventral part of this continuum forms a 
    distinctly gad immunoreactive stratum of tubercle neuropil , which 
    is oriented horizontally deep to <labelingLocation>the dense cell 
    layer of the tu</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">this stratum is in many places very closely associated 
    with <labelingDescription>the dense , tubular cell 
    collections</labelingDescription> of <labelingLocation>the islands 
    of calleja</labelingLocation> ( see also fallon et al . , 83 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112">the gad - ir lamina runs longitudinally between the 
    rostral and caudal tips of the tu , and is joined by the more 
    massive gad - ir ventral extension from <labelingLocation>the 
    globus pallidus at approximately the midsection of the caudal half 
    of the tu</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">at <labelingLocation>the region of this articulation , 
    ventral pallidum ( vp )</labelingLocation> is penetrated by the 
    longitudinally oriented fascicles of the medial forebrain bundle 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114">Rostrally, the GADIR region descending from the globus 
    pallidus is bounded by the ventral parts of the caudate-putamen and 
    the nucleus accumbens.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">its posterior neighbors are<neuroanatomicalLocation> the 
    sublenticular substantia innominata</neuroanatomicalLocation> 
    dorsally , and elements of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the diagonal 
    band system</neuroanatomicalLocation> ventrally .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116"><neuroanatomicalLocation>the mediolateral extent of 
    vp</neuroanatomicalLocation> is more readily appreciated in coronal 
    sections ( fig . 2 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">within <neuroanatomicalLocation>the tu the width of 
    vp</neuroanatomicalLocation> corresponds to that of the multiform 
    layer of the tu .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118">dorsomedially elements of vp appear interspersed between 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nucleus accumbens and vertical limb of 
    the diagonal band</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s119">The ventral 
    striatopallidal projection originating in the dense cell layer of 
    the olfactory tubercle (Tu)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120">The following results are based on three different 
    methods that provide independent and complementary demonstrations 
    of the axonal projections originating in <labelingLocation>the 
    dense cell layer of the Tu</labelingLocation>.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121"><labelingLocation>the silver impregnation of axonal 
    degeneration</labelingLocation> following superficial heat lesions 
    in the tu produced <labelingLocation>a reasonably complete picture 
    of the termination areas of the projections from the superficial 
    cell layer of the tu</labelingLocation> , while the use of the 
    anterogradely transported lectin , <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> , and the retrograde fluorescent tracer allowed 
    the cells of origin to be reliably identified .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s122">Degeneration studies</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">superficial heat lesions involving extensive areas of 
    the tu surface ( fig . 3a ) suggested that the most massive 
    projection field of the pathway from <connxOrigin>the superficial 
    part of the tu</connxOrigin> is restricted to <connxTermination>the 
    vp</connxTermination> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124">This is clearly demonstrated in parasagittal sections 
    (Fig. 4), where VP can be most easily appreciated.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125"><labelingDescription>heavy terminal 
    degeneration</labelingDescription> was seen in 
    <labelingLocation>the multiform layer of tu</labelingLocation> and 
    in <labelingLocation>the vp immediately dorsal to the medial 
    forebrain bundle</labelingLocation> , which also exhibits 
    degeneration but primarily in 
    <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126">sections prepared for electron microscopy ( fig . 5a , b 
    ) demonstrated that following laminar heat lesions , 
    <labelingDescription>many degenerating 
    boutons</labelingDescription> appeared in <labelingLocation>the 
    areas</labelingLocation> where terminal degeneration was indicated 
    by the presence of argyrophilic particles in the light microscopic 
    analysis .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127">in other words ,<labelingLocation> vp 
    areas</labelingLocation> , which showed <labelingDescription>the 
    presence of terminal degeneration</labelingDescription> in silver 
    impregnated , semithin plastic embedded sections , were seen to 
    contain <labelingDescription>a larger number of degenerating 
    boutons</labelingDescription> characterized primarily by increased 
    electron density of the axoplasm .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">the increased density was obvious in 
    <labelingLocation>many boutons</labelingLocation> already in 
    animals with 16 - 18 hours survival ( fig . 5a ) , and 
    <labelingDescription>the boutons</labelingDescription> often 
    appeared collapsed and surrounded by astroglial processes a few 
    hours later ( fig . 5b ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><labelingDescription>the degenerating 
    boutons</labelingDescription> were usually scattered among 
    <labelingDescription>a series of normal 
    boutons</labelingDescription> , which ensheathed large dendrites 
    like a sleeve in a fashion typical for both 
    <labelingLocation>dorsal and ventral pallidum</labelingLocation> ( 
    fox et al . , 74 heimer and wilson , 75 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s130">it came as no surprise that <labelingDescription>all 
    degenerating boutons</labelingDescription> seemed to establish 
    symmetric contacts with pallidal dendrites , since that is the 
    typical pattern also for the striatopallidal projection system in 
    the dorsal part of the basal ganglia ( kemp , 70 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">the overall distribution of 
    <connxOrigin>tu</connxOrigin> 
    <labelingDescription>fibers</labelingDescription> projecting to 
    <connxTermination>the vp</connxTermination> is depicted in figure 6 
    , which is a diagrammatic representation of the degeneration 
    pattern following a large laminar heat lesion .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">due to the proximity of 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>vp</neuroanatomicalLocation> to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the ventral surface of the 
    tu</neuroanatomicalLocation> , it was occasionally difficult to 
    discriminate terminal degeneration from the increased argyrophilia 
    that usually surrounded the experimental lesion .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133">Nevertheless, it was generally possible, even at rostral 
    levels, to identify terminal degeneration relatively close to the 
    lesion (Fig. 6A).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134">it should be noted that striatal cell bridges , which 
    extend from <labelingLocation>the ventral parts of the nucleus 
    accumbens and caudate - putamen to the dense cell layer of the 
    tu</labelingLocation> and which are a striking cytological feature 
    of the rostral tubercle ( nauta and haymaker , 69 heimer , 781 , 
    were consistently avoided by terminal degeneration ( fig . 6a , b ) 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">nor were significant amounts of degeneration found in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral parts of accumbens or caudate - 
    putamen</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">At more caudal levels, where the VP expands dorsally 
    (Fig. 6B), the lesion was less likely to interfere with the clear 
    recognition of terminal degeneration.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">at these levels , where <labelingLocation>the boundaries 
    between striatal and pallidal territories</labelingLocation> are 
    pronounced , it was easy to appreciate the fact that the terminal 
    degeneration not only was restricted to , but nearly filled , 
    <labelingLocation>the ventrolateral part of vp</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138">indeed , <labelingDescription>the massive terminal 
    degeneration</labelingDescription> stops abruptly along an 
    undulating curved line that defines the ventral boundary of 
    <labelingLocation>the caudate - putamen</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">near <neuroanatomicalLocation>the caudal tip of the 
    tu</neuroanatomicalLocation> , <neuroanatomicalLocation>the nucleus 
    of the horizontal limb of the diagonal 
    band</neuroanatomicalLocation> ( hdb ) makes its appearance ( fig . 
    6c ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140">Significant accumulations of terminal degeneration 
    appeared both below and above <labelingLocation>the 
    HDB</labelingLocation>, which appeared not to contain terminal 
    degeneration.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">On the dorsolateral aspect of <labelingLocation>the 
    HDB</labelingLocation>, the terminal degeneration formed a 
    characteristic cap (arrow in Figs. 6C, 71, which ended rather 
    abruptly just caudal to this level.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142">bands of terminal degeneration , representing pallidal 
    bridges , could be observed to sweep around <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral edge of the hdb</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6c ) to 
    establish continuity with terminal degeneration in 
    <labelingLocation>the multiform layer of the tu below the 
    hdb</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">whereas the degeneration above <labelingLocation>the 
    hdb</labelingLocation> could be appreciated as typical terminal 
    degeneration , that below the hdb appeared to include 
    <labelingDescription>both terminals and axons of 
    passage</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">above and below hdb , terminal degeneration stopped 
    abruptly at <labelingLocation>the caudal tip of the 
    tu</labelingLocation> , but degenerating 
    <labelingDescription>axons</labelingDescription> could be followed 
    dorsally to <labelingLocation>the mediodorsal nucleus of the 
    thalamus ( md )</labelingLocation> , and often in 
    <labelingLocation>the medial forebrain bundle</labelingLocation> to 
    more caudal parts of <labelingLocation>the lateral 
    hypothalamus</labelingLocation> , including <labelingLocation>the 
    nuclei gemini</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145">Although it was not a particular focus of this 
    experiment, we did not see evidence for terminations in 
    <labelingLocation>the mesencephalon</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s146"><tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> studies</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">one of the advantages of the <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> method is its ability to demonstrate cell 
    morphology at the origin of the pathway under study ( gerfen and 
    sawchenko , 84 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">this feature is of particular value in 
    <labelingLocation>the tu</labelingLocation> , where striatal and 
    pallidal cell territories are often intermingled .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149">the approximate location of the <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> injection in <injectionLocation>the superficial 
    dense cell layer of the tu</injectionLocation> is indicated in 
    figure 3b .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150">following injection of <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the dense cell layer of 
    the tu</injectionLocation> , clusters of neurons displaying a 
    golgilike impregnation of immunoreactive product marked the centers 
    of the injection sites ( fig . 8 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">The clusters typically were 100300 pm in diameter and 
    were located near the centers of spherical or ovoid halos of 
    variably dense, diffusely deposited reaction product.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152">The halos were generally 200-500 pm in diameter.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">Impregnated dendrites radiated through the zones of 
    diffusely deposited reaction product, and fully impregnated 
    perikarya could commonly be observed near the periphery of the 
    diffusely labeled zone.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">the morphological detail exhibited by 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> impregnation rivals that 
    of a golgi impregnation .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155">this was particularly illustrated by 
    <labelingDescription>neurons</labelingDescription> at some distance 
    from the central cluster , which , hence , were relatively 
    unobscured by other impregnated neural elements .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">for example , injections centered in 
    <labelingLocation>the medium - sized cell territories of the 
    tu</labelingLocation> revealed dendrites that were studded with 
    dendritic spines .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">This feature can be appreciated even in the low 
    magnification photograph in Figure 8A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">injection of <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> 
    into <injectionLocation>the plexiform layer of the 
    tu</injectionLocation> often resulted in the impregnation of 
    neurons in <injectionSpread>the dense cell layer and most 
    superficial part of multiform layer</injectionSpread> , which 
    appeared to represent a single morphological class resembling the 
    striatal medium spiny neuron ( e . g . , kemp and powell , 71 chang 
    et al . , 82 ) with a diameter of 10 - 20 pm , and dendrites that 
    radiated from the impregnated neurons in all directions .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">Many dendrites were oriented perpendicular to the pial 
    surface of the Tu, and they appeared to extend ventrally all the 
    way into the plexiform layer, even when the impregnated cells were 
    located deep in the multiform layer.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">in fact , we were never successful in impregnating only 
    neurons of the dense cell layer , even when the <tracerChemical>pha 
    - l</tracerChemical> appeared to have been deposited in 
    <injectionLocation>the plexiform layer</injectionLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">following less superficial injections of 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> involving 
    <injectionLocation>deeper layers of the tu</injectionLocation> , 
    more than one morphological class of neurons frequently exhibited 
    the characteristic golgilike impregnation .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s162">in addition to <labelingDescription>the medium - sized , 
    putatively striatal neurons</labelingDescription> , medium to large 
    ( 15 - 25 pm ) <labelingDescription>fusiform 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were observed , which typically had 3 
    to 5 large primary dendrites , which extended relatively long 
    distances from the impregnated perikarya with 
    <labelingDescription>little or moderate amounts of 
    branching</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">These resembled pallida1 -type neurons (Millhouse and 
    Heimer, 84; Iwahori and Mizuno, 80) and were present in 
    <labelingLocation>VP-territories of the Tu</labelingLocation>.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">since the sections stained with <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> could be conveniently alternated with sections 
    stained for gad , the positions of impregnated cells as well as 
    <labelingDescription>their terminal fields</labelingDescription> 
    identified in the <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> section 
    could be matched with the topographic distribution of 
    <labelingLocation>ventral pallidal areas</labelingLocation> as 
    revealed by gad - ir on nearby sections ( fig . 9 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">The light microscopic appearance of anterogradely 
    transported PHAL consisted of <labelingDescription>a large number 
    of isolated puncta</labelingDescription>, many of which were joined 
    by threadlike interconnections (Fig. 9B).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">following restricted injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the superficial part of the 
    tu</injectionLocation> , <labelingDescription>such areas of 
    terminal labeling</labelingDescription> were invariably identified 
    in <labelingLocation>neighboring parts of vp</labelingLocation> , 
    usually with additional <labelingDescription>terminal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>more remote 
    caudodorsal areas of vp</labelingLocation> ( figs . 10 , 11 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167">electron microscopic observations confirmed that the 
    puncta seen in <labelingDescription>the light microscope were 
    indeed labeled boutons</labelingDescription> in contact with 
    typical pallidallike dendrites ( fig . 5c see also zahm and heimer 
    , 85 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">another striking feature is presented by the appearance 
    of <labelingDescription>terminal labeling</labelingDescription> 
    among the fascicles of <labelingLocation>the medial forebrain 
    bundle ( mfb )</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">this phenomenon is easily understood when one realizes 
    that ventral pallidal components invade <labelingLocation>the area 
    of the mfb</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170">Indeed, one of the most obvious topographical relations 
    of <labelingLocation>the rostra1 part of the MFB</labelingLocation> 
    is represented by its close relations to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the VP</neuroanatomicalLocation>, which in 
    many places completely surrounds the fascicles of the MFB 
    (Zaborszky et al., 86).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s171">this is most easily appreciated in gad - stained 
    sections ( fig . 9a ) , which were prepared as complement to the 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> sections , and for the 
    purpose of outlining in detail <neuroanatomicalLocation>ventral 
    pallidal areas</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">this close correlation of anterogradely transported 
    <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> with <labelingLocation>the 
    areas of ventral pallidum</labelingLocation> in nearby sections 
    stained for gad provided convincing demonstration of the 
    termination of the ventral striatopallidal pathway within 
    <labelingLocation>vp areas surrounding the fascicles of the 
    mfb</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">fibers ending in <labelingLocation>vp</labelingLocation> 
    appeared to represent the entire projection of <connxOrigin>the 
    superficial dense cell layer of the tu</connxOrigin> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">when injections were less superficial and involved 
    <labelingDescription>larger cells</labelingDescription> in the 
    multiform layer , long projections to known pallidal targets such 
    as <connxTermination>mediodorsal thalamic nucleus and substantia 
    nigra</connxTermination> were observed in addition to the 
    projections just described .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">in addition , control injections placed in 
    <injectionLocation>the nucleus accumbens</injectionLocation> 
    resulted in anterograde transport of the lectin to a number of 
    targets including <labelingLocation>vp , lateral hypothalamus , the 
    ventral tegmental area</labelingLocation> , and 
    <labelingLocation>substantia nigra</labelingLocation>  , as well as 
    <labelingLocation>cell groups in tegmentum of the pons and 
    medulla</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s176">if the absence of downstream projections following 
    superficial <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> injections in 
    <injectionLocation>the tu</injectionLocation> is the result of 
    inadequate transport of the lectin by those cells , there was no 
    evidence that nearby 
    <labelingDescription>cells</labelingDescription> in 
    <injectionSpread>the vp and other parts of the ventral 
    striatum</injectionSpread> shared the deficiency  .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s177">Labeling with retrograde 
    tracers</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Because of its limited dorsocaudal 
    extent,<injectionLocation> the multiform layer of the 
    Tu</injectionLocation> proved difficult to hit without direct 
    involvement of <injectionSpread>nearby laminae and structures 
    including the accumbens or the HDB</injectionSpread>.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">only 2 of the 6 injections were well centered within 
    <injectionLocation>the multiform layer of the 
    tu</injectionLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">In these, the rostrocaudal extent of the injection site 
    was quite limited with no tracer deposit in the overlying pipette 
    track.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">an injection centered in <injectionLocation>the 
    multiform layer of the tu</injectionLocation> labeled almost the 
    entire rostrocaudal extent of the dense cell layer ( arrow in fig . 
    12b ) , while labeling in <labelingLocation>the mediolateral 
    dimension</labelingLocation> was more confined .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">as expected from our anterograde experiments , 
    <labelingDescription>most labeled neurons</labelingDescription> 
    were in <labelingLocation>the dense cell layer of the 
    tubercle</labelingLocation> , with <labelingDescription>many fewer 
    and more scattered neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the deeper layers</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">of course , at more rostral levels , 
    <labelingDescription>labeled neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the deeper layers of the 
    tubercle</labelingLocation> may represent cells labeled through 
    axons traversing the injection site enroute to thalamus or caudal 
    hypothalamus .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">consistent with our anterograde experiments and with 
    observations in golgi material ( see below ) , 
    <labelingDescription>many neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>caudal tu</labelingLocation> were labeled by 
    rostral tracer injections , indicating the rostral course taken by 
    their axons before terminating in <labelingLocation>more dorsal 
    regions of vp</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s185">Topography of the 
    ventral striatopallidal projection originating in the olfactory 
    tubercle</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">There is a definite mediolateral topography in the 
    ventral striatopallidal projection originating in <connxOrigin>the 
    striatal parts of the Tu</connxOrigin>.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">in other words , small superficial laminar heat lesions 
    give rise to areas of <labelingDescription>dense terminal 
    degeneration</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>vp</labelingLocation> immediately deep to the 
    lesion ( see fig . 13 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">this impression is supported by the results obtained 
    with the <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> method ( fig . 9 
    ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">if <neuroanatomicalLocation>the dense cell layer and the 
    overlying horizontal lamina of vp</neuroanatomicalLocation> are 
    imagined as planar structures marked with coordinate grids in the 
    rostrocaudal and mediolateral dimensions , the origins and 
    <labelingDescription>most dense terminations of 
    projections</labelingDescription> from <connxOrigin>the dense cell 
    layer</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>suprajacent 
    vp</connxTermination> are located in corresponding positions on the 
    respective grids .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">This is especially the case for the rostral 
    three-fourths of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">furthermore , from each locus of 
    <labelingDescription>dense termination</labelingDescription> within 
    <labelingLocation>the horizontal lamina of vp</labelingLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>an additional more moderate number of 
    fibers</labelingDescription> <labelingModifier>extend caudally to 
    terminate</labelingModifier> within <labelingLocation>the pallidal 
    core of the tu</labelingLocation> or to ascend to 
    <labelingLocation>more dorsal parts of the vp</labelingLocation> 
    along the same parasagittal coordinate , diminishing gradually in 
    more caudal sections ( figs . 10 , ll ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">an interesting phenomenon , first observed in golgi 
    studies ( millhouse and heimer , &apos; 84 ) , is that many of 
    <labelingDescription>the fibers</labelingDescription> originating 
    in <connxOrigin>the superficial caudolateral part of the 
    tu</connxOrigin> first sweep forward in a rostrally convex curve to 
    circumvent the hdb before turning caudally to end in 
    <connxTermination>more dorsal parts of the vp</connxTermination> 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">This projection is illustrated in Figures 6C and 7, in 
    which the terminal degeneration forms a characteristic cap 
    immediately above the HDB.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s194"><labelingDescription>the projection 
    fibers</labelingDescription> from <labelingLocation>the caudomedial 
    part of the dense cell layer</labelingLocation> are somewhat 
    exceptional in the sense that they have a tendency to sweep 
    laterally and to some extent even rostrally to terminations in 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>ventral pallidal areas within the 
    multiform layer</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s195">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">The olfactory tubercle (Tu) of the rat has traditionally 
    been conceived of as part of the olfactory cortex, and there has 
    generally been little effort to recognize different subterritories 
    in the tubercle when its extrinsic connections have been 
    examined.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">Indeed, surveys (e.g., Stephan, &apos;75) of the 
    available literature on Tu connections have implied that the 
    tubercle is an integral part of the neighboring olfactory 
    (piriform) cortex in the sense that its extrinsic connections 
    seemed to be reminiscent of those of the olfactory cortex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">The similarities between the two structures were 
    perceived particularly on the basis of their efferent connections, 
    which according to most accounts were restricted primarily to 
    nearby olfactory related structures such as the olfactory bulb, 
    retrobulbar areas, amygdaloid body, and periamygdaloid cortex, as 
    well as the medial septum-diagonal band complex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">Efferent fibers from both the Tu and olfactory cortex, 
    furthermore, were generally thought to be incorporated in the 
    medial forebrain bundle and destined to reach the lateral 
    preoptic-hypothalamic continuum and the nuclei gemini, as well as 
    the mediodorsal thalamic nucleus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">It should be said in all fairness that the above 
    description of the Tu projections was based primarily on the study 
    of normal anatomical material and experimental silver impregnation 
    studies.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Modern tracer techniques have only occasionally been 
    applied to the study of the Tu connections, but when they have, the 
    results have not been altogether consistent with the preceding 
    schemes.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">For instance, an associative pathway from the tubercle 
    to neighboring olfactory or periamygdaloid cortices, which one 
    might reasonably have expected if the Tu is an integral part of the 
    primary olfactory cortex, has not been confirmed (e.g., Haberly and 
    Price, &apos;78).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Nor has much evidence come forward in support of a 
    significant pathway from the Tu to the septum-diagonal band 
    complex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">It also seems clear from retrograde tracing experiments 
    that the cells projecting from the Tu to bulbar or retrobulbar 
    areas are located, not in the Tu proper, but among the fascicles of 
    the medial forebrain bundle deep to the tubercle (e.g., Dennis and 
    Kerr, &apos;76; de Olmos et al., &apos;78; Zaborszky et al., 
    &apos;86).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">A pathway from the region of the Tu to the nuclei gemini 
    in the posterolateral part of the hypothalamus is well established 
    (Lundberg, &apos;60; Scott and Leonard, &apos;71; Heimer, &apos;72; 
    Scott and Chafh, &apos;75), but the identity and exact location of 
    the cells projecting to the nuclei gemini is not well specified.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">Nor is much known about the Tu projection to the lateral 
    preoptic-hypothalamic continuum, although the existence of such 
    projections was implicit in terms such as the &quot;deep olfactory 
    radiation&quot; (Dhjerine, 1895) and the &quot;olfactohypothalamic 
    system&quot; (Herrick, &apos;10).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">More recent Golgi studies (e.g., Valverde-Garcia, 
    &apos;65; Millhouse, &apos;69) have perpetuated this notion, but 
    studies employing experimental silver methods (e.g., Scott and 
    Leonard, &apos;71) have not produced much evidence for the 
    existence of a projection from the Tu to the lateral 
    preoptic-hypothalamic area.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">There is one olfactory tubercle projection, however, 
    whose cells of origin have been positively identified, namely the 
    projection to the mediodorsal thalamus (e.g., Siege1 et al., 
    &apos;77; Benjamin et al., &apos;82; Price and Slotnick, 
    &apos;83).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">Using a combination of fluorescent retrograde tracers 
    and immunohistochemical techniques, Young et al. (&apos;84) have 
    convincingly shown that the Tu projection to mediodorsal thalamus 
    originates from cells located in those parts of the Tu, which in 
    have been identified as the VP on the basis of GAD-IR.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s210">Since many of these 
    neurons also appear to have ultrastrucTu tural characteristics 
    typical for pallidal neurons, we have proposed that this Tu pathway 
    represents part of a general the pallidothalamic projection system 
    rather than a corticothalamic pathway (Young et al., &apos;84; Zahm 
    et al., &apos;86). the The ventral pallidum (VP)</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">In sagittal sections, the globus pallidus is 
    conventionally identified as a triangular structure above and 
    behind the anterior commissure.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">It is characteristically penetrated by the bundles of 
    the internal capsule.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">The rostroventral borthe der of the globus pallidus 
    underneath the anterior commisa sure has really never been well 
    defined, which in retrospect out is not surprising, since there is 
    now considerable evidence that such a border does not exist at this 
    level.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s214">Rather, the cytoarchitectural and histochemical 
    features, which are accepted as typically pallidal, extend as a 
    continuum to more the rostroventral parts of the forebrain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">We have referred to this rostroventral extension of 
    dense GAD-IR, which passes downward and forward into the multiform 
    layer of the Tu the as the &quot;ventral pallidum&quot; (Heimer, 
    &apos;78; Switzer, et al., &apos;82). ary The VP appears to be 
    composed of neurons similar, if not the identical in morphology, to 
    those in globus pallidus.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Most important in the context of the present report is 
    that VP seems to receive a well-organized and dense input from 
    striatallike neurons in nucleus accumbens and olfactory 
    tubercle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">The projection from nucleus accumbens to the the portion 
    of VP immediately ventral to the anterior commissure is well 
    documented (Wilson, &apos;72; Swanson and Cowan, &apos;75; Nauta et 
    al., &apos;78; Zaborszky et al., &apos;82; Haber and in Nauta, 
    &apos;83; Mogenson et al., &apos;83; Groenewegen and a Russchen, 
    &apos;841, while the projection from Tu to VP was only reported in 
    preliminary form (Heimer and Wilson, &apos;75; Goldschmidt and 
    Heimer, &apos;80; Zaborszky et al., &apos;82) prior to the present 
    paper.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">Together, the efferents from nucleus a accumbens and 
    from the dense cell layer of the Tu completely outline the VP, 
    which may be independently described by histochemistry for iron 
    (Switzer et al., &apos;82), or immunohistochemistry for GAD, 
    substance P, enkephalin, epidermal growth factor, or ferritin 
    (Haber and Nauta, &apos;81, to &apos;83; Zaborszky et al., 
    &apos;82; Young et al., &apos;84; Fallon et al., &apos;84; Martin 
    et al., &apos;851, and by retrograde labeling after large 
    injections in mediodorsal thalamus (Young et al., &apos;84).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">The results of the present experiments strengthen the 
    concept of the ventral striatopallidal system, while providing 
    additional details about the subdivision represented by the Tu.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s220">The ventral 
    striatopallidal projection originating in the striatal cell 
    territories of the olfactory tubercle</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">General distribution.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">It has now become apparent that the Tu represents the 
    most ventral component of the corpus striatum and that it contains 
    both ventral striatal and ventral pallidal cell territories (see 
    review by Heimer et al., &apos;85).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">The complicated cytology of the Tu, however, which 
    features extensive interdigitations of the various neuronal 
    populations and which has been described in detail by Millhouse and 
    Heimer (&apos;841, has conspired against forming definite 
    conclusions regarding the relations of the striatal and pallidal 
    components of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">When attempting to interpret the results obtained in 
    this study, it is important to realize that the medium-sized 
    densely spined striatal cells the superficial dense cell layer are 
    so numerically predominant that the superficial laminar heat 
    lesions of the were likely to involve predominantly striatal cells, 
    especially if the lesions were confined to restricted areas of 
    tubercle (see below).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">The laminar heat lesions were often well demarcated in 
    silver impregnated sections and surrounding tissue well preserved, 
    which made it possible in most instances to discriminate between 
    terminal degeneration and degenerating fibers of passage even in 
    regions close to the lesion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">As witnessed by the dense terminal degeneration obtained 
    after superficial but extensive Tu lesions (Figs. 4,6), ventral 
    striatopallidal pathway originating in the &apos;hi is prominent 
    projection system, which terminates throughthe main ventral and 
    lateral parts of the VP.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">In other words, its projection field is in general 
    restricted to the areas of VP that are located immediately above 
    the Tu, thereby leaving the dorsomedial parts of the VP free for 
    projections from the accumbens.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">The dense terminal degeneration, furthermore, is 
    strictly confined to the VP.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">This is convincingly demonstrated in Figure 4, in which 
    area of terminal degeneration exhibits a sharp boundboth toward the 
    caudate-putamen (CPu) dorsally and to nucleus of the horizontal 
    limb of the diagonal band (HDB) ventrally.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">The HDB, however, does contain degeneration, which has 
    the character of degenerating axons of passage, and it is a 
    reasonable assumption that they represent, in large part at least, 
    degenerating fibers on route to MD, nuclei gemini, and possibly 
    other areas of the upper brainstem.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">The series of more restricted laminar heat lesions, as 
    well as the PHA-L injections, which were placed various parts of 
    the Tu, served to confirm the presence of prominent and 
    well-defined ventral striatopallidal projection system within the 
    Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s232">Although the heavily corrugated dense cell layer reaches 
    the surface of the Tu in several places, it was nevertheless 
    possible in some cases to avoid more extensive involvement of the 
    deep multiform layer when making the small laminar heat lesions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">Degenerating fibers and terminal degeneration in such 
    instances were restricted to ventral pallidal areas in the Tu 
    region, and there was little or no sign of degeneration in Tu 
    pathways the mediodorsal thalamus or nuclei gemini, which was 
    typically the case if the multiform layer with its content of 
    pallidallike large cells had been included in the lesion.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">The results obtained by the PHA-L method provided some 
    additional insight, which cannot generally be obtained by studying 
    the pattern of degenerating axons and axon terminals as a result of 
    experimental lesions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">The most obvious advantage of the PHA-L method in this 
    study was fact that the injection in several cases appeared to have 
    involved only medium-sized densely spined neurons in the 
    superficial part of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Such injections resulted in transport of PHA-L to axon 
    terminals that were located entirely within the boundaries of 
    pallidal domains as identified by GAD immunocytochemistry on 
    adjacent sections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">Although is usually difficult to exclude the possibility 
    that PHA-L has been taken up by fibers passing through the 
    injection site, the likelihood for this type of complication is 
    quite remote in this case, especially since the injection is 
    located the surface of the brain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">Furthermore, there was never any evidence of terminal 
    labeling in the MD unless large pallidallike neurons had been 
    labeled in the area of the injections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">The initial report by Gerfen and Sawchenko (&apos;84), 
    finally, tend to show that labeling of fibers of passage does not 
    occur when using the PHA-L method.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="26" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s240">Topography in the 
    ventral striatopallidal pathway originating in the olfactory 
    tubercle</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">A significant finding of the present investigation is 
    that the mediolateral topography of the dense cell layer is 
    maintained by the ventral striatopallidal projection originating in 
    the dense cell layer of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">However, the projection is characterized by a 
    significant spread in the rostrocaudal direction.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">This was clearly demonstrated both in cases with small 
    laminar heat lesions and with restricted PHA-L injections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Indeed, even the experiments in which a retrograde 
    tracer was centered in themultiform layer of the Tu tended to 
    support this notion.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">In other words, the number of retrogradely labeled cells 
    in the dense cell layer decreased rather rapidly in a lateral and 
    medial direction away from the injection, while practically the 
    entire rostrocaudal extent of the dense cell layer was marked by 
    retrograde cell labeling in parasagittal sections (Fig. 12).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">Clearly, these retrograde tracing experiments are of 
    limited value by themselves, but they do provide some valuable 
    information and, as in this case, even a striking illustration of 
    some of the main features of the ventral striatopallidal pathway 
    when considered in conjunction with the results obtained by the 
    anterograde tracer methods used in this study.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">&quot;he topographic pattern described above is most 
    clearly revealed with the PHA-L method as illustrated schematically 
    in Figures 10 and 11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Injections of PHA-L, especially in the rostral one-half 
    to three-fourths of the superficial part of the Tu, give rise to 
    terminal labeling that is especially dense directly above in the VP 
    of the multiform layer.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">In addition, there is a considerable spread of the 
    projection in the sagittal plane, especially in caudal 
    direction.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">Hence, successively caudal primary projections are 
    supplemented by moderate secondary projections from more rostral 
    parts of the tubercle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">The spread of the terminations of the ventral 
    striatopallidal fibers in a rostrocaudal direction is reminiscent 
    of the spread of the striatopallidal fibers described by Chang et 
    al. (&apos;81) in the dorsal part of the basal ganglia.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">The presence of PHA-L labeled terminals among the 
    fascicles of the MFB (Fig. 9) no doubt reflects the fact that the 
    MFB penetrates the ventral pallidal territory deep to the Tu, and 
    in some places even appears to separate, at least partly, the most 
    ventral territory of the VP (that part located in the multiform 
    layer of the Tu) from the rest of the VP.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">This would seem to explain the rather common appearance 
    of two main foci or patches of labeled terminals or of terminal 
    degeneration, one below and another above the fascicles of the MFB, 
    especially in cases where the PHA-L injection or the heat lesion 
    was restricted to the more caudal parts of the Tu.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">That this phenomenon is most easily revealed in cases 
    with caudal lesions can be explained by the fact that it is only at 
    this rostrocaudal level that VP shows a significant expansion in a 
    dorsal direction above the MFB (Figs. 1, 2).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Indeed, the most pronounced demonstration of two major 
    separate terminal fields occurs at the extreme caudal part of the 
    Tu, at which point the HDB rather than the MF&apos;B separates the 
    pallidal region in the multiform layer of the Tu from the main 
    dorsal expanse of pallidum (e.g., Figs. 6C, 7, 13A).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">The idealized drawing in Figure 14B is intended to 
    illustrate the close topographic relations that exist between the 
    HDB, MF&apos;B, and VP, and to portray in a schematic fashion the 
    general organization of the ventral striatopallidal system 
    originating in the Tu.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="26" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s257">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s258">The antibodies against GAD 
    were kindly provided by Drs.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s259">D.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s260">Schmechel and W.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s261">Oertel.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s262">Rose Powell and Barbara Sisk 
    are gratefully acknowledged for skillful clerical assistance.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s263">This work was supported by 
    USPHS grants NS 17743, NS 01799, and BRSG 2-507RRO5431-24.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="26" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s264">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s265">Alheid, G.F., and J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Carlsen (1982) Small injections of fluorescent tracers 
    by iontophoresis or chronic implantation of micropipettes.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Brain Res. 235: 174-178.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">Beckstead, R.M. (1984) The thalamostriatal Neurol. 
    223:313-346.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Benjamin, R.M., J.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Jackson, G.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Golden, and C.H.K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">West (19821 Sources of olfactory input to opossum 
    mediodorsal nucleus identified by horseradish peroxidase and 
    autoradiographic methods.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">Neurol. 207:358-368.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Chang, H.T., C.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Wilson, and S.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Kitai (19811 Single neostriatal efferent axons in the 
    globus pallidus: A light and electron microscopic study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Science 213:915-918.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Chang, H.T., C.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Wilson, and S.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Kitai (1982) A Golgi study of rat neostriatal neurons: 
    Light microscopic analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Neurol. 208:107126.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Crosby, E.C., and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Humphrey (1941) Studies of the vertebrate telencephalon. 
    11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">The nuclear pattern of the anterior olfactory nucleus, 
    tuberculum olfactorium, and the amygdaloid complex in adult man.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Neurol. 74:309-352.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Dejerine, J.J. (1895) Anatomie des centres nerveux.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Rueff.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">de Olmos, J.S. (1969) A cupric-silver method for 
    impregnation of terminal axon degeneration and its further use in 
    staining granular argvroohilic neurons.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Brain Behav.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Evol. 2.213-237.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Olmos, J.S., G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Alheid, and C.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">Beltramino (1985) Amygdala.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">In G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">Paxinos (ed.): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Vol. 1.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Orlando: Academic Press, pp. 223-334.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Olmos, J., H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Hardy, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Heimer (1978) The afferent connections of the main and 
    the accessory olfactory bulb formations in the rat: An experimental 
    HRP-study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Neurol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">I81:213-244.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Dennis, B.J., and D.I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Kerr (1976) Origins of olfactory bulb centrifugal fibers 
    in the cat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">Brain Res. 110:593-600.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">Fallon, J.H., S.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Loughlin, and C.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Ribak (1983) The islands of Calleja complex of rat basal 
    forebrain. 111.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Histochemical evidence for a striatopallidal system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Neurol. 218r91-126.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Fallon, J.H., K.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Seroogy, S.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Loughlin, R.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Morrison, R.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Bradshaw, D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Knaur, and D.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Cunningham (1984) Epidermal growth factor immunoreactive 
    material in the central nervous system: Location and 
    development.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">Science 224:1107-1109.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Fink, R.P., and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Heimer (1967) Two methods for selective silver 
    impregnation of degenerating axons and their synaptic endings in 
    the central nervous system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Brain Res. 4~369-374.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Fox, C.A., A.N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Andrade, I.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Lu Qui, and J.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Rafols (1974) The primate globus pallidus: A Golgi and 
    electron microscopic study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">J. fur Hirnforsch. 15:75-93.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Fuxe, K. (1965) Evidence for the existence of monoamine 
    neurons in the central nervous system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Distribution of monoamine nerve terminals in the central 
    nervous system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Acta Physiologica Scandinavica 64 (Suppl. 247):39-85.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Gallyas, F., J.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Wolff, H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Bottcher, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Zaborszky (1980) A reliable and sensitive method to 
    locate terminal degeneration and lysosomes in the CNS.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Stain Technol. 55:299-306.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Gerfen, C.R., and P.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Sawchenko (1984) An anterograde neuroanatomical tracing 
    method that shows the detailed morphology of neurons, their axons 
    and terminals: Immunohistochemical localization of an axonally 
    transported plant lectin, Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Brain Res. 290:219-238.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Goldschmidt, R.B., and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Heimer (1980) The rat connections and relations to the 
    striato-pallidal Abstr. 6:271.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Groenewegen, H.J., and F.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Russchen (1984) Organization of the efferent projections 
    of the nucleus accumbens to pallidal, hypothalamic and 
    mesencephalic structures: A tracing and immunohistochemical study 
    in the cat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Neurol. 223t347-367.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Haber, S.N., and W.J.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Nauta (1981) Substance P but not enkephalin, 
    immunoreactivity distinguishes ventral from dorsal pallidum.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Abstr. 7:916.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Haber, S.N., and W.J.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Nauta (1983) Ramifications of the globus pallidus in the 
    rat as indicated by patterns of immunohistochemistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neurosci. 9:245-260.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Haber, S.N., H.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Groenewegen, E.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Grove, and W.J.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">Nauta (1985) Efferent connections of the ventral 
    pallidum: Evidence of a dual striatopallidofugal pathway.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Neural. 235:322-335.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Haberly, I.B., and J.I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">Price (1978) Association and commissural fiber systems 
    of the olfactory cortex of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Systems originating in the piriform cortex and adjacent 
    areas.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Neurol. 178:711-740.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Hedreen, J.C., and J.P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Chalmers (1972) Neuronal degeneration in rat brain 
    induced by 6-hydroxydopamine; a histological and biochemical 
    study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Brain Res. 47:l-36.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Heimer, L. (1968) Synaptic distribution of centripetal 
    and centrifugal nerve fibers in the olfactory system of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Anat. 103:413-432.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Heimer, L. (1970) Bridging the gap between light and 
    electron microscopy in the experimental tracing of fiber 
    connections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">In W.J.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Nauta and S.O.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Ebbesson (eds.): Contemporary Research Methods in 
    Neuroanatomy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">New York Springer-Verlag, pp.162-172.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Heimer, L. (1972) The fiber connections between the 
    olfactory cortex and the diencephalon in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">In W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Riss (ed): Thalamic Structure and Function.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">Brain Behav.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Evol. 6r484-523.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">Heimer, L. (1978) The olfactory cortex and the ventral 
    striatum.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">In K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">Livingston and 0.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">Hornykiewicz (eds.): Limbic Mechanisms.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">The Continuing Evolution of the Limbic System 
    Concept.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">New York: Plenum Press, pp. 96-187.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">Heimer, L., G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Alheid, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">Zaborszky (1985) The basal ganglia.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">In G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Paxinos (ed.): The Rat Nervous System.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Vol. 1.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Orlando: Academic Press, pp. 37-86.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Heimer, L., J.S. de Olmos, H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Hardy, and M.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Robards (1975) The olfactory tubercle projections in the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">Abstr. 1:680.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Heimer, L., and A.H.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Lohman (1975) Anatomical methods for tracing connections 
    in the central olfactory system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">In M.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Gazzaniga and C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Blakemore (eds.): Handbook of Psychobiology.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Orlando: Academic Press, pp. 73-106.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">Heimer, L., R.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Switzer, and G.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Van Hoesen (1982) Ventral striatum and ventral 
    pallidum.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Components of the motor system?</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Trends Neurosci.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">5:83-87.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Heimer, L., and G. van Hoesen (1979) Ventral 
    striatum.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">In J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Divac and R.G.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Oberg (eds.): The Neostriatum.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">New York Pergamon Press, pp.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">147-158.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Heimer, L., and R.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Wilson (1975) The subcortical projections of allocortex: 
    Similarities in the neural associations of the hippoearnpus, the 
    piriform cortex and the neocortex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">In M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Santini (ed.): Golgi Centennial Symposium 
    Proceedings.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">New York Raven Press, pp. 177-193.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Herrick, C.J. (1910) The morphology of the forebrain in 
    Amphibia Reptilia.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Neurol. 2CX413-547.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Itoh, K., A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Konishi, S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Nomura, N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Mizuno, Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Nakamura, and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Sugimoto (1979) Application of coupled oxidation 
    reaction to electron microscopic demonstration of horseradish 
    peroxidase: Cobalt-glucose oxidase method.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">Brain Res. 175:341-346.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Iwahori, N., and N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Mizuno (1981) A Golgi study on the globus pallidus of 
    the mouse.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Neurol. 197.29-43.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Karnovsky, M.J. (1965) A formaldehyde-glutaraldehyde 
    fixative of high osmolality for use in electron microscopy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Cell.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">Bid. 27r137A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Kemp, J.M. (1970) The termination of strio-pallidal and 
    strio-nigral fibers.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Brain Res. 17:125-128.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Kemp, J.M., and T.P.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Powell (1971) The structure of the caudate nucleus of 
    the cat: Light and electron microscopy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Phil.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Trans.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Roy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">London (Biol.) 262r383-401.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Krettek, J.F., and J.L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Price (1978) Amygdaloid projections to subcortical 
    structures within the forebrain and brainstem in the rat and 
    cat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Neurol. 178:225-254.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Lundberg, P.O. (1960) Cortico-hypothalamic connections 
    in the rabbit: An experimental neuroanatomical study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Acta Physiologica Scandinavica 49(Suppl. 171):l-80.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Martin, T.L., R.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Switzer, 111, J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Joshi, and A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Zimmerman (1985) Ferritin localization in rat brain by 
    immunocytochemistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Abstr. 11(Part 1):502.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Millhouse, O.E. (1969) A Golgi study bundle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Brain Res. 15r341-363.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Millhouse, O.E., and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">Heimer (1984) Cell configurations tubercle of the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Neurol. 228r571-597.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Mogenson, G.J., L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Swanson, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Wu (1983) Neural projections from nucleus accumbens to 
    globus pallidus, substantia innominata and lateral preoptic-lateral 
    hypothalamic area: An anatomical and eledrophysiological 
    investigation in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Neurosci. 3:189-202.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Nauta, W.J.H., and W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">Haymaker (1969) Hypothalamic nuclei and fiber 
    connections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">In W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Haymaker and E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Anderson (eds.): The Hypothalamus.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Springfield C.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Thomas.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Nauta, W.J.H., G.P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Smith,R.L.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">Faull, andV.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Domesick(1978)Efferent connections and nigral afferents 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Neurosci. 3:385-401.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Newman, R., and S.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Winans (1980) An experimental study of the ventral 
    striatum of the golden hamster. 11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Neuronal connections of the olfactory tubercle.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Neurol. 191:193-212.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">Oertel, W., A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Graybiel, E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Mugnaini, R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Elde, D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Schmechel, and I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Kopin (1981) Coexistence of glutamate decarboxylase 
    immunoreactivity and somatostatin-like immunoreactivity in neurons 
    of nucleus reticularis thalami of the cat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">Abstr. 7223.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Oertel, W.H., E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Mugnaini, D.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Schmechel, M.L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Tappaz, and I.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">Kopin (1982) The immunoeytochemical demonstration of 
    gamma-aminobutyric acid-ergic neurons-methods and application.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">In V.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Chan-Palay and S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Palay (eds.): Cytochemical Methods in Neuroanatomy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">New York Alan R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Liss, Inc., pp. 297-329.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Watson (1982) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Orlando: Academic Press.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Price, J.L., and B.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Slotnick (1983) Dual olfactory representation in the rat 
    thalamus: An anatomical and electrophysiological study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">Neurol. 21553-77.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Ribak, C.E., J.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Vaughn, and E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Roberts (1979) The GABA neurons and their axon terminals 
    in rat corpus striatum as demonstrated by GAD 
    immunocytochernistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">Neurol. 187t281-284.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Richardson, K.D., L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Jarrett, and E.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Finke (1960) Embedding in epoxy resins for ultrathin 
    sectioning in electron microscopy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">Stain Technology 35313-323.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Scott, J.W., and B.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Chafin (1975) Origin of olfactory projections to lateral 
    hypothalamus and nuclei gemini of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Brain Res. 88:64-68.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Scott, J.W., and C.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Leonard (1971) The olfactory connections of the lateral 
    hypothalamus in the rat, mouse and hamster.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Neurol. 141,331344.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Siegel, A., T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Fukushima, R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Meibach, L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Burke, H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Edinger, and S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Weinger (1977) The origin of the afferent supply to the 
    mediodorsal thalamic nucleus: Enhancement of HRP transport by 
    selective lesions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Brain Res.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">13511-23.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Stephan, H. (1975) Allocortex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">In Handbuch der Microscopischen Anatomie des Menschen, 
    IV/9.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">Berlin: Springer-Verlag.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Swanson, L.W., and W.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Cowan (1975) A note on the connections and development 
    of the nucleus accumbens.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Brain Res. 92:324-330.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Switzer, R.C., 111, J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Hill, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Heimer (1982) The globus pallidus and its rostroventral 
    extension into the olfactory tubercle of the rat: A cytoand 
    chemoarchitectural study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Neurosci. 7:1891-1904.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Ungerstedt, U. (1971) Stereotaxic mapping of the 
    monamine pathways the rat brain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Acta Physiologica Scandinavica 367:l-48.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">Valverde-Garcia, F. (1965) Studies on the Piriform 
    Lobe.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Wilson, R.D. (1972) Efferent connections of the nucleus 
    accumbens in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Master&apos;s Thesis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Young, W.S., 111, G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Alheid, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Heimer (1984) The ventral pallidal projection to the 
    mediodorsal thalamus: A study with fluorescent retrograde tracers 
    and immunohistofluorescence.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Neuroscience 4:16261638.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Zaborszky, L., G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Alheid, V.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">Alones, W.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Oertel, D.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Schmechel, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Heimer (1982) Afferents of the ventral pallidum studied 
    with a combined immunohistochemical-anterograde degeneration 
    method.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Abstr. 8:218.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Zaborszky, L., G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Alheid, M.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Beinfeld, L.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Eiden, L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Heimer, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Palkovits (1985) Cholecystokinin innervation of the 
    ventral striatum: A morphological and radioimmunological study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Neuroscience 14:427-453.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Zaborszky, L., J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Carlsen, H.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Brashear, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">Heimer (1986) Cholinergic and Gabaergic afferents to the 
    olfactory bulb in the rat with special emphasis on the projection 
    neurons in the nucleus of the horizontal limb of the diagonal 
    band.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Neurol. 243:488-509.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Zahm, D.W., and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Heimer (1985) Synaptic contacts of ventral striatal 
    cells in the olfactory tubercle of the rat: Correlated light 
    microscopy and EM of anterogradely transported Phaseolus 
    vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHAL).</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Lett. 6Ot169-175.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Zahrn, D.S., L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Zaborszky, G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Alheid, and L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Heimer (1987).</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">The ventral striatopallidothalamic projection: 11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">The ventral pallidothalarnic link.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Cornp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Neural. 255t592-605.</S>
  </References>

</File>

