<?xml version='1.0'?>
<File>

  <Title>Organization of Medullary Adrenergic and Noradrenergic 
  Projections to the Periaqueductal Gray Matter in the Rat</Title>

  <Authors>HORST HERBERT AND CLIFFORD B. SAPER</Authors>

  <Abstract>

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s0">ABSTRACT</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s1">The periaqueductal or midbrain central gray matter (CG) in 
    the rat contains a dense network of adrenergic and noradrenergic 
    fibers.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s2">We examined the origin of this innervation by using 
    retrograde and anterograde axonal tracers combined with 
    immunohistochemistry for the catecholamine biosynthetic enzymes 
    tyrosine hydroxylase (TH), dopamine p-hydroxylase (DBH), and 
    phenylethanolamine N-methyltransferase (PNMT).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s3">Following injections of the fluorescent tracers Fast Blue 
    or Fluorogold into the CG, double-labeled neurons in the medulla 
    were identified mainly in the noradrenergic A1 group in the caudal 
    ventrolateral medulla (VLM) and A2 group in the medial part of the 
    nucleus of the solitary tract (NTS); and in the adrenergic Cl group 
    in the rostral ventrolateral medulla and C3 group in the rostral 
    dorsomedial medulla.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s4">Injections of Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L) 
    into these cell groups resulted in a distinct pattern of axonal 
    labeling in various subdivisions of the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s5">Anterogradely labeled fibers originating in the medial NTS 
    were predominantly found in the lateral portion of the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus and in the adjacent part of the lateroventral CG (CGlv).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s6">Following PHA-L injections into the C3 region the 
    anterogradely labeled fibers were diffusely distributed in the CGlv 
    and the dorsal raphe nucleus at caudal levels, but rostrally tended 
    to be located laterally in the CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s7">In contrast, ascending fibers from the caudal and rostral 
    VLM terminated in the rostral dorsal part of the CGlv and in the 
    dorsal nucleus of the CG, whereas ventral parts of the CG, 
    including the dorsal raphe nucleus, contained few afferent 
    fibers.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s8">Double-label studies with antisera against DBH and PNMT 
    confirmed that noradrenergic neurons in the A1 and A2 groups and 
    adrenergic neurons in the Cf and C3 groups contributed to these 
    innervation patterns in the CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="abstract.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s9">Noradrenergic and adrenergic projections from the medulla 
    to the CG may play an important role in a variety of autonomic, 
    sensory and behavioral processes.</S>
  </Abstract>

  <Introduction>

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s10">The periaqueductal or central gray matter of the midbrain 
    (CG) consists of the cellular region surrounding the cerebral 
    aqueduct (of Sylvius).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s11">The CG also contains major ascending and descending fiber 
    systems that link the hypothalamus with the brainstem.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s12">Recent studies have indicated that the CG plays an 
    important role in the modulation of nociceptive sensory 
    transmission (Abols and Basbaum, &apos;81; Fardin et al., 
    &apos;84a,b; Nichols et al., &apos;89; Morgan et al., &apos;89; 
    Hamba et al., &apos;go), regulation of the cardiovascular system 
    (Skultety, &apos;63; Depaulis et al., &apos;88; Carrive et al., 
    &apos;88, &apos;89), and in a variety of behaviors including 
    feeding (Skultety and Gray, &apos;62; Weiss and Liebowitz, 
    &apos;851, defensive behavior (Bandler et al., &apos;85a,b; Carrive 
    et al., &apos;891, and sexual response (Sakuma and Pfaff &apos;79, 
    &apos;80).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s13">Previous studies of CG connections have emphasized its 
    relationships with the cortex, thalamus, and hypothalamus in the 
    forebrain (Morrell et al., &apos;81; Beitz, &apos;82; Eberhart et 
    al., &apos;85; Carstens et al., &apos;90) and its descending 
    connections with the nucleus raphe magnus, ventrolateral medulla 
    and spinal cord (Abols and Basbaum, &apos;81; Beitz et al., 
    &apos;83; Morrell and Pfaff, &apos;83; Carrive et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s14">In the course of our own investigations of the 
    projections from autonomic cell groups in the medulla to the 
    parabrachial nucleus (Herbert et al., &apos;901, we observed 
    prominent innervation of the CG as well.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s15">Many of these afferents originated from cell groups 
    containing adrenergic or noradrenergic neurons.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s16">We have therefore systematically examined the 
    catecholaminergic afferents to the CG from the medulla, by using 
    combined tracer methods and immunocytochemistry for catecholamine 
    synthetic enzymes.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="introduction.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s17">A preliminary report of this work has appeared (Herbert 
    and Saper, &apos;88).</S>
  </Introduction>

  <Methods>

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s18">MATERIALS AND METHODS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s19">Retrograde 
    double-labeling experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s20">A total of 11 Sprague-Dawley rats of both sexes, ranging 
    in weight from 250-400 g were anesthetized with 7% chloral hydrate 
    (350 mg/kg) and stereotaxic injections of fluorescent tracers were 
    made into the lateral portion of the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s21">The animals received unilateral injections of either 
    50-100 nl of Fast Blue (Illing, GmbH) in dH,O (n = 5) or 30-50 nl 
    of 4% Fluorogold (Fluorochrom, Inc.) in saline (n = 6).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s22">After 5-11 days of survival, the rats were deeply 
    anesthetized and perfused through the aorta with 0.9% saline, 
    followed by 4% paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M phosphate buffer (PB) at 
    pH 7.4.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s23">The brains were removed from the skull and post-fixed in 
    the perfusate overnight at 4°C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s24">The brainstems were cut on a freezing microtome at 40 (*m 
    and sections were divided into four series.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s25">These were then processed by the indirect 
    immunofluorescence method with antibodies against the catecholamine 
    biosynthetic enzymes tyrosine hydroxylase (TH), dopamine 
    p-hydroxylase (DBH), or phenylethanolamine N-methyltransferase 
    (PNMT).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s26">Zmmunohistochemistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s27">The sections were rinsed for several minutes in PB 
    containing 0.9% NaCl (PBS) and then preincubated in PBS containing 
    3% goat serum and 0.25% Triton X-100, which served as a diluent for 
    all further incubations.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s28">After 1 hour, the sections were transferred into 
    polyclonal whole antisera raised in rabbits (Eugene Tech), diluted 
    1:750 (anti-TH), or 1:400 (antiDBH, anti-PNMT).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s29">After incubation in the primary antisera for 24-48 hours 
    at 4&quot;C, the sections were washed several times in PBS, 
    transferred to a biotinylated goat anti-rabbit IgG (BRL) diluted 
    1:200, and incubated for 50 minutes at room temperature.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s30">After three additional rinses in PBS, the sections were 
    incubated for 50 minutes at room temperature in streptavidin-Texas 
    red conjugate (BRL), diluted 1500.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s31">Sections were washed again in PBS, mounted onto 
    gelatin-coated slides, air dried, cleared in xylene, and 
    coverslipped with DPX.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s32">In preliminary studies, omitting either the primary or 
    secondary antisera abolished staining.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s33">Colchicine treatment did not increase the numbers of 
    TH-immunoreactive neurons in the medulla, and PNMTimmunoreactive 
    staining corresponded nearly perfectly with TH staining in the 
    medulla (Tucker et al., 1987); hence, no colchicine treatment was 
    used in this series of experiments.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s34">Data analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s35">Sections were viewed under a Leitz Orthoplan microscope 
    with Ploem fluorescence illumination, under a N2 filter system for 
    Texas red and an A filter system for Fast Blue and Fluorogold.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s36">Retrogradely labeled, immunofluorescent, and 
    double-labeled neurons in the medulla were plotted with the aid of 
    a microscope stage position plotter system (Minnesota 
    Datametrics).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s37">The coverslips were then removed, and the sections were 
    counterstained with thionin to identify brainstem 
    cytoarchitecture.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s38">Cell counts of catecholaminergic neurons and 
    doublelabeled neurons in the Al, A2, and (21-3 cell groups were 
    performed on TH-stained sections from two brains (total of 22 
    sections) and PNMT-stained sections from one brain (total of 9 
    sections).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s39">Anterograde 
    double-labeling experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s40">Fourteen female Sprague-Dawley rats weighing 300-350 g 
    received iontophoretic injections of 2.5% Phasedus 
    vulgaris-leucoagglutinin (PHA-L; Vector) into medullary 
    catecholaminergic cell groups.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s41">A stereotaxic surgical method similar to the retrograde 
    experiments was used for the injections into the medullary 
    reticular formation, but the injections into the nucleus of the 
    solitary tract were made through the foramen magnum, with the aid 
    of brain surface landmarks for stereotaxic orientation.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s42">PHA-L was dissolved in 10 mM phosphate buffer, pH 8, and 
    was injected from glass micropipettes with 25-40 pm tip diameter by 
    means of a pulsed positive current of 5 pA with a 50% duty cycle, 
    applied for 15-20 minutes.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s43">After 8-12 days of survival the animals were 
    reanesthetized and perfused through the aorta with 0.9% saline 
    followed by a two step pH-change procedure (Berod et al., 
    &apos;81).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s44">First, rats were perfused with 180 ml of ice-cold 4% 
    paraformaldehyde in 0.1 M sodium acetate buffer, pH 6.5, followed 
    by 300 ml of ice cold 4% paraformaldehydein 0.1 M borate buffer, pH 
    11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s45">The brains were removed and postfixed overnight at 4°C in 
    the borate buffered fixative containing 5% sucrose.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s46">Tissue blocks were then cut and soaked for 2 days in 30% 
    sucrose in 0.1 M phosphate buffer, pH 7.4 at 4°C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s47">Sections were cut at 40 km on a freezing microtome, and 
    alternate series were then processed by a double immunofluorescence 
    method (see below) to identify PHA-L labeled fibers that were also 
    immunoreactive either for DBH or PNMT.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s48">Additional series of sections through the CG from each 
    case were also processed by an immunoperoxidase method (see below) 
    to visualize either PHA-L labeled fibers or the DBH-immunoreactive 
    (-ir) or PNMT-ir fiber plexus.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s49">Double immunofluorescence staining.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s50">Sections were rinsed for several minutes in 50 mM 
    Tris-buffered 0.9% saline, pH 7.6 (TBS) and preincubated in a 
    diluent consisting of 3% horse serum and 0.25% Triton X-100 in PBS 
    1 hour at room temperature.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s51">Sections were transferred into diluent containing the 
    primary goat anti-PHA-L (Vector) diluted 1: 1,000 and rabbit 
    anti-DBH (Eugene Tech) diluted 1:800 or rabbit anti-PNMT (Incstar) 
    diluted 1:5,000, and incubated at 4°C for 2-3 days.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s52">After being washed several times in PBS, sections were 
    incubated in fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC-) labeled donkey 
    anti-goat IgG (Jackson) diluted 1:30 for 1 hour at room 
    temperature, followed by three rinses in PBS and then incubation in 
    biotinylated donkey anti-rabbit IgG (Jackson) diluted 1:800 for 45 
    minutes at room temperature.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s53">Sections were washed again three times and transferred to 
    streptavidin-Texas red conjugate (Jackson) diluted 1:1,000 for 45 
    minutes at room temperature, then washed in PBS, mounted on 
    gelatincoated glass slides, air dried, cleared in xylene, and 
    coverslipped with DPX containing 5% v/v @-mercaptoethanol (Merck) 
    to retard fading (Franklin and Filion, &apos;85).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s54">Immunohistochemical controls.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s55">To control for potential cross-reactivity of the 
    secondary antisera, sections incubated in either primary antiserum 
    (rabbit anti-DBH or goat anti-PHA-L) alone were stained with both 
    secondary antisera as in the double immunofluorescence protocol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s56">No immunocytochemical staining with the FITC-labeled 
    donkey anti-goat antiserum was seen when the goat antiPHA-L was 
    omitted; and no staining with Texas red was seen when the anti-DBH 
    was omitted.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s57">Further evidence of lack of cross-reactivity is provided 
    by the presence of numerous axons that stained with one but not the 
    other double immunofluorescence material (see marker in the 
    Results).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s58">Data analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s59">We viewed the sections with a ReichertJung Polyvar 
    microscope fitted with a B1 filter system for FITC and a G1 system 
    for the Texas Red.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s60">Areas containing double-labeled fibers were subsequently 
    photographed with the two filter systems.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s61">Enlargements of these photomicrographs were photocopied 
    onto acetate sheets and then superimposed to identify 
    double-labeled fibers and varicosities.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s62">Double-labeling was further validated by comparing the 
    shape, size and orientation of the structures on the original 
    photomicrographs and by measuring distances with the aid of a 
    caliper.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s63">Immunoperoxidase 
    staining</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s64">Additional series of sections were stained to visualize 
    the anterogradely labeled fibers and the DBHor PNMTcontaining fiber 
    plexus by the peroxidase-antiperoxidase (PAP) method.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s65">Sections were first rinsed in several changes of TBS and 
    then incubated in a blocking solution containing 10% normal swine 
    serum, 2% bovine serum albumin, and 0.3% Triton X-100 in TBS.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s66">After 1 hour the sections were directly transferred into 
    the primary antiserum, either rabbit anti-PHA-L (Dako) diluted 
    1:3,000, rabbit anti-DBH (Eugene Tech) diluted 15300, or rabbit 
    anti-PNMT (Incstar) diluted 1:5,000 in a diluent containing 1% 
    normal swine serum, 1% bovine serum albumen, and 0.3% Triton X-100 
    in TBS, and incubated for 2-3 days at 4°C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s67">Sections were then rinsed for 30 min in several changes 
    of TBS, and incubated for 1.5 h at room temperature in unlabeled 
    swine anti-rabbit IgG diluted 1:50 in the same diluent.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s68">Sections were extensively washed in TBS and then 
    incubated in rabbit PAP-complex (Dako) at 1:ZOO dilution.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s69">After 1.5 h at room temperature, sections were rinsed 
    again in several changes of TBS and then incubated for 8-10 minutes 
    in 0.05% 3,3-diaminobenzidine (DAB, Sigma) containing 0.0 1% 
    hydrogen peroxide (H,O,).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s70">Sections were mounted onto gelatin-coated glass 
    microscope slides, air dried, dehydrated in graded ethanols, 
    cleared in xylene, and coverslipped with Entellan mounting 
    medium.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s71">Adjacent series were stained with thionin to identify 
    cytoarchitectonic landmarks.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s72">Data analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s73">Sections were viewed under both brightfield and darkfield 
    illumination.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s74">The subnuclear distribution of PHA-L labeled fibers in 
    the CG was mapped with a camera lucida drawing apparatus.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s75">Cytoarchitectural boundaries were defined by 
    superimposing projections of the adjacent thionin-stained sections 
    onto the drawings, with the aid of brain outlines and blood vessels 
    as reference points.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="methods.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s76">Cytoand chemoarchitecture 
    of the CG</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s77">To demonstrate the subnuclear organization of the CG, 
    rats were perfused with 4% paraformaldehyde and the brains removed 
    and cut in the transverse plane at 40 km on a freezing 
    microtome.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="methods.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s78">The sections were stained histochemically for 
    NADPH-diaphorase (Scherer-Singler et al., &apos;83) or for 
    Nissl-substance with thionin.</S>
  </Methods>

  <Results>

    <S avgH="28" class="results.heading" format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT"
     id="s79">RESULTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s80">Subdivisions of the CG</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s81">Previous studies have proposed a subdivision of the rat 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>CG</neuroanatomicalLocation> based upon 
    the cytoarchitecture in Nissland Golgistained material (Beitz, 
    &apos;85; Beitz and Shepard, &apos;85; Paxinos and Watson, 
    &apos;86) and upon cytochrome oxidase histochemistry (Conti et al., 
    &apos;88).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s82">In the sections processed histochemically for 
    NADPH-diaphorase, we have made additional observations that bear 
    upon the delineation of the CG subdivisions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s83">The terminology for the CG subdivisions is adapted from 
    that of Paxinos and Watson (&apos;86).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s84">in nadph - diaphorase - stained material the cgld stands 
    out clearly because of <labelingDescription>the dense 
    staining</labelingDescription> of its neuropil ( indicated by 
    arrowheads in fig . la , d ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s85">in the thioninstained sections <labelingLocation>the 
    laterodorsal subdivision of the cg ( cgld )</labelingLocation> can 
    be appreciated by its granular appearance ( e . g . , fig . 1b 
    &apos; ) compared with <labelingLocation>the dorsal subdivision ( 
    cgd )</labelingLocation> which consists of larger , 
    <labelingDescription>more darkly stained 
    neurons</labelingDescription> ( fig . 1a &apos; c &apos; ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s86"><labelingLocation>the lateroventral subdivision ( cglv 
    )</labelingLocation> is composed of heterogeneous cell populations 
    of various sizes .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s87">All three subdivisions show a gradient of cell density 
    which increases from medial to lateral (Fig. 1A&apos;-C&apos;).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s88">The cell poor band of tissue surrounding the aqueduct 
    corresponds to <labelingLocation>the medial subdivision 
    (CGm;</labelingLocation>indicated by the dashed lines in Fig. 
    1A&apos;-D&apos;).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s89">in the rostral aspect of <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    cg</neuroanatomicalLocation> , <neuroanatomicalLocation>the 
    lateroventral subdivision</neuroanatomicalLocation> is bordered 
    ventrally by <neuroanatomicalLocation>the supraoculomotor 
    nucleus</neuroanatomicalLocation> ( fig . 1a &apos; ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s90">at the midlevel , <labelingLocation>the ventromedial part 
    of the cg</labelingLocation> is occupied by the 
    <labelingLocation>dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> , which 
    is characterized by <labelingDescription>numerous nadph - 
    diaphorase - positive neurons exhibiting intensely staining 
    dendritic arbors</labelingDescription> ( fig . 1c ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s91"><labelingDescription>fewer nadph - diaphorase - stained 
    cells</labelingDescription> are seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    lateral portion of the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s92">in thioninstained sections , though , 
    <labelingLocation>the midline portion of the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> as well as its lateral portion are 
    clearly visible ( fig . 1c &apos; ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s93">caudally , <labelingLocation>the cg</labelingLocation> 
    contains ventrally <labelingLocation>the dorsal and laterodorsal 
    tegmental nuclei</labelingLocation> , both of which are clearly 
    demonstrated in the two stains ( fig . ld , ld &apos; ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s94"><labelingLocation>the laterodorsal tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>intensely nadph 
    - diaphorasestained</labelingDescription> , whereas 
    <labelingLocation>the medially located dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>less intensely 
    stained</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s95">in <labelingLocation>the thionin - stained material the 
    laterodorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> is seen as 
    <labelingDescription>a cluster of large , darkly stained 
    neurons</labelingDescription> that are bordered medially by 
    <labelingLocation>the pericentral portion of the dorsal tegmental 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>a circular group 
    of densely packed , medium size cells</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s96"><labelingLocation>the midline region of the caudal 
    cg</labelingLocation> is made up of <labelingDescription>nadph - 
    diaphorase - positive somata</labelingDescription> that belong to 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig 
    . 1d ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s97">distribution of 
    <labelingDescription>catecholaminergic fibers</labelingDescription> 
    in the cg</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s98">sections through the midbrain stained 
    immunohistochemically for catecholamine synthetic enzymes reveal 
    <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of dbhand pnmt - immunoreactive 
    ( - ir ) fibers and puncta</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the cg</labelingLocation> ( see also : ungerstedt 
    , &apos; 71 lindvall and bjorklund , &apos; 74 swanson and hartman 
    , &apos; 75 hokfelt et al . , &apos; 84a moore and card , &apos; 84 
    chandler et al . , &apos; 88 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s99"><labelingDescription>the dbhand pnmt - 
    positive</labelingDescription> structures are not evenly 
    distributed , but restricted to <labelingLocation>certain parts of 
    specific cg subdivisions</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s100"><labelingDescription>Prominent DBHir and PNMTir 
    staining</labelingDescription> is present in the CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s101">at the level of transition from <labelingLocation>the 
    superior to the inferior colliculus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 2 0 
    , <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of catecholaminergic fibers 
    and varicosities</labelingDescription> is seen in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the cglv , overlapping the 
    lateral portion of the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> ( cf 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s102">Fig. 1C&apos;).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s103">laterally , the staining in <labelingLocation>the 
    cglv</labelingLocation> is <labelingDescription>rather 
    sparse</labelingDescription> , and <labelingLocation>the more 
    dorsal subdivisions of the cg</labelingLocation> are nearly 
    <labelingDescription>devoid of stained axons</labelingDescription> 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s104">overall , dbhir axons are more abundant than pnmtir 
    fibers , suggesting that both adrenergic and noradrenergic cells 
    contribute to this pattern .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s105">Combined retrograde 
    tracing and immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s106">unilateral injections of the fluorescent tracers 
    <tracerChemical>fast blue</tracerChemical> or 
    <tracerChemical>fluorogold</tracerChemical> were placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the region of the catecholaminergic fiber plexus 
    in the cglv at the intercollicular level</injectionLocation> ( figs 
    . 3 , 4 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s107">in cases in which the injection was clearly confined to 
    <injectionLocation>the cg</injectionLocation> , 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    medulla</labelingLocation> were predominantly found in 
    <labelingLocation>the nuclei of the reticular 
    formation</labelingLocation> , including <labelingLocation>the 
    dorsal and ventral medullary reticular fields caudally and the 
    parvocellular and gigantocellular reticular nuclei 
    rostrally</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s108"><labelingDescription>additional labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were seen in <labelingLocation>the 
    medullary raphe nuclei , the trigeminal promontorium , the dorsal 
    column nuclei and the vtastibular nuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s109">this distribution of <labelingDescription>retrogradely 
    labeled neurons</labelingDescription> is in general agreement with 
    earlier studies in the rat ( e . g . , beitz , &apos; 82 marchand 
    and hagino , &apos; 83 morrell and pfaff , &apos; 83 beitz et al . 
    , &apos; 86 hamba et al . , &apos; 90 ) , the cat ( bandler and 
    tork , &apos; 871 , and the rabbit ( meller and dennis , &apos; 861 
    , and will not be described in detail .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s110">we concentrate here on the numerous retrogradely labeled 
    neurons that were intermingled with the al / a2 noradrenergic and 
    the cl - c3 adrenergic groups in <labelingLocation>the nucleus of 
    the solitary tract ( nts ) , the caudal and rostral ventrolateral 
    medulla ( vlm ) , and the dorsomedial medulla ( dmm ) in the region 
    of the nucleus prepositus and medial longitudinal 
    fasciculus</labelingLocation> ( figs . 3 , 4 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s111">subsequent immunohistochemical staining for the 
    catecholamine synthetic enzymes th , dbh , or pnmt revealed that 
    <labelingDescription>numerous neurons</labelingDescription> in 
    these regions contained both labels .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s112"><labelingLocation>nucleus of the solitary 
    tract</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s113">in the nts <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were distributed throughout 
    <labelingLocation>the a2 cell group in the caudal commissural and 
    medial subnuclei</labelingLocation> ( figs . 3 , 4 ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s114"><labelingDescription>the total number of retrogradely 
    labeled neurons</labelingDescription> was about twice as high on 
    the ipsilateral compared to <labelingLocation>the contralateral 
    side</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s115">only <labelingDescription>scattered retrograde 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was found in <labelingLocation>the 
    ventrolateral and rostral nts subnuclei</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s116">overall , of the thir neurons in <labelingLocation>the 
    nts</labelingLocation> , 22% were double - labeled ipsilaterally ( 
    e . g . , fig . 5a , a &apos; ) and 9% contralaterally .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s117">among pnmtir neurons , 15% of those in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsomedial nts were retrogradely labeled on 
    the ipsilateral side and 8% contralaterally</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s118"><labelingDescription>very few thir 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the area 
    postrema</labelingLocation> or in <labelingLocation>the classical 
    c2 group</labelingLocation> , along <labelingLocation>the 
    rostromedial border of the nts</labelingLocation> , were 
    retrogradely labeled , however .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s119"><labelingLocation>ventrolateral 
    medulla</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s120"><labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were intermingled with the allcl cell 
    group at every level of the vlm .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s121">although <labelingDescription>similar numbers of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons</labelingDescription> were identified 
    on <labelingLocation>the two sides of the brain</labelingLocation> 
    ( figs . 3 , 41 , <labelingDescription>double labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were predominantly found 
    ipsilaterally .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s122">For example, 36% of THir and 42% of PNMTir neurons were 
    double-labeled ipsilaterally, whereas only 18% and 13%, 
    respectively, were double-labeled contralaterally.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s123">rostra1 to <labelingLocation>the area 
    postrema</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>the numbers of 
    thir and pnmtir neurons</labelingDescription> per section in 
    <labelingLocation>the vlm</labelingLocation> was similar , 
    indicating mainly an adrenergic projection .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s124"><labelingLocation>caudal to the area 
    postrema</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>few pnmtir 
    neurons</labelingDescription> were seen , so that 
    <labelingDescription>the double - labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> were mainly noradrenergic .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s125">we conclude that <labelingLocation>the a1 noradrenergic 
    and c1 adrenergic cell groups</labelingLocation> each provides a 
    major source of catecholamiriergic innervation of the cg( fig . 5b 
    , b &apos; , c , c &apos; ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s126"><labelingLocation>dorsomedial medulla</labelingLocation> 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s127"><labelingLocation>the region of the c3 adrenergic cell 
    group , surrounding the nucleus prepositus and medial longitudinal 
    fasciculus</labelingLocation> , also contained 
    <labelingDescription>substantial numbers of double - labeled 
    cells</labelingDescription> ( fig . 5d , d &apos; ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s128">as in the vlm , <labelingDescription>equal numbers of 
    retrogradely labeled cells</labelingDescription> were found 
    bilaterally ( figs . 3 , 4 ) , but <labelingDescription>double - 
    labeled cells</labelingDescription> were primarily found on the 
    ipsilateral side .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s129"><labelingDescription>a total of 23% of pnmtir 
    cells</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the c3 group ( 
    bilaterally )</labelingLocation> were also 
    <labelingDescription>retrogradely labeled</labelingDescription> 
    .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s130">Anterograde tracer 
    experiments</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s131">to determine the distribution of catecholaminergic 
    afferents from the medulla within the cg , injections of the 
    anterograde tracer <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> were 
    placed into <injectionLocation>the cell</injectionLocation> groups 
    containing <labelingDescription>double - labeled 
    neurons</labelingDescription> in the first series of experiments 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s132">in each case , <labelingDescription>a well - defined 
    plexus of varicose fibers and terminals</labelingDescription> was 
    identified in <labelingLocation>the cg</labelingLocation> .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s133"><labelingLocation>nucleus of the solitary 
    tract</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s134"><injectionLocation>the medial subnucleus of the 
    nts</injectionLocation> was injected at different rostro - caudal 
    levels in five experiments .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s135">the pattern of <labelingDescription>axonal 
    labeling</labelingDescription> in <labelingLocation>the 
    cg</labelingLocation> was similar in each of these , and is 
    represented by experiment nts 7 in which the injection site was 
    centered in <injectionLocation>the medial subnucleus at the level 
    of the area postrema</injectionLocation> ( shaded area in fig . 6a 
    ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s136">caudally , <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled 
    efferent fibers</labelingDescription> entered the cg mainly from 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the parabrachial 
    complex</neuroanatomicalLocation>, coursing medially across the 
    fascicles of <labelingLocation>the trochlear nerve and the 
    mesencephalic trigeminal tract</labelingLocation> , to form 
    <labelingDescription>a dense plexus of varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> in - <labelingLocation>the ventral 
    aspect of the cglv and adjacent cgm</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6e ) 
    .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s137">further rostrally , at the intercollicular level , 
    <labelingDescription>terminal fibers</labelingDescription> were 
    predominantly located in <labelingLocation>the medioventral part of 
    the cglv and cgm</labelingLocation> , and extending into 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral portion of the dorsal raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6d ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s138"><labelingDescription>individual varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> also ran dorsally into 
    <labelingLocation>the cgd</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6d , e ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s139">in <labelingLocation>the anterior portion of the 
    cg</labelingLocation> <labelingDescription>the density of labeled 
    fibers was sparser</labelingDescription> , but the majority of 
    efferent axons was still found in <labelingLocation>the ventral cgm 
    and the medioventral cglv</labelingLocation> ( fig . 6b , c ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s140"><labelingLocation>the posterior portion of the midline 
    dorsal raphe</labelingLocation> was largely 
    <labelingDescription>devoid of fibers</labelingDescription> from 
    <labelingLocation>the medial nts</labelingLocation> , but 
    <labelingLocation>the anterior portion</labelingLocation> was 
    <labelingDescription>moderately densely 
    innervated</labelingDescription> ( fig . 6c ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s141">the projection from <connxOrigin>the medial 
    nts</connxOrigin> to <connxTermination>the cg</connxTermination> 
    was bilateral with an ipsilateral predominance , in agreement with 
    the retrograde transport experiments .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s142"><neuroanatomicalLocation>dorsomedial 
    medulla</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s143">in four rats the <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> injections were placed into 
    <injectionLocation>the dmm</injectionLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s144">in <exptLabel>experiment dmm 2</exptLabel> , the center 
    of the injection was located just <injectionLocation>ventral to the 
    nucleus prepositus and lateral to the medial longitudinal 
    fasciculus</injectionLocation> ( dots in fig . 7a ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s145"><labelingDescription>pha - l labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were widespread in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateroventral subdivision of the 
    cg</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s146">caudally , they were located predominantly in 
    <labelingLocation>the ventral part of the cglv , in the 
    laterodorsal tegmental nucleus</labelingLocation> and in 
    <labelingLocation>the midline dorsal raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 7e ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s147">at <labelingLocation>the midlevel of the 
    cg</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>varicose 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were present in 
    <labelingDescription>fairly high density</labelingDescription> in 
    <labelingLocation>the midline and lateral dorsal raphe 
    nucleus</labelingLocation> ( fig . 7c , d ) , whereas in the cglv 
    <labelingDescription>the labeled fibers were more sparsely and 
    diffusely distributed</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s148">rostrally in <labelingLocation>the 
    cct</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> tended to accumulate bilaterally in 
    <labelingLocation>the lateral aspect of the cglv</labelingLocation> 
    , in <labelingLocation>the region of the mesencephalic trigeminal 
    neurons</labelingLocation> ( fig . 7b , c ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s149"><labelingDescription>dense 
    innervation</labelingDescription> was also seen in 
    <labelingLocation>the supraoculomotor nucleus</labelingLocation> ( 
    fig . 7b ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s150"><labelingDescription>only sparse 
    innervation</labelingDescription> was present in 
    <labelingLocation>the cgd and the cgld</labelingLocation> ( fig . 
    7b - d ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s151">The innervation from <connxOrigin>the DMM</connxOrigin> 
    to <connxTermination>the CG</connxTermination> was bilaterally 
    symmetric, in agreement with the retrograde transport experiments 
    (above).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s152"><neuroanatomicalLocation>ventrolateral 
    medulla</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s153">five rats received injections of <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> into <injectionLocation>the ventrolateral 
    medulla</injectionLocation> at different rostrocaudal levels .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s154">the results were similar in all of these experiments , 
    and are represented by <exptLabel>experiment vlm 3</exptLabel>, in 
    which the <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> deposit was 
    located just <injectionLocation>ventral to the nucleus 
    ambiguus</injectionLocation> ( dots in fig . 8a ) at the level of 
    transition from <neuroanatomicalLocation>the c1 
    adrenergic</neuroanatomicalLocation> to 
    <neuroanatomicalLocation>the a1 noradrenergic 
    group</neuroanatomicalLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s155"><labelingDescription>efferent 
    fibers</labelingDescription> entered <labelingLocation>the 
    cg</labelingLocation> caudally through <labelingLocation>the 
    parabrachial complex</labelingLocation> , across the fascicles of 
    <labelingLocation>the trochlear nucleus and the mesencephalic 
    trigeminal tract</labelingLocation> , <labelingModifier>to 
    innervate</labelingModifier> 
    <labelingDescription>diffusely</labelingDescription> 
    <labelingLocation>the posterior part of the cg</labelingLocation> ( 
    fig . 8e ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s156">in <labelingLocation>the anterior portion of the 
    cg</labelingLocation> , <labelingDescription>prominent fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> was present dorsally in 
    <labelingLocation>the cglv and the cgd</labelingLocation> ( fig . 
    8b - d ) .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s157">in the latter , <labelingDescription>the 
    fibers</labelingDescription> predominantly 
    <labelingModifier>innervated</labelingModifier> the cluster of 
    large neurons located in <labelingLocation>the center of the 
    cgd</labelingLocation>( indicated by dashed lines in fig . 8b , c 
    cf .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s158">Fig. lA&apos;,B&apos;).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s159">the cgld contained <labelingDescription>only a few 
    individual labeled fibers</labelingDescription> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s160">the projection from <connxOrigin>the vlm</connxOrigin> 
    to <connxTermination>the cg</connxTermination> was 
    <labelingDescription>bilateral with an equal density of efferent 
    fibers</labelingDescription> on either side , in agreement with the 
    retrograde transport studies ( above ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s161">in summary , <tracerChemical>pha - l</tracerChemical> 
    injections into <injectionLocation>the medullary adrenergic and 
    noradrenergic cell groups</injectionLocation> resulted in three 
    distinct patterns of <labelingDescription>anterogradely labeled 
    axons</labelingDescription> ( figs . 6 - 8 ) in 
    <labelingLocation>the cg subdivisions</labelingLocation> that also 
    exhibited thir , dbhir , or pnmtir fibers ( compare with fig . 2 
    see also fig . 9 ) .</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="28" class="results.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s162">Combined anterograde 
    tracing and immunohistochemistry</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s163">to determine which anterogradely labeled fibers in the 
    cg were catecholaminergic , we employed a double immunofluorescence 
    technique using antisera against <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> and either dbh or pnmt .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s164">midbrain sections from cases with <tracerChemical>pha - 
    l</tracerChemical> injections into <labelingLocation>the a2 / c2 
    cell group in the medial nts ( n = 21</labelingLocation> , into 
    <labelingLocation>the al / cl cell group in the 
    vlm</labelingLocation>  ( n = l ) , or into <labelingLocation>the 
    c3 cell group in the dmm</labelingLocation> ( n = 1 ) were 
    processed using each antiserum .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s165">adjacent series from these cases which were processed 
    for pha - l immunoperoxidase histochemistry showed the expected 
    patterns of <labelingDescription>anterograde fiber 
    labeling</labelingDescription> , as described above .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s166">high magnification fluorescence microscopy revealed 
    <labelingDescription>substantial numbers of varicose fibers and 
    terminals</labelingDescription> that were both pha - land dbhir ( 
    figs . 10 , 11a , a ) or pha - land pnmtir ( fig . 1 lb , b ) , 
    although <labelingDescription>the numbers of double - labeled 
    fibers</labelingDescription> were small compared to the profusion 
    of single - labeled fibers with each antiserum .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s167"><labelingDescription>double - labeled 
    structures</labelingDescription> were most frequently found in 
    <labelingLocation>the dorsal raphe nucleus</labelingLocation> ( e . 
    g . , fig .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s168">loa , a ) and <labelingLocation>the medial portion of 
    the cglv</labelingLocation> , but were present in 
    <labelingDescription>smaller numbers</labelingDescription> 
    throughout the dbhand pnmtir terminal fields in 
    <labelingLocation>the cg</labelingLocation> .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s169">in agreement with the retrograde transport data , 
    <labelingDescription>double - labeled fibers</labelingDescription> 
    were predominantly found on the ipsilateral side of the brain .</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="results.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s170"><labelingDescription>the double - labeled varicosities 
    and intensely beaded fibers</labelingDescription> presumably 
    indicated the presence of synaptic contacts that use noradrenaline 
    or adrenaline as neurotransmitters .</S>
  </Results>

  <Discussion>

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s171">DISCUSSION</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s172">Our results indicate that noradrenergic neurons in the 
    A1 and A2 groups and adrenergic neurons in the C1 and C3 groups are 
    major sources of medullary afferents to the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s173">In particular, A2 neurons in the NTS contribute to a 
    dense noradrenergic fiber plexus in the caudal ventral part of the 
    CGlv, adjacent to the lateral aspects of the dorsal raphe and 
    laterodorsal tegmental nuclei.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s174">Adrenergic C3 neurons in the DMM contribute to an 
    adrenergic terminal field in the ventral CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s175">In contrast, adrenergic C1 and noradrenergic A1 neurons 
    in the ventrolateral medulla more heavily innervate the dorsal part 
    of the CGlv, bordering the CGld.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s176">Technical 
    considerations</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s177">Although there are extensive noradrenergic and 
    adrenergic terminal fields in the CG of medullary origin, a 
    majority of medullary neurons that were retrogradely labeled from 
    the CG did not stain for catecholamine synthetic enzymes.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s178">Our injections were clearly confined to the CG; hence, 
    it is unlikely that we included cells that do not project to the CG 
    in our analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s179">Furthermore, the numbers of immunoreactive cells seen 
    per section were similar to those reported in previous studies 
    using different antisera (e.g., Ruggiero et al., 85; Tucker and 
    Saper, 871, so that our immunocytochemistry appears to be 
    sufficiently sensitive.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s180">We conclude, therefore, that many non-catecholaminergic 
    neurons in the DMM, NTS, and VLM contribute axons to terminal 
    fields in the CG where they are intermixed with catecholaminergic 
    fibers.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s181">In agreement with this interpretation, our anterograde 
    transport studies identified many PHA-L-labeled axons, and many 
    catecholaminergic axons, but double-labeled fibers were more sparse 
    and difficult to find in the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s182">We attribute this problem to several technical 
    limitations of the technique that we used.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s183">First, the PHA-L method by nature labels the efferents 
    from only a small population of neurons.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s184">Hence, many catecholaminergic neurons in the cell group 
    containing the injection site (and their axons in the CG) may not 
    be labeled by the anterograde tracer.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s185">Second, the fluorescent PHA-L method that we used may be 
    slightly less sensitive than the immunoperoxidase method.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s186">Although we did not quantify the numbers of labeled 
    fibers, it appeared that the fiber densities were marginally 
    greater in the immunoperoxidase series from the same brains.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s187">It is possible that the smaller, less intensely labeled 
    axom that are most difficult to stain may be disproportionately 
    catecholaminergic.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s188">Finally, the visual complexity of the innervation 
    patterns with each marker makes the identification of labeled 
    fibers difficult (see, e.g., Figs. 10, 11).</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s189">We have partially compensated for this problem by using 
    photographic overlays, thus allowing us to identify even short 
    pieces of axons that are double-labeled in a haystack of 
    single-labeled fibers.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s190">However, in areas of dense innervation the random 
    apparent overlap of labeled structures (particularly terminals) 
    that in fact are located in slightly different planes makes this 
    procedure difficult to apply.</S>
     
    <S avgH="21" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s191">Hence, we have not been able to analyze as thoroughly 
    the densest areas of the plexus, where the bulk of doublelabeled 
    structures may be located.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s192">Nevertheless, our observations indicate that 
    catecholaminergic axons contribute to all of the CGlv terminal 
    fields labeled with PHA-L from the DMM, NTS, and VLM.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s193">Although it is difficult to exclude the possibility that 
    there may be a differential contribution by catecholaminergic axons 
    to some portion of these fields, it is likely that the medullary 
    innervation of the CG arises from mixed catecholaminergic and 
    non-catecholaminergic axons throughout.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s194">Medullary 
    catecholaminergic afferents to the CG</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s195">Previous studies examining medullary afferents to the CG 
    in the rat (Beitz, &apos;82; Morrell and Pfaff, &apos;83; Hamba et 
    al., &apos;90) are difficult to compare with our own results, as 
    the injections of retrograde tracers vary with respect to 
    rostrocaudal and dorso-ventral level of placement.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s196">We deliberately placed our injections into the region of 
    densest catecholaminergic innervation, in the ventrolateral 
    division of the CG at the intercollicular level.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s197">These experiments resulted in substantial numbers of 
    retrogradely labeled neurons in medullary cell groups that contain 
    catecholaminergic neurons, including the NTS, the DMM, and the 
    VLM.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s198">Morrell and Pfaff (&apos;83) and Hamba et al. (&apos;90) 
    reported retrograde labeling of numerous neurons in the VLM and 
    DMM, but few in the NTS.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s199">However, their injection sites were placed more dorsally 
    in the CGlv, causing retrograde labeling of neurons in the 
    ventromedial part of the caudal spinal trigeminal nucleus that was 
    not present in our experiments.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s200">Beitz (&apos;82) found retrograde labeling of neurons in 
    the NTS and the VLM mainly after injections placed into the 
    lateroventral component of the CG, a finding that is consistent 
    with our own results.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s201">Kwiat and Basbaum (&apos;90) recently examined the 
    overall origin of catecholaminergic afferents to the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s202">They confirmed our preliminary report (Herbert and 
    Saper, &apos;88) that tyrosine hydroxylase-immunoreactive neurons 
    in the NTS, the DMM, and the VLM project to the CG, also 
    identifying noradrenergic neurons in the locus coeruleus and the A5 
    and A7 groups as contributing to this innervation.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s203">Previous studies employing lesions of the locus 
    coeruleus had come to conflicting conclusions concerning its 
    contribution to catecholaminergic innervation of the CG (Loizou, 
    &apos;69; Levitt and Moore, &apos;79).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s204">Our results indicate that noradrenergic fibers to the 
    PAG from the medulla enter through the lateral edge of the CG, near 
    the locus coeruleus, so that locus coeruleus lesions may have 
    disrupted, in part, the medullary afferents as well.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s205">Recently Fritschy and Grzanna (&apos;90) employed 
    anterograde transport of PHA-L combined with immunocytochemistry 
    for dopamine P-hydroxylase to identify noradrenergic innervation 
    arising from the locus coeruleus (Fritschy and Grzanna, 
    &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s206">They reported only limited innervation of the CG, which 
    largely overlaps with the noradrenergic terminal fields that we 
    found arising from the medulla.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s207">However, it would be interesting to compare directly the 
    relative innervation patterns within the CG of the pontine and 
    medullary noradrenergic afFerents.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s208">We did not address the extent to which the projections 
    from the medullary catecholaminergic cell groups to the CG 
    represent collaterals of other medullary catecholaminergic 
    projections.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s209">The same cell groups that we found innervating the CG 
    also project in the forebrain to the hypothalamus (median preoptic, 
    paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei) and in the brainstem to the 
    parabrachial nucleus (Sawchenko and Swanson, &apos;81, &apos;82; 
    Blessing et al., &apos;82; Saper et al., &apos;83; Milner et al., 
    &apos;86; Tucker et al., &apos;87; Cunningham and Sawchenko, 
    &apos;88; Cunningham et al., &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s210">In addition the C1 and C3 adrenergic groups innervate 
    the locus coeruleus, and many rostral C1 neurons innervate the 
    spinal cord (Ross et al., &apos;84; Pieribone et al., &apos;88; 
    Minson et al., &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s211">Double retrograde labeling combined with 
    immunocytochemistry to tyrosine hydroxylase indicates that many of 
    the catecholaminergic neurons in the medulla that project to the CG 
    also send axon collaterals to the spinal cord (Kwiat and Basbaum, 
    &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s212">These results are consistent with earlier studies 
    showing that a large proportion of baroreceptive Cl cells that send 
    axons to the spinal cord also have ascending collaterals (Haselton 
    and Guyenet, &apos;go), but very few of these apparently reach the 
    hypothalamus (Tucker et al., &apos;87).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s213">These observations suggest that the CG may be a major 
    terminal field for adrenergic s o n s from sympathoexcitatory 
    neurons.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s214">Topographic organization 
    of the CG and its connections</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s215">The anatomical parcellation of the CG used in this study 
    was derived from the cytoarchitectonic studies of Beitz (&apos;82, 
    &apos;85; Beitz and Shepard, &apos;85) and Paxinos and Watson 
    (&apos;86).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s216">Our results in general support their observations 
    dividing the CG into dorsal, laterodorsal, lateroventral, and 
    medial components.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s217">Staining for NADPH-diaphorase demonstrated the sharp 
    distinction between the CGld and the adjacent CGd and CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s218">These borders were also respected by the medullary 
    afferents that we traced: axons from the DMM and NTS were clearly 
    concentrated in the ventral part of the CGlv whereas the VLM 
    afferents were densest in the dorsal part of the CGlv and in the 
    CGd.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s219">None of the medullary fields we injected projected to 
    the CGld, nor did this latter subdivision receive much 
    catecholaminergic innervation.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s220">The CGd, on the other hand, received an extensive 
    projection from the VLM, but none of it was catecholaminergic.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s221">We also identified a rostro-caudal gradient within the 
    medullary afferents to the CG.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s222">The NTS projection to the ventral part of the CGlv was 
    most dense caudally, as was the VLM projection to the dorsal 
    CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s223">The DMM projection was more evenly distributed in a 
    rostro-caudal dimension.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s224">These observations are consistent with the findings of 
    Beitz (&apos;821, who noted that larger numbers of NTS and VLM 
    cells were retrogradely labeled from caudal as opposed to rostral 
    CGlv sites.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s225">Other afferents to the CG follow this same pattern of 
    topographical organization.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s226">The NTS terminal zone in the caudal ventral CGlv 
    overlaps with afferents from the infralimbic cortex (Hurley et al., 
    &apos;91; Shipley et al., &apos;911, the central nucleus of the 
    amygdala (Gray and Magnuson, &apos;87; Rizvi et al., &apos;911, the 
    substantia innominata (Grove, &apos;88); the median preoptic 
    nucleus (Swanson et al., &apos;87; Simerly and Swanson, &apos;881, 
    the lateral hypothalamus (Saper et al., &apos;79; Luiten et al., 
    &apos;87; Allen and Cechetto, &apos;90; Veening et al., &apos;901, 
    and the lateral parabrachial nucleus (Saper and Loewy, &apos;80; 
    Beitz, &apos;82).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s227">As catecholaminergic neurons in the NTS receive direct 
    vagal afferents (Sumal et al., &apos;83), it is likely that the 
    caudal ventral CGlv is concerned with autonomic control.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s228">The caudodorsal CGlv, which is the terminal field for 
    VLM afferents, also receives inputs from forebrain structures 
    including the prelimbic cortex (Hurley et al., &apos;911, the 
    central nucleus of the amygdala (Gray and Magnuson, &apos;87; Rivzi 
    et al., &apos;911, the dorsomedial nucleus of the hypothalamus 
    (Luiten et al., &apos;87; ter Horst and Luiten, &apos;861, the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus (Saper et al., &apos;76; 
    Luiten et al., &apos;87; Dornan et al., &apos;go), the dorsal 
    premammillary nucleus, and the zona incerta (Luiten et al., 
    &apos;87).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s229">In addition, it receives somatosensory (presumably 
    nociceptive) information from lamina I of the spinal cord (Mehler 
    et al., &apos;60; Swett et al., &apos;85; Yezierski, &apos;88) and 
    the spinal trigeminal nucleus (Hamba et al., &apos;go), suggesting 
    a role in somatosensory processing.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s230">Efferents from the CGlv reach the same hypothalamic and 
    basal forebrain sites that project to it (Tohyama et al., &apos;78; 
    Berk and Finkelstein, &apos;82; Eberhart et al., &apos;85; Hamba et 
    al., &apos;90); the intralaminar, paraventricular, and reticular 
    nuclei of the thalamus (Eberhart et al., &apos;85; Carstens et al., 
    &apos;90; Tohyama et al., &apos;78); the parabrachial nucleus (Moga 
    et al., &apos;90) and nucleus of the solitary tract (Bandler and 
    Tork, &apos;87; Herbert and Saper, unpublished data); and the 
    medullary raphe (Abols and Basbaum, &apos;81; Beitz et al., 
    &apos;83) and reticular formation (Sakuma and Pfaff, &apos;80; van 
    Bockstaele et al., &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s231">Little is known, however, about the topographic 
    arrangement of these projection neurons with respect to afferents 
    to the CGlv.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="27" class="discussion.subtitle"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s232">Functional organization 
    of the CG</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s233">The topographic relationships of the CG have been 
    associated with a variety of physiological responses.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s234">Nociceptiue afferents from the spinal cord and spinal 
    trigeminal nucleus terminate primarily in the dorsal part of the 
    CGlv (Mehler et al., &apos;60; Yezierski, &apos;88; Hambaet al., 
    &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s235">On the other hand, analgesic responses can be recorded 
    during stimulation of the ventral CGlv as well as the areas dorsal 
    to it (Ness and Gebhart, &apos;871, and the descending projection 
    to the nucleus raphe magnus, which has been associated with this 
    response, originates from the ventral CGlv (Abols and Basbaum, 
    &apos;81; Beitz et al., &apos;83).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s236">Hence it is likely that intrinsic connections between 
    the different subdivisions of the CG may be involved in mediating 
    the modulation of nociception.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s237">It would be interesting to determine whether specific 
    sets of catecholaminergic terminals in the CG play a role in this 
    process.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s238">The CG has also been implicated in a variety of 
    behavioral processes, including sexual receptivity in female rats 
    (Sakuma and Pfaff, &apos;80).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s239">The lordotic posture, which facilitates mounting by male 
    rats, is disrupted by lesions of the CG in estrogen-primed 
    females.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s240">The lordosis response is facilitated by 
    estrogen-sensitive neurons in the ventrolatera1 part of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus (see Sakuma and Pfaff, 
    &apos;79).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s241">A projection to the CG from the ventrolateral part of 
    the ventromedial nucleus, in part originating from enkephalin and 
    substance P immunoreactive neurons, has been identified (Saper et 
    al., &apos;76; Krieger et al., &apos;79; Akaishi and Sakuma, 
    &apos;86; Yamano et al., &apos;86; Chung et al., &apos;90; Dornan 
    et al., &apos;90).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s242">Most of these axons end in the dorsal and medial parts 
    of the CGlv.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s243">On the other hand, descending projections to parts of 
    the gigantocellular and magnocellular medullary reticular formation 
    that are important in motor response primarily originate from 
    neurons in the more ventral CGlv (Sakuma and Pfaff, &apos;80).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s244">Furthermore, injections of excitatory amino acids, or 
    antagonists of GABA, into the CG, particularly the CGlv, produce 
    behavioral hyperresponsiveness to innocuous cutaneous stimuli on 
    the contralateral body surface (Bandler et al., &apos;85a,b).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s245">Thus, the descending sensory and motor connections of 
    the CGlv may allow it to modulate a variety of behavioral 
    responses.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s246">The interactions of catecholaminergic inputs with other 
    afferents to the CGlv may allow them to influence behavioral 
    responses regulated by the CG.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s247">A marked increase in blood pressure and heart rate is 
    often associated with behavioral responses elicited by injections 
    of excitatory agents into the CGlv of the cat (McDougall et al., 
    &apos;85; Carrive et al., &apos;88, &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s248">Although these response patterns are similar to the 
    &quot;defense reaction&quot; elicited by electrical stimulation of 
    parts of the hypothalamus and amygdala, more careful dissection of 
    the functional anatomy of the CG has demonstrated that the CG 
    responses are more complex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s249">Stimulation sites in the dorsal part of the rostral CGlv 
    in the cat demonstrate increases in arterial pressure and iliac and 
    renal artery resistance, accompanied by behavior characterized as 
    &quot;threat display&quot; (Carrive et al., &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s250">The most responsive site for this pattern corresponds 
    well with the terminal field for catecholaminergic axons from the 
    VLM in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s251">Injection of retrograde tracers into the caudal part of 
    the subretrofacial region in the cat (the rostral VLM at 
    approximately the same level as our PHA-L injections) labeled 
    neurons in the rostral CGlv (Carrive et al., &apos;88, &apos;891, 
    and injections of anterograde tracer into this part of the CGlv 
    labeled axons innervating the subretrofacial region (Carrive et 
    al., &apos;88).</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s252">Injection of retrograde tracer into the rostral pole of 
    the subretrofacial nucleus in the cat labeled neurons in the CGd 
    and the caudal ventral part of the CGlv (Carrive et al., 
    &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s253">We found anterogradely labeled axons from the VLM in the 
    CGd of the rat, but none of these were catecholaminergic, and no 
    cardiovascular responses are elicited in this area in the cat 
    (Bandler et al., &apos;85a,b; Carrive et al., &apos;88, 
    &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s254">The caudal ventral CGlv is preferentially innervated by 
    the NTS, including theA2 cell group in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s255">Electrical or chemical stimulation in this area in the 
    cat produces a distinct pattern of increased arterial pressure 
    and&apos;renal artery resistance, with a fall in iliac artery 
    resistance (i.e., increased hindlimb blood flow) and an escape 
    behavior pattern (Carrive et al., &apos;89).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s256">Stimulation of an intermediate portion of the CGlv was 
    noted in preliminary experiments in the cat to cause a fall in 
    blood pressure and arterial resistance in both the renal and iliac 
    beds (Carrive et al., &apos;89), suggesting that the functional 
    organization of cardiovascular regulatory responses in the CG may 
    be quite complex.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s257">Similar effects produced by chemical stimulation in the 
    rat have been less extensively studied (e.g., Robinson, 
    &apos;87).</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="discussion.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s258">However, the marked innervation by catecholaminergic 
    afferents from the medulla of each of the CG sites involved in 
    cardiovascular control suggests that these inputs may play an 
    important role in cardiovascular regulation.</S>
  </Discussion>

  <Acknowledgements>

    <S avgH="28" class="acknowledgements.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s259">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s260">The authors thank Helga 
    Zillus, Quan Hue Ha, and Sabina Herbert for excellent technical 
    assistance, and Jens Frerichs (Dianova, GmbH) for the generous gift 
    of antisera from Jackson Immuno Research.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s261">This work was supported by a 
    DAAJIiNATO Research Training Fellowship to H.H</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s262">.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s263">(3001402 1530 161, the 
    Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (SFB 307), USPHS grant NS22835, 
    American Heart Association-Wyeth-Ayerst Grant-in-aid 881 120, the 
    Brain Research Foundation, and the William D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="22" class="acknowledgements.body"
     format="TimesNewRomanPSMT" id="s264">Mabie Research Fund.</S>
  </Acknowledgements>

  <References>

    <S avgH="28" class="references.heading"
     format="TimesNewRomanPS-BoldMT" id="s265">LITERATURE CITED</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s266">Ahols, LA., and A.I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s267">Basbaum (1981) Afferent connections of the rostral 
    medulla of the cat: a neural substrate for midbrain-medullary 
    interactions in the modulation ofpain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s268">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s269">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s270">Neurol. 201:285-297.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s271">Akaishi, T., and Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s272">Sakuma (1986) Projections of oestrogen-sensitive neurons 
    from the ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus of the female rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s273">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s274">Physiol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s275">(Lond.) 372:207-220.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s276">Allen, G.V., and D.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s277">Cechetto (1990) Functional and anatomical organization 
    of posterior hypothalamic cardiovascular pressor and depressor 
    sites.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s278">Soc.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s279">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s280">Abstr. 16:556.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s281">Bandler, R., A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s282">Depaulis, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s283">Vergnes (1985a) Identification of midbrain neurones 
    mediating defensive behavior in the rat by microinjections of 
    excitatory amino acids.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s284">Behav.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s285">Brain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s286">Res. 15:107-119.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s287">Bandler, R., S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s288">Prineas, and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s289">McCulloch (1985b) Further localization of midbrain 
    neurones mediating the defence reaction in the cat by 
    microinjections of excitatory amino acids.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s290">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s291">Lett. 56:311-316.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s292">Bandler, R., and I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s293">Tork (1987) Midbrain periaqueductal grey region in the 
    cat has afferent and efferent connections with solitary tract 
    nuclei.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s294">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s295">Lett. 74:l-6.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s296">Beitz, A.J. (1982) The organization of afferent 
    projections to the midbrain periaqueductal gray of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s297">Neuroscience 7:133-159.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s298">Beitz, A.J. (1985) The midbrain periaqueductal gray in 
    the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s299">I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s300">Nuclear volume, cell number, density, orientation, and 
    regional subdivisions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s301">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s302">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s303">Neurol. 237r445.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s304">Beitz, A.J., J.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s305">Clements, M.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s306">Mullett, and L.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s307">Ecklund (1986) Differential origin of hrainstem 
    serotoninergic projections to the midhrain periaqueductal gray and 
    superior colliculus of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s308">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s309">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s310">Neurol. 250:498-509.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s311">Beitz, A.J., and R.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s312">Shepard (19851 The midbrain periaqueductal the rat. 
    11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s313">AGolgi analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s314">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s315">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s316">Neurol. 237:460.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s317">Beitz, A.J., R.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s318">Shepard, and W.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s319">Wells 11983) The periaqueductal gray-raphe magnus 
    projection contains somatostatin neurotensin and serotonin hut not 
    cholecystokinin.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s320">Brain Res. 261:132-137.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s321">Berk, M.L., and J.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s322">Finkelstein (1982) Efferent connections of the lateral 
    hypothalamic area of the rat: An autoradiographic investigation.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s323">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s324">Bull. 8:511-526.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s325">Berod, A., B.K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s326">Hartman, and J.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s327">Pujol (1981) Importance of fixation in 
    immunohistochemistry: use of formaldehyde solutions at variable pN 
    for the localization of tyrosine hydrosylase.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s328">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s329">Histochem.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s330">Cytochem. 29:844850.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s331">Blessing, W.W., C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s332">Jaeger, D.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s333">Ruggiero, and D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s334">Keis (1982) Hypothalamic projections of medullary 
    catecholamine neurons in the rabbit: A combined catecholamine 
    fluorescence and HRP transport study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s335">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s336">Bull. 9:279-286.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s337">Carrive, P., R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s338">Bandler, and R.A.L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s339">Dampney (19881 Anatomical evidence that hypertension 
    associated with the defence reaction in the cat is mediated by a 
    direct projection from a restricted protion of the midbrain 
    periaqueductal grey to the subretrofacial nucleus of the 
    medulla.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s340">Brain Res. 460:339-345.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s341">Carrive, P., R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s342">Bandler, and R.A.L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s343">Dampney (1989) Viscerotopic control of regional vascular 
    beds by discrete groups of neurons within the midbrain 
    periaqueductal gray.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s344">Brain Res. 493:385-390.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s345">Carstens, E., J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s346">Leah, J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s347">Lechner, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s348">Zimmermann (1990) Demonstration of extensive brainstem 
    projections to medial and lateral thalamus and hypothalamus in the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s349">Neuroscience 35609-626.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s350">Chandler, S.D., M.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s351">Behbehani, and M.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s352">Shipley (1988) Properties of an adrenergic network in 
    the rat periaqueductal gray (PAG).</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s353">SOC.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s354">Neurosc.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s355">Abstr. 14:403.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s356">Chung, S.K., D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s357">Pfaff, and R.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s358">Cohen (1990) Projections of ventromedial hypothalamic 
    neurons to the midbrain central gray-an ultrastructural study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s359">Neuroscience 38:395408.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s360">Conti, F., P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s361">Barbaresi, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s362">Fahri (1988) Cytochrome oxidase histochemistry reveals 
    regional subdivisions in the rat periaqueductal gray matter.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s363">Neuroscience 24:629-633.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s364">Cunningham, E.T., M.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s365">Bohn, and P.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s366">Sawchenko (1990) Organization of adrenergic inputs to 
    the paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei of the hypothalamus in 
    the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s367">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s368">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s369">Neurol. 292.651-667.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s370">Cunningham, E.T., and P.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s371">Sawchenko (1988) Anatomical specificity of noradrenergic 
    inputs to the paraventricular and supraoptic nuclei of the rat 
    hypothalamus.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s372">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s373">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s374">Neurol. 274r60-76.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s375">Depaulis, A,, R.N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s376">Pechnick, and J.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s377">Liebeskind (1988) Relationship between analgesia and 
    cardiovascular changes induced by electrical stimulation of the 
    mesencephalic periaqueductal gray matter in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s378">Brain Res. 451:326-332.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s379">Dornan, W.A., T.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s380">Akesson, and P.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s381">Micevych (1990) A substance-P projection from the VMH to 
    the dorsal midbrain central grayimplication for lordosis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s382">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s383">Bull. 25:791.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s384">Eberhart, J.A., J.I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s385">Morrell, M.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s386">Krieger, and D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s387">Pfaff (1985) Au autoradiographic study of projections 
    ascending from the midbrain central gray, and from the region 
    lateral to it, in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s388">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s389">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s390">Neurol. 241;285-310.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s391">Fardin, V., J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s392">-L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s393">Oliveras, and J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s394">-M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s395">Besson (1984a) A reinvestigation of the analgesic 
    effects induced by stimulation of the periaqueductal gray matter in 
    the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s396">I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s397">The production of behavioral side effects together with 
    analgesia.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s398">Brain Res. 306r105-123.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s399">Fardin, V., J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s400">-L.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s401">Oliveras, and J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s402">-M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s403">Besson (1984b) A reinvestigation of the analgesic 
    effects induced by stimulation of the periaqueductal gray matter in 
    the rat. 11.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s404">Differential characteristics of the analgesia induced by 
    ventral and dorsal PAG stimulation.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s405">Brain Res. 306r125-139.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s406">Franklin, A.L., and W.G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s407">Filion (1985) A new technique for retarding of 
    fluorescence: DPX-BME.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s408">Stain Technol. 60:125-135.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s409">Fritschy, J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s410">-M., and R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s411">Grzanna (1990) Distribution of locus coeruleus axons 
    within the rat brainstem demonstrated by Phaseoh uulgaris 
    leucoagglutinin anterograde tracing in combination with 
    dopamine-0-hydroxylase immunofluorescence.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s412">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s413">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s414">Neurol. 293r616631.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s415">Gray, T.S., and D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s416">Magnuson (1987) Galanin-like immunoreactivity within 
    amygdaloid and hypothalamic neurons that project to the midbrain 
    central grey in rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s417">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s418">Lett. 83.264-268, Grove, E.A. (1988) Efferent 
    connections of the substantia rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s419">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s420">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s421">Neurol. 277:347-364.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s422">Hamba, M., H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s423">Hisamitsu, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s424">Muro (1990) Nociceptive projection from tooth pulp to 
    the lateral hypothalamus in rats.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s425">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s426">Bull. 25.355364.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s427">Haselton, J.R., and P.G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s428">Guyenet (1990) Ascending collaterals of medullary 
    barosensitive neurons and Cl cells in rats.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s429">Am.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s430">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s431">Physiol. 258:R1051R1063.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s432">Herbert, H., M.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s433">Moga, and C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s434">Saper (1990) Connections of theparabrachial nucleus with 
    the nucleus of the solitary tract and the medullary reticular 
    formation in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s435">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s436">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s437">Neurol. 293.540-580.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s438">Herbert, H., and C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s439">Saper (1988) Catecholaminergic projection from the 
    medulla to the midbrain central gray matter.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s440">Soc.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s441">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s442">Abstr. 14r404.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s443">Hokfelt, T., 0.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s444">Johansson, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s445">Goldstein (1984a) Central catecholamine neurons as 
    revealed by immunohistochemistry with special reference to 
    adrenaline neurons.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s446">In A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s447">Bjorklund and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s448">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s449">Vol. 2: Classical Transmitters in the CNS, Part I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s450">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 157-276.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s451">Hurley, K.M., H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s452">Herbert, M.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s453">Moga, and C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s454">Saper (1991) Efferent projections of the infralimbic 
    cortex of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s455">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s456">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s457">Neurol., 308.249-276.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s458">Krieger, M.S., L.C.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s459">Conrad, study of the efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s460">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s461">Neurol. 183:785-816.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s462">Kwiat, G.C., and A.I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s463">Basbaum (1990) Organization of tyrosine 
    hydroxylaseimmunoreactive and serotonin-immunoreactive brainstem 
    neurons with axon collaterals to the periaqueductal gray and the 
    spinal cord in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s464">Brain Res. 528r83-94.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s465">Levitt, P., and R.Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s466">Moore (1979) Origin and organization of brainstem 
    catecholaminergic innervation in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s467">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s468">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s469">Neurol. 186:505-528.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s470">Lindvall, O., and A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s471">Bjorklund (1974) The organization of the ascending 
    catecholamine neuron systems in the rat brain as revealed by the 
    glyoxylic acid fluorescence method.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s472">Acta Physiol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s473">Scand. 412: 1-48.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s474">Loizou, L.A. (1969) Projections of the nucleus locus 
    coeruleus in the albino rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s475">Brain Res. 15563-566.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s476">Luiten, P.G.M., G.J. ter Horst, and A.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s477">Steffens (1987) The hypothalamus, intrinsic connections 
    and outflow pathways to the endocrine system in relation to the 
    control of feeding and metabolism.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s478">Prog.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s479">Neurobiol. 28:l-54.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s480">Marchand, J.E., and N.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s481">Hagino (1983) Afferents to the periaqueductal in the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s482">A horseradish peroxidase study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s483">Neuroscience 9:95-106.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s484">MeDougall, A,, R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s485">Dampney, and R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s486">Bandler (1985) Cardiovascular components of the defence 
    reaction evoked by excitation of neuronal cell bodies in the 
    midbrain periaqueductal grey of the cat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s487">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s488">Lett. 60:69-75.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s489">Mehler, W.R., M.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s490">Feferman, and W.J.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s491">Nauta (1960) Ascending axon degeneration following 
    anterolateral cordotomy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s492">An experimental study in the monkey.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s493">Brain 83:718-752.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s494">Meller, S.T., and B.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s495">Dennis (1986) Afferent projections to the periaqueductal 
    gray in the rabbit.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s496">Neuroscience 19t927-964.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s497">Milner, T.A., T.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s498">Joh, and V.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s499">Pickel (1986) Tyrosine hydroxylase in the rat 
    parabrachial region: Ultrastructural localization and extrinsic 
    sources of immunoreactivity.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s500">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s501">Neurosci. 6:2585-2603.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s502">Minson, J., I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s503">Llewellyn-Smith, A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s504">Neville, P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s505">Somogyi, and J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s506">Chalmers (1990) Quantitative analyses of spinally 
    projecting adrenaline-synthesising neurons of C1, C2, and C3 groups 
    in rat medulla oblongata.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s507">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s508">Auton.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s509">New.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s510">Syst. 30:209-220.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s511">Moga, M.M., H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s512">Herbert, K.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s513">Hurley, Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s514">Yasui, T.S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s515">Gray, and C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s516">Saper (1990) Organization of cortical, basal forebrain, 
    and hypothalamic afferents to the parabrachial nucleus in the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s517">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s518">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s519">Neurol. 295624-661.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s520">Moore, R.Y., and J.P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s521">Card (1984) Noradrenaline-containing neuron systems.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s522">In A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s523">Bjorklund and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s524">Hokfelt (eds): Handbook of Chemical Neuroanatomy.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s525">Vol. 2: Classical Transmitters in the CNS, Part I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s526">Amsterdam: Elsevier, pp. 123-156.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s527">Morgan, M.M., J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s528">-H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s529">Sohn, and J.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s530">Liebeskind (1989) Stimulation of the periaqueductal gray 
    matter inhibits nociception at the supraspinal as well as spinal 
    level.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s531">Brain Res. 502.61-66.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s532">Morrell, J.I., L.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s533">Greenberger, and D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s534">Pfaff (1981) Hypothalamic, other diencephalic, and 
    telencephalic neurons that project to the dorsal midbrain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s535">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s536">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s537">Neurol. 201r589-620.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s538">Morrell, J.I., and D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s539">Pfaff (1983) Retrograde HRP identification of neurons in 
    the rhombencephalon and spinal cord of the rat that project to the 
    dorsal mesencephalon.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s540">Am.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s541">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s542">Anat. 167:229-240.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s543">Ness, T.J., and G.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s544">Gebhart (1987) Quantitative comparison of inhibition of 
    visceral and cutaneous spinal nociceptive transmission from the 
    midbrain and medulla in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s545">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s546">Neurophysiol. 58.850-865.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s547">Nichols, D.S., B.E.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s548">Thorn, G.G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s549">Berntson (1989) Opiate and serotonergic mechanisms of 
    stimulation-produced analgesia within the periaqueductal gray.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s550">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s551">Bull. 22717-724.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s552">Paxinos, G., and C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s553">Watson (1986) The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic 
    Coordinates.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s554">Sydney: Academic Press.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s555">Pieribone, V.A., G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s556">Aston-Jones, and M.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s557">Bohn (1988) Adrenergic and non-adrenergic neurons in the 
    C1 and C3 areas project to locus coeruleus: a fluorescent double 
    labeling study.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s558">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s559">Lett. 85,297-303.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s560">Rizvi, T.A., M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s561">Ennis, M.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s562">Behbehani, and M.T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s563">Shipley (1991) Connections between the central nucleus 
    of the amygdala and the midbrain periaqueductal gray: Topography 
    and reciprocity.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s564">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s565">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s566">Neurol. 303.121-131.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s567">Robinson, S.E. (1987) Cardiovascular effects of 
    cholinergic agents in the ventral-lateral midbrain periaqueductal 
    gray of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s568">Neuropharmacology 26:1701-1706.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s569">Ross, C.A., D.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s570">Ruggiero, T.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s571">Joh, H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s572">Park, and D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s573">Reis (1984) Rostra1 ventrolateral medulla: selective 
    projections to the thoracic autonomic cell column from the region 
    containing C1 neurons.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s574">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s575">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s576">Neurol. 228.168-184.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s577">Ruggiero, D.A., C.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s578">Ross, M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s579">Anwar, D.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s580">Park, T.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s581">Joh, and D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s582">Reis (1985) Distribution of neurons containing 
    phenylethanolamine N-methyltransferase in 239: 127-154.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s583">Sakuma, Y., and D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s584">Pfaff (1979) Facilitation of female reproductive 
    behavior from mesencephalic central gray in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s585">Am.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s586">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s587">Physiol. 237:R278-R284.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s588">Sakuma, Y., and D.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s589">Pfaff (1980) Cells of origin of medullar projections in 
    central gray of rat mesencephalon.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s590">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s591">Neurophysiol. 44:1002-1011.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s592">Saper, C.B., and A.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s593">Loewy (1980) Efferent connections of the parabrachial 
    nucleus in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s594">Brain Res. 197:291-317.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s595">Saper, C.B., D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s596">Reis, and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s597">Joh (1983) Medullary catecholamine inputs to the 
    anteroventral third ventricular cardiovascular regulatory region in 
    the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s598">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s599">Lett. 4.2285-291.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s600">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s601">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s602">Cowan (1976) The efferent connections of the 
    ventromedial nucleus of the hypothalamus of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s603">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s604">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s605">Neurol. 169:409-442.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s606">Saper, C.B., L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s607">Swanson, and W.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s608">Cowan 11979) An autoradiographic study of the efferent 
    connections of the lateral hypothalmic area in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s609">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s610">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s611">Neurol. 183:689-706.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s612">Sawchenko, P.E., and L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s613">Swanson (1981) Central noradrenergic pathways for the 
    integration of hypothalamic neuroendocrine and autonomic 
    responses.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s614">Science 21 4: 685-687.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s615">Sawchenko, P.E., and L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s616">Swanson (19821 The organization of noradrenergic 
    pathways from the brainstem to the paraventricular and supraoptic 
    nuclei in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s617">Brain Res. 4,275-325.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s618">Scherer-Singler, U., S.R.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s619">Vincent, H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s620">Kimura, and E.G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s621">McGeer (1983) Demonstration of a unique population of 
    neurons with NADPHdiaphorase histochemistry.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s622">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s623">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s624">Methods 9:229-234.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s625">Shipley, M.T., M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s626">Ennis, T.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s627">Rizvi, and M.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s628">Behbehani 11991) Topographical specificity of forebrain 
    inputs to the midbrain periaqueductal gray: evidence for discrete 
    longitudinally organized input columns.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s629">In A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s630">Depaulis and A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s631">Bandler (eds): The Midbrain Periaqueductal Gray Matter 
    (in press).</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s632">Simerly, R.B., and L.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s633">Swanson (1988) Projections of the medial preoptic 
    nucleus: A Phuseolus uulguris leucoagglutinin anterograde 
    tract-tracing study in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s634">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s635">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s636">Neurol. 270:209-242.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s637">Skultety, F.M. 119631 Stimulation of periaqueductal 
    mus.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s638">Arch.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s639">Neurol. 8:609-620.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s640">Skultety, F.M., and T.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s641">Gray (1962) Experimental hyperphagia following 
    destructive midbrain lesions.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s642">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s643">Neurol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s644">I2394-401.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s645">Sumal, K.K., W.W.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s646">Blessing, T.H.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s647">Joh, D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s648">Reis, and V.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s649">Pickel (1983) Synaptic interaction of vagal afferents 
    and catecholaminergic neurons in the rat nucleus tractus 
    solitarius.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s650">Brain Res. 277:31-40.</S>
    <BR />

    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s651">Swanson, L.W., and B.K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s652">Hartman (1975) The central adrenergic system.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s653">An immunofluorescence study of the location of cell 
    bodies and their efferent connections in the rat utilizing 
    dopamine-B-hydroxylase as a marker.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s654">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s655">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s656">Neurol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s657">I63:467-506.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s658">Swanson, L.W., G.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s659">Mogensen, R.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s660">Simerly, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s661">Wu (1987) Anatomical and electrophysiological evidence 
    for a projection from the medial preoptic area to the mesencephalic 
    and subthalamic locomotor regions in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s662">Brain Res. 405:10%122.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s663">Swett, J.E., S.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s664">McMahon, and P.D.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s665">Wall (1985) Longascendingprojections to the midbrain 
    from cells of lamina I and nucleus of the dorsolateral funiculus of 
    the rat spinal cord.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s666">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s667">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s668">Neurol. 238,401-416.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s669">Horst, G.J., and P.G.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s670">Luiten (1986) The projections of the dorsomedial 
    hypothalamic nucleus in the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s671">Brain Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s672">Bull. 16,231-248.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s673">Tohyama, M., K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s674">Satoh, T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s675">Sakumoto, Y .</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s676">Kimoto, Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s677">Takahashi, K.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s678">Yamamoto, and T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s679">Itakura (1978) organization and projections of the 
    neurons in the dorsal tegmental area of the rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s680">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s681">Hirnforsch.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s682">Z9:165176.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s683">Tucker, D.C., C.B.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s684">Saper, D.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s685">Ruggiero, and D.J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s686">Reis (1987) Organization of central adrenergic pathways: 
    I.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s687">Relationships of ventrolateral medullary projections to 
    the hypothalamus and spinal cord.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s688">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s689">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s690">Neurol. 259:591-603.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s691">Ungerstedt, U. 11971) Stereotaxic mapping of the 
    monoamine pathways in the rat brain.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s692">Acta Physiol.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s693">Scand. 95(Suppl. 367~:1-48.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s694">Bockstaele, E.J., V.A.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s695">Pieribone, and G.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s696">Aston-Jones (19891 Diverse afferents converge on the 
    nucleus paragigantocellularis in the rat ventrolateral medulla: 
    retrograde and anterograde tracing studies.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s697">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s698">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s699">Neurol. 290:561-584.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s700">Veening, J.G., P.C.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s701">Stroeken, P.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s702">Posthuma, and H.W.M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s703">Steinhusch (1990) A comparison of the descending 
    hypothalamic and some other diencephalic projections to the nucleus 
    raphe magnus and the mesencephalic periaqueductal gray in the 
    rat.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s704">Neurosci.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s705">Res.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s706">Commun. 7:123.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s707">Weiss, G.F., and S.F.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s708">Leibowitz (1985) Efferent projections from the 
    paraventricular nucleus mediating alpha2-noradrenergic feeding.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s709">Brain Res. 347:225-238.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s710">Yamano, M., S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s711">Inagaki, S.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s712">Kito, T.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s713">Matsuzaki, Y.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s714">Shinohara, and M.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s715">Tohyama 11986) Enkephalinergic projection from the 
    ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus to the midbrain central gray 
    matter in the rat: an immunocytochemical analysis.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s716">Brain Res. 398:33 7-346.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s717">Yezierski, R.P. (1988) Spinomesencephalic tract: 
    projections from the lumbosacral spinal cord of the rat, cat, and 
    monkey.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s718">J.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s719">Comp.</S>
     
    <S avgH="17" class="references.body" format="TimesNewRomanPSMT"
     id="s720">Neurol. 267:131-146.</S>
  </References>

</File>

